<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225480A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230707" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225480</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17577258</doc-number>
<date>20220117</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>17</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>45</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>29</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>45</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>29</main-group>
<subgroup>023</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="zddvou67ecgxl">Trimmings Collecting Nail Clipping Device</invention-title>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Pride</last-name>
<first-name>Darnell</first-name>
<address>
<city>Cookville</city>
<state>TN</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Pride</last-name>
<first-name>Darnell</first-name>
<address>
<city>Cookville</city>
<state>TN</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A trimmings collecting nail clipping device for hygienic nail trimming includes a lower blade extending from a first end of a bottom plate. Pairs of first and second posts extend from the bottom plate proximate to the lower blade and a second end of the bottom plate, respectively. A first terminus of a center plate is engaged to the second posts distal from the bottom plate. The center plate extends between and past the first posts. An upper blade, which is engaged to the center plate, and the lower blade define a gap. A lever is hingedly engaged to the first posts distal from the bottom plate. Upon levering of the lever, a nail positioned in the gap is severed. A panel is engageable to the bottom plate to define an interior space that receives a clipping generated upon severing of the nail.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="146.22mm" wi="207.60mm" file="US20230225480A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="205.32mm" wi="143.43mm" file="US20230225480A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="183.47mm" wi="160.02mm" file="US20230225480A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="227.50mm" wi="77.55mm" file="US20230225480A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="223.44mm" wi="82.80mm" file="US20230225480A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="224.20mm" wi="166.71mm" file="US20230225480A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading level="1" id="h-0001">(B) CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">Not Applicable</p>
<heading level="1" id="h-0002">(C) STATEMENT REGARDING FEDERALLY SPONSORED RESEARCH OR DEVELOPMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Not Applicable</p>
<heading level="1" id="h-0003">(D) THE NAMES OF THE PARTIES TO A JOINT RESEARCH AGREEMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Not Applicable</p>
<heading level="1" id="h-0004">(E) INCORPORATION-BY-REFERENCE OF MATERIAL SUBMITTED ON A COMPACT DISC OR AS A TEXT FILE VIA THE OFFICE ELECTRONIC FILING SYSTEM</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Not Applicable</p>
<heading level="1" id="h-0005">(F) STATEMENT REGARDING PRIOR DISCLOSURES BY THE INVENTOR OR JOINT INVENTOR</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Not Applicable</p>
<heading level="1" id="h-0006">(G) BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<heading level="1" id="h-0007">Field of the Invention</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The disclosure relates to nail clipping devices and more particularly pertains to a new nail clipping device for hygienic nail trimming. The present invention discloses a nail clipping device comprising a lever which is engaged to, and which extends between, a pair of first posts extending from a bottom plate. A clipping is able to pass freely into an interior space defined by the bottom plate, a center plate, and a panel inserted between the bottom plate and the center plate.</p>
<heading level="1" id="h-0008">Description of Related Art Including Information Disclosed Under 37 CFR 1.97 and 1.98</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The prior art relates to nail clipping devices. Prior art nail clipping devices may comprise clippers with apertures in their bottom plates leading to containers, containers positionable around all but the levers of clippers, and clippers having substantially closed sides. The design of prior clippers is not optimal for collection of clippings as impediments to movement of the clippings are present. More specifically, most prior art nail clipping devices have a center post extending from the bottom plate, with a center plate and lever being engaged to the center post. What is lacking in the prior art is a nail clipping device comprising a lever which is engaged to, and which extends between, a pair of first posts extending from a bottom plate. A clipping is able to pass freely into an interior space defined by the bottom plate, a center plate, and a panel inserted between the bottom plate and the center plate.</p>
<heading level="1" id="h-0009">(H) BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">An embodiment of the disclosure meets the needs presented above by generally comprising a lower blade, which is engaged to and extends from a first end of a bottom plate. A pair of first posts and a pair of second posts are engaged to and extend from the bottom plate proximate to the lower blade and a second end of the bottom plate, respectively. A center plate is engaged by a first terminus to the second posts distal from the bottom plate. The center plate extends between and past the first posts. The center plate comprises spring steel. An upper blade is engaged to a second terminus of the center plate and extends toward the lower blade. The upper blade and the lower blade define a gap. A lever is hingedly engaged to the first posts distal from the bottom plate. The lever and the bottom plate bracket the center plate. The lever is configured to be levered so that a nail positioned in the gap is severed by the upper blade contacting the lower blade. A panel is selectively engageable to the bottom plate so that the panel, the bottom plate, and the center plate define an interior space. The interior space is configured to receive a clipping generated upon severing of the nail.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">There has thus been outlined, rather broadly, the more important features of the disclosure in order that the detailed description thereof that follows may be better understood, and in order that the present contribution to the art may be better appreciated. There are additional features of the disclosure that will be described hereinafter and which will form the subject matter of the claims appended hereto.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The objects of the disclosure, along with the various features of novelty which characterize the disclosure, are pointed out with particularity in the claims annexed to and forming a part of this disclosure.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading level="1" id="h-0010">I BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF SEVERAL VIEWS OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The disclosure will be better understood and objects other than those set forth above will become apparent when consideration is given to the following detailed description thereof. Such description makes reference to the annexed drawings wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is an isometric perspective view of a trimmings collecting nail clipping device according to an embodiment of the disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a side view of an embodiment of the disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a front view of an embodiment of the disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is an in-use view of an embodiment of the disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is a bottom view of an embodiment of the disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is an exploded view of an embodiment of the disclosure. Center plate shown detached from second posts for clarity.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading level="1" id="h-0011">(J) DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">With reference now to the drawings, and in particular to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> through <b>6</b></figref> thereof, a new nail clipping device embodying the principles and concepts of an embodiment of the disclosure and generally designated by the reference numeral <b>10</b> will be described.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">As best illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> through <b>6</b></figref>, the trimmings collecting nail clipping device <b>10</b> generally comprises a lower blade <b>12</b>, which is engaged to and extends from a first end <b>14</b> of a bottom plate <b>16</b>. A pair of first posts <b>18</b> and a pair of second posts <b>20</b> are engaged to and extend from the bottom plate <b>16</b> proximate to the lower blade <b>12</b> and a second end <b>22</b> of the bottom plate <b>16</b>, respectively, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>. The present invention also anticipates the pair of second posts <b>20</b> comprising a single plate (not shown) engaged to and extending from the bottom plate.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">A center plate <b>24</b> is engaged by a first terminus <b>26</b> to the second posts <b>20</b> distal from the bottom plate <b>16</b>. The center plate <b>24</b> extends between and past the first posts <b>18</b>. The center plate <b>24</b> comprises spring steel. An upper blade <b>28</b> is engaged to a second terminus <b>30</b> of the center plate <b>24</b> and extends toward the lower blade <b>12</b>. The upper blade <b>28</b> and lower blade <b>12</b> define a gap <b>32</b>. The upper blade <b>28</b> and the lower blade <b>12</b> may be convexly arcuate, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, so that the upper blade <b>28</b> and the lower blade <b>12</b> complement a curvature of the nail.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">A lever <b>38</b> is hingedly engaged to the first posts <b>18</b> distal from the bottom plate <b>16</b>. The lever <b>38</b> and the bottom plate <b>16</b> bracket the center plate <b>24</b>. The lever <b>38</b> is configured to be levered so that a nail positioned in the gap <b>32</b> is severed by the upper blade <b>28</b> contacting the lower blade <b>12</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The lever <b>38</b> comprises a first section <b>40</b> and a second section <b>42</b>. The first section <b>40</b> is hingedly engaged to the pair of first posts <b>18</b> and is substantially parallel to the center plate <b>24</b> when the lever <b>38</b> is in an unhinged position. The second section <b>42</b> extends transversely from the first section <b>40</b> distal from the pair of first posts <b>18</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">A pair of hinge pins <b>44</b> is engaged to the lever <b>38</b>. Each of a pair of pin holes <b>46</b> is positioned in a respective first post <b>18</b> distal from the bottom plate <b>16</b>. Each hinge pin <b>44</b> is positioned in an associated pin hole <b>46</b> so that the lever <b>38</b> is hingedly engaged to the pair of first posts <b>18</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">A panel <b>48</b> is selectively engageable to the bottom plate <b>16</b> so that the panel <b>48</b>, the bottom plate <b>16</b>, and the center plate <b>24</b> define an interior space <b>50</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>. The interior space <b>50</b> is configured to receive a clipping generated upon severing of the nail. The panel <b>48</b> comprises an end piece <b>52</b> and a pair of side pieces <b>54</b>. Each side piece <b>54</b> is engaged to and extends substantially perpendicularly from a respective opposed edge <b>56</b> of the end piece <b>52</b>. The panel <b>48</b> is slidable between the bottom plate <b>16</b> and the center plate <b>24</b> until the end piece <b>52</b> abuts the pair of second posts <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Each of a pair of rails <b>58</b> is engaged to the bottom plate <b>16</b> proximate to a respective opposing edge <b>60</b> of the bottom plate <b>16</b>. The rail <b>58</b> extends from a respective second post <b>20</b> to proximate to an associated first post <b>18</b>. The rail <b>58</b> and the associated first post <b>18</b> define a tab slot <b>62</b>. Each of a pair of tabs <b>64</b> is engaged to and extends transversely from a lower edge <b>66</b> of a respective side piece <b>54</b> distal from the end piece <b>52</b>. The tab <b>64</b> is selectively insertable into a respective tab slot <b>62</b> to removably engage the panel <b>48</b> to the bottom plate <b>16</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Each of a pair of flaps <b>68</b> is engaged to a respective opposed side <b>70</b> of the center plate <b>24</b>. The flap <b>68</b> is positioned between the second terminus <b>30</b> of the center plate <b>24</b> and an associated first post <b>18</b>. The flaps <b>68</b> are resiliently deformable and are configured to retain the clipping between the center plate <b>24</b> and the bottom plate <b>16</b> prior to the clipping entering the interior space <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">In use, the trimmings collecting nail clipping device <b>10</b> is grasped in digits of a hand of a user, typically with the bottom plate <b>16</b> resting on fingers of the hand and with a thumb of the hand positioned upon the lever <b>38</b>. A nail then is inserted into the gap <b>32</b> and the lever <b>38</b> is levered to sever the nail. A clipping generated upon severing of the nail is prevented from becoming a projectile by the pair of flaps <b>68</b>. The clipping enters the interior space <b>50</b> upon tilting of the trimmings collecting nail clipping device <b>10</b>. Upon completion of nail trimming, or when convenient to the user, the panel <b>48</b> can be separated from the bottom plate <b>16</b> to empty the clippings.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">With respect to the above description then, it is to be realized that the optimum dimensional relationships for the parts of an embodiment enabled by the disclosure, to include variations in size, materials, shape, form, function and manner of operation, assembly and use, are deemed readily apparent and obvious to one skilled in the art, and all equivalent relationships to those illustrated in the drawings and described in the specification are intended to be encompassed by an embodiment of the disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Therefore, the foregoing is considered as illustrative only of the principles of the disclosure. Further, since numerous modifications and changes will readily occur to those skilled in the art, it is not desired to limit the disclosure to the exact construction and operation shown and described, and accordingly, all suitable modifications and equivalents may be resorted to, falling within the scope of the disclosure. In this patent document, the word &#x201c;comprising&#x201d; is used in its non-limiting sense to mean that items following the word are included, but items not specifically mentioned are not excluded. A reference to an element by the indefinite article &#x201c;a&#x201d; does not exclude the possibility that more than one of the element is present, unless the context clearly requires that there be only one of the elements.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>I claim:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A trimmings collecting nail clipping device comprising:
<claim-text>a bottom plate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a lower blade engaged to and extending from a first end of the bottom plate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of first posts engaged to and extending from the bottom plate proximate to the lower blade;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of second posts engaged to and extending from the bottom plate proximate to a second end of the bottom plate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a center plate having a first terminus engaged to the second posts distal from the bottom plate, the center plate extending between and past the first posts, the center plate comprising spring steel;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an upper blade engaged to a second terminus of the center plate and extending toward the lower blade defining a gap;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a lever hingedly engaged to the first posts distal from the bottom plate, such that the lever and the bottom plate bracket the center plate, wherein the lever is configured for levering such that a nail positioned in the gap is severed by the upper blade contacting the lower blade; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a panel selectively engageable to the bottom plate, such that the panel, the bottom plate, and the center plate define an interior space, wherein the interior space is configured for receiving a clipping generated upon severing of the nail.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The trimmings collecting nail clipping device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the upper blade and the lower blade are convexly arcuate, such that the upper blade and the lower blade complement a curvature of the nail.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The trimmings collecting nail clipping device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the lever comprises:
<claim-text>a first section hingedly engaged to the pair of first posts, the first section being substantially parallel to the center plate when the lever is in an unhinged position; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second section extending transversely from the first section distal from the pair of first posts.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The trimmings collecting nail clipping device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further including:
<claim-text>a pair of hinge pins engaged to the lever; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of pin holes, each pin hole being positioned in a respective first post distal from the bottom plate, each hinge pin being positioned in an associated pin hole, such that the lever is hingedly engaged to the pair of first posts.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The trimmings collecting nail clipping device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the panel comprises:
<claim-text>an end piece; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of side pieces, each side piece being engaged to and extending substantially perpendicularly from a respective opposed edge of the end piece, such that the panel is slidable between the bottom plate and the center plate until the end piece abuts the pair of second posts.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The trimmings collecting nail clipping device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, further including:
<claim-text>a pair of rails, each rail being engaged to the bottom plate proximate to a respective opposing edge of the bottom plate, the rail extending from a respective second post to proximate to an associated first post, such that the rail and the associated first post define a tab slot; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of tabs, each tab being engaged to and extending transversely from a lower edge of a respective side piece distal from the end piece, such that the tab is selectively insertable into a respective tab slot for removably engaging the panel to the bottom plate.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The trimmings collecting nail clipping device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further including a pair of flaps, each flap being engaged to a respective opposed side of the center plate, the flap being positioned between the second terminus of the center plate and an associated first post, the flaps being resiliently deformable, wherein the pair of flaps is configured for retaining the clipping between the center plate and the bottom plate prior to the clipping entering the interior space.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. A trimmings collecting nail clipping device comprising:
<claim-text>a bottom plate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a lower blade engaged to and extending from a first end of the bottom plate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of first posts engaged to and extending from the bottom plate proximate to the lower blade;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of second posts engaged to and extending from the bottom plate proximate to a second end of the bottom plate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a center plate having a first terminus engaged to the second posts distal from the bottom plate, the center plate extending between and past the first posts, the center plate comprising spring steel;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an upper blade engaged to a second terminus of the center plate and extending toward the lower blade defining a gap, the upper blade and the lower blade being convexly arcuate, such that the upper blade and the lower blade complement a curvature of the nail;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a lever hingedly engaged to the first posts distal from the bottom plate, such that the lever and the bottom plate bracket the center plate, wherein the lever is configured for levering such that a nail positioned in the gap is severed by the upper blade contacting the lower blade, the lever comprising:
<claim-text>a first section hingedly engaged to the pair of first posts, the first section being substantially parallel to the center plate when the lever is in an unhinged position, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second section extending transversely from the first section distal from the pair of first posts;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of hinge pins engaged to the lever;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of pin holes, each pin hole being positioned in a respective first post distal from the bottom plate, each hinge pin being positioned in an associated pin hole, such that the lever is hingedly engaged to the pair of first posts;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a panel selectively engageable to the bottom plate, such that the panel, the bottom plate, and the center plate define an interior space, wherein the interior space is configured for receiving a clipping generated upon severing of the nail, the panel comprising:
<claim-text>an end piece, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of side pieces, each side piece being engaged to and extending substantially perpendicularly from a respective opposed edge of the end piece, such that the panel is slidable between the bottom plate and the center plate until the end piece abuts the pair of second posts;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of rails, each rail being engaged to the bottom plate proximate to a respective opposing edge of the bottom plate, the rail extending from a respective second post to proximate to an associated first post, such that the rail and the associated first post define a tab slot;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of tabs, each tab being engaged to and extending transversely from a lower edge of a respective side piece distal from the end piece, such that the tab is selectively insertable into a respective tab slot for removably engaging the panel to the bottom plate; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of flaps, each flap being engaged to a respective opposed side of the center plate, the flap being positioned between the second terminus of the center plate and an associated first post, the flaps being resiliently deformable, wherein the pair of flaps is configured for retaining the clipping between the center plate and the bottom plate prior to the clipping entering the interior space.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
