<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225439A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225439</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17576961</doc-number>
<date>20220116</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>17</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>0033</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>0016</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Method and Apparatus for Securing a Head-Covering to a Head</invention-title>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>TOMER</last-name>
<first-name>Zafrir</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kiryat Ata.</city>
<country>IL</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>IL</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>TOMER</last-name>
<first-name>Zafrir</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kiryat Ata.</city>
<country>IL</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An apparatus for securing a head-covering to a head, including: a first portion having a fastening section formed between connecting edges, the fastening section including a plurality of teeth and made from a flexible material; a second portion include one or more bridging pieces, the second portion coupled to the first portion at the connecting edges such that at least the fastening section is deformed forming a concave arc relative to the bridging pieces when coupled together; and a silicone material disposed on at least one surface of the second portion that is adapted to come into contact with skin of the head; wherein the apparatus is adapted to be flexibly deformed between an open state wherein the plurality of teeth are biased away from the bridging pieces and a closed state wherein the plurality of teeth are biased against the bridging pieces.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="64.26mm" wi="158.75mm" file="US20230225439A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="218.78mm" wi="177.63mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225439A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="210.82mm" wi="125.56mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225439A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="223.01mm" wi="132.08mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225439A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="199.05mm" wi="152.23mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225439A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention relates to accessories for adhering a head-covering (e.g., a skullcap, wig, toupee etc.) to a head and more specifically to a type of clip for adhering the head-covering to the head.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The Jewish skullcap, also referred to by the Hebrew name &#x201c;kipa&#x201d; or Yiddish name &#x201c;yarlmuka&#x201d;, was invented about <b>400</b> years ago in Europe, and since then there have developed may different variations and different sizes.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The adhering/coupling/sticking of the skullcap and/or head-covering and/or wig to the head and/or hair, is an issue that is of particular concern to anyone who wears such a skullcap or head-covering.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Some versions of the skullcap have a diameter which is smaller than the diameter of the head on which is rests, making it particularly difficult to affix to, or secure on, the head. A particularly difficult situation is to adhere/affix such a skullcap to a bald head. Similarly, wigs, toupees and other head-coverings need to be secured in place on the head, in a non-permanent fashion.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">According to the present invention there is provided an apparatus for securing a head-covering to a head, the apparatus including: (a) a first portion having a fastening section formed between connecting edges, the fastening section including a plurality of teeth and made from a flexible material; (b) a second portion include one or more bridging pieces, the second portion coupled to the first portion at the connecting edges such that at least the fastening section is deformed to form a concave arc relative to the one or more bridging pieces when coupled together; and (c) a silicone material disposed on at least one surface of the second portion that is adapted to come into contact with skin of the head; wherein the apparatus is adapted to be flexibly deformed between an open state wherein the plurality of teeth are biased away from the one or more bridging pieces and a closed state wherein the plurality of teeth are biased against the one or more bridging pieces.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">According to examples the first portion and the second portion are integrally formed. According to further examples the first portion and the second portion are coupled together. According to examples the first and second portions are coupled together via a coupling means selected from the group including: coupling pins, rivets, welding, adhesive and ultrasonic bonding.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">According to further examples the fastening section presents the concave arc relative to a virtual plane in the open state and a convex arc relative to the virtual plane in the closed state, wherein the connecting edges lie on the virtual plane.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">According to further examples the silicone material is a silicone adhesive. According to further examples the silicone material is a silicone sleeve or tube that is slid over at least one of the one or more bridging pieces. According to further examples the silicone material is adhered to the at least one surface of the second portion.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">According to another embodiment there is provided an apparatus for securing a head-covering to a head, the apparatus including: a base plate of flexible material having a first surface on one side of the base plate and a second surface on an opposite side of the base plate, the base plate having an upper section relative to an imaginary midline running a length of the based plate and a lower section relative to the midline; an upper set of tines disposed on the upper section of the base plate, on the first surface; and a lower set of tines disposed on the lower section of the base plate, on the second surface.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">According to further examples the upper set of tines and the lower set of tines each extend in a direction away from the imaginary midline. According to further examples the set upper set of tines extends in a direction away from the imaginary midline and the lower set of tines extends in a direction towards the imaginary midline or vice versa.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">According to another embodiment there is provided a system for securing a head-covering to a head, the system including: (a) the apparatus as described herein; (b) the head-covering; and (c) silicone material disposed on a head-facing surface of the head-covering in positions corresponding to hairless areas of a bald, semi-bald or clean-shaven head.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Various embodiments are herein described, by way of example only, with reference to the accompanying drawings, wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A-<b>1</b>E</figref> are various views of an embodiment of the apparatus;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>A-<b>2</b>B</figref> are illustrations of the first portion in a flexed state relative to virtual plane;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A-<b>3</b>B</figref> depict additional example configurations of first portions of an embodiment of the apparatus;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>A and <b>4</b>B</figref> are example embodiments of another configuration of an apparatus;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is an example head-covering HC with a plurality of a dots of silicone material <b>562</b> disposed on an inside surface of the head-covering HC.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The principles and operation of an apparatus and method for coupling a skullcap or hair-covering to a head according to the present invention may be better understood with reference to the drawings and the accompanying description.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Attaching the skullcap, head-covering, or wig (also referred to herein, in the collective, as &#x201c;head-covering&#x201d;) to the head needs to be addressed in two main situations:</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">A. securing the head-covering to a head with hair; and</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">B. securing the head-covering to a head with spikey hair, shaved or a bald (complete or partial) head.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Securing the head-covering to the head in these situations is a mechanical and engineering challenge. Prior art clips snag hair between the teeth or tongue of the clip and an opposing member or members. However, such clips are not able to provide an adequate solution for a bald or cleanshaven head.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref> illustrates a first portion <b>100</b> of an apparatus <b>10</b> according to one embodiment. The first portion <b>100</b> includes a fastening section <b>110</b> formed between two connecting edges <b>120</b>. The fastening section <b>110</b> includes a plurality of teeth <b>112</b>. As manufactured, the first portion is thin and planar piece made from a flexible (plastic elastic) material. The material may be, for example, metal or plastic. The first portion has a generally rectangular shape. In the depicted example, the connecting edges <b>120</b> include a plurality of holes <b>122</b>. These holes are adapted to receive coupling pins or other fastening means.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">One option manner of manufacturing the first portion is by laser cutting a small, thin, rectangular sheet of metal. The design of the fastening section is merely an example, and many different designs and configurations can be employed.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>B</figref> depicts an example of a bridging piece <b>150</b>. One or more bridging pieces <b>150</b> make up a second portion <b>140</b> of the apparatus <b>10</b>. The bridging piece, like the first portion, is flat, thin, planar, and flexible. The bridging piece includes connecting holes <b>152</b> on each end of the piece. The bridging piece has an overall length that is shorter than the length of the first portion. For example, as depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A and <b>1</b>B</figref>, the length of the first portion is 33.90 mm and the length of the bridging piece <b>150</b> is 33.63 mm.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref> depicts the first portion and second portion of an example of the instant apparatus, with guide arrows indicating how the pieces are coupled together. In the example configuration, the second portion <b>140</b> includes two bridging pieces <b>150</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>D</figref> depicts the first portion and second portion coupled together. The connecting edges of first portion are aligned with the coupling holes of the second portion and coupled together. The relative lengths of the two portions ensures that the first portion is deformed, i.e., flexed, to line up the holes. The portions can be coupled together via connecting pins through the corresponding holes, welding, adhesive, etc. In summary, the second portion is coupled to the first portion at the connecting edges such that at least the fastening section is deformed to form a concave arc relative to the one or more bridging pieces when coupled together.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The apparatus further includes a silicone material disposed on at least one surface of second portion adapted to come into contact with skin of the head. In examples, the silicone material may be a thin silicone tube or sleeve that is slid over (i.e., disposed on) one or more of the bridging pieces. In other examples, the silicone material is a silicone adhesive. In some examples, silicone material is adhered to the at least one surface of the second portion. The silicone may be droplets of silicone <b>162</b> that have been deposited on the surface or surfaces of the bridging pieces or a layer of silicone deposited on the surface(s).</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">In some embodiments, the first portion and the second portion are integrally formed. In some embodiments the first portion and the second portion are coupled together. In examples, the first and second portions are coupled together via a coupling means selected from the group including: coupling pins, rivets, welding, adhesive and ultrasonic bonding.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>E</figref> depicts the one example of an apparatus of the instant innovation with the first portion and second portion coupled together. The second portion is coupled to the first portion at the connecting edges such that at least the fastening section is deformed to form a concave arc relative to the one or more bridging pieces.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>A</figref> depicts the first portion in a flexed state relative to virtual plane P in an open state. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>B</figref> depicts the first portion in a flexed state relative to virtual plane in closed state. The fastening section presents a concave arc relative to a virtual plane P in an open state and a convex arc relative to the virtual plane in a closed state/The connecting edges of the first portion lie on the virtual plane P.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Another possible configuration of the first portion <b>100</b><i>a </i>is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref> and yet another configuration of a first portion <b>100</b><i>b </i>is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>B</figref>. For each of the configurations <b>100</b><i>a </i>and <b>100</b><i>b, </i>all of the details provided above with regards to first portion <b>100</b> likewise apply, mutatis mutandis, thereto.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Yet another configuration is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>A</figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>A</figref> is a front view of a facing surface of a unique clip <b>400</b> for securing a head covering to a head. The clip <b>400</b> includes a two-way mechanical structure for gripping the hair. In example embodiments, the clip <b>400</b> is formed from a thin, planar sheet or base plate <b>402</b> of metallic or polymeric material. The clip includes tines or teeth <b>410</b>. One set of tines, e.g., an upper set of tines <b>412</b>, is disposed above an imaginary midway line that separates the clip into an upper half and a lower half. The tines, in the instant example, are disposed longitudinally across almost the entire width of the base plate. The upper tines <b>412</b> are bent away from the base sheet/plate on the facing side.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Conversely, the apparatus <b>400</b> includes a second set of tines on a lower half of the base plate <b>402</b>. The lower tines <b>414</b> protrude (e.g., are bent away) from the base plate <b>402</b> on the opposite side of the clip. Both the upper tines and the lower tines face outwardly, away from the imaginary midline</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">According to one example, the tines <b>410</b> (i.e., both sets of tines <b>412</b> and <b>414</b> [see below]) are laser cut from the base sheet. According to another example, the tines are mechanically attached. to the base sheet <b>402</b> (e.g., by welding, rivets, pins, adhesive and/or any other methods well known in the art).</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The clip <b>400</b> may be attached to the inside surface of a head-covering by any means known in the art. For example, clip <b>400</b> may be sewn into the inside lining of the head covering by holes <b>404</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">An alternative configuration similar clip <b>400</b> is depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>B</figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>B</figref> illustrates a clip <b>400</b><i>a </i>which is similar to, but a variation on, clip <b>400</b>. All of the characteristics of the clip <b>400</b><i>a </i>are similar to those of clip <b>400</b> except for one distinction. Accordingly, the description provided for clip <b>400</b> should be seen as if fully set forth herein, mutatis mutandis, in relation to clip <b>400</b><i>a </i>(each element being identified with a same reference number) besides for the following exception: the lower set of tines <b>414</b><i>a </i>extends towards the direction of the midline (as opposed to extending away from the midline in clip <b>400</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Clip <b>400</b><i>a </i>can be adhered to the inside surface of the head covering in a similar fashion to that which was described in relation to clip <b>400</b>. Alternatively, the tines on one side of the clip can be adhered to a peripheral edge of a head covering such as a skullcap/yarmulka or headscarf while the tines on the other side of the clip snag hair.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">In some embodiments, clip <b>400</b> and/or clip <b>400</b><i>a </i>additionally include a silicone (or similar) material disposed on the clip. In examples, droplets of silicone <b>420</b> can be arrayed in a line across the imaginary midline of the clip <b>400</b>/<b>400</b><i>a. </i>Alternatively, a full line of silicone or a peripheral border of silicone material (not shown) can be disposed on the clip <b>400</b>/<b>400</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">According to embodiments, there is provided a system for securing a head-covering to a head. The system includes any one of the configurations of the apparatus disclosed above that is applicable. For each type of head covering, a different type of clip may be applicable The system further includes a head-covering, where the head covering has disposed on an internal surface thereof: a plurality of a dots of silicone material. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> depicts an example head-covering HC with a plurality of a dots of silicone material <b>562</b> disposed on an inside surface of the head-covering HC. A single unbroken line or various shapes of the material may be additionally or alternatively applied to the inside surface of the head covering. The silicone material (or material with similar properties to silicone) is disposed on the internal surface of the head-covering in positions corresponding to hairless areas of a bald, semi-bald and clean-shaven head. In some cases, the silicone material (or its alternatives) can be disposed on a periphery of the head covering.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">A silicone adhesive material may be used in place of, or in addition to, the aforementioned silicone material. The desired characteristics being a soft rubbery material that sticks, clings or gives at least some degree of purchase when placed on a bald or clean-shaven head.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The silicone material can be made of or include glow-in-the-dark and/or reflective material. Accordingly, one wearing the head covering (e.g., a skullcap) can invert the head covering at night in order to be visible to passing traffic etc.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">It is made clear that any use of the instant apparatus/clip, according to any of the aforementioned configurations/embodiments, is included within the scope of the invention. The clip is adapted to connect a head covering or any other relevant object to hair and/or a hairless head as well as being adapted for any other use, such as, but not limited to, connecting inanimate objects together.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">While the invention has been described with respect to a limited number of embodiments, it will be appreciated that many variations, modifications and other applications of the invention may be made. Therefore, the claimed invention as recited in the claims that follow is not limited to the embodiments described herein.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. An apparatus for securing a head-covering to a head, the apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>(a) a first portion having a fastening section formed between connecting edges, said fastening section including a plurality of teeth and made from a flexible material;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) a second portion include one or more bridging pieces, said second portion coupled to said first portion at said connecting edges such that at least said fastening section is deformed to form a concave arc relative to said one or more bridging pieces when coupled together; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) a silicone material disposed on at least one surface of said second portion that is adapted to come into contact with skin of the head;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the apparatus is adapted to be flexibly deformed between an open state wherein said plurality of teeth are biased away from said one or more bridging pieces and a closed state wherein said plurality of teeth are biased against said one or more bridging pieces.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said first portion and said second portion are integrally formed.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said first portion and said second portion are coupled together.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein said first and second portions are coupled together via a coupling means selected from the group including: coupling pins, rivets, welding, adhesive and ultrasonic bonding.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said fastening section presents said concave arc relative to a virtual plane in said open state and a convex arc relative to said virtual plane in said closed state, wherein said connecting edges lie on said virtual plane.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said silicone material is a silicone adhesive.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said silicone material is a silicone sleeve or tube that is slid over at least one of said one or more bridging pieces.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said silicone material is adhered to said at least one surface of said second portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. An apparatus for securing a head-covering to a head, the apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a base plate of flexible material having a first surface on one side of said base plate and a second surface on an opposite side of said base plate, said base plate having an upper section relative to an imaginary midline running a length of said based plate and a lower section relative to said midline;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an upper set of tines disposed on said upper section of said base plate, on said first surface; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a lower set of tines disposed on said lower section of said base plate, on said second surface.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said upper set of tines and said lower set of tines each extend in a direction away from said imaginary midline.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said set upper set of tines extends in a direction away from said imaginary midline and said lower set of tines extends in a direction towards said imaginary midline or vice versa.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. A system for securing a head-covering to a head, the system comprising:
<claim-text>(a) the apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) the head-covering; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) silicone material disposed on a head-facing surface of the head-covering in positions corresponding to hairless areas of a bald, semi-bald or clean-shaven head.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
