<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225621A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225621</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17580300</doc-number>
<date>20220120</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>17</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>0205</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>02028</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>0205</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>7246</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>742</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>024</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">SYSTEM AND METHOD FOR EVALUATING CARDIAC PUMPING FUNCTION</invention-title>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Curtis</last-name>
<first-name>Guy P.</first-name>
<address>
<city>San Diego</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Curtis</last-name>
<first-name>Guy P.</first-name>
<address>
<city>San Diego</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A system for evaluating a cardiac pumping function includes an oximeter which is attached to a patient for the purpose of recording a pulse oximeter waveform. A computer is connected to the oximeter to receive metric information from the waveform. With this information, the computer determines the value and location of a second derivative acceleration, d<sup>2</sup>A/dt<sup>2 </sup>in the waveform, which indicates the rate of rise/fall of the waveform. A comparator in the computer then compares this with the value and location of maximum second derivative acceleration, d<sup>2</sup>A/dt<sup>2</sup>, in earlier waveforms. With this comparison, the computer identifies a trend which can be clinically used to evaluate the efficacy of a cardiac pumping function.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="74.42mm" wi="142.92mm" file="US20230225621A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="202.86mm" wi="144.95mm" file="US20230225621A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="197.87mm" wi="144.19mm" file="US20230225621A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention pertains to systems and methods for monitoring and evaluating a cardiac pumping function. More particularly, the present invention pertains to systems and methods that evaluate cardiac pumping functions which are based on dynamic changes in blood pulse waveforms measured by an oximeter. The present invention is particularly, but not exclusively, useful for evaluating cardiac pumping functions by comparing the maximum second derivatives from a sequence of successive pulse oximeter waveforms, to assess the rise or fall of the waveforms as being indicative of the efficacy of the cardiac pumping function.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">A pulse oximeter waveform is well known in the pertinent art as a graphical indication of the blood pressure response to a heart muscle function. Specifically, a pulse waveform shows the change in the amplitude A of blood pressure during a single contraction of the heart muscle. These waveforms are relatively short in duration and are, therefore, typically presented and considered as a continuous succession of pulse waveforms.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">When considered individually each pulse waveform provides visual information of the velocity at which the amplitude A of the waveform is increasing or decreasing. Mathematically, this information is referred to as a first derivative, dA/dt. In addition to first derivative changes in velocity, pulses may also exhibit a rise or fall in amplitude of the entire waveform. This rise and/or fall of the waveform provides information about the acceleration of the waveform's amplitude A and is mathematically referred to as a second derivative, d<sup>2</sup>A/dt<sup>2</sup>.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">At the point of care, e.g., during surgery, information regarding changes in a heart muscle function can be quite helpful. Specifically, by monitoring a second derivative for the rise and/or fall of pulse waveforms, medical personnel can determine the beneficial or detrimental effect surgical activity may have had on heart muscle function. With this information, appropriate corrective action can be taken. In the event, it is obvious that corrective action, if needed, must be taken as soon as possible, i.e., immediately.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">With the above in mind, it is an object of the present invention to provide a system and method for immediately evaluating a cardiac pumping function. Another object of the present invention is to provide a system and method for evaluating heart muscle function to determine when immediate corrective action may be advisable. Yet another object of the present invention is to provide a system and method for evaluating a cardiac pumping function by monitoring the acceleration of the pulse oximeter waveform as indicated by the second derivative of its amplitude, d<sup>2</sup>A/dt<sup>2</sup>. Still another object of the present invention is to provide a system and method for monitoring a cardiac pumping function which is simple to use, is easy to manufacture, and is comparatively cost effective.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">A system and method for evaluating a cardiac pumping function requires attaching an oximeter to a patient to monitor a pulse oximeter waveform of the patient. A computer is then connected to the oximeter for receiving metric information from the pulse oximeter waveform. This metric information is received directly from the computer as input for calculating the rate of rise or fall of the pulse oximeter waveform per unit time. Mathematically, the rate of rise/fall of a pulse oximeter waveform is expressed as a second derivative of the waveform's amplitude A, d<sup>2</sup>A/dt<sup>2</sup>. This second derivative is particularly important because it immediately provides an early detection, from a single pulse waveform, of an indication in trends for the overall heat muscle function.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">A comparator, which is included with the computer, compares each pulse oximeter waveform with the immediately preceding waveform to calculate the second derivative d<sup>2</sup>A/dt<sup>2</sup>. Furthermore, the computer identifies a maximum value for the second derivative and its location in the pulse oximeter waveform. This value and location information is then compared with similar value and location information obtained from earlier pulse oximeter waveforms to identify a trend with which to evaluate a cardiac pumping function.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In detail, each pulse oximeter waveform has a time interval that begins at a time t<sub>o </sub>and ends at a time t<sub>e</sub>. A plurality of time segments &#x394;t can be identified between t<sub>o </sub>and t<sub>e </sub>with each time segment &#x394;t having a respective amplitude A. There are two mathematical expressions of interest here for describing a change in A with respect to each time segment &#x394;A. The first expression is a velocity term which describes a change in the value of A as a function of time. Mathematically, this velocity term is a first derivative which is expressed as &#x201c;dA/dt&#x201d;. Stated differently, in the context of the present invention, the first derivative, dA/dt, describes the slope, i.e., shape, of the pulse oximeter waveform. The second expression of interest is an acceleration term that describes a change of the velocity term as a function of time. Mathematically this acceleration term is a second derivative which is expressed as, &#x201c;d<sup>2</sup>A/dt<sup>2</sup>&#x201d;. In the context of the present invention, the second derivative, d<sup>2</sup>A/dt<sup>2</sup>, describes the rise and fall of the pulse oximeter waveform. As a practical consideration, it is the second derivative that is indicative of blood flow volume and thus, the efficacy of a cardiac pumping function.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">For the present invention, the value and location of a maximum second derivative is determined for each consecutive pulse oximeter waveform. The value and location for the maximum second derivative of each pulse oximeter waveform is then compared with the value and location of the maximum second derivative in the immediately preceding waveform. The purpose here is to determine a trend in the value of successive second derivatives for a comparative evaluation that is helpful for determining the efficacy of a cardiac pumping function.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">For the evaluation of a cardiac pumping function, a rise in the value of the second derivative is indicative of an improving function. On the other hand, a drop in the value of the second derivative is indicative of a worsening function. Most likely the maximum value of the second derivative for each pulse oximeter waveform occurs during a plurality of time segments &#x394;t immediately following t<sub>o</sub>. In any event, the present invention envisions the use of a visual display for showing trends in the maximum value of the second derivative, to thereby determine the efficacy of the cardiac pumping function.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The novel features of this invention, as well as the invention itself, both as to its structure and its operation, will be best understood from the accompanying drawings, taken in conjunction with the accompanying description, in which similar reference characters refer to similar parts, and in which:</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a schematic presentation of components of a system for evaluating a cardiac pumping function in accordance with the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a graph of a portion of a pulse oximeter waveform showing a mathematical first derivative expression for the velocity (i.e., slope) of the waveform;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref> is a graph showing a mathematical second derivative expression for the acceleration (i.e., rise) of the waveform;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>B</figref> is a graph showing a mathematical second derivative expression for the deceleration (i.e., fall) of the waveform; and</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is a composite graph showing the rise and fall of a pulse oximeter waveform resulting respectively from a positive second derivative (rise) and a negative second derivative (fall).</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Referring initially to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> a system for evaluating a cardiac pumping function is shown and is generally designated <b>10</b>. As shown, the system <b>10</b> includes an oximeter <b>12</b> which can be connected with a patient <b>14</b> for the purpose of monitoring blood flow characteristics of the patient <b>14</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> also shows that the system <b>10</b> includes a computer <b>16</b> which is attached to the oximeter <b>12</b>, and that the computer <b>16</b> includes a differentiator <b>18</b> and a comparator <b>20</b>. A display <b>22</b> is provided to present clinical results of measurements from the oximeter <b>12</b> that are pertinent to the blood flow characteristics of the patient <b>14</b>. Specifically, these blood flow characteristics are based on measurements of a pulse oximeter waveform <b>24</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>) that is obtained by the oximeter <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Operationally, the oximeter <b>12</b> is typically connected with a finger <b>26</b> of the patient <b>14</b> to measure and record the physical characteristics of the patient's pulse oximeter waveform <b>24</b>. The obtained measurements are then transmitted as metric information to the computer <b>16</b> via an electronic connection <b>28</b>. Of particular interest for the present invention are mathematical expressions which are based on this metric information. Specifically, these mathematical expressions are first and second derivatives which are generated by the differentiator <b>18</b> in the computer <b>16</b>. More specifically, the mathematical expressions are pertinent to changes in the pulse oximeter waveform <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a graphical presentation of an exemplary portion of a pulse oximeter waveform <b>24</b> whereon a change in the amplitude A of the pulse oximeter waveform <b>24</b> is shown as a function of time. Mathematically, such a change is expressed as &#x394;A/&#x394;t (dA/dt). This expression is referred to as a first derivative, which establishes the &#x201c;slope&#x201d; of the waveform <b>24</b>. The expression &#x394;A/&#x394;t, or dA/dt, is also commonly often referred to as the &#x201c;velocity&#x201d; of the waveform <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Graphically, a change in the amplitude, &#x394;A, of the waveform <b>24</b> is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> to occur between points <b>30</b> and <b>32</b> during the time interval &#x394;t between t<sub>1 </sub>and t<sub>2</sub>. In accordance with the present invention, this first derivative dA/dt, that occurs during the time interval t<sub>1 </sub>to t<sub>2</sub>, is used by the comparator <b>20</b> of computer <b>16</b> for comparison with the first derivative of the waveform <b>24</b> during the immediately subsequent same time interval &#x394;t between t<sub>2 </sub>and t<sub>3</sub>. As disclosed below, this comparison is done to determine an acceleration of amplitude A of waveform <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Another mathematical expression of interest for the present invention is the second derivative of the pulse oximeter waveform <b>24</b>, d<sup>2</sup>A/dt<sup>2</sup>. This derivative expresses the time rate of change of the first derivative. It is also commonly referred to as the &#x201c;acceleration&#x201d; of the pulse oximeter waveform <b>24</b>. This second derivative, i.e. acceleration, is of singular importance for the system <b>10</b> as it mathematically expresses the rise and/or fall of the waveform <b>24</b> as a function of time. Stated differently, as a practical consequence, the rise and fall of a waveform <b>24</b> is indicative of the volume of blood flow; with a rise being indicative of improved blood flow for the patient <b>14</b>, and a fall (or drop) being indicative of a worsening of his/her blood flow condition.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref>, the line curve <b>34</b> represents an increasing second derivative (+d<sup>2</sup>A/dt<sup>2</sup>), which indicates an acceleration in the magnitude of A. On the other hand, the line curve <b>36</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>B</figref> represents a decreasing second derivative (&#x2212;d<sup>2</sup>A/dt<sup>2</sup>), which indicates a deceleration in the magnitude of A. The consequences of these accelerations and decelerations are shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The pulse oximeter waveform <b>24</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is representative of a constant waveform <b>24</b> in which the amplitude A of the waveform <b>24</b> has neither accelerated nor decelerated. However, when the comparator <b>20</b> in computer <b>16</b> detects a second derivative change in the amplitude A, the display <b>22</b> presents a visual indication of the change. Specifically, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> an acceleration will show on the display <b>22</b> as a movement of the waveform <b>24</b> toward a raised position shown for a waveform <b>24</b>&#x2032;. A deceleration, however, will show on the display <b>22</b> as a movement of the waveform <b>24</b> toward a lower position shown for a waveform <b>24</b>&#x2033;. As noted above, these movements provide valuable information to an attending physician at the time of care for an immediate response, if needed.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">While the particular System and Method for Evaluating Cardiac Pumping Function as herein shown and disclosed in detail is fully capable of obtaining the objects and providing the advantages herein before stated, it is to be understood that it is merely illustrative of the presently preferred embodiments of the invention and that no limitations are intended to the details of construction or design herein shown other than as described in the appended claims.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A system for evaluating a cardiac pumping function which comprises:
<claim-text>an oximeter adapted to be attached to a patient to monitor a pulse oximeter waveform of the patient;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a computer connected to the oximeter for receiving metric information from the pulse oximeter waveform as input for calculating the rate of rise of the pulse oximeter waveform per unit time, wherein the rate of rise is mathematically expressed as a second derivative;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a comparator included with the computer for comparing each pulse oximeter waveform with the immediately preceding waveform to calculate the second derivative and identify a maximum value therefor; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a display for showing changes in the maximum value of the second derivative to determine the state of the cardiac pumping function.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein each pulse oximeter waveform has a time interval that begins at a time t<sub>o </sub>and ends at a time t<sub>e</sub>, with a plurality of time segments &#x394;t therebetween, wherein each time segment &#x394;t of the pulse oximeter waveform has a respective amplitude A, and wherein the mathematical expression for the second derivative is d<sup>2</sup>A/dt<sup>2 </sup>and has a respective value for each time segment &#x394;t.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the computer calculates the second derivative of A over the entire time interval from t<sub>o </sub>to t<sub>e </sub>at each time segment &#x394;t.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref> wherein the magnitude of the second derivative of A is identified for each time segment &#x394;t.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref> wherein a location for the maximum value of the second derivative is compared with the value of the second derivative at the same location in the immediately preceding waveform to determine a trend in the value of the second derivative.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref> wherein a rise in the value of the second derivative is indicative of an improving cardiac pumping function and a drop in the value of the second derivative is indicative of a worsening cardiac pumping function.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref> wherein the maximum value of the second derivative occurs during a plurality of time segments &#x394;t immediately following t<sub>o</sub>.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. A method for evaluating a cardiac pumping function which comprises the steps of:
<claim-text>attaching an oximeter to a patient to monitor a pulse oximeter waveform of the patient;</claim-text>
<claim-text>providing metric information received from the pulse oximeter waveform as input to a computer for calculating the rate of rise of the pulse oximeter waveform per unit time;</claim-text>
<claim-text>expressing the rate of rise of the pulse oximeter waveform mathematically as a second derivative; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>comparing a maximum value of the second derivative to a previously calculated value of the second derivative to determine the state of the cardiac pumping function.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref> wherein each pulse oximeter waveform has a time interval that begins at a time t<sub>o </sub>and ends at a time t<sub>e</sub>, with a plurality of time segments &#x394;t therebetween, wherein each time segment &#x394;t of the pulse oximeter waveform has a respective amplitude A, and wherein the mathematical expression for the second derivative is d<sup>2</sup>A/dt<sup>2 </sup>and has a respective value for each time segment &#x394;t.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref> further comprising the step of calculating the second derivative of A over the entire time interval from t<sub>o </sub>to t<sub>e </sub>at each time segment &#x394;t.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref> further comprising the step of identifying a time segment &#x394;t having a maximum value of the second derivative of A in the pulse oximeter waveform.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref> further comprising the step of comparing the location for the maximum value of the second derivative with the value of the second derivative at the same location in the immediately preceding waveform to determine a trend in the value of the second derivative.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref> wherein a rise in the second derivative is indicative of an improving cardiac pumping function and a drop in the second derivative is indicative of a worsening cardiac pumping function.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref> wherein the maximum value of the second derivative occurs during a plurality of time segments &#x394;t immediately following t<sub>o</sub>.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. A non-transitory, computer-readable medium having executable instructions stored thereon that direct a computer system to perform a process for evaluating a cardiac pumping function, the medium comprising instructions for:
<claim-text>receiving metric information from a pulse oximeter waveform as input to a computer for calculating the rate of rise of the pulse oximeter waveform per unit time;</claim-text>
<claim-text>expressing the rate of rise of the pulse oximeter waveform mathematically as a second derivative; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>comparing a maximum value of the second derivative to a previously calculated value of the second derivative to determine the state of the cardiac pumping function.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. The medium of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref> wherein the pulse oximeter waveform has a time interval that begins at a time t<sub>o </sub>and ends at a time t<sub>e</sub>, with a plurality of time segments &#x394;t therebetween, wherein each time segment &#x394;t of the pulse oximeter waveform has a respective amplitude A, and wherein the mathematical expression for the second derivative is d<sup>2</sup>A/dt<sup>2 </sup>and has a respective value for each time segment &#x394;t.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. The medium of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref> further comprising instructions for:
<claim-text>calculating the second derivative of A over the entire time interval from t<sub>o </sub>to t<sub>e </sub>at each time segment &#x394;t; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>identifying a time segment &#x394;t having a maximum value of the second derivative of A in the pulse oximeter waveform.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. The medium of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref> further comprising an instruction for comparing the location for the maximum value of the second derivative with the value of the second derivative at the same location in the immediately preceding waveform to determine a trend in the value of the second derivative.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. The medium of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref> further comprising an instruction for displaying a rising trend in the second derivative as indicative of an improving cardiac pumping function and a dropping trend in the second derivative as indicative of a worsening cardiac pumping function.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. The medium of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref> wherein the maximum value of the second derivative occurs during a plurality of time segments &#x394;t immediately following t<sub>o</sub>.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
