<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225538A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225538</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18120649</doc-number>
<date>20230313</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>33</main-group>
<subgroup>06</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>33</main-group>
<subgroup>06</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">MULTI-WIRE QUICK ASSEMBLE TREE</invention-title>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>16949995</doc-number>
<date>20201123</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11602237</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18120649</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation>
<continuation>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>15837140</doc-number>
<date>20171211</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>10842306</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>16949995</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation>
<continuation>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>15081067</doc-number>
<date>20160325</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>9839315</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>15837140</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>62139046</doc-number>
<date>20150327</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Polygroup Macau Limited (BVI)</orgname>
<address>
<city>Road Town</city>
<country>VG</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>VG</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Leung</last-name>
<first-name>Chi Yin Alan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Apleichau</city>
<country>HK</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="01" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>He</last-name>
<first-name>Chang Jun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="02" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kwok</last-name>
<first-name>Chi Kin Samuel</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A power transfer system to facilitate the transfer of electrical power between tree trunk sections of an artificial tree is disclosed. The power transfer system can advantageously enable neighboring tree trunk sections to be electrically connected without the need to rotationally align the tree trunk sections. Power distribution systems can be disposed within the trunk sections. The power distribution systems can comprise a male end, a female end, or both. The male ends can have prongs and the female ends can have voids. The prongs can be inserted into the voids to electrically connect the power distribution systems of neighboring tree trunk sections. In some embodiments, the prongs and voids are designed so that the prongs of one power distribution system can engage the voids of another power distribution system without the need to rotationally align the tree trunk sections.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="217.17mm" wi="146.81mm" file="US20230225538A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="185.25mm" wi="123.11mm" file="US20230225538A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="188.81mm" wi="127.93mm" file="US20230225538A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="210.14mm" wi="128.44mm" file="US20230225538A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="223.60mm" wi="128.52mm" file="US20230225538A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="235.80mm" wi="143.59mm" file="US20230225538A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="234.44mm" wi="143.59mm" file="US20230225538A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="234.61mm" wi="71.97mm" file="US20230225538A1-20230720-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="202.01mm" wi="157.31mm" file="US20230225538A1-20230720-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="230.04mm" wi="158.50mm" file="US20230225538A1-20230720-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="227.50mm" wi="114.38mm" file="US20230225538A1-20230720-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="227.16mm" wi="159.85mm" file="US20230225538A1-20230720-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00012" num="00012">
<img id="EMI-D00012" he="222.67mm" wi="165.78mm" file="US20230225538A1-20230720-D00012.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00013" num="00013">
<img id="EMI-D00013" he="193.46mm" wi="164.25mm" file="US20230225538A1-20230720-D00013.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00014" num="00014">
<img id="EMI-D00014" he="220.05mm" wi="171.03mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225538A1-20230720-D00014.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00015" num="00015">
<img id="EMI-D00015" he="226.31mm" wi="148.84mm" file="US20230225538A1-20230720-D00015.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00016" num="00016">
<img id="EMI-D00016" he="229.36mm" wi="130.89mm" file="US20230225538A1-20230720-D00016.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00017" num="00017">
<img id="EMI-D00017" he="233.60mm" wi="100.08mm" file="US20230225538A1-20230720-D00017.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00018" num="00018">
<img id="EMI-D00018" he="226.82mm" wi="152.40mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225538A1-20230720-D00018.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00019" num="00019">
<img id="EMI-D00019" he="222.33mm" wi="124.63mm" file="US20230225538A1-20230720-D00019.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00020" num="00020">
<img id="EMI-D00020" he="219.71mm" wi="163.58mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225538A1-20230720-D00020.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00021" num="00021">
<img id="EMI-D00021" he="221.32mm" wi="91.78mm" file="US20230225538A1-20230720-D00021.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION AND PRIORITY CLAIM</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a continuation application of U.S. patent application Ser. No. 16/949,995, filed Nov. 23, 2020, entitled &#x201c;MULTI-WIRE QUICK ASSEMBLE TREE,&#x201d; which is a continuation of U.S. patent application Ser. No. 15/837,140, filed Dec. 11, 2017, entitled &#x201c;MULTI-WIRE QUICK ASSEMBLE TREE,&#x201d; now pending, which is a continuation of U.S. patent application Ser. No. 15/081,067, filed 25 Mar. 2016, entitled &#x201c;MULTI-WIRE QUICK ASSEMBLE TREE,&#x201d; which claims the benefit under 35 U.S.C. &#xa7; 119(e) of U.S. Provisional Patent Application No. 62/139,046, filed 27 Mar. 2015, the entire contents and substance of which are incorporated herein by reference in their entirety.</p>
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="tail"?>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">FIELD OF THE DISCLOSURE</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Embodiments of the present disclosure relate generally to power transfer systems, and, more particularly, to power transfer systems for use with artificial trees, such as artificial Christmas trees.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">As part of the celebration of the Christmas season, many people traditionally bring a pine or evergreen tree into their home and decorate it with ornaments, lights, garland, tinsel, and the like. Natural trees, however, can be quite expensive and are recognized by some as a waste of environmental resources. In addition, natural trees can be messy, leaving both sap and needles behind after removal, and requiring water to prevent drying out and becoming a fire hazard. Each time a natural tree is obtained it must be decorated, and at the end of the Christmas season the decorations must be removed. Because the needles have likely dried and may be quite sharp by this time, removal of the decorations can be a painful process. In addition, natural trees are often disposed in landfills, further polluting these overflowing environments.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">To overcome the disadvantages of a natural Christmas tree, yet still incorporate a tree into the holiday celebration, a variety of artificial Christmas trees are available. For the most part, these artificial trees must be assembled for use and disassembled after use. Artificial trees have the advantage of being usable over a period of years and thereby eliminate the annual expense of purchasing live trees for the short holiday season. Further, they help reduce the chopping down of trees for a temporary decoration, and the subsequent disposal, typically in a landfill, of same.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Generally, artificial Christmas trees comprise a multiplicity of branches each formed of a plurality of plastic needles held together by twisting a pair of wires about them. In other instances, the branches are formed by twisting a pair of wires about an elongated sheet of plastic material having a large multiplicity of transverse slits. In still other artificial Christmas trees, the branches are formed by injection molding of plastic.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Irrespective of the form of the branch, the most common form of artificial Christmas tree comprises a plurality of trunk sections connectable to one another. For example, in many designs, a first and second trunk section each comprise an elongate body. A first end of the body includes a receiving portion (e.g., a female end) and a second end of the body includes an extending portion (e.g., a male end). Typically, the body is a cylinder. Near the second end the body tapers slightly to reduce the diameter of the body. In other words, the diameter of the first end, i.e., the receiving portion, is larger than the diameter of the second end, i.e., the extending portion. To connect the trunk sections, the first end of a first trunk sections receives the second end of a second trunk sections. For example, the tapered end of the first trunk section is inserted into the non-tapered end of the second trunk section. In this manner, a plurality of trunk sections can be connected and a tree assembled.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">One difficulty encountered during assembly, however, is the rotational alignment of the trunk sections. In some designs, the trunk sections comprise electrical systems. The electrical systems allow electricity to flow through the trunk of the tree and into accessories that can extend from the trunk or that can be plugged into outlets disposed on the trunk. To connect neighboring trunk sections, however, electrical prongs of one trunk section must be rotationally aligned with, and inserted into, electrical slots in another trunk section. This alignment process can be frustrating because it can be difficult for a user to judge whether the prongs will engage the slots when trunk sections are joined together. It may therefore take several attempts before a user can electrically connect two trunk sections.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Further, consumers often desire options for lighting combinations that go beyond traditional white or multicolored string lights. Customers desire artificial trees that can emit thousands of light combinations. In addition to the light combinations, customers also desire trees that are backlit with white lights that help amplify the light combinations and give the overall tree a pleasing glow that supplements the light combinations.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">What is needed, therefore, is a power transfer system for an artificial tree that supports various light designs and implementations and that allows a user to connect neighboring tree trunk sections without the need to rotationally align the trunk sections. Embodiments of the present disclosure address this need as well as other needs that will become apparent upon reading the description below in conjunction with the drawings.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Briefly described, embodiments of the presently disclosed subject matter generally relate to power transfer systems, and, more particularly, to power transfer systems for use with artificial trees, such as artificial Christmas trees.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Aspects of the present disclosure relate to a power transfer system that provides at least four electrical contacts and allows for near 360&#xb0; alignment between male and female ends of artificial Christmas tree trunk sections that are to be joined. For example, a power transfer system according to the present disclosure can be used with LED light strings that comprise LED lamps with four inputs. In some embodiments, the LEDs may be single color, but in other embodiments, the LEDs may be multicolor (e.g., RGB LEDs). In some embodiments, the power transfer system may include six electrical contacts such that the power transfer system can be used with LED light strings in addition to conventional light strings with two inputs. In addition to electrical prongs (in the male end) and contact devices (in the female end), the respective male and female ends also include clutch elements that in aligning the male and female ends when a user joins them. Further, the clutch elements help maintain rotational alignment once the male and female ends have been joined.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In some examples, embodiments relate to power transfer systems with four electrical contacts. In some embodiments, the power transfer system comprises two artificial tree trunk sections, one having a male end and the other having a female end. For example, in some embodiments, the female end may comprise four electrically isolated contact devices. The contact devices of the female end may include a central contact device disposed proximate the center of a central receiving void of a female end base. Further, the contact devices of the female end may include a first channel contact device disposed proximate the exterior of a female end base extension. The female end may further comprise an outer wall, and second and third channel contact devices may be disposed on the interior surface of the outer wall.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Additionally, in some examples, the male end may comprise four electrical prongs for electrical connection with the female end and to allow for electrical communication between the male and female ends. In some embodiments, the male end may comprise a center male terminal prong as well as first, second, and third channel male terminal prongs. In some embodiments, the center male terminal may be adapted to contact the central contact device, and the first, second, and third channel male terminal prongs may be adapted to contact the first, second, and third channel contact devices of the female end. When the prongs and contact devices come into contact (i.e., when the male and female ends are joined together), it can create a power distribution system. In some embodiments, this power distribution system can be used to power LED light strings (e.g., LED light strings that comprise RGB LED lamps or single-color LED lamps). As will be appreciated, LED lamps typically comprise four leads: one for electronic signal input, one for electronic signal output, and two for power (e.g., AC supply voltage). The four-contact design of the present disclosure can be used in conjunction with such LED light strings. Also, in some embodiments, the electrical isolation of the contacts allows for 360&#xb0; or near-360&#xb0; compatibility between the male and female ends. In other words, when joining the male and female ends, a user is not required to pre-align the ends because electrical communication can be achieved between the prongs and contacts irrespective of the rotational alignment.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In some embodiments, the male and female ends may comprise radially extending clutch elements. These clutch elements may comprise sloped or angled top surfaces (i.e., the clutch elements may comprise a first and second height and a top surface that angles from the first height to the second height). Further, in some embodiments, the top surface may comprise a plurality of facets. In some embodiments, these facets may be configured such that they angle away from one another (e.g., similar to the roof of a house) or, put differently, that extend radially and angle circumferentially downward. Thus, because of the configuration of the clutch elements in some embodiments, when the male end and female end are brought together, the opposing male and female clutch elements can easily disengage from one another, thereby making it simple for a user to join the male and female ends. Further, once the male and female ends of been joined to form a power distribution system, the clutch elements may prevent the male and female ends from rotating relative to one another, thus helping to maintain electrical communication and keeping the trunk sections aligned in the user's desired configuration.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The accompanying drawings, which are incorporated in and constitute a part of this specification, illustrate multiple embodiments of the presently disclosed subject matter and serve to explain the principles of the presently disclosed subject matter. The drawings are not intended to limit the scope of the presently disclosed subject matter in any manner.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> depicts a perspective view of a female end of a tree trunk section, in accordance with some embodiments of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> depicts a perspective view of a male end of a tree trunk section, in accordance with some embodiments of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref> depicts a perspective view of a female end of a tree trunk section in proximity to a male end of a tree trunk section, in accordance with some embodiments of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>3</b>B and <b>3</b>C</figref> depict cross-sectional views of a female end of a tree trunk section being joined with a male end of a tree trunk section, in accordance with some embodiments of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> depicts a cross-sectional view showing a power distribution system of an assembled tree trunk, in accordance with some embodiments of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> depicts a side view of an assembled tree trunk, in accordance with some embodiments of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> depicts a perspective view of a female end of a tree trunk section, in accordance with some embodiments of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> depicts a perspective, cross-sectional view of a female end of a tree trunk section, in accordance with some embodiments of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> depicts a central contact device with contact sections, in accordance with some embodiments of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref> depicts a perspective view of a male end of a tree trunk section, in accordance with some embodiments of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref> depicts a perspective, cross-sectional view of a male end of a tree trunk section, in accordance with some embodiments of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>11</b>A-D</figref> are cross-sectional views showing the connection of a male end with a female end, in accordance with some embodiments of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>12</b></figref> depicts a perspective, cross-sectional view of a female end of a tree trunk section joined with a male end of a tree trunk section, in accordance with some embodiments of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>13</b>A</figref> depicts a perspective view of a male end of a tree trunk section with clutch elements, in accordance with some embodiments of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>13</b>B</figref> depicts a perspective view of a female end of a tree trunk section with clutch elements, in accordance with some embodiments of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>14</b></figref> depicts an exploded view of a female end of a tree trunk section with clutch elements and four electrical connections, in accordance with some embodiments of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>15</b>A and <b>15</b>B</figref> depict perspective views of a female end of a tree trunk section with clutch elements and four electrical connections, in accordance with some embodiments of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>16</b></figref> depicts an exploded view of a male end of a tree trunk section with clutch elements and four electrical connections, in accordance with some embodiments of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>17</b></figref> depicts a perspective view of a male end of a tree trunk section with four electrical connections, in accordance with some embodiments of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>18</b></figref> depicts an assembled artificial Christmas tree, in accordance with some embodiments of the present disclosure.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Although certain embodiments of the disclosure are explained in detail, it is to be understood that other embodiments are contemplated. Accordingly, it is not intended that the disclosure is limited in its scope to the details of construction and arrangement of components set forth in the following description or illustrated in the drawings. Other embodiments of the disclosure are capable of being practiced or carried out in various ways. Also, in describing the embodiments, specific terminology will be resorted to for the sake of clarity. It is intended that each term contemplates its broadest meaning as understood by those skilled in the art and includes all technical equivalents which operate in a similar manner to accomplish a similar purpose.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">It should also be noted that, as used in the specification and the appended claims, the singular forms &#x201c;a,&#x201d; &#x201c;an&#x201d; and &#x201c;the&#x201d; include plural references unless the context clearly dictates otherwise. References to a composition containing &#x201c;a&#x201d; constituent is intended to include other constituents in addition to the one named.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Ranges may be expressed herein as from &#x201c;about&#x201d; or &#x201c;approximately&#x201d; or &#x201c;substantially&#x201d; one particular value and/or to &#x201c;about&#x201d; or &#x201c;approximately&#x201d; or &#x201c;substantially&#x201d; another particular value. When such a range is expressed, other exemplary embodiments include from the one particular value and/or to the other particular value.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Herein, the use of terms such as &#x201c;having,&#x201d; &#x201c;has,&#x201d; &#x201c;including,&#x201d; or &#x201c;includes&#x201d; are open-ended and are intended to have the same meaning as terms such as &#x201c;comprising&#x201d; or &#x201c;comprises&#x201d; and not preclude the presence of other structure, material, or acts. Similarly, though the use of terms such as &#x201c;can&#x201d; or &#x201c;may&#x201d; are intended to be open-ended and to reflect that structure, material, or acts are not necessary, the failure to use such terms is not intended to reflect that structure, material, or acts are essential. To the extent that structure, material, or acts are presently considered to be essential, they are identified as such.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">It is also to be understood that the mention of one or more method steps does not preclude the presence of additional method steps or intervening method steps between those steps expressly identified. Moreover, although the term &#x201c;step&#x201d; may be used herein to connote different aspects of methods employed, the term should not be interpreted as implying any particular order among or between various steps herein disclosed unless and except when the order of individual steps is explicitly required.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The components described hereinafter as making up various elements of the disclosure are intended to be illustrative and not restrictive. Many suitable components that would perform the same or similar functions as the components described herein are intended to be embraced within the scope of the disclosure. Such other components not described herein can include, but are not limited to, for example, similar components that are developed after development of the presently disclosed subject matter.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">To facilitate an understanding of the principles and features of the disclosure, various illustrative embodiments are explained below. In particular, the presently disclosed subject matter is described in the context of being an artificial tree power system. The present disclosure, however, is not so limited, and can be applicable in other contexts. For example and not limitation, some embodiments of the present disclosure may improve other power systems, such as light poles, lamps, extension cord systems, power cord connection systems, and the like. These embodiments are contemplated within the scope of the present disclosure. Accordingly, when the present disclosure is described in the context of a power transfer system for an artificial Christmas tree, it will be understood that other embodiments can take the place of those referred to.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">When assembling an artificial tree, decorators commonly desire to illuminate the tree with one or more light strings, i.e., strands of lights. The light strings require electrical power and are conventionally connected in series. In many designs, at least one of the light strings is connected to a wall outlet to provide power to all of the light strings. When decorating a tree, the decorator can walk around the tree, placing the light strings on various locations on the branches of the tree. In order to provide power to all of the light strings, typical light strings come with a first end in the form of a male end and a second end in the form of a female end.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">To provide power to more than one light string, the decorator can insert the male end of one light string into the female end of another light string. In doing so, the light string that is electrically connected to a wall outlet (or other power outlet) transfers electrical energy from the outlet to subsequent light strings. In some conventional systems, the lights strings can have multiple points of electrical connectivity, providing for parallel or serial connectivity. Even so, the flow of power is usually from one light string connected to the power outlet to one or more downstream light strings.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The act of providing power from the outlet to one or more light strings can be cumbersome and frustrating for a decorator. In order to attach multiple light strings together, the decorator will either need to attach the light strings prior to their placement on the tree or attach the light strings after they have been placed on the tree. If the decorator attaches multiple light strings together, in order to &#x201c;wrap&#x201d; the tree with the light strings, the decorator often must walk around the tree, carrying the multiple strings. If the decorator waits until after the light strings are placed on the tree, the decorator will need to reach through the tree branches and electrically connect the light strings. The decorator would also likely need to manipulate the light strings in order to connect the strings together. This process can be difficult and can take an extended amount of time.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">To alleviate issues associated with providing power to light strings in conventional artificial trees, and to provide further advantages, the present disclosure comprises a power transfer system for an artificial tree. In an exemplary embodiment, an artificial tree trunk comprises tree trunk sections that are engaged with one another to form the trunk of an artificial tree. At least some of the tree trunk sections can have hollow voids. Within the hollow voids can be components of power distribution systems. In some embodiments, a female end or a male end is located proximate the end of the tree trunk sections. For example, a tree trunk section could have a male end on one end and a female end on the other end. Or, a tree trunk section could have male ends or female ends on both ends. In some embodiments, when one tree trunk section is engaged with another tree trunk section, the male end engages with and is electrically connected to the female end to form a power distribution system, which may be a subcomponent of an overall power distribution system. Thus, by electrically connecting a power distribution system of a tree trunk section to a power outlet, electrical power flows from the outlet to those combined tree trunk sections and can also flow from those trunk sections to other tree trunk sections.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">A variety of systems exist to facilitate joining the male and female ends to form a power distribution system. Although conventional plug and outlet systems can be used, such as those manufactured in accordance with NEMA standards, in some cases, it can be difficult in conventional designs to align the male prongs of one tree trunk section with the female holes of another tree trunk section. In order to engage the male end with the female end, the assembler of the tree often must vertically align the tree trunk sections so that the male prongs of the male end are not angled to the female end in a manner that prevents insertion of the male prongs. The assembler must also rotationally align the two tree trunk sections to allow the prongs to line up with the female holes. Even if the tree trunk sections are perfectly vertical, in conventional systems, the male prongs can only engage the female holes if the male prongs are rotationally aligned with the female holes. If not, the male prongs abut the area around the female holes, which prevents insertion of the male prongs. Attempting to align the male prongs and the female holes can therefore take significant time and effort, and can be a frustrating experience for a user.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">To alleviate this problem, in one embodiment, the present disclosure comprises a female end having a central void for receiving a first male prong of the male end and a channel void disposed around the central void for receiving a second male prong. In this configuration, the assembler of the tree trunk sections can be less concerned with the rotational, or angular, displacement of the two tree trunk sections, as the channel provides for engagement with the male end at various angular displacements. In exemplary embodiments, the channel is disposed 360 degrees around the central void so that, regardless of the angular displacement between the tree trunk sections, the male prongs can engage the female voids. This can make the assembly process much easier and more enjoyable for a user. Further, in some embodiments, the power distribution system formed between the male and female ends may comprise four electrical contacts. Thus, embodiments of the present disclosure may provide a power distribution system that can be used with LED light strings that comprise, for example, RGB LED lamps that require four contacts (two for AC supply voltage, one for electronic signal input, and one for electronic signal output).</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Embodiments of the present disclosure can also be used in a variety of systems. For example, some embodiments can be used in low voltage systems, and other embodiments can be used in normal, higher voltage systems.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Referring now to the figures, wherein like reference numerals represent like parts throughout the views, exemplary embodiments will be described in detail.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> depicts an exemplary embodiment of a female end <b>105</b> of a power distribution system of a tree trunk section <b>100</b>. In some embodiments, female end <b>105</b> can have one or more electrical voids for receiving power from, or distributing power to, a male end of a power distribution system of a tree trunk section. Female end <b>105</b> can comprise central receiving void <b>110</b> for engaging with a prong of a male end and channel receiving void <b>115</b> for engaging with another prong of a male end.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">In some embodiments, the voids <b>110</b>, <b>115</b> can be hollows or apertures that receive and engage with other electrical connectors, such as prongs, and enable the electrical connectors to conduct electrical power through the trunk of the tree. In some embodiments, the central receiving void <b>110</b> can be located proximate the center of the female end <b>105</b>. The channel receiving void <b>115</b>, therefore, can be a round or circular channel that encircles the central receiving void <b>110</b>. Accordingly, the central receiving void <b>110</b> can be located proximate the center of the channel receiving void <b>115</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> depicts an exemplary embodiment of a male end <b>205</b> of a power distribution system of a tree trunk section. In some embodiments, male end <b>205</b> can have one or more prongs for receiving power from, or distributing power to, a female end <b>105</b> of a power distribution system of a tree trunk section. In some embodiments, the male end <b>205</b> comprises two prongs. A first prong can provide a &#x201c;positive&#x201d; flow path for electricity and a second prong can provide a &#x201c;negative&#x201d; flow path for electricity.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, male end <b>205</b> can have a central male prong <b>210</b> and a channel male prong <b>215</b>. In some embodiments, central male prong <b>210</b> can be sized and shaped to fit inside of and engage central receiving void <b>110</b>, and channel male prong <b>215</b> can be sized and shaped to fit inside of and engage channel receiving void <b>115</b>. In some embodiments, when central male prong <b>210</b> and channel male prong <b>215</b> of the male end <b>205</b> are inserted into the central receiving void <b>110</b> and channel receiving void <b>115</b> of the female end <b>105</b>, respectively, electrical power can be conducted from male end <b>205</b> to female end <b>105</b>, or vice versa, depending on the direction of electrical power flow. In this manner, electrical power can be conducted from a first power distribution system to a second power distribution system.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> and <b>2</b></figref>, by having channel receiving void <b>115</b> disposed in a circular manner around central receiving void <b>110</b> of female end <b>105</b>, assembly issues concerning the angular relationship (i.e., rotational alignment) of male end <b>205</b> and female end <b>105</b> can be reduced or eliminated. In other words, central male prong <b>210</b> can be located in the center of the male end <b>205</b>, and central receiving void <b>210</b> can be located in the center of female end <b>105</b>, enabling central male prong <b>210</b> and central receiving void <b>210</b> to line up regardless of the rotational alignment of the male end <b>205</b> and female end <b>105</b>. In addition, channel male prong <b>215</b> of male end <b>205</b> can be inserted at a plurality of locations along channel receiving void <b>115</b> of female end <b>105</b>, and still establish and maintain electrical connectivity between female end <b>105</b> and male end <b>205</b>. More particularly, the channel prong <b>215</b> can engage the channel receiving void <b>115</b> in a plurality of configurations, and each configuration can provide a different rotational alignment between the two trunk sections (i.e., <b>100</b> and <b>200</b>). This design enables the male end <b>205</b> and the female end <b>105</b> to electrically engage regardless of the angular relationship, or rotational alignment, between the male end <b>205</b> and the female end <b>105</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">In some embodiments, therefore, the angular displacement between connecting trunk sections <b>100</b> and <b>200</b> is not problematic during assembly because the trunk sections <b>100</b> and <b>200</b> can be joined at any number of angular displacements. Thus, a person assembling a Christmas tree utilizing an embodiment of the present disclosure can more readily assemble the various trunk sections (e.g., <b>100</b> and <b>200</b>) without having to rotationally align male end <b>205</b> with female end <b>105</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">In addition, because some embodiments of the present disclosure allow rotation while assembled, the assembler of the Christmas tree can rotate the various trunk sections to some degree after assembly to achieve a desired appearance. But, in some embodiments, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> and <b>2</b></figref>, the male end <b>205</b> and the female end <b>105</b> can comprise one or more alignment mechanisms <b>125</b>, <b>225</b>. The alignment mechanisms <b>125</b>, <b>225</b> can comprise ridges and grooves, or similar structures such as detents, bumps, or teeth. In some embodiments, the ridges and grooves of the alignment mechanism <b>125</b> of the female end <b>105</b> and the ridges and grooves of the alignment mechanism <b>225</b> of the male end <b>205</b> can engage when the female end <b>105</b> and the male end <b>205</b> join together. This engagement can prevent the trunk sections <b>100</b> and <b>200</b> from rotating with respect to one another. Preventing rotation can be advantageous to a user who desires to prevent portions of a tree from rotating after assembly, such as when the user decorates the tree with lights and other accessories.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">In some embodiments, central male prong <b>210</b> and/or channel male prong <b>215</b> can be spring loaded. For example, when male end <b>205</b> is physically disconnected from female end <b>105</b>, central male prong <b>210</b> and/or channel male prong <b>215</b> can be recessed or retracted. Likewise, when male end <b>205</b> is physically connected to female end <b>105</b>, central male prong <b>210</b> and/or channel male prong <b>215</b> can be extended, by spring action, to provide for electrical connectivity. Employing spring loaded prongs <b>210</b>, <b>215</b> can help to reduce wear and tear on the prongs <b>210</b>, <b>215</b> and can also help to reduce the likelihood of electrical shock when central male prong <b>210</b> and/or channel male prong <b>215</b> are energized.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">Embodiments of the present disclosure can comprise a central receiving void <b>110</b> and/or a channel receiving void <b>115</b> with spring loaded safety covers. More specifically, the central receiving void <b>110</b> and/or a channel receiving void <b>115</b> can have one or more covers that obstruct access to the voids when they are not engaged with prongs of a male end <b>205</b>. In this manner, the safety covers can prevent a user from unintentionally inserting a finger or other object into the voids and receiving an electric shock. The covers can be spring loaded so that they can be depressed by the prongs of the male end <b>205</b> as the male end <b>205</b> and the female end <b>105</b> are joined.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">In some embodiments, it can be desirable to have a guide system, such as a sleeve system, that assists the assembler in aligning the various tree trunk sections with each other during assembly. In some embodiments, a sleeve system can also help secure the tree trunk sections to each other when assembled, and can prevent the assembled tree from swaying or wobbling.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> shows outer sleeve <b>120</b> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> shows inner sleeve <b>220</b> of a sleeve system. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> and <b>2</b></figref>, the outer sleeve <b>120</b> is disposed proximate the female end <b>105</b> and the inner sleeve <b>220</b> is disposed proximate the male end <b>205</b>. But, in some embodiments, the outer sleeve <b>120</b> may be disposed proximate the male end <b>205</b> and the inner sleeve <b>220</b> may be disposed proximate the female end <b>105</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">When an assembler is joining female end <b>105</b> to male end <b>205</b>, and thus joining their respective tree trunk sections <b>100</b> and <b>200</b>, outer sleeve <b>120</b> and inner sleeve <b>220</b> can engage and act as guides to help bring the two tree trunk sections <b>100</b> and <b>200</b> together. Moreover, the use of a sleeve system, such as outer sleeve <b>120</b> and inner sleeve <b>220</b>, can provide additional benefits. For example, the inner diameter of outer sleeve <b>120</b> can be the same size, or nearly the same size, as the outer diameter of inner sleeve <b>220</b> to provide for a secure fit between female end <b>105</b> and male end <b>205</b>. This can help provide lateral support to the joined tree trunk sections <b>100</b> and <b>200</b>, thus reducing the likelihood that a force applied to one of the tree trunk sections (i.e., <b>100</b> and/or <b>200</b>) will cause the tree trunk sections <b>100</b> and <b>200</b> to wobble or separate. An exemplary sleeve system can be found in U.S. Pat. No. 8,916,242, entitled, &#x201c;Connector System,&#x201d; which is owned by the Applicant and the contents of which are hereby incorporated by reference.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>3</b>A-C</figref> show a process of connecting a male end <b>205</b> with a female end <b>105</b> to form a power distribution system <b>305</b>. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref>, illustrated are male end <b>205</b> of a first tree trunk section <b>100</b> and female end <b>105</b> of a second tree trunk section <b>200</b> in a disconnected configuration. When assembling a tree, according to various embodiments of the present disclosure, a user can connect trunk sections <b>100</b> and <b>200</b> by connecting male end <b>205</b> with female end <b>105</b>. More specifically, the user can vertically align the trunk sections <b>100</b> and <b>200</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>B</figref>, which is a cross-sectional view. Once vertically aligned, or at least sufficiently aligned to permit joining, the assembler can move one trunk section <b>100</b> closer to the other trunk section <b>200</b> until the trunk sections <b>100</b> and <b>200</b> engage and are joined, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>C</figref>. In doing so, the assembler has also joined male end <b>205</b> with female end <b>105</b>, providing electrical connectivity between the two pictured trunk sections <b>100</b> and <b>200</b>. More particularly, the central male prong <b>210</b> is inserted into central receiving void <b>110</b> and channel male prong <b>215</b> is inserted into channel receiving void <b>115</b>, allowing electricity to flow between the male end <b>205</b> and the female end <b>105</b>, thus completing power distribution system <b>305</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> shows a cross-section of an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure. Shown are three trunk sections <b>100</b>, <b>200</b>, and <b>400</b>, and two connection areas <b>407</b> and <b>409</b>. Connection area <b>407</b> is where the female end <b>105</b> of trunk section <b>100</b> and the male end <b>205</b> of trunk section <b>200</b> join. Connection area <b>409</b> is where the female end <b>401</b> of trunk section <b>200</b> and the male end <b>403</b> of trunk section <b>400</b> join. Accordingly, the connection areas <b>407</b> and <b>409</b> are areas where trunk sections <b>100</b>, <b>200</b>, and <b>400</b> are connected to form power distribution system <b>305</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>, a power distribution system <b>305</b> can comprise a first female end <b>105</b> connected to a first male end <b>205</b>, a second female end <b>401</b> connected to a second male end <b>403</b>, and one or more electrical wires <b>410</b>. The wires <b>410</b> enable electricity to flow through the trunk sections <b>100</b>, <b>200</b>, and <b>400</b>, and between the first male and female ends <b>205</b>, <b>105</b> and the second male and female ends <b>403</b>, <b>401</b> of power distribution system <b>305</b>. Thus, the wires <b>410</b>, as part of the power distribution system <b>305</b>, enable power to flow from a power source, such as a wall outlet, through the tree and to certain accessories, such as a one more lights or strands of lights. The lights or strands of lights can therefore be illuminated when power is supplied to the tree.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">In some embodiments, it can be desirable to provide for one or more electrical outlets <b>415</b> on the trunk sections <b>100</b> and <b>200</b> along the length of the assembled tree. Thus, one or more power distribution systems <b>305</b> can comprise one or more electrical outlets (e.g., <b>415</b><i>a</i>, <b>415</b><i>b</i>). Outlets <b>415</b><i>a</i>, <b>415</b><i>b</i>, and <b>415</b><i>c </i>can be configured to receive power from wires <b>410</b> to provide a user with the ability to plug in devices, such as tree lights or other electrical components. By providing a convenient location to plug in lights, outlets (e.g., <b>415</b><i>a</i>&#x2014;c) can minimize the amount of effort required to decorate a tree. More specifically, a user can plug a strand of lights directly into an outlet (e.g., <b>415</b><i>a</i>) on a trunk section <b>100</b>, instead of having to connect a series of strands together, which can be cumbersome and frustrating for a user.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">Embodiments of the present disclosure can further comprise strands of lights that are unitarily integrated with the power transfer system. Thus, the lights can be connected to the wires <b>410</b> without the need for outlets (e.g., <b>415</b><i>a</i>&#x2014;c), although outlets <b>415</b><i>a</i>&#x2014;c can be optionally included. Such embodiments can be desirable for trees that come pre-strung with lights, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">In some embodiments, one or more trunk sections (e.g., <b>100</b>, <b>200</b>, <b>400</b>) can comprise a power cord <b>420</b> for receiving power from an outside power source, such as a wall outlet or a battery. The power cord <b>420</b> can be configured to engage a power source and distribute power to the rest of the tree. More specifically, power can flow from the wall outlet, through the power cord, through the power distribution system <b>305</b>, and to accessories on the tree, such as lights or strands of lights. In some embodiments, the power cord <b>420</b> can be located on a lower trunk section <b>100</b> of the tree for reasons of convenience and appearance (i.e., the power cord <b>420</b> is close to the wall outlets and exits the tree at a location that is not immediately visible).</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">Embodiments of the present disclosure can also comprise a bottom section <b>425</b> of one or more trunk sections <b>100</b>. The bottom section <b>425</b> can be substantially conical in shape, and can be configured to engage a stand for the tree (not shown). Accordingly, the bottom section <b>425</b> can be inserted into the stand, and the stand can support the tree, usually in a substantially vertical position.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">In some embodiments, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>, it can be advantageous for a lowest trunk section <b>100</b> of a tree to comprise a female end <b>105</b>. During assembly, a male end <b>205</b> of a neighboring trunk section <b>200</b> can be joined with the female end <b>105</b> of the lowest trunk section <b>100</b>. This can improve safety during assembly because the exposed male prongs are not energized, i.e., they do not have electricity flowing through them until they are inserted into the female end <b>105</b>. To the contrary, if the lowest trunk section comprises a male end (e.g., <b>205</b>), energized prongs can be exposed, and accidental electrical shock can result. Ideally, the power cord <b>420</b> is not plugged into a wall outlet until the tree is fully assembled, but embodiments of the present disclosure are designed to minimize the risk of injury if the tree is plugged in prematurely.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is an external, side view of an assembled tree trunk according to various embodiments of the present disclosure. Three tree trunk sections <b>100</b>, <b>200</b>, and <b>400</b> are assembled and physically connected to one another to support the tree. As discussed previously, it can be desirable to use a sleeve system to secure one tree trunk section <b>100</b> to another tree trunk section <b>200</b>, and outer sleeves <b>120</b> of the sleeve system are also shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>. Power outlets <b>415</b> and power cord <b>420</b> are also shown.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">Other embodiments of the present disclosure can comprise additional features, different features, and/or different combinations of features than the embodiments described above. Some of these embodiments are described below.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> shows an exemplary embodiment of a female end <b>605</b> of a tree trunk section <b>600</b>, which may be used in a power distribution system. Like previously described embodiments, female end <b>605</b> can have a one or more of power voids for receiving power from, or distributing power to, a male end of a tree trunk section (e.g., <b>200</b>). In the embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>, female end <b>605</b> can comprise central receiving void <b>608</b> for engaging with a prong of a male end and channel receiving void <b>610</b> for engaging with another prong of a male end. In some embodiments, the channel receiving void <b>610</b> can be protected by a safety cover <b>615</b> when it is not engaged with a prong of a male end. Outlet <b>620</b>, as described above, is also shown.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> shows a cross-section of female end <b>605</b> adapted for use in a power distribution system. The interior of the central receiving void <b>608</b> and channel receiving void <b>610</b> are shown. Also shown is central contact device <b>705</b> and channel contact device <b>710</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">Central contact device <b>705</b> can be at least partially disposed within central receiving void <b>608</b> and can be designed to make electrical contact with a prong inserted into central receiving void <b>608</b>. Similarly, channel contact device <b>710</b> can be at least partially disposed within channel receiving void <b>610</b>, and can be designed to make electrical contact with a prong inserted into channel receiving void <b>610</b>. In this manner, central contact device <b>705</b> and channel contact device <b>710</b> can conduct power from a male end to a female end <b>605</b>, or from a female end <b>605</b> to a male end, which combine to form a power distribution system.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">Safety cover <b>615</b> and spring member <b>715</b> are also shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref>. Safety cover <b>615</b> can provide a covering for channel receiving void <b>610</b> when the female end <b>605</b> is not engaged with a male end. The safety cover <b>615</b> can therefore prevent a person from inadvertently touching channel contact device <b>810</b>, which could lead to electric shock. The safety cover <b>615</b> can also prevent various items from entering channel receiving void <b>610</b> and causing damage to or blocking access to the channel contact device <b>710</b>. Safety cover <b>615</b> can be supported by spring member <b>715</b>, which can apply a force to the safety cover <b>615</b> to obstruct access to the channel receiving void <b>610</b> when not in use. When a male end is joined with the female end <b>605</b>, the pushing surface <b>1020</b> of the male end cylinder <b>915</b> can push against the safety cover <b>615</b>. This can cause the spring member <b>715</b> to flex and become depressed, depressing the safety cover <b>615</b>, and thereby enabling access to channel receiving void <b>610</b> and channel contact device <b>710</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">Female end <b>605</b> can further comprise a safety gate <b>720</b> at the opening of the central receiving void <b>608</b>. The safety gate <b>720</b> can comprise an opening <b>730</b> that can be the same dimensions as, or nearly the same dimensions as, a prong of a male end that is inserted through the safety gate <b>720</b>. In some embodiments, therefore, the opening <b>730</b> of the safety gate <b>720</b> can be too small to accommodate a finger, and can therefore prevent a user from inserting his or her finger into receiving void <b>608</b> and receiving an electric shock. The opening <b>730</b> can also be small enough to prevent insertion of many other foreign objects, such as metal kitchen utensils, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref>, in some embodiments, central contact device <b>705</b> can have one or more contact sections <b>805</b> that utilize spring action to make contact with a prong inserted into central receiving void <b>608</b>. More specifically, the contact sections <b>805</b> can be configured such that they contact a prong as the prong is inserted into the central receiving void <b>608</b>. As the prong is further inserted into the void, the prong can abut the contact sections <b>805</b>, pushing the contact sections <b>805</b> outwardly, and causing the contact sections <b>805</b> to press against (i.e., spring back against) the prong. In this manner, the spring action of the contact sections <b>805</b> can ensure that the electrical connection between the contact sections <b>805</b> and the prong is effective to transfer electrical power. In addition, the contact sections <b>805</b> can be sufficiently large to ensure an effective electrical connection.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref> depicts an exemplary embodiment of a male end <b>905</b> of a tree trunk section <b>900</b>, which may be used in a power distribution system. Similar to previously described embodiments, male end <b>905</b> can have one or more prongs for receiving power from, or distributing power to, a female end <b>605</b> of a tree trunk section <b>100</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref>, male end <b>905</b> can have a central male prong <b>908</b> and a channel male prong <b>910</b>. In some embodiments, when the central male prong <b>908</b> and channel male prong <b>910</b> of the male end <b>905</b> are inserted into the central receiving void <b>608</b> and channel receiving void <b>610</b> of the female end <b>605</b>, respectively, electrical power can be conducted from male end <b>905</b> to female end <b>605</b>, or vice versa, depending on the direction of electrical power flow. Further, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref>, a male end <b>905</b> may comprise a male end cylinder <b>915</b> having an interior wall <b>920</b> and exterior wall <b>925</b>. In one embodiment, the central male prong <b>908</b> may be disposed proximate the center of the cylinder, and the channel male prong <b>910</b> may be disposed proximate the interior wall <b>920</b> of the cylinder <b>915</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref> shows a cross-section of male end <b>905</b> adapted for use in a power distribution system. The central male prong <b>908</b> and the channel male prong <b>910</b> are both shown. In some embodiments, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref>, the central male prong <b>908</b> has a rounded end that enables the central male prong to engage and separate the contact sections <b>805</b> of the central contact device <b>705</b>. In this manner, after being pushed apart, the contact sections <b>805</b> of the central contact device <b>705</b> can abut the central male prong <b>908</b>, providing an effective electrical connection.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">In some embodiments, channel male prong <b>910</b> can be a bendable prong that flexes as it makes contact with channel contact device <b>710</b>. More specifically, channel male prong <b>910</b> can flex inwardly and outwardly, as required, as it slides into channel receiving void <b>610</b> and abuts channel contact device <b>710</b>. The channel male prong <b>910</b> can be sufficiently resilient to flex, or spring toward channel contact device <b>710</b>, thereby providing an effective electrical connection between the channel male prong <b>910</b> and the channel contact device <b>710</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">In some embodiments, the channel male prong <b>910</b> can comprise a contact area <b>1015</b> that extends from the prong to engage the channel contact device <b>710</b>, thereby facilitating contact between the channel male prong <b>910</b> and the channel contact device <b>710</b>. Further, in some embodiments, the male end cylinder <b>915</b> can comprise a pushing surface <b>1020</b>. The pushing surface <b>1020</b> can be configured to apply a force to the safety cover <b>615</b>, thereby depressing the safety cover <b>615</b> as the male end <b>905</b> and the female end <b>705</b> are joined to form a power distribution system.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>7</b> and <b>10</b></figref> show that the male end <b>905</b> and the female end <b>605</b> of a power distribution system can comprise leads <b>725</b>, <b>1005</b>. The leads <b>725</b>, <b>1005</b> can be electrically connected to one or more of the central male prong <b>908</b>, channel male prong <b>910</b>, central contact device <b>705</b>, and channel contact device <b>710</b>. In some embodiments, therefore, the leads <b>725</b>, <b>1005</b> can electrically connect to wires of a power distribution system (e.g., power distribution system <b>305</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>) to provide electrical connectivity between a male end <b>905</b> and a female end <b>605</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>11</b>A-D</figref> are cross-sections showing the connection of a male end <b>905</b> with a female end <b>605</b>. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>11</b>A and <b>11</b>B</figref>, illustrated are male end <b>905</b> of a first tree trunk section <b>900</b> and female end <b>605</b> of a second tree trunk section <b>600</b> in a disconnected configuration. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b>A</figref> shows a front cross-sectional view of this configuration, whereas <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b>B</figref> shows a side cross-sectional view. When assembling a tree, according to various embodiments of the present disclosure, the assembler can connect trunk sections <b>600</b> and <b>900</b> by connecting male end <b>905</b> with female end <b>605</b>, thus forming a power distribution system. Initially, the assembler can vertically align the trunk sections <b>600</b> and <b>900</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>11</b>A and <b>11</b>B</figref>. Once vertically aligned, or at least sufficiently aligned to permit the adjoining, the assembler can move one trunk section (e.g., <b>900</b>) closer to the other trunk section (e.g., <b>600</b>) until the trunk sections <b>600</b> and <b>900</b> engage, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>11</b>C-D</figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b>C</figref> shows a side cross-sectional view of this configuration, whereas <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b>D</figref> shows a front cross-sectional view. By connecting the male end <b>905</b> and the female end <b>605</b> as described above, the assembler provides electrical connectivity between in the power distribution system <b>1105</b> formed by joining male end <b>905</b> and female end <b>605</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">As described above, in some embodiments, channel receiving void <b>610</b> is disposed in a circular manner around central receiving void <b>608</b>, alleviating any issues concerning the angular rotation of male end <b>905</b> and female end <b>605</b> during assembly. More specifically, channel male prong <b>910</b> can be inserted at any number of positions or locations along channel receiving void <b>610</b>, and establish and maintain electrical connectivity between female end <b>605</b> and male end <b>905</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">To provide effective electrical connectivity, in some embodiments, the center male prong <b>908</b>, the channel male prong <b>910</b>, the central contact device <b>705</b>, and the channel contact device <b>710</b> can comprise electrically conductive material. In some embodiments, for example, the center male prong <b>908</b>, the channel male prong <b>910</b>, the central contact device <b>705</b>, and the channel contact device <b>710</b> can comprise one or more of copper, copper alloy, or any other conductive material.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>11</b>C and <b>11</b>D</figref>, when male end <b>905</b> and female end <b>605</b> are joined, the safety cover <b>615</b> is depressed into an open position. This allows the channel male prong <b>910</b> to enter the channel receiving void <b>610</b>, now occupied by channel male prong <b>910</b> and the safety cover <b>615</b>, and electrically contact the channel contact device <b>710</b>. In addition, central male prong <b>908</b> can contact the contact sections <b>805</b> of the central contact device <b>705</b>, thereby completing the electrical connection between the male end <b>905</b> and female end <b>605</b> of the power distribution system <b>1105</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>12</b></figref> shows a perspective, cross-sectional view of two joined trunk sections <b>600</b> and <b>900</b>. In some embodiments, joined trunk sections <b>600</b> and <b>900</b> can comprise one or more pivot areas. A first pivot area <b>1205</b> can be disposed proximate the area where the male end <b>905</b> and the female end <b>605</b> join. A second pivot area <b>1210</b> can be at a location proximate an area where the outer sleeve <b>1215</b> terminates. Thus, the inclusion of two pivot areas can prevent rocking of the trunk sections <b>600</b> and <b>900</b> when they are joined. This can be advantageous as it can enable the assembled tree maintain balance, thereby preventing the tree from unintentionally falling over.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>13</b>A</figref> shows an exemplary embodiment of a male end <b>905</b> of a a tree trunk section <b>900</b>. In some embodiments, the male end <b>905</b> can comprise one or more first clutch elements <b>1305</b>. In some embodiments, the first clutch elements <b>1305</b> can be protrusions that extend inwardly or outwardly proximate the sides of the male end <b>905</b>. In other embodiments, the first clutch elements <b>1305</b> can be detents, grooves, tabs, slots, and the like. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>13</b>A</figref>, in some embodiments, the first clutch elements <b>1305</b> have a top surface <b>1310</b>. For example, in one embodiment, the top surface <b>1310</b> may angle down from a first height <b>1315</b> (represented by dashed lines) to a second height <b>1320</b> (similarly represented by dashed lines). In one embodiment, a top surface <b>1320</b> that angles from a first height <b>1315</b> to a second height <b>1320</b> may allow the first clutch element <b>1305</b> to disengage from a clutch element of a female end (e.g., female end <b>605</b>). Further, while the top surface <b>1320</b> may be a flat surface, the top surface <b>1320</b> may comprise two or more facades, which may be angled away from one another (e.g., similar to the roof of a house), adapted to assist the first clutch element <b>1305</b> from disengaging a clutch element of a female end (e.g., female end <b>605</b>) when the first clutch element <b>1305</b> comes into contact with a clutch element of a female end.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>13</b>B</figref> shows an exemplary embodiment of a female end <b>605</b> of a tree trunk section <b>600</b>. As shown, the female end <b>605</b> can comprise one or more second clutch elements <b>1350</b>. In some embodiments, the second clutch elements <b>1350</b> can be protrusions that extend inwardly or outwardly proximate the sides of the female end <b>605</b>. In other embodiments, the second clutch elements <b>1350</b> can be detents, grooves, tabs, slots, and the like. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>13</b>B</figref>, the second clutch elements <b>1350</b> may comprise a top surface <b>1355</b>. As with the first clutch element <b>1305</b>, the top surface <b>1355</b> may angle from a first height to a second height. Further, the top surface <b>1355</b> may be flat or comprise a plurality of facades to assist is disengaging the second clutch element <b>1350</b> from a first clutch element <b>1305</b> when a female end <b>605</b> comes into contact with a male end <b>905</b> when, for example, an assembler puts together a Christmas tree of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">As noted above, when two trunk sections (e.g., <b>600</b> and <b>900</b>) are joined such that they are in electrical communication, the first clutch elements <b>1305</b> of the male end <b>905</b> and the second clutch elements <b>1355</b> of the female end <b>605</b> can engage. The engaging clutch elements can prevent the two trunk sections <b>600</b>, <b>900</b> from rotating with respect to one another after tree assembly is complete. This can be advantageous as it can allow a user to align and maintain the trunk sections <b>600</b>, <b>900</b>, and thus the branches of the tree, in a desired configuration. Accordingly, the trunk sections <b>600</b>, <b>900</b> and branches cannot later rotate out of configuration when the tree is decorated or otherwise touched, pulled, bumped, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">Moreover, it would be advantageous for the type of rotational trees discussed herein to be adapted for use with, for example, various LED lights that allow for thousands of color combinations. In some embodiments, a string of LED lights may comprise a plurality of LED lamps. These LED lamps may be referred to as &#x201c;RGB LED lamps&#x201d; and may comprise three LED chips (i.e., red, green, and blue) in addition to an embedded microcontroller unit (MCU). In some embodiments, the embedded MCU comprises at least four leads: two for voltage connections, an electronic signal input, and an electronic signal output. In some embodiments, a separate MCU (i.e., an MCU that is not embedded in an LED lamp and may be mounted proximate to the base of a Christmas tree) transmits a signal that is received by the embedded MCU at the electronic signal input. The embedded MCU processes the signal and outputs signals to each of the red, green, and blue LED chips, as necessary, to enable the LED to produce the desired color.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">In some embodiments, the string of RGB LED lights can be connected in series. Thus, the embedded MCU can transmit the received signal, via the signal output, to the next embedded MCU, which receives the signal via its signal input line, and so on down the series of lights. Accordingly, in some embodiments, the male and female components of a power distribution system comprise at least four electrical connections for compatibility with such LED lamps. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>14</b>-<b>17</b></figref> illustrate components of a power distribution system comprising four electrical connections.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>14</b></figref> is an exploded view of a female end <b>1405</b> of a tree trunk section <b>1400</b>, according to one embodiment. As shown, the female end may comprise an outer collar (or outer sleeve) <b>1415</b> for coupling the tree trunk section <b>1400</b> to a second trunk section (e.g., <b>900</b>) to form a power distribution system. Further, the female end <b>1405</b> may comprise a female end base <b>1420</b>, which may comprise a plurality of clutch elements <b>1422</b> with functionality the same as or similar to first and second clutch elements <b>1305</b>, <b>1350</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">The female end <b>1405</b> may further comprise a female end base <b>1448</b> that comprises a central receiving void (or central void) <b>1450</b> and channel receiving void (or channel void) <b>1452</b>, which may be configured similarly to central receiving void <b>608</b> and channel receiving void <b>610</b> as discussed above. Further, in some embodiments, a female end base <b>1448</b> may comprise a female end base extension <b>1449</b> and an outer wall <b>1451</b>. In some embodiments, the central receiving void <b>1450</b> may be disposed within the female end base extension <b>1449</b>. Further, the female end base extension <b>1449</b> may be disposed proximate the center of the channel receiving void <b>1452</b>, in some embodiments. The outer wall <b>1451</b> may have exterior and interior surfaces, and the outer wall <b>1451</b> may define the perimeter (or circumference) of the channel receiving void <b>1452</b> (i.e., the interior surface of the outer wall <b>1451</b> may define the perimeter (or circumference) of the channel receiving void <b>1452</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">Also, the female end <b>1405</b> may comprise a safety cover <b>1425</b>, safety cover stopper <b>1426</b>, and spring member <b>1427</b> to provide covering for central receiving void <b>1450</b> and channel receiving void <b>1452</b> when the female end <b>1405</b> is not engaging a male end (e.g., <b>905</b>). In some embodiments, the safety cover <b>1425</b>, safety cover stopper <b>1426</b>, and spring member <b>1427</b> may provide functionality the same as or similar to safety cover <b>615</b>, as discussed above.</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">To accommodate the RGB LED lamps, as discussed above, the female end <b>1405</b> may comprise four electrical contacts. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>14</b></figref>, the female end <b>1405</b> may comprise a central contact device <b>1430</b> and a first channel contact device <b>1435</b>, which are similar to central contact device <b>705</b> and channel contact device <b>710</b>, discussed previously. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>14</b></figref>, in some embodiments, the central contact device <b>1430</b> may be disposed within the circumference provided by the first channel contact device <b>1435</b>, which can be ring-shaped, and the central contact device <b>1430</b> may be spring loaded (i.e., the central contact device comprises one or more spring activated contact sections). Further, female end <b>1405</b> may comprise a second and third channel contact device <b>1440</b> and <b>1445</b>, respectively. In some embodiments, the second channel contact device <b>1440</b> and the third channel contact device <b>1445</b> may each be configured as a half circle such that, when brought together, they form a circular enclosure inside which the first channel contact device <b>1435</b> and the central contact device <b>1430</b> are disposed. Further, as will be appreciated, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>14</b></figref>, the second channel contact device <b>1440</b> and the third channel contact device <b>1445</b> provide near-360&#xb0; contact surface that can be in electrical communication with one or more male prongs. The second channel contact device <b>1440</b> and the third channel contact device <b>1445</b> may be made from a conductive material and function similar to, for example, channel contact device <b>710</b>. Finally, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>14</b></figref>, in one embodiment, the central contact device <b>1430</b> and first, second, and third channel contact devices <b>1435</b>, <b>1440</b>, <b>1445</b> comprise leads that can be connected to corresponding male prongs to complete a power distribution system.</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0098"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>15</b>A and <b>15</b>B</figref> are alternate perspective views of a female end <b>1405</b>, according to one embodiment. As shown, the central contact device <b>1430</b> is disposed within the central receiving void <b>1450</b>. In addition, the first channel contact device <b>1435</b> may be disposed proximate the exterior of female end base extension <b>1449</b>. Further, as shown, the second and third channel contact devices <b>1440</b>, <b>1445</b> may be disposed proximate the interior of the outer wall <b>1451</b> of the female end base <b>1448</b>. As shown, the second channel contact device <b>1440</b> and third channel contact device <b>1445</b> may form a ring-shaped structure that encircles the first channel contact device <b>1435</b> with the channel receiving void <b>1452</b> disposed between the ring formed by the second channel contact device <b>1440</b> and third channel contact device <b>1445</b> and the first channel contact device <b>1435</b>. As shown, in one embodiment, the second channel contact device <b>1440</b> and third channel contact device <b>1445</b> are electrically isolated, as are first channel contact device <b>1435</b> and central contact device <b>1430</b>. As such, the contact devices (i.e., <b>1430</b>, <b>1435</b>, <b>1440</b>, and <b>1445</b>) are not pole sensitive and may be configured to carry a low voltage input signal or AC supply voltage. Accordingly, they allow for ease of connectivity between the female end <b>1405</b> and a male end (e.g., <b>905</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0099"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>16</b></figref> is an exploded view of a male end <b>1605</b> of a tree trunk section <b>1600</b>, which may be adapted to be inserted into female end <b>1405</b> to form a power distribution system. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>16</b></figref>, in some embodiments, the male end <b>1605</b> may comprise a male connector base (or inner collar) <b>1610</b>, which may be further adapted for engaging a female end <b>1405</b> and creating a coupling between the male end <b>1605</b> and the female end <b>1405</b>. In particular, the male connector base <b>1610</b> may be adapted for engaging an outer collar <b>1415</b> of the female end <b>1405</b>. Further, the male end <b>1605</b> may comprise various electrical prongs for electrical connection with the female end <b>1405</b> to allow for electrical communication between the male and female ends <b>1605</b>, <b>1405</b>. For example, in one embodiment, the male end <b>1605</b> may comprise a center male terminal prong (or central prong) <b>1615</b> that can be inserted into the central receiving void <b>1450</b> to make contact with the central contact device <b>1430</b>. In some embodiments, then the center male terminal prong <b>1615</b> contacts the central contact device <b>1430</b>, the center male terminal prong <b>1615</b> causes the central contact device <b>1430</b> to retract or recess, and when the center male terminal prong <b>1615</b> disengages the central contact device <b>1430</b>, the central contact device <b>1430</b> returns to a neutral position.</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0100">Further, in certain embodiments, the male end <b>1605</b> may comprise a first channel male terminal prong (or first channel prong) <b>1620</b> that can be inserted into the channel receiving void <b>1452</b> to make contact with the first channel contact device <b>1435</b>. Similarly, in certain embodiments, the male end <b>1605</b> may comprise second and third channel male terminal prongs (or second channel prong and third channel prong) <b>1625</b> and <b>1630</b>, respectively. Second channel male terminal prong <b>1625</b> and third channel male terminal prong <b>1630</b> may be configured such that when inserted into channel receiving void <b>1452</b>, second channel male terminal prong <b>1625</b> and third channel male terminal prong <b>1630</b> engage second channel contact device <b>1440</b> and third channel contact device <b>1445</b>. Further, in some embodiments, first, second, and third channel male terminal prongs <b>1620</b>, <b>1625</b>, and <b>1630</b> may comprise a contact area <b>1640</b>, <b>1645</b>, and <b>1650</b>, respectively, that extends from the respective prongs to engage a channel contact device (e.g., <b>1435</b>, <b>1440</b>, and <b>1445</b>), thereby facilitating contact between the respective channel male prongs and the channel contact devices. The respective contact areas <b>1640</b>, <b>1645</b>, and <b>1650</b> may be flexible such that they can flex toward and away from contact devices (e.g., <b>1435</b>, <b>1440</b>, <b>1445</b>). Additionally, in some embodiments, first, second, and third channel male terminal prongs <b>1620</b>, <b>1625</b>, and <b>1630</b> can be spring loaded. For example, when male end <b>1605</b> is physically disconnected from female end <b>1405</b>, first, second, and/or third channel male terminal prongs <b>1620</b>, <b>1625</b>, and <b>1630</b> can be recessed or retracted. Likewise, when male end <b>1605</b> is physically connected to female end <b>1405</b>, central first, second, and/or third channel male terminal prongs <b>1620</b>, <b>1625</b>, and <b>1630</b> can be extended, by spring action, to provide for electrical connectivity. As will be appreciated, employing spring loaded prongs <b>1620</b>, <b>1625</b>, and <b>1630</b> can help to reduce wear and tear on the prongs <b>1620</b>, <b>1625</b>, and <b>1630</b> and can also help to reduce the likelihood of electrical shock when the male end <b>1605</b> and female end <b>1405</b> are energized.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0101">As discussed, because second channel contact device <b>1440</b> and third channel contact device <b>1445</b> are electrically isolated, second male terminal prong <b>1625</b> and third male terminal prong <b>1630</b> can contact either of the second channel contact device <b>1440</b> and third channel contact device <b>1445</b> to create an electrical communication.</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0102"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>17</b></figref> is a perspective view of a male end <b>1605</b>, according to some embodiments. As shown, the center male terminal prong <b>1615</b> is disposed proximate the center of a male end cylinder <b>1715</b>. Further, the first channel male terminal <b>1620</b> may be disposed proximate the interior wall of the male end cylinder <b>1715</b>. According to one embodiment, the second and third channel male terminal prongs <b>1625</b>, <b>1630</b> may be disposed proximate the exterior wall of the male end cylinder <b>1715</b>. As shown, in one embodiment, the second and third channel male terminal prongs <b>1625</b>, <b>1630</b> may be disposed about 180&#xb0; apart on the surface of the male end cylinder <b>1715</b>. Further, as shown, the male end cylinder <b>1715</b> may comprise various apertures to accommodate the various channel male terminals <b>1620</b>, <b>1625</b>, and <b>1630</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0103">As will be understood, female end <b>1405</b> and male end <b>1605</b>, and the electrical contacts (e.g., <b>1435</b>, <b>1440</b>, <b>1440</b>, and <b>1445</b>) and prongs (e.g., <b>1615</b>, <b>1620</b>, <b>1625</b>, <b>1630</b>) composing the female end <b>1405</b> and male end <b>1605</b>, respectively, may function the same as or similar to, and be connected to form a power distribution system in a manner the same as or similar to, the components discussed in relation to, for example, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>3</b>B and <b>3</b>C</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0104">Further embodiments may include a male end (e.g., <b>1605</b>) and female end (e.g., <b>1405</b>) adapted to form a power distribution system with six electrical contacts. For example, consumers may desire Christmas trees that can accommodate LED light strings (e.g., RGB LED light strings) as well as back-fill lights. So, in such configurations, four wires are necessary for powering the RGB LED lights, and two additional wires are necessary to supply power to the back-fill lights. Typically, the four wires are used for signal lines (input and output) as well as +ve and &#x2212;ve supply connections (e.g., 120V AC). The two remaining wires can be reserved for the back-fill lights and supply, for example, 29V DC. In one embodiment, the four wires are connected to a control box at the base of the tree, and the two wires for the back-fill lights are connected to a power adapter of DC power (e.g., 29V DC).</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0105"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>18</b></figref> shows a completed tree <b>1800</b> in accordance with some embodiments of the present disclosure. The tree has been assembled by electrically connecting various trunk sections as described herein, and has been decorated in accordance with a user's liking.</p>
<p id="p-0107" num="0106">While the present disclosure has been described in connection with a plurality of exemplary aspects, as illustrated in the various figures and discussed above, it is understood that other similar aspects can be used or modifications and additions can be made to the described aspects for performing the same function of the present disclosure without deviating therefrom. For example, in various aspects of the disclosure, methods and compositions were described according to aspects of the presently disclosed subject matter. However, other equivalent methods or composition to these described aspects are also contemplated by the teachings herein. Therefore, the present disclosure should not be limited to any single aspect, but rather construed in breadth and scope in accordance with the appended claims.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. An artificial tree system comprising:
<claim-text>a plurality of tree trunk sections;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a male end of a first trunk section of the plurality of tree trunk sections, the male end having a central prong and a first, a second, and a third channel prong, the central prong and the first, second, and third channel prongs configured to conduct electricity; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a female end of a second trunk section of the plurality of tree trunk sections, the female end comprising:
<claim-text>a substantially circular outer wall (i) comprising an interior surface and (ii) defining a substantially circular channel void, the channel void having a first, a second, and a third channel contact device disposed at least partially therein, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a substantially circular female end base extension (i) comprising an outer surface, (ii) disposed proximate the channel void's center, and (iii) defining a central void, the central void having a central contact device disposed at least partially therein,</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the central prong is configured to engage the central contact device, the first channel prong is configured to engage the first channel contact, and the second and third channel prongs are configured to engage the second and third channel contacts to conduct electricity between the male end of the first trunk section and the female end of the second trunk section.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The artificial tree system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first channel contact device is ring-shaped and substantially abuts the outer surface of the female base end extension.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The artificial tree system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the second and third channel contact devices substantially abut the interior surface.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The artificial tree system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first trunk section further comprises a first and a second light string, a second trunk section further comprises a third, a fourth, a fifth, and a sixth light string, and a third trunk section further comprises a seventh and an eighth light string.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The artificial tree system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein at least one of the first, second, third, fourth, fifth, sixth, seventh, and eighth light strings comprises a plurality of single-color LED lamps.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The artificial tree system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein at least one of the first, second, third, fourth, fifth, sixth, seventh, and eighth light strings comprises a plurality of RGB LED lamps.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The artificial tree system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein each RGB LED lamp of the plurality of RGB LED lamps comprises an embedded microcontroller unit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The artificial tree of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the central contact device comprises one or more spring activated contact sections, and wherein, when the central prong engages the central contact device, the central prong pushes a spring activated contact section of the one or more spring activated contact sections causing the spring activated contact section to press against the central prong to maintain electrical contact between the central prong and the central contact device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The artificial tree of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the male end further comprises a first plurality of distinct, radially extending clutch elements, each radially extending clutch element having a first height and a first surface extending downward at a first angle from the first height.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The artificial tree of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the female end further comprises a second plurality of distinct, radially extending clutch elements, each radially extending clutch element having a second height and a second surface extending downward at a second angle from the second height.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The artificial tree of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the first plurality of radially extending clutch elements are configured to mate with the second plurality of radially extending clutch elements such that, when the trunk sections are mated, the rotation of the first trunk section is restricted with respect to the second trunk section.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. An artificial tree comprising:
<claim-text>a plurality of tree trunk sections;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a male end of a first trunk section of the plurality of tree trunk sections, the male end comprising a central prong, a first channel prong, a second channel prong, and a third channel prong, the central prong and the first, second, and third channel prongs configured to conduct electricity; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a female end of a second trunk section of the plurality of tree trunk sections, the female end comprising:
<claim-text>a substantially circular outer wall (i) comprising an interior surface and (ii) defining a perimeter of a channel void, the channel void being substantially circular;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a substantially circular female end base extension disposed proximate the substantially circular channel void's center, the female end base extension defining a central void, the female end base extension comprising an outer surface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first, a second, and a third channel contact device disposed at least partially within the channel void, the first, second, and third channel contact devices configured to conduct electricity; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a central contact device disposed at least partially within the central void, the central contact device configured to conduct electricity,</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the central prong is configured to engage the central contact device, the first channel prong is configured to engage the first channel contact, and the second and third channel prongs are configured to engage the second and third channel contacts to conduct electricity between the male end of the first trunk section and the female end of the second trunk section, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first trunk section comprises an inner sleeve proximate the male end of the first trunk section and the second trunk section comprises an outer sleeve proximate the female end of the second trunk section, the inner sleeve configured to engage the outer sleeve.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. The artificial tree of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the first channel contact device being ring-shaped and substantially abutting the outer surface of the female end base extension, and the second and third channel contact devices substantially abutting the interior surface.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The artificial tree of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the first, second, and third channel contact devices are electrically isolated, and wherein the first channel prong is configured to engage the first channel contact device at a plurality of locations, the second channel prong is configured to engage the second or third channel contact device at a plurality of locations, and the third channel prong is configured to engage the second or third channel contact device that is not engaged by the second channel prong, each configuration providing a different rotational alignment of the first trunk section with respect to the second trunk section.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. The artificial tree of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the inner sleeve further comprises a first plurality of distinct, radially extending clutch elements, each radially extending clutch element having a first height and a first surface extending downward at a first angle from the first height.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. The artificial tree of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the outer sleeve further comprises a second plurality of distinct, radially extending clutch elements, each radially extending clutch element having a second height and a second surface extending downward at a second angle from the second height.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. The artificial tree of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the first plurality of radially extending clutch elements are configured to mate with the second plurality of radially extending clutch elements such that, when the trunk sections are mated, the rotation of the first trunk section is restricted with respect to the second trunk section.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. The artificial tree of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref> further comprising a safety cover to obstruct access to the channel void, the safety cover supported by a spring member.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. The artificial tree of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the first channel prong of the male end is configured to engage the first channel contact device of the female end at a plurality of locations, each configuration providing a different rotational alignment of the first trunk section with respect to the second trunk section.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. An artificial Christmas tree comprising:
<claim-text>a first tree trunk section having:
<claim-text>a male end, the male end comprising a central prong, a first channel prong, a second channel prong, and a third channel prong, the central prong and the first, second, and third channel prongs configured to conduct electricity;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of distinct, radially extending clutch elements, each radially extending clutch element having a height and a surface extending downward at an angle from the height, the radially extending clutch elements restricting the first trunk section from rotating with respect to the second trunk section,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second tree trunk section having:
<claim-text>a female end of a second trunk section of the plurality of tree trunk sections, the female end comprising:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a substantially circular outer wall having an interior surface, the outer wall defining a perimeter of a substantially circular channel void;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a substantially circular female end base extension disposed proximate the substantially circular channel void's center, the female end base extension defining a central void and having an outer surface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first channel contact device configured in a ring shape and substantially abutting the outer surface of the female end base extension;</claim-text>
<claim-text>second and third channel contact devices substantially abutting the interior surface of the outer wall, the first, second, and third channel contact devices configured to conduct electricity; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a central contact device disposed at least partially within the central void, the central contact device and the first, second, and third channel contact devices configured to conduct electricity; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second plurality of distinct, radially extending clutch elements, each radially extending clutch element having a height and a surface extending downward at an angle from the height, the radially extending clutch elements restricting the first trunk section from rotating with respect to the second trunk section,</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the central prong is configured to engage the central contact device, the first channel prong is configured to engage the first channel contact, and the second and third channel prongs are configured to engage the second and third channel contacts to conduct electricity between the male end of the first trunk section and the female end of the second trunk section.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
