<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225456A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225456</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17989290</doc-number>
<date>20221117</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>17</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>43</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>13</main-group>
<subgroup>22</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>43</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>13</main-group>
<subgroup>22</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">SOCK SHOE</invention-title>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>63300931</doc-number>
<date>20220119</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>AJ &#x26; B Consulting Limited C/O Trident Trust</orgname>
<address>
<city>Sheung Wan</city>
<country>HK</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>HK</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Fox</last-name>
<first-name>David</first-name>
<address>
<city>Five Dock</city>
<country>AU</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A sock shoe has a single layer of base fabric having a volumetric configuration for receiving at least a forefoot portion of a user's foot. The sock shoe is configured with an upper portion for receiving a top portion of the user's foot and a bottom portion for receiving a bottom portion of the user's foot. The base fabric has a knit or woven structure that is resiliently elastic. An elastomeric coating is fused to the base fabric in a single-layer unitary structure to provide at least two of: (i) a retention function, (ii) a durability/foot protection function, (iii) a grip or anti-slip function, and (iv) an outsole function. The bottom portion having an outer-facing, ground-contacting surface and an inner-facing, foot-contacting surface, the ground-contacting surface including at least one outsole portion being formed of the fused elastomeric material, and the inner-facing, foot-contacting surface being formed of the fused elastomeric material.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="230.63mm" wi="102.28mm" file="US20230225456A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="217.93mm" wi="194.31mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225456A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="173.14mm" wi="181.53mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225456A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="162.98mm" wi="121.50mm" file="US20230225456A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="172.38mm" wi="150.71mm" file="US20230225456A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="240.37mm" wi="104.31mm" file="US20230225456A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="192.53mm" wi="169.84mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225456A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="242.57mm" wi="99.74mm" file="US20230225456A1-20230720-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="217.68mm" wi="167.30mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225456A1-20230720-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="245.19mm" wi="117.52mm" file="US20230225456A1-20230720-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="193.04mm" wi="118.45mm" file="US20230225456A1-20230720-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">PRIORITY</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims benefit of and priority to U.S. Provisional Patent Application No. 63/300,931, filed Jan. 19, 2022, which is hereby incorporated by reference in its entirety as if fully set forth herein, for all purposes.</p>
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="tail"?>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The inventive subject matter is generally directed to a lightweight and supple item of footwear that is constructed to provide an almost barefoot experience. The footwear may be used in fitness activities like bane, Pilates, yoga, athleisure. It may also be used in sports outdoor activities like rock climbing (indoor/outdoor), kickboxing, surfing, standup paddle board wrestling, and other activities which would benefit from a more barefoot-like shoe. Participants in such activities desire an unencumbered foot, a barefoot effect for better proprioception, comfort, agility and aesthetics during their activities. They also may prefer a barefoot aesthetic, with minimum foot coverage or disruption to the natural contours of the foot.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Modern sneakers and athletic shoes do not serve such users well in any of the foregoing respects. They are made of various layers of materials including bulky midsole and outsole materials, insoles, and relatively heavy and coarse upper materials, which may be in multiple plies. They also require clunky or unwieldly fit and closure systems such as laces, tongues, Velcro &#xae; fasteners, and cable systems. Such shoes are not only bulky and clunky, but they are also heavy and lack breathability.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">A simple sock might be considered as a solution that is lightweight. Socks are typically knit structures because of the inherent stretchiness of knit structures relative to woven structures. The stretchiness allows the sock to conform well to a user's foot when encased in a shoe. But when not encased in a shoe, socks do not stay secured to a user's foot during activities&#x2014;they slide around and can bunch up. They also do not provide traction, durability or protection during activities.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Some attempts have been made to modify socks so that they have such features. They may have rubberized coatings on their bottoms or other portions. However, such sock shoes, particularly knit socks, while providing some traction, durability or protection still suffer from the problem of sliding around and bunching up. Therefore, there have been attempts to address the problems. Some prior art shoe socks may go above ankle to attain a secure hold on foot; or use they use bulky and inconvenient laces or straps to secure to the foot. They may also be made of heavier or coarser materials that impact breathability or detract from the natural aesthetics of the foot.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Accordingly, an adequate sock shoe has not been developed that fills the needs of those seeking a barefoot effect and look during activities like bane and yoga, for example.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">A sock shoe has a single layer of base fabric having a volumetric configuration for receiving at least a forefoot portion of a user's foot. The sock shoe is configured with an upper portion for receiving a top portion of the user's foot and a bottom portion for receiving a bottom portion of the user's foot. The base fabric has a knit or woven structure that is resiliently elastic. An elastomeric coating is fused to the base fabric in a single-layer unitary structure to provide at least two of: (i) a retention function, (ii) a durability/foot protection function, (iii) a grip or anti-slip function, and (iv) an outsole function. The bottom portion having an outer-facing, ground-contacting surface and an inner-facing, foot-contacting surface, the ground-contacting surface including at least one outsole portion being formed of the fused elastomeric material, and the inner-facing, foot-contacting surface being formed of the fused elastomeric material.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In certain embodiments, the inventive subject matter can overcome problems in the prior art by providing a knitted or woven sock-like foot compartment that has a base fabric with more elasticity than a conventional knit sock. For example, the base fabric used in certain embodiments may have relatively more elastane fibers to provide more elasticity, i.e., more resilient stretch, which will enhance how the foot compartment conforms to the contours of a foot. Selectively adding an elastomeric coating to such a base fabric, according to the inventive subject matter, offers further advantage, allowing the foot compartment to retain an original shape and yet allowing stretch where needed.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">These and other embodiments are described in more detail in the following detailed descriptions and the figures.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The following is a non-exhaustive description of various possible inventive lines under the inventive subject matter.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In one possible general embodiment, the inventive subject matter is directed to a sock shoe that includes a foot compartment formed of a single-layer, unitary structure of a base fabric. An elastomeric coating is fused to the base fabric. The compartment includes two tiers of mesh, the first tier is defined in the base fabric, and second tier is defined in the coating. The sock shoe is resiliently stretchable and conforming to the contours of the intended user's foot.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In any embodiment, the sock shoe may have a unitary structure that represents at least 50% of the surface area of the foot compartment.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In any embodiment, The base fabric may be a synthetic fabric comprising elastic yarns. In any embodiment, the base fabric may be a knit structure.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In any embodiment, the sock shoe may have one or more patterns or zones of elastomeric material heat fused to base fabric or unitary structure, the patterns or zones providing a foot retention function, the elastomeric material having relatively less elasticity than the base fabric and forming part of the unitary structure. In any embodiment, the pattern may be configured to create tension around the user's instep and/or at least one side of the foot.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In any embodiment, the foot compartment may be configured to have a topline that fits under the ankle of the intended user.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In any embodiment, the foot compartment may be tongueless.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In any embodiment, the foot compartment may be laceless and free of any retention system other than what is inherent in the single-layer, unitary structure.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In any embodiment, the sock shoe may include one or more outsole portions formed of elastomeric material fused to the base fabric and forming part of the unitary structure.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In any embodiment, there may be a forefoot outsole portion and/or a rearfoot outsole portion, and the midfoot is free or substantially free of an outsole portion.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">In any embodiment, the sock shoe may include an insole portion formed of elastomeric material fused to the base fabric and forming part of the unitary structure, the insole portion coating the base fabric in a pattern that provides grippiness and anti-foot slip.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In any embodiment, an elastomeric coating on outer surface of the foot compartment may enhance grippiness for interaction with other surfaces.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In any embodiment, the mesh openings of the second tier of the elastomeric coating may have a larger area than the first-tier mesh openings in the base fabric.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In any embodiment, the elastomeric coating may be configured in a pattern that provides selective, anisotropic restriction stretchability of the upper in desired areas.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The elastomeric coating may be configured as one or more bands extending over the top and sides shoe that are configured to resiliently stretch when receiving the user's foot and tension the sock shoe's upper on the user's foot.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In any embodiment, the mesh openings in the elastomeric coating may have a diameter or a width of from 1 mm to 1.5 mm and the diameter or width of the mesh openings in the base fabric are 0.5 mm to 0.75 mm, when both meshes are under static (untensioned) conditions.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">In any embodiment, the mesh openings of the elastomeric coating may have a geometric shape configured for an anisotropic stretch effect.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">In any embodiment, the mesh opening in the elastomeric coating may be larger than the mesh openings in the base fabric.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">In any embodiment, the openings may have a hexagonal shape.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">In another possible general embodiment, the inventive subject matter is directed to a sock shoe that includes a single layer of base fabric having a volumetric configuration for receiving at least a forefoot portion of a user's foot and configured with an upper portion for receiving a top portion of the user's foot and a bottom portion for receiving a bottom portion of the intended user's foot. The base fabric is a woven or knit structure that is resiliently elastic. An elastomeric coating material is fused to the base fabric in a single-layer unitary structure to provide at least two of: (i) a retention function, (ii) a durability/foot protection function, (iii) a grip or anti-slip function, and (iv) an outsole function. The bottom portion has an outer-facing, ground-contacting surface and an inner-facing, foot-contacting surface. The ground-contacting surface includes at least one outsole portion being formed of the fused elastomeric material, and the inner-facing, foot-contacting surface is formed of the fused elastomeric material.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">In any embodiment, the upper portion of the sock shoe may have on its outer surface a coating of the fused elastic material in a pattern configured to provide a foot-retention function.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">In any embodiment, the elastomeric material may be deposited in a pattern on the upper portion of the sock shoe that extends transverse to the longitudinal axis of the sock shoe thereby being tensionable around the foot of the intended user and retentive to the foot.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">In any embodiment, the elastomeric material may be applied to the outer surface of the sock shoe and thereby also provides a grippy areas for a user to engage other surfaces.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">In any embodiment, the sock shoe may have a topline that includes the fused elastomeric material, which is configured to provide a foot-retention function.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">In any embodiment, the sock shoe may include a toe cap formed of the fused elastomeric material to provide durability and toe protection.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">In any embodiment, the distal portion of the sock shoe may include one or more toe openings to expose some or all of an intended user's toes. In any embodiment, any toe openings may include an elastic web structure that tensions around the toe or toes of the intended user.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In any embodiment, the sock shoe may not include a rearfoot section and/or a midfoot/rearfoot sections.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The foregoing is not intended to be an exhaustive list of the general and specific embodiments and features of the inventive subject matter. Persons skilled in the art are capable of appreciating other embodiments and features from the following detailed description in conjunction with the drawings.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The appended figures show embodiments according to the inventive subject matter, unless noted as showing prior art.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">FIG.<b>1</b></p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref> shows a top view of a shoe.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>B</figref> shows a lateral view of a shoe.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref> shows a medial view of a shoe.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>D</figref> shows a front view of a shoe.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>E</figref> shows a bottom view of a shoe.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>F</figref> shows a rear view of a shoe.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">FIG.<b>2</b></p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>A</figref> shows a top view of a shoe.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>B</figref> shows a bottom view of a shoe.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>C</figref> shows a medial view of a shoe.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>D</figref> shows a front view of a shoe.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>E</figref> shows a lateral view of a shoe.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>F</figref> shows a rear view of a shoe.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">FIG.<b>3</b></p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref> shows a top view of a shoe.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>B</figref> shows a lateral view of a shoe.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>C</figref> shows a bottom view of a shoe.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref></p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>A</figref> shows an upper portion of a shoe.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>B</figref> shows a lower and heel portion of a shoe.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref></p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b>A</figref> shows an upper portion of a shoe.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b>B</figref> shows a lower and heel portion of the shoe.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref></p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref> shows an upper and strap portion of a shoe.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>B</figref> shows a lower and heel portion of a shoe.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> shows foot anatomy and shoe portions that correspond to certain anatomical areas.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">Representative embodiments according to the inventive subject matter are shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>-<b>7</b></figref> wherein the same or generally similar features share common reference numerals.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">The inventive subject matter is generally directed to a sock shoe having a foot receiving compartment having a volumetric configuration for receiving a user's foot. Advantageously, the entire foot compartment can be a single-layer, unitary structure with multiple built functions discussed below. In some embodiments the foot compartment has a low-top design with a topline that is disposed below a user's ankle. Low tops may be desirable for certain activities like yoga, pilates, etc. In other embodiments, it may be desirable for the foot compartment to have a high-top design with a topline that is disposed above a user's ankle. High tops may be desirable for certain activities like surfing, wrestling, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">The compartment includes an upper portion for receiving a top portion of the user's foot and sole portion having a first surface for receiving a bottom portion of the user's foot and an opposite, second surface for contacting the ground. The compartment is made from a supple, foot-conforming base fabric that has elasticity so that it resiliently conforms to the contours of all sides of a foot.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">A thermoplastic elastomeric material is heat fused to selected areas of the base fabric or other textile to create a unitary, single-layer structure. On a bottom side of the compartment (sole portion), the elastomeric material may provide outsole functions. On the foot-facing surface of the sole portion, the elastomeric material may be provided in a pattern and locations that provide anti-slip functions for the foot so that the compartment does not shift on the foot during activities. The foot-facing side of the upper portion may also have a pattern of elastomeric material that is grippy and anti-slip so the upper does not shift on the user's foot.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">The elastomeric material may be applied in thin layers that allow the compartment to remain flexible and follow the contours of the foot. The material may be applied in a liquid or solid phase. Example thermoplastic polymer materials include polyurethane, nylon, polyester, polyethylene, neoprene, and polyolefin. Liquid silicone rubbers although they may not technically be a thermoplastic elastomer may be considered as such for purposes of the inventive subject matter.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">Patterns and shapes of the elastomeric material may be defined in molds with defined patterns or shapes on sheet materials, which are die cut, laser cut, manually cut, etc. The processing of liquid materials into a pattern or shape may be by direct application to a base textile or by first forming the pattern or shape and then applying the part to the base material. Various techniques are known for fusing thermoplastic materials to textiles, including and heat sealing, high frequency welding, injection molding, heat/pressure molding, laser welding, impulse welding, and ultrasonic welding.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">The elastomeric material may be fused on the base fabric in a mesh pattern that mimics a mesh pattern in the base fabric, although the openings in the elastomeric mesh coating may be larger or smaller than the openings in the base fabric. In certain embodiments, the mesh fabric (in a static, unstretched condition) has mesh openings of from 0.5 mm to 0.75 mm in diameter or in a width dimension, or thereabout such range endpoints, and including any points in the range. In certain embodiments, the overlying elastomeric mesh pattern (in a static, unstretched condition) has mesh openings of from 1 mm to 1.5 mm in diameter or in a width dimension, or thereabout such range endpoints. Accordingly, the inventive subject matter contemplates a foot compartment that can be made with a single, unitary structure consisting of a first tier of an elastomeric mesh fused to a second tier of base fabric. Moreover, the unitary structure could have additional tiers. For example, a foot compartment could have an outer tier of elastomeric mesh, and intermediate tier of base fabric, and inner tier of elastomeric mesh. The elastomeric tier(s) could also be formed with other patterns or shapes, in addition or instead of a mesh pattern.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">Coextensive tiers of the mesh patterns of the elastomeric and underlying base fabrics may represent some or all of the surface area of the compartment. For example, in some embodiments, they represent at least 50%, 60%, 70%, 80% or more of the compartment's surface area. By making the compartment with at least a 50% mesh coverage, the sock shoe provides enhanced breathability. The overlying elastomeric mesh structure also helps provide better foot retention, grippiness durability and foot protection than an uncoated mesh base fabric.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">The mesh openings of the elastomeric coating can have any geometrical shape. They may be circular, square, parallelogram, diamond, triangular, other polygonal shape, oval, irregular. The elastomeric coating on the base fabric shown in the Figures has hexagonal openings. By making the opening asymmetric, e.g., diamond or oval, the mesh structure can be tuned to provide more stretch in one direction versus another, i.e., the foot compartment can an anisotropically stretch. In discussing sizes of mesh openings, it is to be understood that a section of material might have a variation of sizes. So, in referencing or comparing sizes of openings, the average or predominant opening size in the section may be used as the size. For example, if one mesh pattern is being compared with another and the mesh openings are not uniformly sized, the average or dominating sizes for each pattern may be used to compare one with another. Further, the term &#x201c;size&#x201d; generally assumes diameter for a circular opening or a width dimension of a non-circular opening like a square. In the case of other shapes, sizing comparisons may be based on comparison of the average surface area of openings in each pattern, i.e., the surface area is considered a &#x201c;size&#x201d;.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">As discussed in more detail below, selected areas of the compartment may have elastomeric material heat fused to the base material in predetermined patterns or shapes to provide desired functions such as foot retention features or durability and foot protection. Particularly suitable elastomeric materials include thermoplastic rubbery materials like thermoplastic polyurethane (e.g., TPU, KPU). (KPU is thermo-pressed polyurethane liquid or PU liquid. It is available as Kurim &#x2122; polyurethane from Taiwan Kurim Enterprises Co., Ltd., Taichung City, Taiwan, https://www.kurim.com.tw/)</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">Accordingly, the inventive subject matter provides a sock-like shoe that may be based on a single layer of material with multiple functions built in. Advantageously, the shoe does not require laces, tongues, binding, straps, insoles, heel cups, midsoles or other complicating systems or features.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">The shoe may be assembled from a pattern on a flat sheet of material where the upper and bottom portions of the shoe are laid out. The base fabric is simply heat infused with the elastomeric material, and the upper and bottom parts are stitched or otherwise connected together to form the foot compartment.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">Before looking at the inventive subject matter in more detail, an overview of foot anatomy will help illustrate the invention and facilitate a better understanding of it. The forefoot is composed of five toes and their connecting long bones, the metatarsals. Each toe, or phalanx, is made up of small bones, the phalanges. The big toe, or hallux has two phalanges, two joints, the interphalangeal joints; and two tiny, round sesamoid bones that enable it to move up and down. The other four toes each have three bones and two joints. The second row of phalanges is connected to the metatarsal heads by five metatarsal phalangeal joints at the ball of the foot, i.e., where the foot is normally at its widest.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">The midfoot has five irregularly shaped tarsal bones, which form the foot's arch. The rearfoot is composed of three joints and links the midfoot to the ankle (talus). The top of the talus is connected to the two long bones of the lower leg (tibia and fibula), forming a hinge that allows the foot to move up and down. The heel bone (calcaneus) is the largest bone in the foot. It joins the talus to form the subtalar joint, which enables the foot to rotate at the ankle.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">Now looking at the general construction of the inventive subject matter, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> illustrates one of many possible embodiments of the inventive subject matter. In general, a foot covering, or shoe sock includes a compartment for receiving a foot. Hereinafter, the terms &#x201c;sock shoe&#x201d; and &#x201c;foot covering&#x201d; may be used interchangeably. References to &#x201c;intended user&#x201d; or &#x201c;user&#x201d; mean the individual a shoe is designed for. For instance, the intended user of a size 8 shoe would be a typical person with a size 8 foot.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">Sock shoe <b>1</b> is shown with a foot-receiving compartment <b>3</b> having a top or upper portion <b>5</b>, for securing the foot, and a ground-facing surface, bottom or sole portion <b>7</b>. The upper portion includes a heel-covering portion <b>6</b> for covering the backside of the heel.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">The compartment <b>3</b> is formed of a thin and supple textile material, such as a knit or woven fabric that is adapted to cover a foot. The compartment advantageously may be made using a single ply of material. The compartment has foot-conforming, sock-like nature that closely follows the contours of the foot of the intended user. For example, the compartment may be formed of a lightweight, stretchable mesh material, such as a blend of polyester and elastane. The fabric may be a 4-way or 2-way stretch fabric. In some embodiments, the base fabric yarns may include the following mixture of materials in their respective percentages: 25-35% elastane with the balance being polyester, nylon, rayon, cotton, or like materials. An alternative elastic yarn is based on Sorona &#x2122; fiber from DuPont. Other fibers that may be suitable for use in the yarns or filaments of the base fabric include the following: polyester fibers, acrylic fibers, modacrylic fiber, nylon fibers, vinylon fibers, polypropyrene fibers, polyurethane fibers, polyvinyl, chloride fibers, polyethylene fibers, vinylidene fiber, polychlal fibers, benzoate fibers, and aramid fibers. natural and bio-based fibers may also be suitable.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">The fibers may be combined to form multifilament yarns and fabrics of different yarn blends.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">In the illustrated embodiments, the foot compartment is full length, extending from the toes to the heel of the foot. Although not shown, in some embodiments, the shoe sock could leave the midfoot to rearfoot and or just the rearfoot visibly exposed and free of any surrounding foot compartment structure.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">Turning now to the exemplary embodiments of the Figures, the sock shoe includes a topline portion <b>9</b> that defines the opening to the volumetric area of the compartment <b>3</b>. Compartment <b>3</b> includes a toe section <b>11</b>, a heel section <b>13</b>, and a mid-section <b>15</b>. The ground-facing surface <b>7</b> has one or more thin and flexible pads or outsole portions designed to better protect the foot and provide traction. These outsole portions are incorporated into the sole of the sock shoe as a split sole structure, namely the forefoot portion <b>17</b> is separated from the heel portion <b>19</b>. Such a separation allows the midfoot area of the shoe to be free or substantially free of outsole material and unconstrained by the less-forgiving nature of the materials used to form the outsole portions. Accordingly, mid-section <b>15</b> of the foot is not protected by either the forefoot or heel outsole portion but is part of the flexible material of the compartment <b>3</b> that extends between the forefoot and heel outsole portions. As illustrated in Figures, a heel outsole portion <b>19</b>, <b>119</b>, <b>219</b>, <b>319</b> usually underlies the talus of the foot at the heel section <b>13</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b> and <b>3</b></figref> show other embodiments of a shoe <b>101</b>, <b>201</b>, with parts being generally analogous or similar to parts of the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> but with some specific differences described below.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">The foot compartment <b>3</b> of any embodiment may be formed of a single material or a combination of materials in different zones formed into a single layer. Generally, thin plies of material are used to construct the foot compartment, such as synthetic textiles that are knitted, woven, non-woven textiles, natural and synthetic leathers, which are all well known to persons skilled in the art. As used herein &#x201c;textiles&#x201d; and &#x201c;fabrics&#x201d; are interchangeable terms and refer to any supple fiber-based material known and used in the footwear and apparel industries, including without limitation knit and woven fabrics made from interlaced yarns or filaments, and non-woven textiles like felted, matted, carded, spunbound/spunlace, air-laid, dry-laid, wet-laid, fiber-jetted, and electrospun textiles.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">In the embodiments shown in the Figures, foot compartment <b>3</b> includes a thin, compliant upper portion <b>5</b>. For example, upper may be made of a single layer of a base fabric with knit mesh material that resiliently stretches. As described in more detail below, in manufacturing, the base fabric is processed to have elastomeric patterns or zones that provide the functions and aesthetics described below.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>A-<b>4</b>B</figref> show flat patterns that may be cut from a sheet material, e.g., a knit or woven textile. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>A-<b>4</b>B</figref> correspond to sock shoe <b>1</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>A</figref> shows top potion <b>5</b>, except for the covering of the back of the heel <b>6</b>, which is included with the bottom portion <b>7</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>B</figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>5</b>A-B</figref> show the top and bottom patterns for the sock shoe <b>101</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>. The top portion <b>105</b> is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b>A</figref> and the bottom portion <b>1077</b> and covering <b>106</b> are shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b>B</figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b>A-<b>6</b>B</figref> show the top and bottom patterns for the sock shoe <b>201</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>. The top portion <b>205</b> is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref> (along with strap portion <b>208</b>) and the bottom portion <b>207</b> and heel covering <b>206</b> are shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>B</figref>. The upper and lower portions for each shoe<img id="CUSTOM-CHARACTER-00001" he="3.56mm" wi="0.68mm" file="US20230225456A1-20230720-P00001.TIF" alt="custom-character" img-content="character" img-format="tif"/> have edges that are stitched or otherwise joined together to form a complete footwear compartment, as persons skilled in the art can readily appreciated from the Figures.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">The foot compartment may be processed to have functional or aesthetic patterns or zones. For example, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>, and <b>4</b>A-<b>4</b>B</figref> show the sock shoe with a set of bands <b>21</b>, <b>23</b> of elastomeric material disposed on the foot compartment <b>3</b>. In general, the material is a thermoplastic that can fuse to the base fabric or any overlying coating. Example elastomeric materials are as described earlier. The material can be applied to any area of the forefoot, midfoot, and/or rearfoot where desired stretch or tension, grip, and/or aesthetics are needed. It can be applied not only transversely to the longitudinal axis of foot compartment but also in line with the longitudinal axis, which can help limit distal-proximal stretch of the shoe. An effect of disposing elastomeric or other thermoplastic material on the sock shoe may be to provide aesthetic patterns or designs, which may or may not also embody functional effects.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">The bands extend over the instep or midfoot area of the compartment. In the embodiment shown, there are six spaced-apart, generally parallel bands <b>21</b> that run transverse to the longitudinal axis of the sock shoe and collectively cover from about the proximal end of the forefoot area to the distal end of the rearfoot area. The bands extend over the top of the foot to at least where the upper portion merges into sole portion. The bands may even extend fully across the sole for a circumferential configuration. As seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, the bottom or sole portion <b>7</b> has a similar set of banding across its width, which may be a continuation of the upper portion's bands and/or discrete or standalone bands. In the midfoot potion of the bottom of the compartment, smaller bands <b>23</b>, which are not full width, are disposed between bands <b>21</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>5</b>B and <b>6</b>B</figref> shows another arrangement of elastomeric elements in the form of bands <b>123</b>, <b>223</b> in the midfoot section <b>15</b> of the bottom portions <b>107</b>, <b>207</b> of sock shoes <b>101</b>, <b>201</b>. The embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>3</b> and <b>6</b>A-<b>6</b>B</figref>, the upper portion of the foot compartment includes elastomeric elements <b>225</b> on the top portion between the toes and instep, and elastomeric elements <b>227</b> on the side portions, extending from the rear foot to about the end of the forefoot. In this example, the elements are curvilinear. These elements can provide grippiness between the top of the user's foot and another surface.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">The bands can serve one or more functions. A first function is as a retention system for helping to maintain the foot compartment on the foot. The elastomeric bands can stretch and apply tension to a user's foot. The bands may be made relatively less elastic or stiffer than the base textile material onto which they are applied. Other patterns or zones of material can be applied using relatively inelastic or partially elastic materials to selectively control stretchability or tension of a base textile.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">Another function that bands or other patterns of the elastomeric material can provide is to enhance grip of the foot compartment to a work surface, e.g., a yoga mat, ballet bar, etc. The gripping material in the upper portion may be the same or different from material used to form outsole portions.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">As noted above, some or all of mesh base fabric may have an overlying mesh pattern of elastomeric material thinly deposited over the base fabric, and heat fused to it, to create an overall mesh surface for the compartment. The bands or other functional or aesthetic patterns may be disposed over the coated base fabric or directly on uncoated base fabric. As seen best in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>-<b>2</b></figref>, the foot-facing surface of bottom portions <b>7</b>, <b>107</b> have an elastomeric coating in hexagonal, mesh pattern <b>24</b> that can mimic the pattern on the outer and/or inner surface of top portion <b>5</b>, <b>105</b>. In the example shown, the mesh pattern on the upper portion <b>5</b>, <b>105</b> has relatively smaller openings.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">Another function of elastomeric material may be to provide durability of protective zones. For example, the sock shoes shown in the <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>-<b>2</b></figref> include a toe-cap layer <b>25</b> of elastomeric or other thermoplastic material over the distal toe area of the upper portion of the foot compartment. The material may be provided on the outer surface of the base fabric material and/or the inner surface of the base fabric material to provide a region that is resistant to wear and provides protection to the tips of the toes. The covered area may extend over the tops of the distal phalanges of the toes, over the front of the distal phalanges and/or under the distal phalanges. In other embodiments, the coverage may extend fully or partially from the tips of the distal phalanges and partially or fully over the middle phalanges, as well. The toe cap may not only protect the user's toes from external surfaces or objects but may also serve as a reinforcement area to prevent a user's toenails or toes from tearing or rupturing the base fabric.</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">Another function of the elastomeric material is to make the opening of the foot compartment, i.e., the topline <b>9</b>, retentive on the foot. By disposing elastomeric material <b>27</b>, <b>127</b> on the top line of the base textile, the topline can be made resiliently stretchable and retentive to the foot. Accordingly, the need for a separate binding system like laces, a drawstring, or strap is eliminated. Similarly, if the sock shoe has toe compartments, the openings of the toe compartments can include a coating of elastomeric material circumferentially (fully or partially) around the openings for retention around the toes.</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0098"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>, <b>5</b>A</figref>, show another example of a pattern of elastomeric material on the bottom of the shoe but with the upper having no particular pattern.</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0099">The layer of elastomeric material may be applied by techniques described earlier as well as other techniques like heat jet-printing or melting of fusible fibers or yarns included in the base fabric or textile (See, e.g., U.S. Pat. No. 6,910,288, which is hereby incorporated by reference), spray coating, or any other suitable technique. Any such technique may result in the elastomeric material being a deposited coating on the surface of the base textile and/or infused into the structure of the textile. In any case, the heat fusing of the material results in a single-layer, unitary structure of base fabric and fused material. Different areas of the sock shoe may have elastomeric patterns or features with different properties based on, for example, use of different materials or the same material applied in different thicknesses, patterns or shapes.</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0100">The elastomeric patterns, shape or other elements may range in thickness above the surface of a base fabric. A suitable range that allows for the functions noted above is from 0.25 mm to 2 mm, or thereabout such range end points. Suitable durometers are from 50 C to 55 C.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0101">The outsole portions <b>17</b>, <b>19</b>, <b>117</b>, <b>119</b>, <b>217</b>, <b>219</b> may also be formed on the base fabric by applying and fusing elastomeric material. A suitable range that allows for outsole function for studio or gym activities is from 1 mm to 2.5 mm, or thereabout such range end points. Sock shoes for outdoor activities may have a range of from 2 mm to 5 mm. Suitable durometers are from 50 C to 65 C.</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0102"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> illustrates the skeletal structure of a right foot and the perimeter of illustrative outsole portions <b>317</b> and <b>319</b> in relation thereto. This example illustrates a split-sole sock shoe where the forefoot outsole portion <b>317</b> is shorter and wider than the outsole portion of the typical prior art, thus creating a flatter and broader platform on which to pivot. The shorter and wider profile also provides better protection over the areas where protection is most needed. The forefoot outsole portion <b>317</b> is disposed mainly in the forefoot section <b>11</b> of the foot. The shape of the forefoot outsole portion <b>317</b>, covers approximately the width of a foot from about at least the first four metatarsal heads to about the rears of those metatarsals and has a substantially kidney-like shape. The forefoot outsole portion underlies approximately the forefoot section of the foot, corresponding to the toe section and the ball section of the sock shoe. However, the kidney-like shaped outsole portion covers less of the metatarsals towards the mid-section of the sock shoe, compared with the outsoles of the typical prior art sock shoe. The length of forefoot outsole portion <b>317</b> runs along a longitudinal line L of the foot/sock shoe. The forefoot outsole portion may leave as much as possible of the midfoot uncovered with outsole material, while still covering at least four metatarsal heads when the person wearing the foot covering is in demi-position and provide traction when the person wearing the foot covering stands on a flat surface. The length of the forefoot outsole portion extends from just proximal (at about line F, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref>) the metatarsal heads to about the second proximal row of phalanges (at about line E, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref>). The forefoot outsole <b>317</b> is positioned relative to the foot so that the outsole protects the widest part of the foot, which is associated with the metatarsal heads on which weight-bearing moves occur.</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0103">Usually but optionally, the shoe sock may also have a second or heel outsole portion <b>319</b>, which is positioned, for example, at the heel section <b>13</b> of the ground-facing surface <b>7</b> of the compartment <b>3</b>. The forefoot and heel outsole portions are spaced from one another to accommodate changes to the foot as the foot moves through various positions. The exact distances between the outsoles of the forefoot and heel may vary depending upon the size and shape of the foot. Additionally, the exact geometric shape of the outsoles may also vary in response to several factors such as the size of the foot.</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0104">In particular, the length of outsole <b>317</b> is substantially situated in the area of the metatarsal-phalangeal joints, along a metatarsal line N and between two parallel lines E and F, which run perpendicular to the longitudinal line L. Line E is located at the distal end of the foot, approximately at the joining of the first and second rows of the phalanges; while line F is located towards the proximal end of the forefoot. The distal end of outsole portion <b>317</b> touches line E, approximately at the intersection of line E and longitudinal line L. The proximal side of outsole portion touches line F. Thus, the forefoot outsole portion <b>317</b> covers almost all of the metatarsal heads and the second proximal row of phalanges. As illustrated in <b>7</b>, outsole portion <b>317</b> covers at least four of the five metatarsal bones.</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0105">Similarly, the location of the heel outsole portion <b>319</b> at the heel section <b>13</b> is determined by lines G and H, running perpendicular to the longitudinal line L of the foot. Line G is located at the heel section towards the distal end of the foot, while line H is located at the heel section towards the proximal end of the foot. The distal tip of heel outsole portion <b>319</b> touches line G. The proximal end of the outsole portion touches line H. Overall, the heel outsole portion in this embodiment has a substantially kidney-like shaped area that underlies the talus of the foot.</p>
<p id="p-0107" num="0106">The sock shoe <b>1</b> may be held on a foot by an elastic topline <b>9</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>-<b>2</b></figref>. The topline <b>9</b> defines a foot opening in the compartment <b>3</b>. When placing the foot into sock shoe <b>1</b>, the topline <b>9</b> may be stretchable to enlarge the size of the foot opening. In the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, an elastic strap <b>208</b> that goes over an instep helps secure the sock shoe to a foot. In other embodiments, the sock shoe might have a drawstring or other binding around the topline <b>9</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0108" num="0107">Although not shown in the embodiments, the topline or other inner surface of a foot compartment <b>3</b> may include a strip or pattern of elastomeric material that is configured for direct contact with the skin or sock of the dancer's foot. Such elastomeric material may help keep the sock shoe in place even if it becomes moist, e.g., as the user sweats, or generally provide a grippy, anti-slip foot engagement.</p>
<p id="p-0109" num="0108">According to a possible embodiment of the inventive subject matter, the sock shoes are symmetrical and interchangeable for use on left or right foot.</p>
<p id="p-0110" num="0109">While the foot compartment contemplated herein are typically made using a single ply of a lightweight fabric for a sock-like fit and effect, and is free of boards or other stiffening materials, such as foam midsoles or shanks. However, multiple plies of a thin material may still give the same fit and effect.</p>
<p id="p-0111" num="0110">The outsole portions may be made of a thin, flexible material that is more rugged than the fabric for the foot compartment and would typically be formed of a durable material for ground contact, such as natural or synthetic rubber, KPU, TPU, and natural or synthetic leather. Such materials may include patterns, finishes or textures to enhance traction or to provide for low friction in the case of some shows where spinning or sliding might be desirable.</p>
<p id="p-0112" num="0111"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> shows a sock shoe <b>201</b> with toe openings <b>31</b> for some or all toes at a distal end. The sock shoe may have 1, 2, 3, 4 or 5 toe openings. The patterns of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b>A-<b>6</b>B</figref> show top and bottom toe opening portions <b>31</b>A, <b>31</b>B that join to form a complete opening <b>31</b>. The top portion <b>205</b> may optionally include small cutouts <b>33</b> that may be inserted with a more elastic material than the rest of the top portion. The cutouts shown are V-shaped with the top of the V at the distal end of the top portion. By inserting an elastic material in the cut-outs, the toe openings have an elastic webbing section to better the sock shoe to the foot of the intended user.</p>
<p id="p-0113" num="0112">The openings <b>31</b> may be formed directly in the distal end of the foot compartment so as to expose the full toe or they may be sleeves that extend from the compartment. The sleeves may have varying lengths to expose varying portions of a toe. The openings help allow a user's toes to directly contact the under surface to help find equal weight distribution throughout the foot and to flex, grip, pointe, and have a full range of toe movement. A toe sleeve for the big (first) toe may be longer than sleeves of the second to fifth toes (if any). In some embodiments, only the tip of the distal end of the big toe may be exposed. In some embodiments, toe sleeves may have some elasticity that allows comfortably receiving and conforming to the toes of a wearer. Toe sleeves may be formed of an elastic upper portion and an inelastic, wear-resistant outsole of a suede material that are connected together to complete a sleeve. In some embodiments, a separate piece of mesh material may be attached between the toe openings, for example by stitching an insert of mesh material in between the toes. Such inserts may be inserted as an additional strip of mesh material or a V-shaped material covering the sides of the toes and in between the toes. In some embodiments, a stretchable mesh may be stitched to the mesh upper and suede sole to form the wall of the sleeve in between toes.</p>
<p id="p-0114" num="0113">For example, during pilates exercises, a foot covering with one or more exposed toes, according to the inventive subject matter, allows curling of the toes and arches, and flexing of the toes, while also providing a secure feeling of the floor or work out apparatus.</p>
<p id="p-0115" num="0114">The sole of the foot covering optionally may further have a cushioning material underneath at least a portion of the sole. The cushioning material may be positioned between an outer layer and an inner layer of foot covering <b>2</b>. It may me a thin layer of polymeric foam, such as foamed EVA or PU.</p>
<p id="p-0116" num="0115">The foot compartment's upper and/or sole portion of the foot may include ventilation holes or breathing holes or perforations. For example, the top and bottom portions of the compartment may have a mesh structure with predetermined hole sizes to allow for breathability in areas not covered by solid outsole material. In some embodiments, ventilation holes may be provided to the layer of gripping material as well. Ventilation holes or perforations may be grouped in zones.</p>
<p id="p-0117" num="0116">The inventive subject matter disclosed herein also contemplates manufacturing of the protective footwear by assembling parts in the manners disclosed. The following is one possible set of steps:
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0001-0001" num="0000">
    <ul id="ul0002" list-style="none">
        <li id="ul0002-0001" num="0117">Aluminum plates are milled with patterns and shapes of the elastomeric materials that will be applied to a base fabric.</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0002" num="0118">KPU liquid is then squeegeed onto the surface of the plate, to fill the milled-out design, and vacuumed to remove air bubbles.</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0003" num="0119">The plates are sent through a heated conveyor and any excess KPU is then cleaned off of the plate</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0004" num="0120">Flattened fabric for the foot compartment is then placed between the heated plates and put into a heated hydraulic press for time sufficient to fuse the elastomeric material to the base fabric.</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0005" num="0121">The fabric part is now a unitary, single layer structure that is removed from the plates.</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0006" num="0122">The part is then assembled to one or more other fabric parts (which may or may not also have been coated with elastomeric material) to form a completed foot compartment.</li>
    </ul>
    </li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0118" num="0123">Looking at possible steps for assembling the parts, the inventive subject matter contemplates steps of forming a sole sock by forming a compartment for receiving a foot using a footwear last. The compartment is formed on the last by placing on the last a top portion and a bottom portion of the compartment with alignment of complementary edges and joining the edges of top and bottom portions together using stitching or other known means of joining fabrics.</p>
<p id="p-0119" num="0124">Persons skilled in the art will recognize that many modifications and variations are possible in the details, materials, and arrangements of the parts and actions which have been described and illustrated in order to explain the nature of the inventive subject matter, and that such modifications and variations do not depart from the spirit and scope of the teachings and claims contained therein.</p>
<p id="p-0120" num="0125">All patent and non-patent literature cited herein is hereby incorporated by references in its entirety for all purposes.</p>
<p id="p-0121" num="0126">As used herein, &#x201c;and/or&#x201d; means &#x201c;and&#x201d; or &#x201c;or&#x201d;, as well as &#x201c;and&#x201d; and &#x201c;or.&#x201d; Moreover, any and all patent and non-patent literature cited herein is hereby incorporated by references in its entirety for all purposes.</p>
<p id="p-0122" num="0127">The principles described above in connection with any particular example can be combined with the principles described in connection with any one or more of the other examples. Accordingly, this detailed description shall not be construed in a limiting sense, and following a review of this disclosure, those of ordinary skill in the art will appreciate the wide variety of systems that can be devised using the various concepts described herein. Moreover, those of ordinary skill in the art will appreciate that the exemplary embodiments disclosed herein can be adapted to various configurations without departing from the disclosed principles.</p>
<p id="p-0123" num="0128">The previous description of the disclosed embodiments is provided to enable any person skilled in the art to make or use the disclosed innovations. Various modifications to those embodiments will be readily apparent to those skilled in the art, and the generic principles defined herein may be applied to other embodiments without departing from the spirit or scope of this disclosure. Thus, the claimed inventions are not intended to be limited to the embodiments shown herein, but are to be accorded the full scope consistent with the language of the claims, wherein reference to an element in the singular, such as by use of the article &#x201c;a&#x201d; or &#x201c;an&#x201d; is not intended to mean &#x201c;one and only one&#x201d; unless specifically so stated, but rather &#x201c;one or more&#x201d;.</p>
<p id="p-0124" num="0129">Unless context indicates otherwise, all numerical range values provided are inclusive of not only the end points of ranges but any points in between, and any ranges in between the end points.</p>
<p id="p-0125" num="0130">All structural and functional equivalents to the elements of the various embodiments described throughout the disclosure that are known or later come to be known to those of ordinary skill in the art are intended to be encompassed by the features described and claimed herein. Moreover, nothing disclosed herein is intended to be dedicated to the public regardless of whether such disclosure is explicitly recited in the claims. No claim element is to be construed as &#x201c;a means plus function&#x201d; claim under U.S. patent law, unless the element is expressly recited using the phrase &#x201c;means for&#x201d; or &#x201c;step for&#x201d;.</p>
<p id="p-0126" num="0131">The inventor and applicant reserve all rights to the subject matter disclosed herein, including the right to claim all that comes within the scope and spirit of the following claims:</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A sock shoe, comprising:
<claim-text>a foot compartment formed of a single-layer, unitary structure of a base fabric and an elastomeric coating fused to the base fabric, the compartment having two tiers of mesh, the first tier is defined in the base fabric and the second tier is defined in the coating, the sock shoe being resiliently stretchable and conforming to the contours of the intended user's foot.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The sock shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the unitary structure represents at least 50% of the surface area of the foot compartment.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The sock shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the base fabric is a synthetic fabric comprising elastic yarns.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The sock shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref> wherein the base fabric is a knit structure.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The sock shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> further comprising one or more patterns or zones of elastomeric material heat fused to base fabric or unitary structure, the patterns or zones providing a foot retention function, the elastomeric material having relatively less elasticity than the base fabric and forming part of the unitary structure.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The sock shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the pattern is configured to create tension around the user's instep and/or at least one side of the foot.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The sock shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the foot compartment is configured to have a topline that fits under the ankle of the intended user.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The sock shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the foot compartment is tongueless.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The sock shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the foot compartment is laceless and free of any retention system other than what is inherent in the single-layer, unitary structure.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The sock shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> further comprising one or more outsole portions formed of elastomeric material fused to the base fabric and forming part of the unitary structure.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The sock shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein there is a forefoot outsole portion and a rearfoot outsole portion, and the midfoot is free or substantially free of an outsole portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The sock shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> further comprising an insole portion formed of elastomeric material fused to the base fabric and forming part of the unitary structure, the insole portion coating the base fabric in a pattern that provides grippiness and anti-foot slip</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. The sock shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein elastomeric coating on outer surface of the foot compartment enhances grippiness for interaction with other surfaces.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The sock shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the mesh openings of the second tier of the elastomeric coating have a larger area than the first-tier mesh openings in the base fabric.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. The sock shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the elastomeric coating is configured in a pattern that provides selective, anisotropic restriction stretchability of the upper in desired areas.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. The sock shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref> wherein the elastomeric coating comprises one or more bands extending over the top and sides shoe that are configured to resiliently stretch when receiving the user's foot and tension the upper on the user's foot.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. The sock shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the mesh openings in the elastomeric coating are from 1 mm to 1.5 mm diameter or width and the mesh opening in the base fabric are 0.5 mm to 0.75 mm diameter or width, when both meshes are under static (untensioned) conditions.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. The sock shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the mesh openings of the elastomeric coating have a geometric shape configured for an anisotropic stretch effect.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. The sock shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref> wherein the mesh opening in the elastomeric coating are larger than the mesh openings in the base fabric.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. The sock shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref> wherein the openings have a hexagonal shape.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text><b>21</b>. A sock shoe comprising:
<claim-text>a single layer of base fabric having a volumetric configuration for receiving at least a forefoot portion of a user's foot and configured with an upper portion for receiving a top portion of the user's foot and a bottom portion for receiving a bottom portion of the intended user's foot;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the base fabric comprising a woven or knit structure that is resiliently elastic;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an elastomeric coating material is fused to the base fabric in a single-layer unitary structure to provide at least two of: (i) a retention function, (ii) a durability/foot protection function, (iii) a grip or anti-slip function, and (iv) an outsole function; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the bottom portion having an outer-facing, ground-contacting surface and an inner-facing, foot-contacting surface, the ground-contacting surface including at least one outsole portion being formed of the fused elastomeric material, and the inner-facing, foot-contacting surface being formed of the fused elastomeric material.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text><b>22</b>. The sock shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00021">claim 21</claim-ref> wherein the sock shoe is substantially free of any outsole portion in a midfoot section of the sock shoe.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text><b>23</b>. The sock shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00022">claim 22</claim-ref> wherein the outsole portions are disposed in forefoot and rearfoot sections of the shoe.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024" num="00024">
<claim-text><b>24</b>. The sock shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00021">claim 21</claim-ref> wherein the upper portion of the sock shoe has on its outer surface a coating of the fused elastic material in a pattern configured to provide a foot-retention function.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025" num="00025">
<claim-text><b>25</b>. The sock shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00024">claim 24</claim-ref> wherein the elastomeric material is deposited in a pattern on the upper portion of the sock shoe that extends transverse to the longitudinal axis of the sock shoe thereby being tensionable around the foot of the intended user and retentive to the foot.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026" num="00026">
<claim-text><b>26</b>. The sock shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00025">claim 25</claim-ref> wherein the elastomeric material is applied to the outer surface of the sock shoe and thereby also provides a grippy areas for a user to engage other surfaces.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027" num="00027">
<claim-text><b>27</b>. The sock shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00021">claim 21</claim-ref> wherein the sock shoe has a topline comprising fused elastomeric material configured to provide a foot-retention function.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028" num="00028">
<claim-text><b>28</b>. The sock shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00027">claim 27</claim-ref> further comprising a toe cap formed of the fused elastomeric material to provide durability and toe protection.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029" num="00029">
<claim-text><b>29</b>. The sock shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the distal portion of the sock shoe includes one or more toe openings to expose some or all of an intended user's toes.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030" num="00030">
<claim-text><b>30</b>. The sock shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00029">claim 29</claim-ref> wherein the toe openings include an elastic web structure that tensions around the toe or toes of the intended user.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031" num="00031">
<claim-text><b>31</b>. The sock shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the sock shoe does not include a rearfoot section and/or a midfoot/rearfoot sections.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
