<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225477A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225477</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18125201</doc-number>
<date>20230323</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>45</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>8</main-group>
<subgroup>34</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>45</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>8</main-group>
<subgroup>34</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">HAIR TIE</invention-title>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17222643</doc-number>
<date>20210405</date>
</document-id>
<parent-status>ABANDONED</parent-status>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18125201</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation>
<continuation>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>15933273</doc-number>
<date>20180322</date>
</document-id>
<parent-status>ABANDONED</parent-status>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17222643</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>62475141</doc-number>
<date>20170322</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Steyaert</last-name>
<first-name>Ashley</first-name>
<address>
<city>Honolulu</city>
<state>HI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Steyaert</last-name>
<first-name>Ashley</first-name>
<address>
<city>Honolulu</city>
<state>HI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">This invention provides a hair tie comprising a first loop, a second loop, and an elongated elastic member connected at a first end to the first loop and connected at a second end to the second loop. Example embodiments of the invention can be wrapped a plurality of times around lock of hair to form a helix, wherein the length and/or diameter of the helix can optionally varied based on the thickness and/or length of the user's lock of hair.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="57.07mm" wi="158.75mm" file="US20230225477A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="202.10mm" wi="115.91mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225477A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="198.12mm" wi="134.28mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225477A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention relates to hair ties, for example, for tying a pony tail.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">People with long hair often gather and tie their hair, for example, into a pony tail. A popular method of hair control involves tying the hair back away from the field of vision. Tying hair back in an ornate and pleasing fashion currently requires considerable expenditure of time and effort. Various tools and methods have been invented to facilitate this task.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The art of hair tying and control is important not only from an aesthetic point of view but also from a practical standpoint. The control of long hair is essential to prevent tangling, pulling, and loss of vision. These issues can be especially problematic when a person is involved in sports, swimming, and other activities. The manner of hair control may also be attractive in appearance depending on the method of controlling the hair.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">While a single rubber band or scrunchie can be placed at the base of a lock of hair to gather the hair, this still leads to loose hair at the end of the lock that is not attached to the persons head. It has been known to the present inventor to use several rubber bands or scrunchies consecutively at different locations of a lock of hair to secure not only the base of the lock, but also the end of the lock and one or more intermediate locations on the lock of hair. The inventor has discovered that, while this method of tying hair is useful to secure the entire lock of hair, this method has resulted in damage to hair and loss of hair resulting from pulling out when removing the bands after having spent time exercising, especially exercising in water.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">U.S. Pat. No. 7,328,710 to Hall et al. describes a spiral or helical structure for retaining hair or hair-like strands. Hall et al. describes the use of a helix that has a rigid or semi-rigid interior covered or connected with a flexible material, and connected to an elastic loop. The device of Hall et al. is pre-formed in the shape of a helix and thus is not flaccid. Hall et al. does not teach or suggest forming the helix by wrapping a flaccid elastic band around a lock of hair, or a hair tie having an elastic loop connected to an elongated elastic member that can be wrapped multiple times around a lock of hair.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">U.S. Pat. No. 5,167,245 to Harriett describes a hair tying apparatus having strands, such as cloth strands, having an elastic loop at one end. However, Harriett does not teach or suggest a hair tie having an elastic loop connected to an elongated elastic member that can be wrapped multiple times around a lock of hair.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">What is needed in the art is a hair tie that can be quickly used to tie a lock of hair, creates an aesthetic and secure lock of hair when worn, and can quickly be removed from the lock of hair without damaging the hair. The present inventor provides such a hair tie.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The invention provides a hair tie comprising a first elastic loop, a second loop, and an elongated elastic member connected at a first end to the first elastic loop and connected at a second end to the second elastic loop.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Optionally, the first elastic loop and/or the second elastic loop are made from elastic banding.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Optionally, the elongated elastic member is made from elastic banding.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Optionally, one or more of the first elastic loop, the second elastic loop, and the elongated elastic member are made from elastic banding that is flaccid in its resting (i.e. non-stretched) state. Optionally, the elastic banding is made from rubber. Optionally, the elastic banding of the loops comprises a covering, for example a soft covering (e.g. woven or non-woven covering such as a woven or non-woven fabric sheath such as nylon).</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Optionally, the first elastic loop comprises a band thickness that is greater than the band thickness of the second elastic loop. Additionally or alternatively, the length of the first elastic loop is optionally greater than the length of the second elastic loop.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The invention also provides a method of tying hair comprising:
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0001-0001" num="0000">
    <ul id="ul0002" list-style="none">
        <li id="ul0002-0001" num="0014">a. providing a hair tie of the invention,</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0002" num="0015">b. inserting a plurality of strands of hair through the first elastic loop,</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0003" num="0016">c. wrapping the elongated elastic member around the plurality of strands of hair one or more times (e.g. to form a helix), and</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0004" num="0017">d. inserting a plurality of strands of hair through the second elastic loop</li>
    </ul>
    </li>
</ul>
</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> depicts a hair tie of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> depicts the same hair tie depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, showing how to measure the length of L<b>1</b> of an elastic loop <b>1</b>, the thickness T<b>1</b> of an elastic loop <b>1</b>, and the length L<b>2</b> an elongated elastic member <b>3</b>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<heading id="h-0006" level="2">Overview</heading>
<p id="p-0017" num="0020">The invention provides a hair tie comprising a first elastic loop, a second loop, and an elongated elastic member connected at a first end to the first elastic loop and connected at a second end to the second elastic loop.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0021">Optionally, one or more of (e.g. each of) the first elastic loop, the second elastic loop, and the elongated elastic member comprise rubber banding. Optionally, the rubber banding is flaccid in its resting (i.e. un-stretched state). Such a configuration can be provided by tailoring the type of the rubber and the thickness of the banding.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0022">Optionally, the first elastic loop, second elastic loop, and elongated elastic member can each be made of the same material (e.g. the same type of rubber).</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0023">Optionally, the first elastic loop, the second elastic loop, and the elongated elastic member are constructed from the same banding, for example, a band having a first loop formed at one end, and a second loop formed at a second end. Alternatively, two or more of the first elastic loop, the second elastic loop, and the elongated elastic member are constructed from different banding, e.g. tied or adhered to each other.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0024">Whether the first elastic loop, the second elastic loop, and the elongated elastic member are constructed from the same banding or different banding, the hair tie of the invention can optionally comprise bands that are connected together after independent manufacture of the components. For example, the first elastic loop can be manufactured independently of the elongated elastic member and then connected thereto and/or the second elastic loop can be manufactured independently of the elongated elastic member and then connected thereto. As an alternative to independent manufacture, the first elastic loop and the elongated elastic member can be made from the same band (e.g. having a first elastic loop tied or molded at one end of the elongated elastic member) and/or the second elastic loop and the elongated elastic member can be made from the same band (e.g. having a first elastic loop tied or molded at one end of the elongated elastic member.)</p>
<heading id="h-0007" level="2">Elongated Elastic Member</heading>
<p id="p-0022" num="0025">A hair tie of the invention comprises an elongated elastic member. The elongated elastic member optionally comprises an elastic band. As used herein the term elongated means that the member has a length that is longer than its width. Optionally, the elongated elastic member has a length that is greater than the length (i.e. perimeter) of the loops.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0026">Optionally, the elongated elastic member is flaccid it its resting state. Such a configuration can provide, for example, a hair tie that does not have a preformed helix, but that a user can wrap around a lock of hair, e.g. to form a helix. The flaccid elastic nature of the elongated elastic member allows the user to elongate the elongated elastic member to a desired length (e.g. to accommodate a desired length of hair lock) and form a wrap or helix having a desired diameter (e.g. to accommodate a desired diameter or girth of hair lock such as a pony tail). Thus, a hair tie of the invention having this configuration is much more versatile than the devices lacking a flaccid elongated elastic member as described by U.S. Pat. Nos. 7,328,710; 5,167,245 which utilize a rigid or semi rigid helixes or non-elastic cloth strands, respectively. Further, a hair tie of the invention having this configuration, without a preformed shape, is safer for use in active settings (e.g. sports) and, having an elastic nature, provides a more stable configuration than a flaccid non-elastic band. Further, an elongated elastic member having a flaccid nature, when wrapped around a lock of hair as helix, optionally creates a unique &#x201c;braided&#x201d; look, with portions of the hair lock slightly protruding from the helix (e.g. as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> of provisional application U.S. 62/475,141), which is not provided with pre-formed rigid or semi-rigid helix found in the prior art.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0027">The present inventor has discovered that an elongated elastic member having excessive stiffness (i.e. resistance to elongation under force) can cause a user's ponytail to deform (e.g. curve) when the hair tie is worn due to, for example, the pulling forces exerted on the loops from the intermediate elongated elastic member. For example, when one loop is placed near the skull of the user, with another loop placed at the other end of a ponytail and the elastic member wrapped around the portion of the ponytail between the two loops (and elongated by stretching), an elongated elastic member having excessive stiffness can exhibit a tendency to pull the two loops (and the respective portions of hair to which they are attached) together, causing a deformation (e.g. curving) of the ponytail. Some users may find such a deformation unsightly or annoying. However, the inventor has determined that some stiffness (i.e. the inherent resistance to elongation exhibited by an elongated member of the invention that is elastic) is required to provide a stable pony tail. Thus, a hair tie of the invention optionally comprises an elongated member that is elastic (exhibiting some stiffness) but having a reduced stiffness that allows stretching.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0028">An elastic elongated member having reduced stiffness is not limited to a single configuration. For example, optionally, the elongated elastic member has an stiffness such that a force of 1000 grams-force elongates the elongated elastic member by a factor of at least 2 (e.g. 1000 grams under the force of gravity elongates a 20 cm elongated elastic member to at least 40 cm). Said another way, the elongated elastic member has a stiffness such that the force required to elongate the elongated elastic member by a factor of 2 is less than or equal to 1000 grams-force. Optionally, the elongated elastic member has a stiffness such that the force required to elongate the elongated elastic member by a factor of 2 is less than or equal to 500 grams-force. Optionally, the elongated elastic member has a stiffness such that the force required to elongate the elongated elastic member by a factor of 2 is less than or equal to 300 grams-force. Optionally, the elongated elastic member has a stiffness such that the force required to elongate the elongated elastic member by a factor of 2 is less than or equal to 250 grams-force. In any of the above-embodiments, optionally, the elongated elastic member has a stiffness such that the force required to elongate the elongated elastic member by a factor of 2 is greater than or equal to 25 grams-force or greater than or equal to 50 grams-force.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0029">Optionally, the surface of the elastic elongated member comprises a non-slip or gripping (e.g. friction-imparting) surface, e.g. silicon, rubber, pliable plastic, or a tackified surface. Such a surface provides enhanced grip to a lock of hair around which an elastic elongated member is wrapped (e.g. helically) and provides a more stable configuration in which portions of the elastic elongated member are less prone to moving up and down the hair and/or in which the lock of hair is less prone to &#x201c;spilling&#x201d; out from between the helix. In this configuration, stability of the elastic elongated member can be imparted by the friction-imparting surface of the elongated member rather than an overly tightly wound helix (i.e. rather than an excessively stiff elastic member). Optionally, such a surface of an elongated elastic member is provided on a hair tie of the invention wherein the loops of the hair tie have a soft covering or woven or non-woven fabric covering (e.g. as conventional scrunches).</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0030">Optionally, the length of the elongated elastic member is 7 cm to 100 cm. Optionally, the length of the elongated elastic member is 7 cm to 100 cm. Optionally, the length of the elongated elastic member is 7 cm to 100 cm. Optionally, the length of the elongated elastic member is 7 cm to 100 cm. Optionally, the length of the elongated elastic member is 12 cm to 100 cm. Optionally, the length of the elongated elastic member is 25 cm to 75 cm. While an example elongated elastic member can be stretched to different amounts and still provide a stable configuration around a lock of hair, in general, longer or thicker hair can typically utilize a longer elongated member. Thus, while a given length of elongated member can be versatile with respect to the length of hair it can secure, some users may which to select an elongated member that is sized such that it is stretched a desired amount (e.g. not more than about 2 times its resting length) when worn to avoid bending of the hair.</p>
<heading id="h-0008" level="2">Loops</heading>
<p id="p-0028" num="0031">A hair tie of the invention comprises loops (or other hair fasteners such as clips or ties) positioned about the elongated elastic member, for example, at the ends of the elongated elastic member. The loops can be used, for example, for securing the elongated elastic member to a lock of hair. A hair tie of the invention can comprises a first elastic loop connected to a first end of the elongated elastic member and a second elastic loop connected to a second end of the elongated elastic member.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0032">Optionally, the first elastic loop and/or the second elastic loop are made from elastic banding.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0033">Optionally, the first elastic loop comprises a band thickness or stiffness that is greater than that of the second elastic loop. The present inventor has discovered that, many times, the base of a lock of hair (near the skull) requires greater squeezing from the loop to secure it in a stable fashion, relative to the end of a hair lock (e.g. the end of a pony tail). Without being bound by theory, the inventor believes this is due to a greater thickness of the hair lock at the base of the lock or a tighter pull of the hair lock at the base of the lock (noting that pony tails are often formed by gathering a lock of hair tightly at the skull). Accordingly, a configuration in which the first elastic loop is thicker or stiffer provides greater stability of securing the base of the hair lock, wherein the thinner or less stiff second elastic loop provides a securing mechanism that is easier for the user to secure to (e.g. stretch over) the hair and/or is less prone to needlessly damaging the hair.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0034">Optionally, the loops comprise a soft covering or woven or non-woven fabric covering (e.g. as conventional scrunches). Such loops are less prone to damaging hair when tightly looped there around. In such a configuration, the tightness of the loop (e.g. rather than a non-slip surface) provides a stable securing mechanism. Optionally, such a covering of the loops is provided on a hair tie of the invention, wherein the elongated elastic member comprises a gripping or non-slip surface.</p>
<heading id="h-0009" level="2">Elastic Materials</heading>
<p id="p-0032" num="0035">A hair tie of the invention comprises a first elastic loop, a second elastic, and an elongated elastic member, any of which can be made from an elastic material, for example, elastic banding.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0036">Elastic materials include, for example, rubber.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0037">Optionally, the rubber is natural rubber, for example, latex.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0038">Optionally, the rubber is synthetic rubber. Examples of useful synthetic rubber include tyrene sbutadiene (SBR), polyacrylics, and polyvinyl acetate (PVA), polyvinyl chloride (PVC), polychloroprene (e.g. neoprene), and polyurethane.</p>
<heading id="h-0010" level="1">EXAMPLES</heading>
<heading id="h-0011" level="1">Example 1 Hair Tie</heading>
<p id="p-0036" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> depicts a hair tie of the invention. The hair tie comprises a first elastic loop <b>1</b>, a second loop <b>2</b>, and an elongated elastic member <b>3</b> connected at a first end to the first elastic loop <b>1</b> and connected at a second end to the second elastic loop <b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0040">Each of the first elastic loop <b>1</b>, the second elastic loop <b>2</b>, and the elongated elastic member <b>3</b> are made from elastic banding. The elastic banding is selected such that it is flaccid in its resting or un-stretched state. Thus, while <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> depicts hair tie having its first elastic loop <b>1</b> and second elastic loop <b>2</b> forming perfect circles, such a depiction is merely representative of loops. In this example, components <b>1</b>-<b>3</b> are configured to be flaccid to such an extent that this orientation of perfect circles is unlikely to actually exist naturally without careful manipulation of the hair tie components to this circular shape.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0041">The elongated elastic member <b>3</b> was configured with a stiffness such that it could be stretched and wrapped around a lock of hair, connected at the base of the hair (at skull) and the end of a lock of hair, without causing bending. Specifically, the elongated elastic member stiffness that required about 190 grams force to stretch the elongated elastic member to twice its resting length. Specifically, the resting length of the elongated elastic member <b>3</b> was about 60 cm and was stretched to about 120 cm upon hanging 195 grams (under the force of gravity) from the end of the elongated elastic member <b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0042">The flaccid nature of components <b>1</b>-<b>3</b>, and even more particularly the elongated elastic member <b>3</b>, provides several surprisingly advantageous properties not present in prior art hair ties. Example of such properties are as follows:
<ul id="ul0003" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0003-0001" num="0000">
    <ul id="ul0004" list-style="none">
        <li id="ul0004-0001" num="0043">a. The hair tie optionally comprises only flaccid components, with no rigid or semi-rigid (e.g. metal, plastic, or hard rubber) pieces, making the invention safer for active use in active situations such as sports and underwater activities.</li>
        <li id="ul0004-0002" num="0044">b. The flaccid components <b>1</b>-<b>3</b> allow greater ease of use putting on and taking off the device.</li>
        <li id="ul0004-0003" num="0045">c. The flaccid components <b>1</b>-<b>3</b> reduce damage to hair upon removing the hair tie. The present inventor has discovered that flaccid components taught herein are less likely to pull on hair as they are removed.</li>
        <li id="ul0004-0004" num="0046">d. When used in the present invention, an elongated elastic member having a flaccid nature, when wrapped around a lock of hair as helix, optionally creates a unique &#x201c;braided&#x201d; look, with portions of the hair lock slightly protruding from the elastically squeezing helix, e.g. as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> of provisional application U.S. 62/475,141. This feature is not provided with pre-formed rigid or semi-rigid helix found in the prior art, or by non-elastic ropes or wires found in the prior art which are unable to maintain a stable orientation in active settings such as sports and underwater activities.</li>
        <li id="ul0004-0005" num="0047">e. A hair tie of the invention having this flaccid configuration is much more versatile with respect to the thickness and length of lock of hair it can tie. For example, both the diameter of the helix and the helix pitch (or height of one complete helix turn) can be configured at-will by the user. This feature is not provided with rigid or semi-rigid helix found in the prior art which have a pre-formed shape, or by non-elastic ropes or wires found in the prior art which are unable to maintain a stable orientation in active settings such as sports and underwater activities.</li>
        <li id="ul0004-0006" num="0048">f. When used in the present invention, an elongated elastic member having a flaccid nature, when wrapped and stretched around a lock of hair as helix, provides a stable configuration which can be wrapped around various thicknesses of hair lock. This feature is not provided with rigid or semi-rigid helix found in the prior art which have a pre-formed shape, or by non-elastic ropes or wires found in the prior art which are unable to maintain a stable orientation in active settings such as sports and underwater activities.</li>
        <li id="ul0004-0007" num="0049">g. A hair tie of the invention can optionally simulate more than two simultaneously worn scrunchies without causing the damage associated with such, as detailed in Example 3.</li>
    </ul>
    </li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0050">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, components <b>1</b>-<b>3</b> can have their dimensions tailored during manufacture, with loops having a desired length (e.g. length L<b>1</b> of first elastic loop <b>1</b>), and/or with the elongated elastic member <b>3</b> having a desired length (e.g. length L<b>2</b>), and/or with any of the banding having a desired thickness (e.g. thickness T<b>1</b> of first elastic loop <b>1</b>.<i>f </i></p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0051">A user can tie a lock of hair by:
<ul id="ul0005" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0005-0001" num="0000">
    <ul id="ul0006" list-style="none">
        <li id="ul0006-0001" num="0052">a. inserting a lock of hair (a plurality of strands of hair) through the first elastic loop <b>1</b>;</li>
        <li id="ul0006-0002" num="0053">b. wrapping the elongated elastic member <b>3</b> around the plurality of strands of hair one or more times (e.g. to form a helix), and</li>
        <li id="ul0006-0003" num="0054">c. inserting the lock of hair through the second elastic loop <b>2</b>.</li>
    </ul>
    </li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0055">Using this method, after tying the lock of hair, the base of the lock of hair (near the scalp of the user) can be surrounded by first elastic loop <b>1</b> while a lower portion of the lock of hair can be surround by second elastic loop <b>2</b>. The elongated elastic member <b>3</b> will then be wrapped around a section of the lock of hair intermediate of the base of the lock of hair and the lower portion of the lock of hair.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0056">The lock of hair, when tied, optionally has the appearance shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> of provisional application U.S. 62/475,141.</p>
<heading id="h-0012" level="1">Example 2 Water Testing</heading>
<p id="p-0044" num="0057">The inventor tested a hair tie of the invention in water, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> of provisional application US 62/47514.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0058">Prior to creating the present invention, the inventor would secure her pony tail by placing a first scrunchie at the base of her pony tail (at the skull) gather the hair, and then place several scrunchies consecutively at different locations of a lock of hair to secure not only the base of the lock, but also the end of the lock and one or more intermediate locations on the lock of hair. However, the inventor discovered that while this method of tying hair is useful to secure the entire lock of hair, this method has resulted in damage to hair and loss of hair resulting from pulling out when removing the bands after having spent time exercising, especially exercising in water.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0059">Without being bound by theory, the inventor believes that, while wearing elastic scrunchies, moisture (e.g. sweat) or water absorption by the hair causes swelling, expansion, water intercalation, and or movement of a pony tail's strands of hair. When drying up or exiting the water, the opposite can happen, causing irregular contraction and/or tangling of the hair. Then, when attempting to remove these scrunchies from the hair, each scrunchie would be stuck in, tangled, or otherwise prevented from easily being removed. The result of this phenomenon was damage to the hair when removing each scrunchie. This damage is compounded by the number of scrunchies worn consecutively down the length of a pony tail.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0060">Surprisingly, however, as seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> of provisional application US 62/47514, this example of a hair tie of the invention simulates six consecutive scrunchies worn simultaneously (noting the helix is wrapped four times plus the top and bottom loops). However, the hair tie only has two loops that need to be removed while the elongated elastic band can simply be surprisingly unwrapped without damaging the hair.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0061">The citations provided herein are hereby incorporated by reference for the cited subject matter.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A hair tie comprising a first elastic loop, a second elastic loop, and an elongated elastic member connected at a first end to the first elastic loop and connected at a second end to the second elastic loop, wherein
<claim-text>the elongated elastic member is made from elastic banding; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the elongated elastic member is flaccid in its resting state and has a stiffness such that a force required to elongate the elongated elastic member by a factor of two is less than or equal to 1000 grams-force.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The hair tie of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first elastic loop and/or the second elastic loop are made from elastic banding.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The hair tie of the <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein first elastic loop and/or the second elastic loop are made from elastic banding that is flaccid in its resting state.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The hair tie of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the elongated elastic member comprises a non-slip surface.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. A method comprising wearing the hair tie of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> on a lock of hair and engaging in an activity in which the hair tie-worn lock of hair is submerged in water.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
