<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225518A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225518</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17687745</doc-number>
<date>20220307</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>17</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>111200754</doc-number>
<date>20220119</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>19</main-group>
<subgroup>12</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>19</main-group>
<subgroup>12</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e61">FOLDABLE BED ASSEMBLY AND METHOD OF FOLDING THE DAME</invention-title>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>HUANG</last-name>
<first-name>CHIA-YEN</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taichung</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>HUANG</last-name>
<first-name>CHIA-YEN</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taichung</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A foldable bed assembly includes a bed frame unit having support frames and wing support members retractably located at lateral side of the support frames correspondingly. A bed board unit put on the bed frame unit for putting on a mattress. The bed board unit includes main boards and wing boards are foldably located at lateral side of the main boards correspondingly. When the bed frame unit and the bed board unit are expanded, the wing support members respectively support the underside of the wing boards. A method for folding the foldable bed assembly includes folding the wing boards to the main boards, retracting the wing support members into the support frames, and folding the support frames completely.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="102.11mm" wi="150.20mm" file="US20230225518A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="230.12mm" wi="155.02mm" file="US20230225518A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="226.65mm" wi="154.26mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225518A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="209.55mm" wi="147.07mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225518A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="205.91mm" wi="145.12mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225518A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="198.20mm" wi="135.89mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225518A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="182.03mm" wi="136.57mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225518A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="241.30mm" wi="152.23mm" file="US20230225518A1-20230720-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="190.92mm" wi="151.05mm" file="US20230225518A1-20230720-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="222.33mm" wi="159.26mm" file="US20230225518A1-20230720-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This non-provisional application claims priority under 35 U.S.C. 119(a) on Patent Application No. 111200754 filed in Taiwan on Jan. 19, 2022, the entire contents of which are hereby incorporated by reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">1. Fields of the invention</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates to a foldable bed assembly and, in particular, to a foldable bed assembly with bed frame unit and the bed board unit are pivotable to reduce the volume that the foldable bed assembly occupies so as to reduce the packaging space and transportation space required for shipment.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">2. Descriptions of Related Art</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">In order to solve the shortcomings of a larger storage space or freight space is required, and a higher freight cost to the conventional bed frame assembly which does not include a proper folding mechanism so that a foldable bed assembly becomes one of solutions adopted by the industry to solve the above-mentioned deficiencies. The conventional foldable bed frame is composed of two main support frames that are pivotally connected to each other, and can be folded relative to each other along the longitudinal direction of the folding bed frame. A mattress is put on the two main support frames to form a basic structure of a foldable bed. When storing or transporting it, the two main support frames are folded to saves storage or transportation space required.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Taiwanese Utility patent No. M621470 discloses a foldable bend frame assembly and includes a first frame unit, a second frame unit and two hinge units. The hinge units are used for pivoting the first frame unit and the second frame unit, and each hinge unit includes a hinge piece which has two spaced apart connecting walls, and a bottom wall is connected to one end of the connecting walls. The connecting wall has a first pivot portion pivotally connected to the corresponding first end portion, and a second pivot portion opposite to the first pivot portion and pivotably connected to the corresponding second end portion. The second frame unit is folded relative to the first frame unit between an unfolded position and a folded position. However, the patent does not have lateral folding function to the end wing support and the end wing bed board. Therefore, the bed frame and the bed board cannot be folded to each other, and the volume of the folded status of the bed frame assembly cannot be further reduced, which increases the transportation cost.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">US201800254 discloses a folding bed frame and includes two symmetrically arranged bed frame units which are pivotably connected to each other by hinges. The bed frame unit further includes a plurality of first support rods pivotably connected with the bed frame unit by hinges. The direction that the plurality of first support rods are folded is perpendicular to the direction that the bed frame unit is folded.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">US2020205576 discloses a folding bed frame and a bed board put on the bed frame. The bed frame includes a first frame unit and a second frame unit arranged side by side and pivotally connected to each other. The bed board includes a first board unit fixedly located on the first frame unit, and a second board unit fixedly located on the second bed frame unit. Each of the first panel unit and the second panel unit includes one or more panel elements. Each panel element includes a substrate, a sponge layer and a cover. The base plate is located on the first or second frame unit. The sponge layer is arranged on the base material, and the cover layer is arranged on the sponge layer.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">US2021337976 discloses a transportable and foldable bed frame, and includes a base including a first frame having a bottom and a top, a second frame has a bottom and a top, and a connector pivotally connecting the second frame to the first frame. The first frame and the second frame selectively pivot relative to each other about a pivot, such that the first frame and the second frame selectively pivot relative to each other between the expanded position and the unfolded position. The top of the first frame and the second frame are substantially coplanar and adapted to support the mattress and to close the folded position. The bottom is folded and the top of the second frame covers the top of the first frame.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">US2009249545 discloses a portable and foldable bed frame, and includes a triangular support plate installed at the joint between the rotating rod of the rotating support rod and the connecting rod, so as to enhance the supporting strength of the rotating support rod. The width of the fixed support rod is twice of the width of the bed frame. A contact unit is provided between the fixed plate and the fixed support rod, so as to obtain a stable engagement of the fixed support rod. A foldable spring is located between the lower cross bar of the rod and the outer frame of the bed frame, so that the bed can be conveniently folded.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Each of the U.S. Patented bed assemblies mentioned above is able to be folded along the longitudinal direction, however, none of the four bed assemblies provides wing part wing support members, and none of the four bed assemblies provides the features of foldable wing bed board transversely. In other words, the bed board and bed frame cannot be folded transversely to further reduce the storage space and transportation space, and that will increase the transportation cost.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The present invention intends to provide a foldable bed assembly to eliminate the shortcomings mentioned above.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The present invention relates to a foldable bed assembly that wherein the bed frame unit and the bed board unit are pivotable to reduce the volume that the foldable bed assembly occupies so as to reduce the packaging space and transportation space required for shipment. The foldable bed assembly comprises a bed frame unit having multiple support frames which are foldable with respect to each other along the longitudinal direction of the foldable bed assembly. Multiple wing support members are connected to the bed frame unit and located in a row along the longitudinal direction of the foldable bed assembly. The multiple wing support members are respectively located at least one lateral side of the support frames corresponding thereto. The multiple wing support members are retractably located along the transversal direction of the foldable bed assembly. The longitudinal direction of the foldable bed assembly is perpendicular to the transversal direction of the foldable bed assembly. A bed board unit is put on the bed frame unit and includes multiple main boards which are foldable with respect to each other along the longitudinal direction of the foldable bed assembly. The bed board unit includes multiple wing boards which are located in a row along the longitudinal direction of the foldable bed assembly. The multiple wing boards are respectively located at least one lateral side of the multiple main boards corresponding thereto. The wing boards are foldable with respect to the main boards along the transversal direction of the foldable bed assembly. When the bed frame unit and the bed board unit are expanded, the multiple support frames support undersides of the multiple main boards correspondingly, and the multiple wing support members support undersides of the multiple wing boards correspondingly.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The present invention will become more obvious from the following description when taken in connection with the accompanying drawings which show, for purposes of illustration only, a preferred embodiment in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is an exploded view of the foldable bed assembly of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a perspective view to show the bed frame unit of the present invention, wherein the wing support members are extended;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a perspective view to show that the bed frame unit and the bed board unit of the present invention are expanded;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> shows that one of the wing boards is folded toward the main board;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> shows that all of the wing boards are folded toward the main boards;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> shows that all of the wing boards on one end of the foldable bed assembly are folded toward the main boards;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> shows that the bed frame unit and the bed board unit both are folded;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> is a top view of the folded status shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref> shows that the wing support member is retracted into the transport tube;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref> shows that the wing support member extends out from the transport tube, and</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b></figref> shows that the hinge member is a strip connected between the main board and the wing board.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> to <b>8</b></figref>, the foldable bed assembly of the present invention comprises a bed frame unit <b>10</b> and a bed board unit <b>20</b>. The bed frame unit <b>10</b> includes multiple support frames <b>11</b>. The multiple support frames <b>11</b> are foldable with respect to each other along a longitudinal direction &#x201c;L&#x201d; of the foldable bed assembly. Multiple wing support members <b>12</b> are connected to the bed frame unit <b>10</b> and located in a row along the longitudinal direction &#x201c;L&#x201d; of the foldable bed assembly. The multiple wing support members <b>12</b> respectively located at least one lateral side of the support frames <b>11</b> corresponding thereto, and the multiple wing support members <b>12</b> are retractably located along a transversal direction &#x201c;T&#x201d; of the foldable bed assembly. The longitudinal direction &#x201c;L&#x201d; of the foldable bed assembly is perpendicular to the transversal direction &#x201c;T&#x201d; of the foldable bed assembly. In this embodiment, the wing support members <b>12</b> are located symmetrically in pairs and inserted to the two sides of the support frames <b>11</b>. The bed board unit <b>20</b> is put on the bed frame unit <b>10</b> and includes multiple main boards <b>21</b>. The multiple main boards are foldable with respect to each other along the longitudinal direction &#x201c;L&#x201d; of the foldable bed assembly. The bed board unit <b>20</b> includes multiple wing boards <b>22</b> which are located in a row along the longitudinal direction &#x201c;L&#x201d; of the foldable bed assembly. The multiple wing boards <b>22</b> are respectively located at least one lateral side of the multiple main boards <b>21</b> corresponding thereto. Wherein, the wing boards <b>22</b> are foldable with respect to the main boards correspondingly and along the transversal direction &#x201c;T&#x201d; of the foldable bed assembly. Wherein, when the bed frame unit <b>10</b> and the bed board unit <b>20</b> are expanded, the multiple support frames <b>11</b> support undersides of the multiple main boards <b>21</b> correspondingly, and the multiple wing support members <b>12</b> support undersides of the multiple wing boards <b>22</b> correspondingly. Gong further, when folding the foldable bed assembly, the wing support members <b>12</b> are retracted toward the support frames <b>11</b> to reduce the width of the bed frame unit <b>10</b>. The wing boards <b>22</b> are folded toward and overlapping on the top of the main boards <b>21</b> so as to reduce the width of the bed board unit <b>20</b>. The support frames <b>11</b> and the main boards <b>21</b> carrying with the wing boards <b>22</b> are folded along the longitudinal direction &#x201c;L&#x201d; of the foldable bed assembly as disclosed in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>7</b>, <b>8</b></figref>. When in use, the wing support members <b>12</b> are extended from the support frames <b>11</b> to increase the width of the bed frame unit <b>10</b>. The wing boards <b>22</b> are pivotably expanded relative to the main boards <b>21</b> until the wing boards <b>22</b> are positioned horizontally so as to increase the width of the bed board unit <b>20</b>. The support frames <b>11</b> support the main boards <b>21</b>, and the wing support members <b>12</b> support the wing boards <b>22</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>. One method for folding the foldable bed assembly of the present invention is: (a<b>1</b>) firstly the multiple wing boards <b>22</b> being folded toward tops of the multiple main boards <b>21</b> correspondingly; (a<b>2</b>) secondly the multiple wing support members <b>12</b> being retracted toward the multiple support frames <b>11</b> correspondingly, i.e. the wing support members <b>12</b> are retracted into the transverse tubes <b>130</b> correspondingly; and (a<b>3</b>) finally the support frames <b>11</b> together with the main boards <b>21</b> and the wing boards <b>22</b> being folded along the longitudinal direction &#x201c;L&#x201d; of the foldable bed assembly, so that the multiple wing boards <b>22</b> are located between the multiple main boards <b>21</b>, and the multiple wing boards <b>22</b> and the multiple main boards <b>21</b> are located between the multiple support frames <b>11</b>. Another method for folding the foldable bed assembly is: (b<b>1</b>) firstly the multiple wing boards <b>22</b> being folded toward tops of the multiple main boards <b>21</b> correspondingly; (b<b>2</b>) secondly the support frames <b>11</b> together with the main boards <b>21</b> and the wing boards <b>22</b> being folded along the longitudinal direction &#x201c;L&#x201d; of the foldable bed assembly, so that the multiple wing boards <b>22</b> are located between the multiple main boards <b>21</b>, and the multiple wing boards <b>22</b> and the multiple main boards <b>21</b> are located between the multiple support frames <b>11</b>; and (b<b>3</b>) finally the multiple wing support members <b>12</b> being retracted toward the multiple support frames <b>11</b> correspondingly, i.e. the wing support members <b>12</b> are retracted into the transverse tubes <b>130</b> correspondingly.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>, <b>2</b>, <b>9</b> and <b>10</b></figref>, in this embodiment, multiple transverse tubes <b>130</b> extend along the transversal direction &#x201c;T&#x201d; of the foldable bed assembly and are connected to the main support frames <b>11</b>, so that the wing support members <b>12</b> are retractably inserted into the transverse tubes <b>130</b> and retractably extend along the transversal direction &#x201c;T&#x201d; of the foldable bed assembly. When reducing the size of the foldable bed assembly, the wing support members <b>12</b> are retracted into the transverse tubes <b>130</b> to reduce the width of the bed frame unit <b>10</b> and the support frame <b>11</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref>, each wing support member <b>12</b> includes a cap <b>120</b> connected to the distal end thereof. The cap <b>120</b> is made by plastic or rubber to prevent the wing support members <b>12</b> from cutting users. The caps <b>120</b> also position the wing support members <b>12</b> when the caps <b>120</b> contact the transverse tubes <b>130</b>. The caps <b>120</b> also provide a convenient grab when the users pull out the wing support members <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>9</b> and <b>10</b></figref>, each of the transverse tubes <b>130</b> includes at least one engaging hole <b>132</b>, and each wing support member <b>12</b> includes a resilient member <b>121</b> and an engaging protrusion <b>122</b> connected to the resilient member <b>121</b>. The resilient member <b>121</b> is biased in the tubular wing support member <b>12</b> corresponding thereto, and the engaging protrusion <b>122</b> of resilient member <b>121</b> protrudes beyond the wing support member <b>12</b> corresponding thereto by the elastic force of the resilient member <b>121</b> and inserted into the at least one engaging hole <b>132</b> of the transverse tube <b>130</b> corresponding thereto. In one embodiment, each transverse tube <b>130</b> includes two engaging holes <b>132</b>, when the wing support member <b>12</b> is completely received in the transverse tube <b>130</b>, the engaging protrusion <b>122</b> is inserted through one of the two engaging holes <b>132</b>. When the wing support member <b>12</b> extends from the transverse tube <b>130</b> and reaches the position where the wing support member <b>12</b> is sufficiently support the wing board <b>22</b>, the engaging protrusion <b>122</b> is inserted through the other one of the two engaging holes <b>132</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>, <b>3</b></figref>, each of the wing boards <b>22</b> includes at least one hinge member <b>23</b> pivotably connected to at least one lateral side of the main board <b>21</b> corresponding thereto. In this embodiment, the hinge member <b>23</b> is a hinge. The wing boards <b>22</b> each are pivotable about the at least one hinge member <b>23</b> and toward the main board <b>21</b> corresponding thereto, such that each of the wing boards <b>22</b> is foldable with respect to the main board <b>21</b> corresponding thereto and along the transversal direction of the foldable bed assembly.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Preferably, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b></figref>, the hinge member <b>23</b>, in this embodiment, includes a strip <b>231</b> which is foldable and non-extendable. The strip <b>231</b> includes two half portions <b>230</b> which are formed with each other and respectively adhered to and riveted to the main board <b>21</b> and the wing board <b>22</b> corresponding thereto, such that the wing board <b>22</b> is pviotable about a separation line <b>233</b> between the two half portions <b>230</b> and toward the main board <b>21</b>. An indication line <b>232</b> is formed between the two half portions <b>230</b> and identically located along the separation line <b>233</b>, and is used to be in alignment with two respective facing sides between the main board <b>21</b> and the wing board <b>22</b>. The strip <b>231</b> replaces the hinge to prevent from being hooked to the mattress.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> and <b>3</b>-<b>6</b></figref>, there are four main boards <b>21</b> which are located along the longitudinal direction &#x201c;L&#x201d; of the foldable bed assembly in sequence. The first and the fourth main boards <b>21</b> have the same area, and the second and the third main boards <b>21</b> have the same area. The area of the first and the fourth main boards <b>21</b> is larger than that of the second and the third main boards <b>21</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> and <b>3</b></figref>, the multiple wing support members <b>12</b> are respectively and symmetrically located on two opposed lateral sides of the multiple support frames <b>11</b> in pairs. The multiple wing boards <b>22</b> are respectively and symmetrically located on two opposed lateral sides of the multiple main boards <b>21</b> in pairs.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>, <b>3</b> to <b>6</b></figref>, the widths &#x201c;W<b>2</b>&#x201d; in the transversal direction &#x201c;T&#x201d; of the foldable bed assembly of the two wing boards <b>22</b> on the two opposed lateral sides of each main board <b>21</b> are identical. The areas &#x201c;A<b>2</b>&#x201d; of the two wing boards <b>22</b> on the two sides of each main board <b>21</b> are identical. The ratio between the width &#x201c;W<b>2</b>&#x201d; in the transversal direction &#x201c;T&#x201d; of the foldable bed assembly of each of the two wing boards <b>22</b> and the width &#x201c;W<b>1</b>&#x201d; in the transversal direction &#x201c;T&#x201d; of the foldable bed assembly of each main board <b>21</b> is between &#x2159; to &#xbd;. The ratio can be adjusted according practical use, such as single beds and double beds. The ratio between the area &#x201c;A<b>2</b>&#x201d; of each of the two wing boards <b>22</b> and the area &#x201c;A<b>1</b>&#x201d; of each main board <b>21</b> is between &#x2159; to &#xbd;.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> to <b>6</b></figref>, each support frame <b>11</b> supports two main boards <b>21</b> which are folded along the longitudinal direction &#x201c;L&#x201d;, and each support frame <b>11</b> includes multiple legs <b>14</b> removably connected to the underside thereof. A top of each support frame <b>11</b> is pivotably connected at least one angle adjustment frame <b>13</b>. In one embodiment, there are two support frames <b>11</b> each have two angle adjustment frames <b>13</b>. Each angle adjustment frame <b>13</b> is fixed one of the multiple main boards <b>21</b>. Each support frame <b>11</b> has a large angle adjustment frame <b>13</b> and a small angle adjustment frame <b>13</b> on the top thereof. The large angle adjustment frame <b>13</b> is connected to the main board <b>21</b> having large area, and the small angle adjustment frame <b>13</b> is connected to the main board <b>21</b> having small area. A driving unit <b>15</b> is pivotably connected between the support frame <b>11</b> and the angle adjustment frame <b>13</b> correspondingly. The driving unit <b>15</b> drives the angle adjustment frame <b>13</b> to rotate with respect to the multiple support frame <b>11</b> along an axial line parallel to the transversal direction of the foldable bed assembly, i.e. each main board <b>21</b> has a driving unit <b>15</b> connected thereto, and the driving unit <b>15</b> drives the angle adjustment frame <b>13</b> to pivot the wing support member <b>11</b> along the longitudinal direction &#x201c;L&#x201d; of the foldable bed assembly so as to make inclination adjustment of the main board <b>21</b>. In this embodiment, the wing support members <b>12</b> connected to the support frame <b>11</b> with the angle adjustment frame <b>13</b> are located symmetrically in pairs on the two opposed lateral sides of the angle adjustment frame <b>13</b>. In other words, the transverse tube <b>130</b> is located on the angle adjustment frame <b>13</b> so that the wing support member <b>12</b> is transversely inserted into the transverse tube <b>130</b> on the angle adjustment frame <b>13</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> and <b>3</b></figref>, when the bed board unit <b>20</b> is expanded relative to the bed frame unit <b>10</b>, the multiple wing support members <b>12</b> respectively support the underside of the multiple wing boards <b>22</b> so that the wing support members <b>12</b> support the pressure applied to the bed frame unit <b>10</b>. When the bed board unit <b>20</b> is folded relative to the bed frame unit <b>10</b>, the legs <b>14</b> are removed, and the wing boards <b>22</b> are folded toward the main boards <b>21</b>. Each wing support member <b>12</b> is retracted into the transverse tube <b>130</b> corresponding thereto to reduce the width of the bed frame unit <b>10</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b> to <b>6</b></figref>, by the pivotal member between the two support frames <b>11</b> and a proper force, the two support frames <b>11</b> and the four main boards <b>21</b> are folded relative to each other to fold the foldable bed assembly in the longitudinal direction &#x201c;L&#x201d; so as to form the folded status as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>7</b> and <b>8</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>7</b> and <b>8</b></figref>, each support frame <b>11</b> is put on with two main boards <b>21</b>, the multiple wing support members <b>12</b> are located two opposed lateral sides of the multiple support frames <b>11</b> corresponding thereto, and two opposed lateral sides of each main board <b>21</b> are foldably connected with two wing boards <b>22</b>. When the foldable bed assembly is in the folded status, the top of each main board <b>21</b> is overlapped with two wing boards <b>22</b>, the surrounding (outer) contour lines of the two wing boards <b>22</b> projected on a first plane are inside the surrounding (outer) contour lines of the corresponding main board <b>21</b> projected on the first plane. The surrounding (outer) contour lines of every two main boards <b>21</b> put on the same one support frame <b>11</b> projected on a second plane are overlapped and form in a rectangle R<b>1</b>, and the ratio between the length L<b>1</b> of the long side and the length L<b>2</b> of the short side of the rectangle R<b>1</b> is between 1&#x2dc;1.1, i.e. L<b>1</b>/L<b>2</b> is between 1&#x2dc;1.1, preferably L<b>1</b>/L<b>2</b> is between 1&#x2dc;1.05.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> and <b>2</b></figref>, the angle adjustment frame <b>13</b> includes the multiple transverse tubes <b>130</b> in the transversal direction &#x201c;T&#x201d; and multiple longitude tubes <b>131</b> in the longitudinal direction &#x201c;L&#x201d;. The two adjacent transverse tubes <b>130</b> with a small distance formed therebetween each have a pivotal end formed to each of two ends thereof. Each longitude tube <b>131</b> is connected between the two adjacent transverse tubes <b>130</b> with a large distance formed therebetween.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">While we have shown and described the embodiment in accordance with the present invention, it should be clear to those skilled in the art that further embodiments may be made without departing from the scope of the present invention.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A foldable bed assembly comprising:
<claim-text>a bed frame unit having multiple support frames; the multiple support frames being foldable with respect to each other along a longitudinal direction of the foldable bed assembly; multiple wing support members connected to the bed frame unit and located in a row along the longitudinal direction of the foldable bed assembly; wherein, the multiple wing support members being located at least one lateral side of the multiple support frames corresponding thereto, and the multiple wing support members retractably located along a transversal direction of the foldable bed assembly, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a bed board unit put on the bed frame unit and including multiple main boards; the multiple main boards being foldable with respect to each other along a longitudinal direction of the foldable bed assembly; the bed board unit including multiple wing boards which are located in a row along the longitudinal direction of the foldable bed assembly; the multiple wing boards respectively located at least one lateral side of the multiple main boards corresponding thereto; wherein the wing boards being foldable with respect to the main boards correspondingly and along a transversal direction of the foldable bed assembly; wherein when the bed frame unit and the bed board unit are expanded, the multiple support frames support undersides of the multiple main boards correspondingly, and the multiple wing support members support undersides of the multiple wing boards correspondingly.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The foldable bed assembly as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein multiple transverse tubes extend along the transversal direction of the foldable bed assembly and are connected to the multiple support frames correspondingly; the multiple wing support members are retractably inserted into the transverse tubes correspondingly and retractably extend along the transversal direction of the foldable bed assembly.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The foldable bed assembly as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein each of the transverse tubes includes at least one engaging hole, each of the multiple wing support members includes a resilient member and an engaging protrusion connected to the resilient member; the resilient member is biased in each of the multiple wing support members corresponding thereto, the engaging protrusion of the resilient member protrudes beyond each of the multiple wing support members corresponding thereto by an elastic force of the resilient member and inserted into the at least one engaging hole of the transverse tube corresponding thereto.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The foldable bed assembly as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein each of the multiple wing boards includes at least one hinge member pivotably connected to the at least one lateral side of each of the multiple main boards corresponding thereto, such that each of the multiple wing boards is pivotable about the at least one hinge member and toward each of the multiple main boards corresponding thereto, and such that each of the multiple wing boards is foldable with respect to each of the multiple main boards corresponding thereto and along the transversal direction of the foldable bed assembly.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The foldable bed assembly as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one hinge member includes at least one strip which includes two half portions which are formed with each other and respectively adhered to and riveted to each of the multiple main boards and each of the multiple wing boards corresponding thereto, such that each of the multiple wing boards is pviotable about a separation line between the two half portions and toward each of the multiple main boards corresponding thereto.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The foldable bed assembly as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein an indication line is formed between the two half portions and identically located along the separation line, and located in alignment with two respective facing sides between each of the multiple main boards and each of the multiple wing boards corresponding thereto.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The foldable bed assembly as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the multiple wing support members are located two opposed lateral sides of the multiple support frames corresponding thereto; two of the multiple wing boards are respectively and pivotably connected to two opposed lateral sides of each of the multiple main boards, and are foldable with respect to each of the multiple main boards along the transversal direction of the foldable bed assembly.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The foldable bed assembly as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the two wing support members on the two opposed lateral sides of each of the multiple support frames are located symmetrically to each other; the two wing boards on the two sides of each of the multiple main boards are located symmetrically to each other; widths in the transversal direction of the foldable bed assembly of the two wing boards on the two opposed lateral sides of each of the multiple main board are identical.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The foldable bed assembly as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein a ratio between the width in the transversal direction of the foldable bed assembly of each of the two wing boards and a width in the transversal direction of the foldable bed assembly of each of the multiple main boards is between &#x2159; to &#xbd;.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The foldable bed assembly as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the underside of each of the multiple wing boards is supported by at least two of the multiple wing support members.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The foldable bed assembly as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein a top of each of the multiple support frames is pivotably connected at least one angle adjustment frame; the angle adjustment frame is mounted with one of the multiple main boards; a driving unit is pivotably connected between one of the multiple support frames and the angle adjustment frame correspondingly; the driving unit drives the angle adjustment frame to rotate with respect to the corresponding support frame along an axial line parallel to the transversal direction of the foldable bed assembly.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The foldable bed assembly as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein multiple transverse tubes extend along the transversal direction of the foldable bed assembly and are connected to the at least one angle adjustment frame correspondingly; the multiple wing support members are retractably inserted into the transverse tubes correspondingly and retractably extend along the transversal direction of the foldable bed assembly.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. The foldable bed assembly as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the underside of each of the multiple wing boards is supported by at least two of the multiple wing support members.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The foldable bed assembly as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein when the foldable bed assembly is to be folded completely, the multiple wing boards are firstly folded toward tops of the multiple main boards correspondingly, the multiple wing support members are secondly retracted toward the multiple support frames correspondingly, and the multiple support frames together with the multiple main boards and the multiple wing boards are finally folded along the longitudinal direction of the foldable bed assembly, so that the multiple wing boards are located between the multiple main boards, and the multiple wing boards and the multiple main boards are located between the multiple support frames.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. The foldable bed assembly as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein each support frame is put on with two main boards, and two opposed lateral sides of each main board are respectively and foldably connected with one wing board; wherein when the foldable bed assembly is in a completely folded status, one top of each main board is overlapped with two wing boards, surrounding contour lines of the two wing boards projected on a first plane are inside surrounding contour lines of the corresponding main board projected on the first plane; surrounding contour lines of the two main boards put on the same one support frame projected on a second plane are formed in a rectangle and correspondingly overlapped on four sides of the rectangle, and a ratio between lengths of a long side and a short side of the rectangle is between 1&#x2dc;1.1.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. The foldable bed assembly as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the ratio between the lengths of the long side and the short side of the rectangle is between 1&#x2dc;1.05.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. A folding method for a foldable bed assembly, the foldable bed assembly comprising a bed frame unit and a bed board unit; the bed frame unit having multiple support frames; the multiple support frames being foldable with respect to each other along a longitudinal direction of the foldable bed assembly; multiple wing support members connected to the bed frame unit and located in a row along the longitudinal direction of the foldable bed assembly; wherein, the multiple wing support members being located at least one lateral side of the multiple support frames corresponding thereto, and the multiple wing support members retractably located along a transversal direction of the foldable bed assembly; the bed board unit put on the bed frame unit and including multiple main boards; the multiple main boards being foldable with respect to each other along a longitudinal direction of the foldable bed assembly; the bed board unit including multiple wing boards which are located in a row along the longitudinal direction of the foldable bed assembly; the multiple wing boards respectively located at least one lateral side of the multiple main boards corresponding thereto; wherein the multiple wing boards being foldable with respect to the multiple main boards correspondingly and along a transversal direction of the foldable bed assembly; wherein when the bed frame unit and the bed board unit are expanded, the multiple support frames support undersides of the multiple main boards correspondingly, and the multiple wing support members support undersides of the multiple wing boards correspondingly;
<claim-text>wherein, the method comprising the steps of:</claim-text>
<claim-text>firstly the multiple wing boards being folded toward tops of the multiple main boards correspondingly;</claim-text>
<claim-text>secondly the multiple wing support members being retracted toward the multiple support frames correspondingly, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>finally the support frames together with the main boards and the wing boards being folded along the longitudinal direction of the foldable bed assembly, so that the multiple wing boards are located between the multiple main boards, and the multiple wing boards and the multiple main boards are located between the multiple support frames.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein, wherein, each support frame is put on with two main boards, the multiple wing support members are located two opposed lateral sides of the multiple support frames corresponding thereto, and two opposed lateral sides of each main board are respectively and foldably connected with one wing board; wherein when the foldable bed assembly is in a completely folded status, one top of each main board is overlapped with two wing boards correspondingly, surrounding contour lines of the two wing boards projected on a first plane are inside surrounding contour lines of the corresponding main board projected on the first plane; surrounding contour lines of every two main boards put on the same one support frame projected on a second plane are formed in a rectangle and correspondingly overlapped on four sides of the rectangle, and a ratio between lengths of a long side and a short side of the rectangle is between 1&#x2dc;1.1.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. A folding method for a foldable bed assembly, the foldable bed assembly comprising a bed frame unit and a bed board unit; the bed frame unit having multiple support frames; the multiple support frames being foldable with respect to each other along a longitudinal direction of the foldable bed assembly; multiple wing support members connected to the bed frame unit and located in a row along the longitudinal direction of the foldable bed assembly; wherein, the multiple wing support members being located at least one lateral side of the multiple support frames corresponding thereto, and the multiple wing support members retractably located along a transversal direction of the foldable bed assembly; the bed board unit put on the bed frame unit and including multiple main boards; the multiple main boards being foldable with respect to each other along a longitudinal direction of the foldable bed assembly; the bed board unit including multiple wing boards which are located in a row along the longitudinal direction of the foldable bed assembly; the multiple wing boards respectively located at least one lateral side of the multiple main boards corresponding thereto; wherein the multiple wing boards being foldable with respect to the multiple main boards correspondingly and along a transversal direction of the foldable bed assembly; wherein when the bed frame unit and the bed board unit are expanded, the multiple support frames support undersides of the multiple main boards correspondingly, and the multiple wing support members support undersides of the multiple wing boards correspondingly;
<claim-text>wherein, the method comprising the steps of:</claim-text>
<claim-text>firstly the multiple wing boards being folded toward tops of the multiple main boards correspondingly;</claim-text>
<claim-text>secondly the support frames together with the main boards and the wing boards being folded along the longitudinal direction of the foldable bed assembly, so that the multiple wing boards are located between the multiple main boards, and the multiple wing boards and the multiple main boards are located between the multiple support frames, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>finally the multiple wing support members being retracted toward the multiple support frames correspondingly.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein, each support frame is put on with two main boards, the multiple wing support members are located two opposed lateral sides of the multiple support frames corresponding thereto, and two opposed lateral sides of each main board are respectively and foldably connected with one wing board; wherein when the foldable bed assembly is in a completely folded status, one top of each main board is overlapped with two wing boards correspondingly, surrounding contour lines of the two wing boards projected on a first plane are inside surrounding contour lines of the corresponding main board projected on the first plane; surrounding contour lines of every two main boards put on the same one support frame projected on a second plane are formed in a rectangle and correspondingly overlapped on four sides of the rectangle, and a ratio between lengths of a long side and a short side of the rectangle is between 1&#x2dc;1.05.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
