<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225507A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230710" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225507</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17577363</doc-number>
<date>20220117</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>17</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>88</main-group>
<subgroup>477</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>88</main-group>
<subgroup>49</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20170101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>88</main-group>
<subgroup>477</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20170101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>88</main-group>
<subgroup>49</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="uibiedcoqrcrb">EXTENSION LIMITER, REINFORCED STOPPER AND SPACER FOR DRAWER GLIDES</invention-title>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>DICKSON FURNITURE INTERNATIONAL, LLC dba AVALON FURNITURE</orgname>
<address>
<city>HOUSTON</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>SMITH</last-name>
<first-name>BRYAN L.</first-name>
<address>
<city>KERNERSVILLE</city>
<state>NC</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The extension limiter for drawer glides prevents a mobile track of a drawer glide from being fully extended with respect to the middle track of the drawer glide until a user takes a specific action to release the mobile track. The extension limiter for drawer glides is a safety measure to prevent accidental tipping of filing cabinets and the like. Additionally, a fixed track for a drawer glide is provided with a reinforced stopper positioned adjacent a rear end of the fixed track to prevent a rear end of the middle track from moving rearward beyond the rear end of the fixed track. A drawer glide is further provided with at least one spacer including a head portion and a peg. The peg extends outwardly from the head portion and removably snaps into a screw hole of the drawer glide so that the head portion is flush with the glide.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="107.70mm" wi="243.67mm" file="US20230225507A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="210.14mm" wi="153.67mm" file="US20230225507A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="229.53mm" wi="142.16mm" file="US20230225507A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="224.45mm" wi="150.37mm" file="US20230225507A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="202.61mm" wi="155.79mm" file="US20230225507A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="182.88mm" wi="113.79mm" file="US20230225507A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="151.55mm" wi="132.59mm" file="US20230225507A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="203.54mm" wi="158.16mm" file="US20230225507A1-20230720-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="137.92mm" wi="118.87mm" file="US20230225507A1-20230720-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="166.79mm" wi="133.69mm" file="US20230225507A1-20230720-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="156.38mm" wi="93.81mm" file="US20230225507A1-20230720-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading level="1" id="h-0001">BACKGROUND</heading>
<heading level="1" id="h-0002">1. Field</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The disclosure of the present patent application relates to glides for drawers, and particularly to an extension limiter, reinforced stopper and spacer for drawer glides that provide an extension limiter for drawer glides, as well as a reinforced stopper for drawer glides, and also a spacer for drawer glides.</p>
<heading level="1" id="h-0003">2. Description of the Related Art</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Drawer glides (also sometimes referred to as &#x201c;drawer slides&#x201d;) are telescoping supports for mounting a drawer to an inner wall of a filing cabinet, desk or the like. A typical drawer has one drawer glide on either side. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> illustrates a conventional prior art drawer glide <b>100</b>. Drawer glide <b>100</b> includes a mobile track <b>102</b> (drawer part), a middle track <b>104</b>, and a fixed track <b>106</b> (cabinet part). When installed, the fixed track <b>106</b> is attached or affixed to the inner wall of a filing cabinet or the like, and the mobile track <b>102</b> is attached or affixed to one side of the drawer. The middle track <b>104</b> is slidably mounted on the fixed track <b>106</b> using an axially sliding part <b>108</b>, which typically contains ball bearings held within a bearing retainer. Similarly, the mobile track <b>102</b> and the middle track <b>104</b> are slidably connected by a similar axially sliding part <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The mobile track <b>102</b> has a retainer <b>112</b> that engages a block <b>114</b> of the middle track <b>104</b>, stopping movement of the mobile track <b>102</b> at a fixed place to prevent the mobile track <b>102</b> (and the drawer) from becoming disengaged from the fixed track <b>106</b> (and the filing cabinet). The retainer <b>112</b> has a protuberance <b>126</b>, and the block <b>114</b> has a block plate <b>128</b> that engages the protuberance <b>126</b> when the mobile track <b>102</b> moves forward to its point of maximum extension. This engagement prevents the mobile track <b>102</b> from detaching from the middle track <b>104</b> and, by extension, from the fixed track <b>106</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The retainer <b>112</b> prevents the mobile track <b>102</b> from becoming fully disengaged and is positioned such that the mobile track <b>102</b> may reach its point of maximum extension, resulting in the drawer being fully open. In filing cabinets, for example, when an upper drawer is fully open, there is a risk of accidental tipping of the filing cabinet. Since the drawer carries weight, the extension of the drawer out of the cabinet is an increase in lever arm of this weight, which is unsupported by a base, resulting in an ever-increasing torque as the drawer slides out. At maximum extension, the weight of the drawer may be such that there is insufficient counter-torque, resulting in accidental tipping of the cabinet. Present safety standards require the addition of ballast to the base of the cabinet in order to prevent such accidental tipping. However, the addition of this ballast is not only costly, but can cause damage to the cabinet during transportation, as well as structural damage to the cabinet during installation. Although the retainer <b>112</b> is designed to limit forward movement of the mobile track <b>102</b>, it only stops such movement once the drawer has reached a fully open position. Conventional drawer glides do not include any way to allow, for example, only partial opening of the drawer in order to prevent accidental tipping.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Additionally, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, a stopper <b>122</b> is formed at the rear end of the fixed track <b>106</b>. Typically, the stopper <b>122</b> is a rectangular piece made by cutting a U-shaped slit in the web <b>120</b> of the fixed track <b>106</b> and bending the rectangular piece up until the piece is perpendicular to the web <b>120</b>. A cushioned bumper <b>124</b>, typically made from rubber or the like, covers the stopper <b>122</b>. Additionally, the rear end of the mobile track <b>102</b> has a reduced opening <b>116</b>, and the front end of the mobile track <b>102</b> has a bending plate <b>118</b>. When the mobile track <b>102</b> is pushed inward, the bending plate <b>118</b> contacts and pushes the block <b>114</b> of the middle track <b>104</b> until the mobile track <b>102</b> aligns with the fixed track <b>106</b>, while the reduced opening <b>116</b> engages the stopper <b>122</b> and cushioned bumper <b>124</b> to stop the mobile track <b>102</b> from moving any further inward.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Since conventional stoppers <b>122</b> are typically in the form of a small piece of metal bent up from the web <b>120</b>, they often bend backwards due to the continual striking force from the rear of mobile track <b>102</b>. Although this defect in design is well recognized, solutions are often in the form of after-market modifications, such as the addition of a block of a wood glued behind the stopper <b>122</b>. Since such additional elements are added only after the assembly of the filing cabinet, it is extremely difficult to properly place any additional reinforcing element behind the stopper <b>122</b>. At present, there is no reinforcement added to stoppers prior to the full assembly of the drawer glide and its corresponding furniture.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Further, since drawer glides are often manufactured separately from the article of furniture, so that a particular drawer glide design can be used with a wide variety of furniture, there is often a slight mismatch in contours or dimensions between the two. This often results in gaps between the fixed track and the inner wall to which the fixed track is secured. It is common in such situations to use &#x201c;spacers&#x201d;, which are typically pieces of plastic that are attached to the furniture side walls via screws or nails. Since the spacers are added only after manufacture, when the presence of the gap is apparent, the addition of the spacers can be a difficult and time-consuming process. Commercially available spacers are also of various sizes to accommodate drawer boxes and drawer glides of various dimensions, requiring the furniture manufacturer or retailer to select the appropriate spacer for each drawer type. Thus, an extension limiter, a reinforced stopper, and a spacer for drawer glides solving the aforementioned problems are desired.</p>
<heading level="1" id="h-0004">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The extension limiter for drawer glides prevents a mobile track of a drawer glide from being fully extended with respect to the middle track of the drawer glide until a user takes a specific action to release the mobile track. The extension limiter for drawer glides is a safety measure to prevent accidental tipping of filing cabinets and the like. A drawer glide with the extension limiter includes a fixed track, a middle track slidably mounted to the fixed track, a mobile track slidably mounted to the middle track, and a user-actuated retainer mounted on the mobile track. The user-actuated retainer releasably engages an engaging member fixed to the middle track to releasably limit slidable movement of the mobile track with respect to the middle track.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">For example, the user-actuated retainer may be substantially U-shaped, having a first leg with opposed fixed and free ends and a second leg with opposed fixed and free ends. The user-actuated retainer in this example also includes an engaging portion adjacent the fixed end of the second leg. The engaging portion is adapted for releasably engaging the engaging member. Further, a central portion is located adjacent the respective fixed ends of the first and second legs. The central portion is pivotally secured to the web of the mobile track. In this example, the free end of the first leg is adapted for contacting an outer flange of the mobile track. The first leg provides resilient tension between the user-actuated retainer and the outer flange of the mobile track when the second leg of the user-actuated retainer is pivoted to disengage the engaging portion from the engaging member.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">As another example, the user-actuated retainer may include a housing and a lever, the lever having opposed first and second ends and a central portion. The central portion of the lever is pivotally attached within the housing, and the first and second ends each project out of the housing. In this example, the first end of the lever is adapted for releasably engaging the engaging member. In use, the user pivots the second end of the lever to releasably disengage the first end from the engaging member. The lever may be resiliently biased with respect to the housing.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In a further embodiment, a fixed track for a drawer glide is provided with a reinforced stopper. The reinforced stopper is positioned adjacent a rear end of the fixed track to prevent a rear end of the middle track from moving rearward beyond the rear end of the fixed track. Similar to a conventional fixed track of a drawer glide, the fixed track includes a web and a pair of opposed flanges. A stopper tab extends from the web perpendicular thereto. The stopper tab is positioned adjacent the rear end of the fixed track. At least one reinforcement rib is secured to the stopper tab and extends toward the rear end of the fixed track. A pair of the reinforcement ribs may be provided. The pair of reinforcement ribs may be respectively secured to opposed ends of the stopper tab.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In an additional embodiment, a drawer glide may be provided with one more spacers. Each spacer has a head portion and a peg. The peg is secured to the head portion and projects outwardly therefrom. The peg is adapted for removable attachment to a screw hole of the drawer glide. The head portion may have a planar configuration. The head portion may have, for example, a thickness of approximately 1.5 mm. In use, one or more spacers may engage the screw hole(s) of one side of the drawer glide, thus securing the drawer glide when there is a gap of approximately 1.5 mm (in this particular example). If a gap still exists, one or more spacers may also engage the screw hole(s) on the other side of the drawer glide, thus increasing coverage to approximately 3.0 mm. If a gap still exists for the drawer, then one or more spacers may also be used with the other drawer glide on the opposite side of the drawer, increasing coverage to approximately 4.5 mm (when applied to only one side of the other drawer glide), and up to 6.0 mm (when applied to both sides of the other drawer glide).</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">These and other features of the present subject matter will become readily apparent upon further review of the following specification and drawings.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading level="1" id="h-0005">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref> is a side view of an exemplary drawer glide with an extension limiter, shown in a retained configuration, the middle part partially broken away to show details thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>B</figref> is a plan view of the drawer glide of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref>, shown with the mobile or drawer attachment part in a fully extended configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a partially exploded, perspective view of a drawer glide of the prior art.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a perspective attachment view of a fixed track of the prior art drawer glide of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>A</figref> is a side view of an alternative embodiment of a drawer glide with an extension limiter.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>B</figref> is a side view of a user-actuated retainer of the drawer glide of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>A</figref>, shown with the housing partially broken away to show details thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b>A</figref> is a perspective view of a fixed track (or cabinet attachment part) of an exemplary drawer glide with a reinforced stopper.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b>B</figref> is a partial side view of the fixed track of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b>A</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref> is a perspective view of an exemplary drawer glide and spacer kit.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>B</figref> is a top view of a spacer of the drawer glide and spacer kit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>C</figref> is a side view of the spacer of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>B</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Similar reference characters denote corresponding features consistently throughout the attached drawings.</p>
<heading level="1" id="h-0006">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A and <b>1</b>B</figref>, an extension limiter for drawer glides prevents a mobile track <b>12</b> (the part of the glide usually attached to the side of a drawer box) of a drawer glide from being fully extended with respect to the middle track <b>14</b> of the drawer glide until a user takes a specific action to release the mobile track <b>12</b>. The extension limiter for drawer glides is a safety measure to prevent accidental tipping of filing cabinets and the like. As shown, the drawer glide with the extension limiter (designated generally as <b>10</b> in the drawings) includes a fixed track <b>16</b> (usually attached to the furniture case or cabinet), a middle track <b>14</b> slidably mounted to the fixed track <b>12</b>, and a mobile track <b>12</b> slidably mounted to the middle track <b>14</b>, similar to a conventional drawer glide. However, a user-actuated retainer <b>18</b> is mounted on the mobile track <b>12</b>. The user-actuated retainer <b>18</b> releasably engages an engaging member <b>20</b> fixed to the middle track <b>14</b> to releasably limit slidable movement of the mobile track <b>12</b> with respect to the middle track <b>14</b>. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref>, the engaging member <b>20</b> is shown as relatively small rectangular block mounted adjacent the front end <b>50</b> of middle track <b>14</b>. However, it should be understood that the engaging member <b>20</b> is shown for exemplary purposes only, and may have any suitable shape, positioning, and relative size and dimensions.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">In the example of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A and <b>1</b>B</figref>, the user-actuated retainer <b>18</b> has a substantially U-shaped or V-shaped configuration, including a first leg <b>22</b> having opposed fixed and free ends <b>30</b>, <b>32</b>, respectively, and a second leg <b>24</b> having opposed fixed and free ends <b>34</b>, <b>36</b>, respectively. The user-actuated retainer <b>18</b> in this example also includes an engaging portion <b>26</b> adjacent the fixed end <b>34</b> of the second leg <b>24</b>. The engaging portion <b>26</b> is dimensioned and configured to releasably engage the engaging member <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Further, a central portion <b>28</b> is located adjacent the respective fixed ends <b>30</b>, <b>34</b> of the first and second legs <b>22</b>, <b>24</b>. The central portion <b>28</b> is pivotally attached to the web <b>40</b> of the mobile track <b>12</b>. In this example, the free end <b>32</b> of the first leg <b>22</b> is adapted for contacting an outer flange <b>38</b> of the mobile track <b>12</b>. The first leg <b>22</b> provides resilient or spring tension between the user-actuated retainer <b>18</b> and the outer flange <b>38</b> of the mobile track <b>12</b> when the second leg <b>24</b> of the user-actuated retainer <b>18</b> is pivoted to disengage the engaging portion <b>26</b> from the engaging member <b>20</b>. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref>, the mobile track <b>12</b> can only be partially extended because the engaging portion <b>26</b> of the user-actuated retainer <b>18</b> is engaging the engaging member <b>20</b>. When the user wishes to fully extend the mobile track <b>12</b>, the user pivots the second leg <b>24</b> upward (in the orientation of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A and <b>1</b>B</figref>) against the resilient bias, releasing the engaging portion <b>26</b> from the engaging member <b>20</b>. A handle or grasping member <b>42</b> may be mounted on the free end <b>36</b> of the second leg <b>24</b>, as shown. With the second leg <b>24</b> pivoted upward, the user may pull the drawer out, thus pulling mobile track <b>12</b> outward with respect to the middle track <b>14</b> and the fixed track <b>16</b>. When released, the second leg <b>24</b> returns to its original position due to the spring-biasing of the first leg <b>22</b> with respect to the outer flange <b>38</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Another example of an extension limiter is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>A and <b>4</b>B</figref>. In this embodiment, the drawer glide with an extension limiter, designated generally as <b>400</b> in the drawings, includes a fixed track <b>416</b>, a middle track <b>414</b> slidably mounted to the fixed track <b>416</b>, and a mobile track <b>412</b> slidably mounted to the middle track <b>414</b>, similar to a conventional drawer glide and the previous embodiment. In this embodiment, however, the user-actuated retainer <b>418</b> includes a housing <b>402</b> and a lever <b>404</b>, the lever <b>404</b> having opposed first and second ends <b>406</b>, <b>408</b>, respectively, and a central portion <b>410</b>. The central portion <b>410</b> of the lever <b>404</b> is pivotally attached to the housing <b>402</b>, and the first and second ends <b>406</b>, <b>408</b>, respectively, each extend out of the housing <b>402</b>. It should be understood that the configuration and relative dimensions of the housing <b>402</b> are shown for exemplary purposes only. It should be further understood that the housing <b>402</b> may be replaced by, for example, a plate.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">In this example, the first end <b>406</b> of the lever <b>404</b> is adapted for releasably engaging the engaging member <b>420</b>, which is attached to the middle track <b>414</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>A</figref>. In use, the user pivots the second end <b>408</b> of the lever <b>404</b> downward (in the orientation of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>A and <b>4</b>B</figref>) to releasably disengage the first end <b>406</b> from the engaging member <b>120</b>. The lever <b>404</b> may be resiliently biased with respect to the housing <b>402</b> by a spring <b>419</b> or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">In the further embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>5</b>A and <b>5</b>B</figref>, a fixed track for a drawer glide with a reinforced stopper <b>200</b> is shown. In this embodiment, a reinforced stopper is positioned adjacent the rear end <b>210</b> of a fixed track <b>216</b> to prevent the rear end of the middle track of the drawer glide from moving rearward beyond the rear end <b>210</b> of the fixed track <b>216</b> when the drawer is slid into a closed position inside the cabinet, table, or other article of furniture. Similar to a conventional fixed track of a drawer glide, the fixed track <b>216</b> includes a web <b>202</b> and a pair of opposed flanges <b>204</b>, <b>206</b> defining opposing channels. A stopper tab <b>208</b> is extends perpendicular to the web <b>202</b>. The stopper tab <b>208</b> is positioned adjacent the rear end <b>210</b> of the fixed track <b>216</b>. At least one reinforcement rib is secured to the stopper tab <b>208</b> and extends toward the rear end <b>210</b> of the fixed track <b>216</b>. In the non-limiting example of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b>A and <b>6</b>B</figref>, a pair of reinforcement ribs <b>212</b>, <b>214</b> are shown, the pair of reinforcement ribs <b>212</b>, <b>214</b> extending from opposed ends <b>218</b>, <b>220</b> of the stopper tab <b>208</b>. It will be understood, however, that the reinforcement ribs <b>212</b>, <b>214</b> need not extend from the ends <b>218</b>, <b>220</b> of the stopper tab <b>208</b>, but may be placed more medially to brace the rear face of the stopper tab <b>208</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b>A, <b>6</b>B and <b>6</b>C</figref> show a kit <b>300</b>, which includes a drawer glide <b>308</b> provided with one more spacers. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref>, three such spacers <b>302</b>, <b>304</b> and <b>306</b> are shown, although it should be understood that the kit <b>300</b> may include any desired number of spacers. It should further be understood that each spacer is substantially identical. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b>B and <b>6</b>C</figref> show one of the spacers <b>302</b>. Spacer <b>302</b> has a head portion <b>316</b> and a substantially cylindrical peg <b>318</b>. The peg <b>318</b> is secured to the head portion <b>316</b> and extends outwardly therefrom. The peg <b>318</b> is dimensioned and configured for snapping into a screw hole of the drawer glide <b>308</b>, such as the exemplary screw holes <b>310</b>, <b>312</b> and <b>314</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref>. The head portion <b>316</b> may have a planar configuration. It should be understood that the substantially square shape of the head portion <b>316</b> is shown for exemplary purposes only. The head portion <b>316</b> is preferably thin and may have, for example, a thickness of approximately 1.5 mm. In use, one or more spacers may engage the screw hole(s) of one side of the drawer glide <b>308</b>, thus securing the drawer glide <b>308</b> when there is a gap of approximately 1.5 mm, for example. If a gap still exists, one or more spacers may also engage the screw hole(s) of the other side of the drawer glide <b>308</b>, thus increasing coverage to approximately 3.0 mm. If a gap still exists for the drawer, then one or more spacers may also be used with the other drawer glide on the opposite side of the drawer, increasing coverage to approximately 4.5 mm (when applied to only one side of the other drawer glide), and up to 6.0 mm (when applied to both sides of the other drawer glide).</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">It is to be understood that the extension limiter, reinforced stopper and spacer for drawer glides are not limited to the specific embodiments described above, but encompasses any and all embodiments within the scope of the generic language of the following claims enabled by the embodiments described herein, or otherwise shown in the drawings or described above in terms sufficient to enable one of ordinary skill in the art to make and use the claimed subject matter.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A drawer glide with an extension limiter, comprising:
<claim-text>a fixed track;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a middle track slidably mounted to the fixed track;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mobile track slidably mounted to the middle track, the mobile track being adapted for attachment to a drawer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a user-actuated retainer mounted on the mobile track; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an engaging member fixed to the middle track, the user-actuated retainer releasably engaging the engaging member to releasably limit slidable movement of the mobile track with respect to the middle track to less than full extension in an outward direction until a user manually releases the user-actuated retainer to permit full extension of the mobile track and the drawer attached to the mobile track,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said slidable movement of the mobile track with respect to the middle track is limited to less than full extension in said outward direction at a position of at least one of a first outward screw hole, a second intermediate screw hole, and a third inner screw hole.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The drawer glide with an extension limiter as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the user-actuated retainer is substantially U-shaped and comprises:
<claim-text>a first leg having opposed fixed and free ends;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second leg having opposed fixed and free ends;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an engaging portion adjacent the fixed end of the second leg, the engaging portion being adapted for releasably engaging the engaging member; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a central portion adjacent the respective fixed ends of the first and second legs, wherein the central portion is pivotally attached to the mobile track.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The drawer glide with an extension limiter as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the free end of the first leg is adapted for contacting an outer flange of the mobile track, the first leg providing resilient tension between the user-actuated retainer and the outer flange of the mobile track when the second leg of the user-actuated retainer is pivoted to disengage the engaging portion from the engaging member.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The drawer glide with an extension limiter as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the user-actuated retainer comprises:
<claim-text>a housing; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a lever having opposed first and second ends and a central portion, the central portion of the lever being pivotally attached to the housing, and the first and second ends each extending out of the housing.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The drawer glide with an extension limiter as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the first end of the lever is adapted for releasably engaging the engaging member when the mobile track is initially pulled out of the middle track to prevent full extension of the mobile track and the attached drawer, the user manually pivoting the second end of the lever to releasably disengage the first end of the lever from the engaging member to permit full extension of the mobile track and the attached drawer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The drawer glide with an extension limiter as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the lever is resiliently biased with respect to the housing.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. A fixed track for a drawer glide with a reinforced stopper, comprising:
<claim-text>a fixed track for a drawer glide having a web defining lateral edges and a pair of opposed flanges extending from the edges of the web and defining opposed channels, the fixed track having a rear end ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a stopper tab extending perpendicular from the web, the stopper tab being positioned adjacent the rear end of the fixed track; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one reinforcement rib attached to the stopper tab and extending rearward toward the rear end of the fixed track in order to brace the stopper tab.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The fixed track for a drawer glide with a reinforced stopper as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one reinforcement rib comprises a pair of reinforcement ribs respectively attached to opposed ends of the stopper tab.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. A drawer glide and spacer kit, comprising:
<claim-text>a drawer glide having at least one screw hole defined therein; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one spacer having a head portion and a peg, the peg extending outwardly from the head portion, the peg being removably snapped into the at least one screw hole to mount the head portion flush with the drawer glide.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The drawer glide and spacer kit as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the head portion of the at least one spacer has a planar body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The drawer glide and spacer kit as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the head portion of the at least one spacer has a thickness of approximately 1.5 mm.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
