<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225567A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225567</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18127031</doc-number>
<date>20230328</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>202011590170.1</doc-number>
<date>20201229</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>12</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>05</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>30</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>12</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>B</section>
<class>05</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>30</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e61">WATER OUTLET MECHANISM FOR ADJUSTING MIXED RATIO OF FUNCTIONAL LIQUID AND WATER</invention-title>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>PCT/CN2021/142031</doc-number>
<date>20211228</date>
</document-id>
<parent-status>PENDING</parent-status>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18127031</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Xiamen Solex High-Tech Industries Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<address>
<city>Xiamen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>LAI</last-name>
<first-name>Honghui</first-name>
<address>
<city>Xiamen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="01" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>ZHANG</last-name>
<first-name>Lian</first-name>
<address>
<city>Xiamen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="02" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>LIU</last-name>
<first-name>Tingke</first-name>
<address>
<city>Xiamen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="03" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>ZHANG</last-name>
<first-name>Mingfu</first-name>
<address>
<city>Xiamen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A water outlet mechanism for adjusting a mixed ratio of a functional liquid comprises a water operated pump driven by water power, a functional liquid storage chamber, a water outlet channel, a water inlet channel, and a flow rate adjustment mechanism. A liquid inlet of the water operated pump is in communication with the functional liquid storage chamber, a liquid outlet of the water operated pump is in communication with the water outlet channel or the water inlet channel, and the flow rate adjustment mechanism is configured to adjust a water flow rate of the water in the water inlet channel for driving the water operated pump so as to change a suction frequency of the water operated pump.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="71.80mm" wi="118.19mm" file="US20230225567A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="145.37mm" wi="120.23mm" file="US20230225567A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="193.63mm" wi="114.64mm" file="US20230225567A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="192.70mm" wi="108.71mm" file="US20230225567A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="191.69mm" wi="104.82mm" file="US20230225567A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a continuation of and claims priority to International patent application number PCT/CN2021/142031, filed on Dec. 28, 2021, which claims priority to Chinese patent application number 202011590170.1, filed on Dec. 29, 2020. International patent application number PCT/CN2021/142031 and Chinese patent application number 202011590170.1 are incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="tail"?>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">FIELD OF THE DISCLOSURE</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates to a water outlet mechanism, and in particular to a water outlet mechanism configured to discharge a functional liquid.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE DISCLOSURE</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The existing beauty shower basically adopts a method of mixing beauty liquid with water, and a mixing degree of the beauty liquid and the water is adjusted by adjusting a flow rate of the water entering a beauty liquid storage cavity to adjust a concentration of the beauty liquid mixed with the water. Due to this design, the beauty liquid can only be used for a short time, and otherwise the water will easily breed bacteria after entering the beauty liquid storage cavity for a long time. As an amount of the water entering the beauty liquid storage cavity increases, the beauty liquid will be diluted in advance in the beauty liquid storage cavity. The effect will be poor, and the mixing concentration of the beauty liquid and the water cannot be accurately controlled.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE DISCLOSURE</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The present disclosure provides a water outlet mechanism to solve the deficiencies in the background, and a user can control a mixed ratio of a functional liquid and water according to their own needs.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In order to solve the technical problem, the present disclosure provides a water outlet mechanism for adjusting of the mixed ratio of the functional liquid and the water, and the water outlet mechanism comprises a water operated pump driven by a water power, a functional liquid storage chamber, a water outlet channel, a water inlet channel, and a flow rate adjustment mechanism. A liquid inlet of the water operated pump is in communication with the functional liquid storage chamber, and a liquid outlet of the water operated pump is in communication with the water outlet channel or the water inlet channel. The flow rate adjustment mechanism is configured to adjust a water flow rate of the water in the water inlet channel for driving the water operated pump so as to change a suction frequency of the water operated pump.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In a preferred embodiment, the flow rate adjustment mechanism comprises a first water passage hole, a second water passage hole, and an adjusting member for adjusting a water passing area of the second water passage hole.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In a preferred embodiment, the adjusting member moves along an axial direction of the second water passage hole so as to be inserted into or separated from the second water passage hole.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In a preferred embodiment, the flow rate adjustment mechanism comprises a water diversion body, an axis of the water diversion body comprises the second water passage hole, and the water diversion body further comprises a plurality of water diversion holes distributed in rotational symmetry around the second water passage hole to define the first water passage hole.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In a preferred embodiment, the adjusting mechanism is a tapered adjustment core, a side of the tapered adjustment core facing the second water passage hole comprises a tapered column, and the tapered column has a diameter that gradually increases from a first end of the tapered column adjacent to the second water passage hole to a second end of the tapered column.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In a preferred embodiment, the flow rate adjustment mechanism further comprises an operating member for driving the tapered adjustment core to move along the axial direction of the second water passage hole.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In a preferred embodiment, the operating member is disposed outside a water inlet core, and an inside of the water inlet core comprises the water inlet channel A side wall of the water inlet core comprises a position-providing groove extending along a moving direction of the tapered adjustment core, and the operating member is operatively coupled to the tapered adjustment core through the position-providing groove.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In a preferred embodiment, the functional liquid is essence, conditioner, shampoo, shower gel, detergent, or hand soap.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In a preferred embodiment, the water outlet mechanism is a bath shower or a kitchen shower.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In a preferred embodiment, the liquid inlet of the water operated pump is in communication with the functional liquid storage chamber through a liquid inlet pipe, and a diameter of the liquid inlet pipe is unchanged and always in communication with the functional liquid storage chamber and the liquid inlet when a water flow rate of the water passing through the water operated pump is adjusted.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Compared with the existing techniques, the technical solution has the following advantages.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The present disclosure provides the water outlet mechanism for adjusting the mixed ratio of the functional liquid and the water. The above-mentioned shower head is provided by combining beauty and skin care properties with the traditional shower, so that people can perform skin care when bathing, and at the same time a beauty liquid adjustment mechanism (i.e., the flow rate adjustment mechanism <b>5</b>) is provided and is configured to control the mixed ratio of a beauty liquid (i.e., the functional liquid) and the water through a mechanism that adjusts the suction frequency of the water operated pump, which solves a problem of inaccurate mixing concentration of the beauty liquid (i.e., the functional liquid) and the water and a problem of poor use effect of the beauty liquid when the beauty liquid a beauty liquid storage cavity in a chamber is diluted in advance.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The present disclosure controls the mixed ratio of the functional liquid and the water by the flow rate adjustment mechanism. The suction frequency of the water operated pump can be adjusted according to a concentration of the functional liquid, thereby controlling the mixed ratio of the functional liquid and the water.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> illustrates a perspective exploded view of a shower head in a preferred embodiment in the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> illustrates a side view of the shower head in a preferred embodiment in the present disclosure, when a water operated pump works at a minimum speed.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> illustrates a cross-sectional view of the shower head in a preferred embodiment in the present disclosure, when the water operated pump works at the minimum speed.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> illustrates a side view of the shower head in a preferred embodiment in the present disclosure, when the water operated pump works at a middle speed.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> illustrates a cross-sectional view of the shower head in a preferred embodiment in the present disclosure, when the water operated pump works at the middle speed.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> illustrates a side view of the shower head in a preferred embodiment in the present disclosure, when the water operated pump works at a maximum speed.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> illustrates a cross-sectional view of the shower head in a preferred embodiment in the present disclosure, when the water operated pump works at the maximum speed.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The following will clearly and completely describe the technical solutions in the embodiments of the present disclosure with reference to the accompanying drawings. Obviously, the described embodiments are only a portion of the embodiments of the present disclosure, and not all of the embodiments. Based on the embodiments of the present disclosure, all other embodiments obtained by those of ordinary skill in the art without creative work fall within the protection scope of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">In the description of the present disclosure, it should be noted that the terms &#x201c;upper&#x201d;, &#x201c;lower&#x201d;, &#x201c;inner&#x201d;, &#x201c;outer&#x201d;, &#x201c;top/bottom&#x201d;, etc. indicate the orientation or positional relationship based on the orientation shown in the drawings. The positional relationship is only for the convenience of describing the present disclosure and simplifying the description, rather than indicating or implying that the pointed device or element must have a specific orientation, be constructed, and be operated in a specific orientation. Therefore, the positional relationship should not be understood as a limitation of the present disclosure. In addition, the terms &#x201c;first&#x201d; and &#x201c;second&#x201d; are only used for descriptive purposes and should not be understood as indicating or implying relative importance.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">In the description of the present disclosure, it should be noted that the terms &#x201c;installed&#x201d;, &#x201c;provided with&#x201d;, &#x201c;sleeved/connected&#x201d;, &#x201c;connected&#x201d;, etc., should be understood broadly. For example, &#x201c;connected&#x201d; can be a fixed connection, a detachable connection, or an integral connection, a mechanical connection, an electrical connection, a direct connection, or an indirect connection through an intermediate medium, and it can be a connection between two members. For those of ordinary skill in the art, the specific meaning of the above terms in the present disclosure can be understood under specific conditions.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> to <b>7</b></figref>, a water outlet mechanism for adjusting a mixed ratio of a functional liquid and water is provided. In this embodiment, a shower head is provided as an example. Alternatively, this structure can also be applied to other types of the water outlet mechanisms, such as spray guns, kitchen showers, and the like. The shower head comprises a water operated pump <b>1</b> driven by water power, a functional liquid storage chamber <b>2</b>, a water outlet channel <b>3</b>, a water inlet channel <b>4</b>, and a flow rate adjustment mechanism <b>5</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">A liquid inlet <b>11</b> of the water operated pump <b>1</b> is in communication with the functional liquid storage chamber <b>2</b> through a liquid inlet pipe <b>21</b>, and a liquid outlet <b>12</b> of the water operated pump <b>1</b> is in communication with the water outlet channel <b>3</b>. The flow rate adjustment mechanism <b>5</b> is configured to adjust a water flow rate of the water in the water inlet channel <b>4</b> for driving the water operated pump <b>1</b> so as to change a suction frequency of the water operated pump <b>1</b>. Alternatively, the liquid outlet <b>12</b> can be connected to the water inlet channel <b>4</b>, which is a simple replacement in this embodiment and will not be repeated here.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The above-mentioned shower head is provided by combining beauty and skin care properties with the traditional shower, so that people can perform skin care when bathing, and at the same time a beauty liquid adjustment mechanism (i.e., the flow rate adjustment mechanism <b>5</b>) is provided and is configured to control the mixed ratio of a beauty liquid (i.e., the functional liquid) and the water through a mechanism that adjusts the suction frequency of the water operated pump <b>1</b>, which solves a problem of an inaccurate mixing concentration of the beauty liquid (i.e., the functional liquid) and the water and a problem of poor use effect of the beauty liquid when the beauty liquid in a beauty liquid storage cavity in a chamber is diluted in advance.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Structurally, the water operated pump <b>1</b> comprises a water driven part and a liquid sucking-and-discharging part. The water driven part comprises an impeller <b>14</b> that provides power for the water operated pump <b>1</b> and is impacted by the water flow to rotate and a liquid discharge port <b>13</b> for discharging the water flow impacting the impeller <b>14</b> into the water outlet channel <b>3</b>. The liquid sucking-and-discharging part comprises the liquid inlet <b>11</b> and the liquid outlet <b>12</b>, and the liquid sucking-and-discharging part is a diaphragm pump structure or a piston pump structure, which are known structures to those of ordinary skill in the art and will not be described herein in detail.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">In order to adjust the suction frequency of the water operated pump <b>1</b>, the flow rate adjustment mechanism <b>5</b> comprises a first water passage hole <b>51</b>, a second water passage hole <b>52</b>, and an adjusting member for adjusting a water passing area of the second water passage hole <b>52</b>. The first water passage hole <b>51</b> is a main water inlet hole for driving the impeller <b>14</b> of the water operated pump <b>1</b> to rotate, and the second water passage hole <b>52</b> is an auxiliary water inlet hole. By changing the water passing area of the second water passage hole <b>52</b>, more or less of the water can pass through the second water passage hole <b>52</b>, and then the water flowing through the first water passage hole <b>51</b> will naturally become less or more. Therefore, an amount of the water used to drive the impeller <b>14</b> of the water operated pump <b>1</b> to rotate decreases or increases, and the suction frequency of the water operated pump <b>1</b> decreases or increases.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Specifically, the adjusting member adjusts the water passing area of the second water passage hole <b>52</b> in the following manner. The adjusting member moves along an axial direction of the second water passage hole <b>52</b> so as to be inserted into or separated from the second water passage hole <b>52</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The flow rate adjustment mechanism <b>5</b> comprises a water diversion body <b>53</b>, and an axis of the water diversion body <b>53</b> comprises the second water passage hole <b>52</b>. The water diversion body <b>53</b> further comprises a plurality of water diversion holes distributed in rotational symmetry around the second water passage hole <b>52</b> to define the first water passage hole <b>51</b>. The first water passage hole <b>51</b> is inclined holes, and the second water passage hole <b>52</b> is straight holes.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The flow rate adjustment mechanism <b>5</b> further comprises a tapered adjustment core <b>54</b> as the adjusting member. A side of the tapered adjustment core <b>54</b> facing the second water passage hole <b>52</b> comprises a tapered column, and the tapered column has a diameter that gradually increases from a first end of the tapered column adjacent to the second water passage hole <b>52</b> to a second end of the tapered column.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The flow rate adjustment mechanism <b>5</b> further comprises an operating member <b>55</b> for driving the tapered adjustment core <b>54</b> to move along the axial direction of the second water passage hole <b>52</b>. The operating member <b>55</b> is disposed outside a water inlet core <b>6</b>, and an inside of the water inlet core <b>6</b> comprises the water inlet channel <b>4</b>. A side wall of the water inlet core <b>6</b> comprises a position-providing groove <b>61</b> extending along a moving direction of the tapered adjustment core <b>54</b>, and the operating member <b>55</b> is operatively coupled to the tapered adjustment core <b>54</b> through the position-providing groove <b>61</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">When in use, the tapered adjustment core <b>54</b> is driven to move by sliding of the operating member <b>55</b>. The tapered adjustment core <b>54</b> is a tapered shaft, and through the tapered shaft cooperating with the second water passage hole <b>52</b> of the water diversion body <b>53</b>, when the tapered adjustment core <b>54</b> slides, the water passing area of the second water passage hole <b>52</b> of the water diversion body <b>53</b> is changed. Under a condition that a water passing area of the first water passage hole <b>51</b> of the water diversion body <b>53</b> remains unchanged, the first water passage hole <b>51</b> of the water diversion body <b>53</b> achieves water diversion, so that a rotating speed of the water operated pump <b>1</b> is changed through changing an impacting speed of the water in the first water passage hole <b>51</b> of the water diversion body <b>53</b> acting on the impeller, thereby changing a speed at which the water operated pump <b>1</b> pumps the functional fluid, thereby changing the concentration of the functional fluid mixed with the water.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The mechanism can also realize a stepless adjustment of the mixed ratio of the functional liquid and the water, specifically.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">1) When the functional liquid needs to be pumped at a minimum speed, the operating member <b>55</b> needs to be pushed to a position away from the second water passage hole <b>52</b>. At this time, the tapered shaft of the tapered adjustment core <b>54</b> and the second passage of the water diversion body <b>53</b> are completely separated, and the tapered adjustment core <b>54</b> has no flow-limiting effect on the second water passage hole <b>52</b> of the water diversion body <b>53</b>. At this time, the second water passage holes <b>52</b> of the water diversion body <b>53</b> have a largest diversion to the first water passage holes <b>51</b>, the water flow rate of the water flow in the first water passage hole <b>51</b> impacting the impeller <b>14</b> is the smallest, and the water operated pump <b>1</b> pumps the functional liquid at the minimum speed.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">2) When the functional liquid needs to be pumped at a speed between a minimum speed and a maximum speed, the operating member <b>55</b> can be pushed to any position in a middle except for positions at two ends of the position-providing groove <b>61</b>. At this time, the tapered shaft of the tapered adjustment core <b>54</b> cooperates with the second water passage hole <b>52</b> of the water diversion body <b>53</b>. The tapered adjustment core <b>54</b> has a flow-limiting effect on the second water passage hole <b>52</b> of the water diversion body <b>53</b>. At this time, part of the water in the first water passage hole <b>51</b> of the water diversion body <b>53</b> is diverted to the second water passage hole <b>52</b> to reduce a water flow speed of the first water passage hole <b>51</b> and an impact force on the impeller <b>14</b>, thereby reducing the speed at which the water operated pump <b>1</b> pumps the functional liquid.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">3) When the functional liquid needs to be pumped at the maximum speed, the operating member <b>55</b> needs to be pushed to an end of the position-providing groove <b>61</b> adjacent to the second water passage hole <b>52</b>. At this time, the tapered shaft of the tapered adjustment core <b>54</b> and the second water passage hole <b>52</b> of the water diversion body <b>53</b> substantially abut each other, and the tapered adjustment core <b>54</b> completely obstructs the water flow into the second water passage hole <b>52</b> of the water diversion body <b>53</b>. At this time, the water flow in the first water passage hole <b>51</b> will not be diverted to the second water passage hole <b>52</b> of the water diversion body <b>53</b>. At this time, the water flow rate in the first water passage hole <b>51</b> and the impact force on the impeller <b>14</b> are the largest, and the water operated pump <b>1</b> pumps the functional liquid at the maximum speed.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">In this embodiment, the functional liquid is essence, conditioner, shampoo, or shower gel.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The first water passage hole <b>51</b> is in communication with the water outlet channel <b>3</b> after passing through the impeller <b>14</b>, and the second water passage hole <b>52</b> is also in communication with the water outlet channel <b>3</b>. An amount of the water passing through the flow rate adjustment mechanism <b>5</b> and converging on the water outlet channel <b>3</b> is the same as the amount of the water passing through the water inlet channel <b>4</b>. Therefore, the purpose of adjusting the mixed ratio of the functional solution and the water can be achieved by adjusting a liquid output of the functional solution through the flow rate adjustment mechanism <b>5</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">When the water outlet mechanism of the present disclosure is a spray gun or a kitchen shower, the functional liquid may be detergent or hand soap.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The present disclosure controls the mixed ratio of the functional liquid and the water by the flow rate adjustment mechanism <b>5</b>. The suction frequency of the water operated pump can be adjusted according to a concentration of the functional liquid, thereby controlling the mixed ratio of the functional liquid and the water. At the same time, a diameter of the liquid inlet pipe <b>21</b> connecting between the functional liquid storage chamber <b>2</b> and the liquid inlet <b>11</b> remains unchanged during an adjustment process. Therefore, the present disclosure has higher flexibility and accuracy for adjusting the mixed ratio of the functional liquid and the water. Especially in places where the viscosity of the beauty serum itself is high, the applicability is very good.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The aforementioned embodiments are merely some embodiments of the present disclosure, and the scope of the disclosure is not limited thereto. Thus, it is intended that the present disclosure cover any modifications and variations of the presently presented embodiments provided they are made without departing from the appended claims and the specification of the present disclosure.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A water outlet mechanism for adjusting a mixed ratio of a functional liquid and water, comprising:
<claim-text>a water operated pump driven by water power,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a functional liquid storage chamber,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a water outlet channel,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a water inlet channel, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a flow rate adjustment mechanism, wherein:
<claim-text>a liquid inlet of the water operated pump is in communication with the functional liquid storage chamber,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a liquid outlet of the water operated pump is in communication with the water outlet channel or the water inlet channel, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the flow rate adjustment mechanism is configured to adjust a water flow rate of the water in the water inlet channel for driving the water operated pump so as to change a suction frequency of the water operated pump.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The water outlet mechanism for adjusting the mixed ratio of the functional liquid and the water according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the flow rate adjustment mechanism comprises a first water passage hole, a second water passage hole, and an adjusting member for adjusting a water passing area of the second water passage hole.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The water outlet mechanism for adjusting the mixed ratio of the functional liquid and the water according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the adjusting member moves along an axial direction of the second water passage hole so as to be inserted into or separated from the second water passage hole.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The water outlet mechanism for adjusting the mixed ratio of the functional liquid and the water according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the flow rate adjustment mechanism comprises a water diversion body,</claim-text>
<claim-text>an axis of the water diversion body comprises the second water passage hole, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the water diversion body further comprises a plurality of water diversion holes distributed in rotational symmetry around the second water passage hole to define the first water passage hole.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The water outlet mechanism for adjusting the mixed ratio of the functional liquid and the water according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the adjusting member is a tapered adjustment core,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a side of the tapered adjustment core facing the second water passage hole comprises a tapered column, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the tapered column has a diameter that gradually increases from a first end of the tapered column adjacent to the second water passage hole to a second end of the tapered column.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The water outlet mechanism for adjusting the mixed ratio of the functional liquid and the water according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the flow rate adjustment mechanism further comprises an operating member for driving the tapered adjustment core to move along the axial direction of the second water passage hole.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The water outlet mechanism for adjusting the mixed ratio of the functional liquid and the water according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the operating member is disposed outside a water inlet core,</claim-text>
<claim-text>an inside of the water inlet core comprises the water inlet channel,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a side wall of the water inlet core comprises a position-providing groove extending along a moving direction of the tapered adjustment core, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the operating member is operatively coupled to the tapered adjustment core through the position-providing groove.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The water outlet mechanism for adjusting the mixed ratio of the functional liquid and the water according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the functional liquid is essence, conditioner, shampoo, shower gel, detergent, or hand soap.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The water outlet mechanism for adjusting the mixed ratio of the functional liquid and the water according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the water outlet mechanism is a bath shower or a kitchen shower.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The water outlet mechanism for adjusting the mixed ratio of the functional liquid and the water according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the liquid inlet of the water operated pump is in communication with the functional liquid storage chamber through a liquid inlet pipe, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a diameter of the liquid inlet pipe is unchanged and always in communication with the functional liquid storage chamber and the liquid inlet when a water flow rate of the water passing through the water operated pump is adjusted.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
