<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225341A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225341</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17578987</doc-number>
<date>20220119</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>17</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>23</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>4</main-group>
<subgroup>052</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>23</class>
<subclass>Q</subclass>
<main-group>25</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>24</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>15</main-group>
<subgroup>20</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>23</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>4</main-group>
<subgroup>052</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>F</section>
<class>23</class>
<subclass>Q</subclass>
<main-group>25</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>F</section>
<class>24</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>15</main-group>
<subgroup>205</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>23</class>
<subclass>V</subclass>
<main-group>2002</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">PELLET MANAGEMENT IN AN INDOOR SMOKER</invention-title>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Haier US Appliance Solutions, Inc.</orgname>
<address>
<city>Wilrngton</city>
<state>DE</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Garces</last-name>
<first-name>Tomas</first-name>
<address>
<city>Louisville</city>
<state>KY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="01" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Carballo</last-name>
<first-name>Daniel</first-name>
<address>
<city>Louisville</city>
<state>KY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An indoor smoker includes a smoking chamber positioned within a cabinet, a hopper positioned within the cabinet and being configured to receive combustible material to facilitate a smoking process, a smoke generating assembly positioned below the hopper along the vertical direction and being configured to for receive the combustible material and generate a flow of smoke that is directed into the smoking chamber, and a waste container positioned below the smoke generating assembly and being configured to receive and extinguish the combustible material. A volume ratio is defined as a waste container volume to a hopper volume and is between about 2:1 and 6:1.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="174.58mm" wi="154.43mm" file="US20230225341A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="197.36mm" wi="156.46mm" file="US20230225341A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="197.36mm" wi="159.43mm" file="US20230225341A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="206.25mm" wi="153.50mm" file="US20230225341A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="207.43mm" wi="166.20mm" file="US20230225341A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="185.84mm" wi="166.03mm" file="US20230225341A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="166.45mm" wi="168.40mm" file="US20230225341A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="247.82mm" wi="161.97mm" file="US20230225341A1-20230720-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="209.97mm" wi="151.72mm" file="US20230225341A1-20230720-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present subject matter relates generally to indoor smokers, and more particularly to indoor smokers constructions for improved pellet management.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Conventional smokers include a smoking chamber and a firebox positioned within or fluidly coupled to the smoking chamber. The firebox is filled with a combustible material, such as wood or wood byproducts that are ignited or otherwise heated to generate smoke and/or heat. The heat and smoke are routed into the smoking chamber to impart flavor on and cook food items positioned within the smoking chamber. One or more heating elements may be positioned within the smoking chamber and the firebox to maintain the temperatures necessary both for cooking the food and for generating the desired amount of smoke.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">During a conventional smoking process, a hopper of a smoker is loaded with combustible material, e.g., wood pellets, that are smoldered during the smoking process to generate smoke. Notably, it is commonly desirable to load the smoker with a sufficient amount of pellets to last for the entire smoking process, which can often be 4 hours, 12 hours, 24 hours, or longer. While certain outdoor smokers may be resupplied with fuel for long smokes, opening the hopper of an indoor smoker may release generated smoke into the room. Accordingly, refilling an indoor smoker in the middle of a smoking process is often undesirable.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Moreover, indoor smokers are often installed on countertops or in other locations that are space-restricted. Accordingly, conventional indoor smokers have limited heights and volumes within which wood pellets may be stored. In addition, the progression of combustible material in conventional smokers is typically gravity-driven, meaning pellets are supplied above a smoldering heater and the consumed pellets are collected below the smoldering heater and hopper in a waste container. Notably, the waste container is preferably sized to contain all the combustion byproducts from the duration of the smoking process.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Conventional smokers do not have the proper size, configuration, and geometry of the hopper and waste container. For example, conventional smokers have a relatively small hopper that must be frequently resupplied with combustible material to facilitate long smoking processes. In addition, waste reservoirs are often too small to contain the ash from the complete smoking cycle. This may present a hazardous situation if the combusted pellets overflow the waste reservoir. In sum, conventional smokers are not capable of being positioned within confined spaces, such as indoors on a countertop and generated significant difficult and/or hazards relative to pellet management, both in the hopper and the waste reservoir.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Accordingly, a smoker that has features for improved pellet management would be useful. More specifically, an indoor smoker that includes features that facilitate containment of large volumes of wood pellets and safe extinguishment and containment of such pellets would be particularly beneficial.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Aspects and advantages of the invention will be set forth in part in the following description, may be apparent from the description, or may be learned through practice of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In one exemplary embodiment, an indoor smoker defining a vertical direction is provided. The indoor smoker includes a cabinet defining a cabinet height measured along the vertical direction, a smoking chamber positioned within the cabinet, a hopper positioned within the cabinet and being configured to receive combustible material to facilitate a smoking process, the hopper defining a hopper volume, a smoke generating assembly positioned below the hopper along the vertical direction and being configured to for receive the combustible material and generate a flow of smoke that is directed into the smoking chamber, and a waste container positioned below the smoke generating assembly and being configured to receive and extinguish the combustible material, the waste container defining a waste container volume, wherein a wherein a volume ratio is defined as the waste container volume to the hopper volume, and wherein the volume ratio is between about 2:1 and 6:1.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In another exemplary embodiment, an indoor smoker defining a vertical direction is provided. The indoor smoker includes a cabinet defining a cabinet height measured along the vertical direction, a smoking chamber positioned within the cabinet, a hopper positioned within the cabinet and being configured to receive combustible material to facilitate a smoking process, the hopper defining a hopper height, a smoke generating assembly positioned below the hopper along the vertical direction and being configured to for receive the combustible material and generate a flow of smoke that is directed into the smoking chamber, and a waste container positioned below the smoke generating assembly and being configured to receive and extinguish the combustible material, the waste container defining a waste container height, wherein a wherein a height ratio is defined as the waste container height to the hopper height, and wherein the height ratio is between about 0.8:1 and 1.2:1.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">These and other features, aspects and advantages of the present invention will become better understood with reference to the following description and appended claims. The accompanying drawings, which are incorporated in and constitute a part of this specification, illustrate embodiments of the invention and, together with the description, serve to explain the principles of the invention.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">A full and enabling disclosure of the present invention, including the best mode thereof, directed to one of ordinary skill in the art, is set forth in the specification, which makes reference to the appended figures.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> provides a perspective view of an indoor smoker with a door in a closed position in accordance with an example embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> provides a perspective view the exemplary indoor smoker of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> with the door opened.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> provides a partial perspective view of the exemplary indoor smoker of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> according to an exemplary embodiment of the present subject matter.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is a front cross-sectional view of the exemplary indoor smoker of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> according to an exemplary embodiment of the present subject matter.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is a side cross sectional view of the exemplary indoor smoker of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> according to an exemplary embodiment of the present subject matter.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is a schematic cross-sectional view of a smoke generating assembly for use with the exemplary indoor smoker of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> according to an exemplary embodiment of the present subject matter.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> is a schematic cross-sectional view of a smoldering heater and a smoke barrel of the exemplary smoke generating assembly of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> with a rotating auger removed for clarity according to an exemplary embodiment of the present subject matter.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> provides a side, schematic view of the exemplary indoor smoker of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> according to an exemplary embodiment of the present subject matter.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Repeat use of reference characters in the present specification and drawings is intended to represent the same or analogous features or elements of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Reference now will be made in detail to embodiments of the invention, one or more examples of which are illustrated in the drawings. Each example is provided by way of explanation of the invention, not limitation of the invention. In fact, it will be apparent to those skilled in the art that various modifications and variations can be made in the present invention without departing from the scope or spirit of the invention. For instance, features illustrated or described as part of one embodiment can be used with another embodiment to yield a still further embodiment. Thus, it is intended that the present invention covers such modifications and variations as come within the scope of the appended claims and their equivalents.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">As used herein, the terms &#x201c;first,&#x201d; &#x201c;second,&#x201d; and &#x201c;third&#x201d; may be used interchangeably to distinguish one component from another and are not intended to signify location or importance of the individual components. The terms &#x201c;includes&#x201d; and &#x201c;including&#x201d; are intended to be inclusive in a manner similar to the term &#x201c;comprising.&#x201d; Similarly, the term &#x201c;or&#x201d; is generally intended to be inclusive (i.e., &#x201c;A or B&#x201d; is intended to mean &#x201c;A or B or both&#x201d;). In addition, here and throughout the specification and claims, range limitations may be combined and/or interchanged. Such ranges are identified and include all the sub-ranges contained therein unless context or language indicates otherwise. For example, all ranges disclosed herein are inclusive of the endpoints, and the endpoints are independently combinable with each other. The singular forms &#x201c;a,&#x201d; &#x201c;an,&#x201d; and &#x201c;the&#x201d; include plural references unless the context clearly dictates otherwise. The terms &#x201c;upstream&#x201d; and &#x201c;downstream&#x201d; refer to the relative flow direction with respect to fluid flow in a fluid pathway. For example, &#x201c;upstream&#x201d; refers to the flow direction from which the fluid flows, and &#x201c;downstream&#x201d; refers to the flow direction to which the fluid flows.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Approximating language, as used herein throughout the specification and claims, may be applied to modify any quantitative representation that could permissibly vary without resulting in a change in the basic function to which it is related. Accordingly, a value modified by a term or terms, such as &#x201c;generally,&#x201d; &#x201c;about,&#x201d; &#x201c;approximately,&#x201d; and &#x201c;substantially,&#x201d; are not to be limited to the precise value specified. In at least some instances, the approximating language may correspond to the precision of an instrument for measuring the value, or the precision of the methods or machines for constructing or manufacturing the components and/or systems. For example, the approximating language may refer to being within a <b>10</b> percent margin, i.e., including values within ten percent greater or less than the stated value. In this regard, for example, when used in the context of an angle or direction, such terms include within ten degrees greater or less than the stated angle or direction, e.g., &#x201c;generally vertical&#x201d; includes forming an angle of up to ten degrees in any direction, e.g., clockwise or counterclockwise, with the vertical direction V.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> and <b>2</b></figref> provide perspective views of an indoor smoker <b>100</b> according to an exemplary embodiment of the present subject matter with the door in the closed position and the open position, respectively. Indoor smoker <b>100</b> generally defines a vertical direction V, a lateral direction L, and a transverse direction T, each of which is mutually perpendicular, such that an orthogonal coordinate system is generally defined. As illustrated, indoor smoker <b>100</b> includes an insulated cabinet <b>102</b>. Cabinet <b>102</b> of indoor smoker <b>100</b> extends between a top <b>104</b> and a bottom <b>106</b> along the vertical direction V, between a first side <b>108</b> (left side when viewed from front) and a second side <b>110</b> (right side when viewed from front) along the lateral direction L, and between a front <b>112</b> and a rear <b>114</b> along the transverse direction T.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Within cabinet <b>102</b> is a smoking chamber <b>120</b> which is configured for the receipt of one or more food items to be cooked and/or smoked. In general, smoking chamber <b>120</b> is at least partially defined by a plurality of chamber walls <b>122</b>. Specifically, smoking chamber <b>120</b> may be defined by a top wall, a rear wall, a bottom wall, and two sidewalls. These chamber walls <b>122</b> may define smoking chamber <b>120</b> and an opening through which a user may access food articles placed therein. In addition, chamber walls <b>122</b> may be joined, sealed, and insulated to help retain smoke and heat within smoking chamber <b>120</b>. In this regard, for example, in order to insulate smoking chamber <b>120</b>, indoor smoker <b>100</b> includes an insulation gap <b>124</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>) defined between chamber walls <b>122</b> and cabinet <b>102</b>. According to an exemplary embodiment, insulation gap <b>124</b> is filled with insulating material (not shown), such as insulating foam or fiberglass.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Indoor smoker <b>100</b> includes a door <b>126</b> rotatably attached to cabinet <b>102</b> in order to permit selective access to smoking chamber <b>120</b>. A handle <b>128</b> is mounted to door <b>126</b> to assist a user with opening and closing door <b>126</b> and a latch <b>130</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>) is mounted to cabinet <b>102</b> for locking door <b>126</b> in the closed position during a cooking or smoking operation. In addition, door <b>126</b> may include one or more transparent viewing windows <b>132</b> to provide for viewing the contents of smoking chamber <b>120</b> when door <b>126</b> is closed and also to assist with insulating smoking chamber <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Referring still to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> and <b>2</b></figref>, a user interface panel <b>134</b> and a user input device <b>136</b> may be positioned on an exterior of cabinet <b>102</b>. User interface panel <b>134</b> may represent a general purpose Input/Output (&#x201c;GPIO&#x201d;) device or functional block. In some embodiments, user interface panel <b>134</b> may include or be in operative communication with user input device <b>136</b>, such as one or more of a variety of digital, analog, electrical, mechanical or electro-mechanical input devices including rotary dials, control knobs, push buttons, and touch pads. User input device <b>136</b> is generally positioned proximate to user interface panel <b>134</b>, and in some embodiments, user input device <b>136</b> may be positioned on user interface panel <b>134</b>. User interface panel <b>134</b> may include a display component <b>138</b>, such as a digital or analog display device designed to provide operational feedback to a user.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Generally, indoor smoker <b>100</b> may include a controller <b>140</b> in operative communication with user input device <b>136</b>. User interface panel <b>134</b> of indoor smoker <b>100</b> may be in communication with controller <b>140</b> via, for example, one or more signal lines or shared communication busses, and signals generated in controller <b>140</b> operate indoor smoker <b>100</b> in response to user input via user input devices <b>136</b>. Input/Output (&#x201c;I/O&#x201d;) signals may be routed between controller <b>140</b> and various operational components of indoor smoker <b>100</b> such that operation of indoor smoker <b>100</b> can be regulated by controller <b>140</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Controller <b>140</b> is a &#x201c;processing device&#x201d; or &#x201c;controller&#x201d; and may be embodied as described herein. Controller <b>140</b> may include a memory and one or more microprocessors, microcontrollers, application-specific integrated circuits (ASICS), CPUs or the like, such as general or special purpose microprocessors operable to execute programming instructions or micro-control code associated with operation of indoor smoker <b>100</b>, and controller <b>140</b> is not restricted necessarily to a single element. The memory may represent random access memory such as DRAM, or read only memory such as ROM, electrically erasable, programmable read only memory (EEPROM), or FLASH. In one embodiment, the processor executes programming instructions stored in memory. The memory may be a separate component from the processor or may be included onboard within the processor. Alternatively, controller <b>140</b> may be constructed without using a microprocessor, e.g., using a combination of discrete analog and/or digital logic circuitry (such as switches, amplifiers, integrators, comparators, flip-flops, AND gates, and the like) to perform control functionality instead of relying upon software.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Although aspects of the present subject matter are described herein in the context of an indoor smoker having a single smoking chamber, it should be appreciated that indoor smoker <b>100</b> is provided by way of example only. Other smoking appliances having different configurations, different appearances, and/or different features may also be utilized with the present subject matter, e.g., outdoor smokers, conventional oven appliances, or other suitable cooking appliances. Thus, the example embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is not intended to limit the present subject matter to any particular smoking configuration or arrangement. Moreover, aspects of the present subject matter may be used in any other consumer or commercial appliance where it is desirable to regulate a flow of smoke or harmful emissions in an appliance.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Referring now also to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, various internal components of an indoor smoker <b>100</b> and their respective functions will be described according to an exemplary embodiment of the present subject matter. In this regard, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> illustrates a partial perspective view of an indoor smoker <b>100</b> similar to that shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>. As shown, indoor smoker <b>100</b> generally includes smoking chamber <b>120</b> for receiving items to be cooked/smoked, a smoke generating device or smoke generating assembly <b>150</b> for generating a flow of smoke (indicated by reference numeral <b>152</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>), and an exhaust system <b>154</b> for safely discharging that the air and/or smoke into an indoor environment <b>156</b> (i.e., outside of indoor smoker <b>100</b>). Each of these systems and components will be described in detail below.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>5</b> and <b>6</b></figref>, smoke generating assembly <b>150</b> generally defines a smoldering chamber <b>160</b> which is configured for receiving combustible material <b>162</b>. As used herein, &#x201c;combustible material&#x201d; is generally used to refer to any suitable material positioned within smoldering chamber <b>160</b> for generating smoke. Specifically, according to exemplary embodiments, combustible material <b>162</b> includes wood or wood byproducts, such as wood chunks, wood chips, wood pellets, or wood resin. According to the exemplary embodiment, smoke generating assembly <b>150</b> may include a door or another access panel (not shown) for providing selective access to smoldering chamber <b>160</b>, e.g., to add additional combustible material <b>162</b>. Smoke generating assembly <b>150</b> will be described in more detail below with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>3</b> through <b>7</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">As best shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>, in order to ensure a desirable cooking temperature within smoking chamber <b>120</b>, indoor smoker <b>100</b> further includes a chamber heater <b>170</b> that is positioned within or otherwise in thermal communication with smoking chamber <b>120</b> for regulating the temperature in smoking chamber <b>120</b>. In general, chamber heater <b>170</b> may include one or more heating elements positioned within cabinet <b>102</b> for selectively heating smoking chamber <b>120</b>. For example, the heating elements may be electric resistance heating elements, gas burners, microwave heating elements, halogen heating elements, or suitable combinations thereof. Notably, because chamber heater <b>170</b> is operated independently of smoke generating assembly <b>150</b> (e.g., as described below), smoking chamber <b>120</b> may be maintained at any suitable temperature during a smoking process. More specifically, for example, chamber heater <b>170</b> may be turned off or on a very low setting for smoking cheeses or may be turned on high for quickly cooking and smoking meats.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">In some embodiments, indoor smoker <b>100</b> also includes one or more sensors that may be used to facilitate improved operation of the appliance, such as described below. For example, indoor smoker <b>100</b> may include one or more temperature sensors which are generally operable to measure the internal temperature in indoor smoker <b>100</b>, e.g., within smoking chamber <b>120</b> and/or smoldering chamber <b>160</b>. More specifically, as illustrated, indoor smoker <b>100</b> includes a temperature sensor <b>172</b> positioned within smoking chamber <b>120</b> and being operably coupled to controller <b>140</b>. In some embodiments, controller <b>140</b> is configured to vary operation of chamber heater <b>170</b> based on one or more temperatures detected by temperature sensor <b>172</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">As described herein, &#x201c;temperature sensor&#x201d; may refer to any suitable type of temperature sensor. For example, the temperature sensors may be thermocouples, thermistors, or resistance temperature detectors. In addition, temperature sensor <b>172</b> may be mounted at any suitable location and in any suitable manner for obtaining a desired temperature measurement, either directly or indirectly. Although exemplary positioning of certain sensors is described below, it should be appreciated that indoor smoker <b>100</b> may include any other suitable number, type, and position of temperature sensors according to alternative embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">As mentioned briefly above, indoor smoker <b>100</b> further includes an exhaust system <b>154</b> which is generally configured for safely discharging the flow of smoke <b>152</b> from indoor smoker <b>100</b>. Specifically, according to the illustrated embodiment, exhaust system <b>154</b> generally extends between a chamber outlet <b>180</b> and a discharge vent <b>182</b> defined by cabinet <b>102</b> for directing the flow of smoke <b>152</b> from smoking chamber <b>120</b> to the environment <b>156</b>. Although an exemplary exhaust system <b>154</b> is described below, it should be appreciated that variations and modifications may be made while remaining within the scope of the present subject matter. For example, the routing of ducts, the catalytic converter arrangement, and the types of sensors used may vary according to alternative embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">As shown, exhaust system <b>154</b> includes an exhaust duct <b>184</b> that generally extends between and provides fluid communication between chamber outlet <b>180</b> and discharge vent <b>182</b>. Indoor smoker <b>100</b> further includes an air handler <b>186</b> that is operably coupled with exhaust duct <b>184</b> facilitating the smoldering process and smoke generating process. For example, air handler <b>186</b> urges the flow of smoke <b>152</b> through exhaust duct <b>184</b> and out of discharge vent <b>182</b> to environment <b>156</b>. According to the illustrated exemplary embodiment, air handler <b>186</b> is an axial fan positioned within exhaust duct <b>184</b>. However, it should be appreciated that according to alternative embodiments, air handler <b>186</b> may be positioned at any other suitable location and may be any other suitable fan type, such as a tangential fan, a centrifugal fan, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">In addition, according to an exemplary embodiment, air handler <b>186</b> is a variable speed fan such that it may rotate at different rotational speeds, thereby generating different air flow rates. In this manner, the amount of smoke drawn from smoldering chamber <b>160</b> may be continuously and precisely regulated. Moreover, by pulsing the operation of air handler <b>186</b> or throttling air handler <b>186</b> between different rotational speeds, the flow of smoke <b>152</b> drawn into smoking chamber <b>120</b> may enter from a different direction, may have a different flow velocity, or may generate a different flow pattern within smoking chamber <b>120</b>. Thus, by pulsating the variable speed fan or otherwise varying its speed, the flow of smoke <b>152</b> may be randomized, thereby eliminating stagnant regions within smoking chamber <b>120</b> and better circulating the flow of smoke <b>152</b> to provide a more even cooking/smoking profile.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">As illustrated, indoor smoker <b>100</b> further includes a catalytic converter <b>190</b> which is positioned within exhaust duct <b>184</b> for lowering or removing volatile organic compounds (VOCs) from the flow of smoke <b>152</b>. As used herein, &#x201c;catalytic converter&#x201d; or variations thereof may be used to refer to any component, machine, or device that is configured for removing or lowering volatile organic compounds (VOCs), toxic gases, harmful emissions, pollutants, or undesirable compounds from a flow of air and smoke. For example, according to the illustrated embodiment, catalytic converter <b>190</b> generally includes a catalytic element <b>192</b> and a catalyst heater <b>194</b>. Although catalytic converter <b>190</b> is illustrated herein as being positioned within exhaust duct <b>184</b>, it should be appreciated that according to other embodiments catalytic converter <b>190</b> be positioned at any other suitable location, so long as catalytic converter <b>190</b> is inline with the flow of smoke <b>152</b>, such that volatile organic compounds may be reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">In general, catalytic element <b>192</b> includes a material that causes an oxidation and a reduction reaction. For example, precious metals such as platinum, palladium, and rhodium are commonly used as catalyst materials, though other catalysts are possible and within the scope of the present subject matter. In operation, the catalytic element <b>192</b> may combine oxygen O<sub>2</sub>) with carbon monoxide (CO) and unburned hydrocarbons to produce carbon dioxide (CO<sub>2</sub>) and water (H<sub>2</sub>O). In addition, according to exemplary embodiments, catalytic element <b>192</b> may remove nitric oxide (NO) and nitrogen dioxide (NO<sub>2</sub>).</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Notably, catalytic converters typically require that the catalyst be heated to a suitably high temperature in order to catalyze the necessary chemical reactions. Therefore, catalyst heater <b>194</b> is in thermal communication with catalytic element <b>192</b> for heating it to a suitable temperature, such as approximately 800&#xb0; F. According to the illustrated embodiment, catalyst heater <b>194</b> is positioned upstream of catalytic element <b>192</b> to provide thermal energy through convection. However, it should be appreciated that according to alternative embodiments, catalyst heater <b>194</b> may be in direct contact with catalytic element <b>192</b> to provide thermal energy through conduction, or may be thermally coupled to catalytic element <b>192</b> in any other suitable manner. In order to ensure a catalyst temperature of catalytic element <b>192</b> remains above a temperature suitable for controlling emissions, indoor smoker <b>100</b> may further include a catalyst temperature sensor (not shown) that may be monitored by controller <b>140</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Referring now specifically to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>3</b> through <b>7</b></figref>, the construction and operation of smoke generating assembly <b>150</b> will be described in more detail according to an exemplary embodiment of the present subject matter. As best shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, indoor smoker <b>100</b> defines an air inlet <b>200</b> for receiving air to support the combustion or smoldering process. Specifically, air inlet <b>200</b> is configured for receiving a flow of combustion air (indicated by reference numeral <b>202</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>) from the ambient environment <b>156</b> surrounding indoor smoker <b>100</b> or from another air supply source. During a smoking process, combustible material <b>162</b> is ignited and the flow of combustion air <b>202</b> supports the smoldering process to generate the flow of smoke <b>152</b>. Smoke generating assembly <b>150</b> further defines a smoke outlet <b>204</b> for providing a flow of smoke <b>152</b> into smoking chamber <b>120</b> during a smoking operation, as will be described in detail below.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">In addition, indoor smoker <b>100</b> may further include features for preventing or regulating the flow of combustion air <b>202</b> from entering indoor smoker <b>100</b> from environment <b>156</b> when the flow of such air is not desired. In this regard, for example, indoor smoker <b>100</b> may include an inlet check valve <b>210</b> which is operably coupled to air inlet <b>200</b>. In general, this check valve prevents the flow of combustion air <b>202</b> from entering smoldering chamber <b>160</b> when not desired. For example, inlet check valve <b>210</b> may have a &#x201c;cracking pressure,&#x201d; which is used herein to refer to the pressure, or more precisely the negative pressure, required within smoldering chamber <b>160</b> to open inlet check valve <b>210</b>. In this manner, inlet check valve <b>210</b> may be designed to permit the flow of combustion air <b>202</b> only when air handler <b>186</b> is operating and urging air through smoldering chamber <b>160</b>, thus facilitating the quick and effective asphyxiation of combustible material <b>162</b> within smoldering chamber <b>160</b> when desired.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">Referring now specifically to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>5</b> through <b>7</b></figref>, according to the illustrated embodiment, smoke generating assembly <b>150</b> generally includes a smoke barrel <b>230</b> that defines smoldering chamber <b>160</b>. Specifically, smoke barrel <b>230</b> extends between a first end <b>232</b> and a second end <b>234</b> substantially along a central axis <b>236</b>. Specifically, as illustrated, central axis <b>236</b> extends substantially within a horizontal plane within cabinet <b>102</b>, e.g., directly along the transverse direction T. In general, smoke barrel <b>230</b> is configured for receiving the combustible material <b>162</b> and facilitating a smoldering process. As shown, smoke barrel <b>230</b> has a substantially cylindrical shape and is formed from a substantially rigid and temperature resistant material, such as steel. However, it should be appreciated that smoke barrel <b>230</b> may be formed from different materials, may have different geometries, and may be configured differently within cabinet <b>102</b> according to alternative embodiments of the present subject matter.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Smoke generating assembly <b>150</b> further includes a rotating auger <b>240</b> that is rotatably mounted within smoldering chamber <b>160</b> and generally rotates about central axis <b>236</b>, e.g., such that rotating auger <b>240</b> is coaxial with smoke barrel <b>230</b>. As shown, an outer diameter of rotating auger <b>240</b> is substantially equivalent to an inner diameter of smoke barrel <b>230</b>, such that a helical blade <b>242</b> of rotating auger <b>240</b> may advance combustible material <b>162</b> within smoldering chamber <b>160</b> as rotating auger <b>240</b> is rotated about central axis <b>236</b>. More specifically, the combustible material <b>162</b> is generally urged from first end <b>232</b> toward second end <b>234</b> of smoke barrel <b>230</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">As illustrated, smoke generating assembly <b>150</b> may further include a hopper <b>244</b> that is generally configured for storing and selectively depositing combustible material <b>162</b> into smoldering chamber <b>160</b>. More specifically, as illustrated, hopper <b>244</b> may be a large, tapered reservoir with a top opening <b>246</b> positioned at top <b>104</b> of cabinet <b>102</b>. A user may fill hopper <b>244</b> by pouring or providing combustible material <b>162</b> into hopper <b>244</b> through top opening <b>246</b>. Hopper <b>244</b> may taper toward a supply opening <b>248</b> positioned at a bottom of hopper <b>244</b>. As shown, supply opening <b>248</b> opens into smoldering chamber <b>160</b> at a top of smoke barrel <b>230</b>. More specifically, supply opening <b>248</b> is joined to smoke barrel <b>230</b> proximate first end <b>232</b> of smoke barrel <b>230</b>. In this manner, fresh combustible material <b>162</b> is typically provided into smoldering chamber <b>160</b> proximate first end <b>232</b> of smoke barrel <b>230</b> and is urged by rotating auger <b>240</b> toward second end <b>234</b> of smoke barrel <b>230</b>. As illustrated, smoke generating assembly <b>150</b> may generally define a discharge port <b>250</b> proximate second end <b>234</b> of smoke barrel <b>230</b> for discharging consumed combustible material <b>162</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">As best shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b> and <b>7</b></figref>, smoke generating assembly <b>150</b> includes one or more smoldering heaters <b>252</b> which are positioned adjacent smoldering chamber <b>160</b> or otherwise placed in thermal communication with combustible material <b>162</b> stored in smoldering chamber <b>160</b> for smoldering combustible material <b>162</b>. According to an exemplary embodiment, smoldering heater <b>252</b> may include one or more cartridge heaters or silicon nitride igniters. Alternatively, smoldering heater <b>252</b> may include any other suitable type, position, and configuration of heating elements. As used herein, the term &#x201c;heating element,&#x201d; &#x201c;heaters,&#x201d; and the like may generally refer to electric resistance heating elements, gas burners, microwave heating elements, halogen heating elements, or suitable combinations thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">As used herein, the verb &#x201c;smolder&#x201d; or variations thereof is intended to refer to burning a combustible material (e.g., combustible material <b>162</b>) slowly such that smoke is generated but little or no flame is generated. In this manner, the combustible material is not expended quickly, but a large amount of smoke is generated for the smoking process. Notably, the burn rate of combustible material and the amount of smoke generated is regulated using smoldering heater <b>252</b> positioned within smoldering chamber <b>160</b>. For typical combustible material used in smokers, e.g., wood and wood byproducts, a typical smoldering temperature is between about 650&#xb0; F. and 750&#xb0; F. However, the exact temperature may vary depending on the combustible material used, the air flow rate through smoldering chamber <b>160</b>, the level of combustible material <b>162</b>, and other factors.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">According to the exemplary illustrated embodiment, smoldering heater <b>252</b> is positioned proximate second end <b>234</b> of smoke barrel <b>230</b>. For example, smoldering heater <b>252</b> may at least partially define smoke outlet <b>204</b> of smoke generating assembly <b>150</b>. Specifically, as illustrated, smoke outlet <b>204</b> corresponds to discharge port <b>250</b> of smoke generating assembly <b>150</b>, which may simply be an open end of smoldering heater <b>252</b>. In this manner, as rotating auger <b>240</b> rotates, combustible material <b>162</b> positioned within smoldering chamber <b>160</b> is slowly but progressively advanced past smoldering heater <b>252</b>. After combustible material <b>162</b> positioned near smoldering heater <b>252</b> is consumed or smoldered, rotating auger <b>240</b> may rotate to advance the consumed material toward discharge port <b>250</b> where it may be pushed out of smoldering chamber <b>160</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Specifically, as illustrated, smoldering heater <b>252</b> may be positioned adjacent smoke barrel <b>230</b>, e.g., downstream of second end <b>234</b> of smoke barrel <b>230</b>. More specifically, according to exemplary embodiments of the present subject matter, smoldering heater <b>252</b> may be spaced apart from the second end <b>234</b> of smoke barrel <b>230</b> to define an igniter gap <b>254</b> between smoke barrel <b>230</b> and smoldering heater <b>252</b>. More specifically, igniter gap <b>254</b> may be a void defined between smoke barrel <b>230</b> and smoldering heater <b>252</b> and may define a gap width <b>256</b> measured along the central axis <b>236</b> of smoke barrel <b>230</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">As explained briefly above, combustible material <b>162</b> may have a general tendency of at least partially breaking down and forming dust or other small particles, referred to herein generally as pellet dust <b>258</b>. In this regard, although combustible material <b>162</b> may initially be provided as solid pellets, these pellets may break down, e.g., due to agitation within hopper <b>244</b> or under the force of rotating auger <b>240</b> such that pellet dust <b>258</b> is formed. Moreover, as smoke generating assembly <b>150</b> is heated by smoldering heater <b>252</b>, the original combustible material <b>162</b> may have a tendency to dry out and further accelerate the process of pellets breaking down into pellet dust <b>258</b>. Notably, this pellet dust <b>258</b> may create undesirable conditions, e.g., by creating a dust layer or &#x201c;raft&#x201d; with in a water container (e.g., as described in more detail below) which may support combustible material <b>162</b> above the water thereby preventing the combustible material <b>162</b> from being extinguished when dumped into the extinguishing container. In addition, this pellet dust may combust in an undesirable manner or at an undesirable rate, may coat surfaces of smoke generating assembly <b>150</b>, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">As a result, igniter gap <b>254</b> may be particularly sized and positioned for facilitating the removal, collection, and/or rerouting of pellet dust <b>258</b> while retaining usable combustible material <b>162</b> for smoldering via smoldering heater <b>252</b>. In this regard, for example, gap width <b>256</b> may be between about 10 and 300 thousandths of an inch, between about 50 and 200 thousandths of an inch, or about 100 thousandths of an inch. It should be appreciated that the spacing may vary as needed depending on the application, the combustible material used, and the size, shape, and geometry of combustible material <b>162</b>. In addition, it should be appreciated that igniter gap <b>254</b> may be integrally formed into smoke barrel <b>230</b> and/or smoldering heater <b>252</b> instead of having a physical separation between these two components. In this regard, for example, one or both of smoldering heater <b>252</b> and smoke barrel <b>230</b> may define one or more apertures for permitting pellet dust <b>258</b> to fall through these components under the force of gravity.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">As best shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref>, smoldering heater <b>252</b> may be mounted within indoor smoker <b>100</b> using a mounting bracket <b>260</b>. In this regard, mounting bracket <b>260</b> may be secured to cabinet <b>102</b> or another suitable structure within indoor smoker <b>100</b> for supporting smoldering heater <b>252</b> adjacent smoke barrel <b>230</b> and in a manner that defines igniter gap <b>254</b>. For example, as illustrated, smoldering heater <b>252</b> may be mounted to the mounting bracket <b>260</b> using a plurality of fasteners <b>262</b> that each pass through an insulating standoff <b>264</b>, e.g., such as a ceramic standoff. As explained below, the standoffs <b>264</b> may be used to maintain the desirable igniter gap <b>254</b> as well as provide a thermal break between smoke barrel <b>230</b> and smoldering heater <b>252</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">In addition, mounting bracket <b>260</b> may define a barrel aperture <b>266</b> that is designed to receive second end <b>234</b> of smoke barrel <b>230</b>. Specifically, for example, second end <b>234</b> of smoke barrel <b>230</b> may be positioned and/or float within barrel aperture <b>266</b> such that the igniter gap <b>254</b> may be maintained between smoke barrel <b>230</b> and smoldering heater <b>252</b>. Notably, in addition to permitting pellet dust <b>258</b> to fall out of smoke generating assembly <b>150</b> prior to passing through smoldering heater <b>252</b>, igniter gap <b>254</b> may serve to maintain a thermal break or facilitate thermal isolation between smoldering heater <b>252</b> and smoke barrel <b>230</b>. In this manner, further drying out of combustible material <b>162</b> may be prevented and pellet dust <b>258</b> may be minimized prior to the combustible material <b>162</b> reaching smoldering heater <b>252</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">According to exemplary embodiments, smoldering heater <b>252</b> may be positioned on a distal end of rotating auger <b>240</b>, e.g., aligned along central axis <b>236</b> proximate second end <b>234</b>. As such, rotating auger <b>240</b> may pass through smoke barrel <b>230</b> and through a central aperture smoldering heater <b>252</b> to extend out of discharge port <b>250</b>. In this manner, rotating auger <b>240</b> may serve to advance combustible material <b>162</b> from first end <b>232</b> of smoke barrel <b>230</b>, past second end <b>234</b> of smoke barrel <b>230</b>, through and across smoldering heater <b>252</b>, then out of discharge port <b>250</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">According to an exemplary embodiment, a waste container <b>270</b> may be configured for receiving consumed combustible material <b>162</b> when discharged from smoke generating assembly <b>150</b>. In this regard, for example, waste container <b>270</b> may be positioned directly below smoke barrel <b>230</b>, smoldering heater <b>252</b>, and/or discharge port <b>250</b> such that used combustible material <b>162</b> may fall therein and immediately extinguish. For example, according to the illustrated embodiment, waste container <b>270</b> is filled with water <b>272</b> to immediately extinguish combustible material <b>162</b> when dropped into container <b>270</b>. However, it should be appreciated that other liquids or materials for extinguishing combustible material <b>162</b> may be contained within waste container <b>270</b>. In addition, as illustrated, waste container <b>270</b> may be positioned below or directly define a chamber inlet <b>274</b> that is positioned adjacent smoke outlet <b>204</b>. In this manner, the flow of smoke <b>152</b> exiting smoke barrel <b>230</b> may pass directly into smoking chamber <b>120</b> through chamber inlet <b>274</b> while consumed combustible material <b>162</b> may fall directly into water <b>272</b> within container <b>270</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">According to alternative embodiments, consumed combustible material <b>162</b> may be discharged in any other suitable manner into to any other suitable container or reservoir. According to exemplary embodiments such as that illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref>, smoke generating assembly <b>150</b> may further include a dust deflector <b>276</b> that is positioned below smoldering heater <b>252</b> for directing pellet dust <b>258</b> toward a rear of waste container <b>270</b>. In this manner, pellet dust <b>258</b> may collect within one region of container <b>270</b>, e.g., directly below igniter gap <b>254</b>. By contrast, the remaining combustible material <b>162</b> may be advanced through smoldering heater <b>252</b> and may be discharged through discharge port <b>250</b> to a different region within waste container <b>270</b>. As a result, this smoldering combustible material <b>162</b> may be immediately extinguished instead of floating on top of a collection or agglomeration of pellet dust <b>258</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">Specifically, according to the illustrated embodiment, dust deflector <b>276</b> may generally extend toward a rear, bottom of waste container <b>270</b>. In addition, according to exemplary embodiments, another portion of dust deflector <b>276</b> may extend below discharge port <b>250</b> and toward a front bottom of waste container <b>270</b>. Thus, combustible material <b>162</b> and pellet dust <b>258</b> be separated and directed to separate regions within waste container <b>270</b>. According to still other embodiments, waste container <b>270</b> may include a divider wall <b>278</b> that divides waste container <b>270</b> into a first reservoir and a second reservoir. The divider wall <b>278</b> may be positioned directly below smoldering heater <b>252</b> such that combustible material <b>162</b> that passes through discharge port <b>250</b> falls into the first reservoir and is separated from pellet dust <b>258</b> which falls through igniter gap <b>254</b> upstream of smoldering heater <b>252</b> and into the second reservoir.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">As best illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>, smoke generating assembly <b>150</b> may further include a drive mechanism <b>280</b> that is mechanically coupled to rotating auger <b>240</b>. Controller <b>140</b> (or another dedicated controller) may be in operative communication with drive mechanism <b>280</b> and may be configured for intermittently rotating the rotating auger <b>240</b> to advance combustible material <b>162</b> along central axis <b>236</b>. Specifically, as illustrated, drive mechanism <b>280</b> may include a drive motor <b>282</b> and a transmission assembly <b>284</b> or another suitable geared arrangement for transferring torque from drive motor <b>282</b> to rotating auger <b>240</b>. As used herein, &#x201c;motor&#x201d; may refer to any suitable drive motor and/or transmission assembly for driving rotating auger <b>240</b>. For example, drive motor <b>282</b> may be a brushless DC electric motor, a stepper motor, or any other suitable type or configuration of motor. For example, drive motor <b>282</b> may be an AC motor, an induction motor, a permanent magnet synchronous motor, or any other suitable type of AC motor. In addition, drive motor <b>282</b> and transmission assembly <b>284</b> may include any suitable motor or transmission sub-assemblies, clutch mechanisms, or other components.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">In order to facilitate proper smoldering of combustible material <b>162</b>, it may be desirable to drive rotating auger <b>240</b> intermittently, e.g., in a non-continuous manner. Specifically, according to an exemplary embodiment, rotating auger <b>240</b> may be rotated for a particular time duration once during every predetermined rotation period. For example, the time duration of rotation may be the amount of time drive mechanism <b>280</b> should drive rotating auger <b>240</b> to discharge all combustible material <b>162</b> that is smoldering from smoke barrel <b>230</b>. In addition, the predetermined rotation period may be the amount of time necessary for a fresh portion of the smoldering material <b>162</b> to be consumed. Notably, drive mechanism <b>280</b> may discharge combustible material <b>162</b> from smoke barrel <b>230</b> before combustible material <b>162</b> is fully consumed, e.g., to prevent forming ash which may introduce acrid smoke flavors. According to an exemplary embodiment, the time duration of rotation is approximately 12 seconds while the predetermined rotation period is three minutes. Other rotation schedules are possible and within the scope of the present subject matter. Indeed, such rotation schedules may vary based on a variety of factors, such as the combustible material used, the temperature of the smoldering heater, the rate of air flow through smoke barrel <b>230</b>, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">Thus, during operation of indoor smoker <b>100</b>, air handler <b>186</b> draws the flow of combustion air <b>202</b> into smoldering chamber <b>160</b> through air inlet <b>200</b>. The flow of combustion air <b>202</b> and combustible material <b>162</b> in the smoldering chamber <b>160</b> generate the flow of smoke <b>152</b> which is drawn into smoking chamber <b>120</b> as described herein. The flow of smoke <b>152</b> passes through smoking chamber <b>120</b> for performing a smoking process on food items positioned therein before exiting smoking chamber <b>120</b> through chamber outlet <b>180</b>. Air handler <b>186</b> then continues to urge the flow of smoke <b>152</b> through catalytic converter <b>190</b> and exhaust duct <b>184</b> before passing out discharge vent <b>182</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">Referring now specifically to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref>, dimensions, dimensional ratios, and configurations of hopper <b>244</b>, waste container <b>270</b>, smoke generating assembly <b>150</b>, and other features of indoor smoker <b>100</b> will be described according to exemplary embodiments of the present subject matter. As explained herein, these dimensions are carefully selected to solve unique problems associated with an indoor smoker and the resulting solutions provide unexpected and improved smoking conditions in a confined package. Although exemplary dimensions and dimensional ratios will be described herein, it should be appreciated that variations and modifications may be made to indoor smoker <b>100</b> while remaining within the scope of the present subject matter.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">As illustrated, cabinet <b>102</b> may generally define a cabinet height <b>300</b> measured along the vertical direction V. Notably, cabinet height <b>300</b> is commonly limited based on the indoor installation location, such as underneath cabinetry and/or on a countertop. According to exemplary embodiments, cabinet height <b>300</b> may be between about <b>12</b> inches and <b>24</b> inches, between about <b>14</b> inches and <b>18</b> inches, or about <b>16</b> inches. As explained briefly above, indoor smoker <b>100</b> is typically a gravity fed device that includes combustible pellet storage that is positioned above a gravity fed smoke generating assembly <b>150</b>. After the pellets have been consumed, smoke generating assembly <b>150</b> discharges the pellets/ash such that they fall into waste container <b>270</b> which is positioned below smoke generating assembly <b>150</b>. Accordingly, hopper <b>244</b>, smoke generating assembly <b>150</b>, and waste container <b>270</b> may be stacked within cabinet <b>102</b> such that their heights collectively add up to cabinet height <b>300</b> (e.g., approximately <b>16</b> inches).</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">For example, as best illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref>, hopper <b>244</b> may generally define a hopper height <b>302</b> that is measured along the vertical direction V. According to exemplary embodiments, hopper height <b>302</b> may be between about 3 inches and 10 inches, between about 4 inches and 7 inches, or about 5 inches. In addition, according to exemplary embodiments, the ratio of cabinet height <b>300</b> to hopper height <b>302</b> may be between about 6:1 and 3:2, between about 4:1 and 2:1, or about 3:1. Similarly, waste container <b>270</b> may generally define a waste container height <b>304</b> that is measured along the vertical direction V. According to exemplary embodiments, waste container height <b>304</b> may be between about 3 inches and 10 inches, between about 4 inches and 7 inches, or about 5 inches. In addition, according to exemplary embodiments, the ratio of cabinet height <b>300</b> to waste container height <b>304</b> may be between about 6:1 and 3:2, between about 4:1 and 2:1, or about 3:1. Other suitable dimensions of hopper <b>244</b> and waste container <b>270</b> are possible and within the scope of the present subject matter.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">In addition, aspects of the present subject matter are directed to height ratios that relate hopper <b>244</b>, to waste container <b>270</b>, to cabinet <b>102</b>, etc. that produce unexpected and improved smoking efficiency and pellet management. In this regard, for example, a height ratio may be defined as waste container height <b>304</b> to hopper height <b>302</b>. According to exemplary embodiments the height ratio may be between about 0.5:1 and 2:1, between about 0.8:1 and 1.2:1, or about 1:1.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">In addition, hopper <b>244</b> and waste container <b>270</b> may each define volumes, and these respective volume may improve smoker performance when sized as described herein. For example, the volume of hopper <b>244</b> may be the product of hopper height <b>302</b> measured along the vertical direction V, a hopper width <b>310</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>) measured along the lateral direction L, and a hopper depth <b>312</b> measured along the transverse direction T. Similarly, the volume of waste container <b>270</b> may be the product of waste container height <b>304</b> measured along the vertical direction V, a waste container width <b>314</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>) measured along the lateral direction L, and a waste container depth <b>316</b> measured along the transverse direction T. According to exemplary embodiments, a volume ratio may be defined as the waste container volume to the hopper volume. For example, the volume ratio is between about 1:1 and 10:1, between about 2:1 and 6:1, or about 4:1.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">Notably, the heights and the volumes of hopper <b>244</b> and waste container <b>270</b> may not the only parameters that need to be adjusted for optimal pellet management an in indoor smoker. For example, inventors of the present subject matter have unexpectedly discovered that extinguished pellets may have a tendency to overflow waste container <b>270</b> if the footprint or dimensions within a horizontal plane (e.g., defined by the lateral direction L and the transverse direction T) are not selected appropriately. In this regard, the combustible material <b>162</b> may generally form a mountain or peak of pellets as the pellets are dropped into waste container <b>270</b>. Without proper footprint design of waste container <b>270</b>, this pellet mountain may overflow waste container <b>270</b> and result in fire hazards and excessive smoke. For example, if the waste container <b>270</b> is narrow in one or more dimensions, ash or combusted pellets may overflow the waste container <b>270</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">Accordingly, according to exemplary embodiments, a width ratio of waste container <b>270</b> may generally be defined as waste container height <b>304</b> to waste container width <b>314</b>, and this width ratio may be between about <b>1</b>:<b>1</b> and <b>2</b>:<b>1</b>, between about 1.2:1 and 1.8:1, or about 1.5:1. In addition, a depth ratio of waste container <b>270</b> may generally be defined as waste container depth <b>316</b> to waste container height <b>304</b>, and this depth ratio may be between about 1:1 and 2:1, between about 1.2:1 and 1.8:1, or about 1.5:1.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">Notably, as best shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref>, the hopper volume of hopper <b>244</b> is defined at least in part by a bottom wall <b>320</b> of hopper <b>244</b>. In order to properly feed smoke generating assembly <b>150</b> with pellets or combustible material <b>162</b>, bottom wall <b>320</b> may define a hopper angle <b>322</b> measured relative to the horizontal direction (e.g., or the transverse direction T as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref>). According to exemplary embodiments, hopper angle <b>322</b> is between about 30 degrees and 80 degrees, between about 35 degrees and 60 degrees, or about 40 degrees.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">Notably, according to exemplary embodiments, waste container <b>270</b> is generally configured to be filled with water <b>272</b>. As shown, waste container <b>270</b> defines a max fill line <b>330</b> that delineates how much water <b>272</b> should be added to extinguish a full hopper <b>244</b> of pellets. In this regard, when waste container <b>270</b> is filled to max fill line <b>330</b>, the waste container volume is sufficient to extinguish and contain all pellets and water <b>272</b> without overflowing waste container <b>270</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">As explained above, smokers are typically outdoor devices that have minimal space restrictions. However, indoor smoking appliances such as that disclosed herein are typically mounted on a countertop or in a confined location where space restrictions introduce various complex issues related to the design and configuration of the smoker. For example, the hopper of the indoor smoker is preferably capable of containing a sufficient volume of combustible material, e.g., wood pellets, to facilitate a full smoking process, such that reloading pellets or opening the hopper door is not necessary. In addition, indoor smokers preferably include a waste container that is sized to contain all the combustion byproducts from the duration of the smoking process. Moreover, these indoor smokers typically are height- and volume-limited, such that that storage of fresh pellets and the containment of consumed pellets is difficult.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">Accordingly, aspects of the present subject matter are directed to dimensions, dimensional ratios, and configurations of an indoor smoker that uniquely address all of these deficiencies of prior designs. Specifically, the present subject matter is directed to an indoor smoker having the proper size, configuration, and geometry of the hopper and waste container to reduce the necessity to resupply the hopper with combustible material during extended smoking processes. In addition, the waste container is designed to contain the ash from the complete smoking cycle, so that improved overall pellet management is achieved and consumer satisfaction is increased.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">This written description uses examples to disclose the invention, including the best mode, and also to enable any person skilled in the art to practice the invention, including making and using any devices or systems and performing any incorporated methods. The patentable scope of the invention is defined by the claims, and may include other examples that occur to those skilled in the art. Such other examples are intended to be within the scope of the claims if they include structural elements that do not differ from the literal language of the claims, or if they include equivalent structural elements with insubstantial differences from the literal languages of the claims.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. An indoor smoker defining a vertical direction, the indoor smoker comprising:
<claim-text>a cabinet defining a cabinet height measured along the vertical direction;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a smoking chamber positioned within the cabinet;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a hopper positioned within the cabinet and being configured to receive combustible material to facilitate a smoking process, the hopper defining a hopper volume;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a smoke generating assembly positioned below the hopper along the vertical direction and being configured to for receive the combustible material and generate a flow of smoke that is directed into the smoking chamber; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a waste container positioned below the smoke generating assembly and being configured to receive and extinguish the combustible material, the waste container defining a waste container volume, wherein a wherein a volume ratio is defined as the waste container volume to the hopper volume, and wherein the volume ratio is between about 2:1 and 6:1.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The indoor smoker of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the volume ratio of the waste container volume to the hopper volume is about 4:1.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The indoor smoker of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the hopper defines a hopper height and the waste container defines a waste container height, wherein a height ratio is defined as the waste container height to the hopper height, and wherein the height ratio is between about 0.8:1 and 1.2:1.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The indoor smoker of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the height ratio of the waste container height to the hopper height is about 1:1.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The indoor smoker of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein a width ratio is defined as a waste container height to a waste container width, and wherein the width ratio is between about 1:1 and 2:1.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The indoor smoker of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the width ratio of the waste container height to the waste container width is about 1.5:1.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The indoor smoker of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein a depth ratio is defined as a waste container depth to a waste container height, and wherein the depth ratio is between about 1.2:1 and 1.8:1.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The indoor smoker of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein a bottom wall of the hopper defines a hopper angle relative to a horizontal direction, wherein the hopper angle is between about 30 degrees and 60 degrees.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The indoor smoker of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the hopper angle is about 40 degrees.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The indoor smoker of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the waste container is fillable with water and defines a max fill line where a volume of the water plus an extinguished pellet volume associated with a full hopper is less than the waste container volume.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The indoor smoker of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>an air handler fluidly coupled to the smoking chamber for urging a flow of smoke through the smoking chamber; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a catalytic converter positioned inline with the flow of smoke for lowering volatile organic compounds from the flow of smoke.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. An indoor smoker defining a vertical direction, the indoor smoker comprising:
<claim-text>a cabinet defining a cabinet height measured along the vertical direction;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a smoking chamber positioned within the cabinet;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a hopper positioned within the cabinet and being configured to receive combustible material to facilitate a smoking process, the hopper defining a hopper height;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a smoke generating assembly positioned below the hopper along the vertical direction and being configured to for receive the combustible material and generate a flow of smoke that is directed into the smoking chamber; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a waste container positioned below the smoke generating assembly and being configured to receive and extinguish the combustible material, the waste container defining a waste container height, wherein a wherein a height ratio is defined as the waste container height to the hopper height, and wherein the height ratio is between about 0.8:1 and 1.2:1.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. The indoor smoker of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the height ratio of the waste container height to the hopper height is about 1:1.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The indoor smoker of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein a volume ratio is defined as a waste container volume to a hopper volume, and wherein the volume ratio is between about 2:1 and 6:1</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. The indoor smoker of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein the volume ratio of the waste container volume to the hopper volume is about 4:1.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. The indoor smoker of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein a width ratio is defined as a waste container height to a waste container width, and wherein the width ratio is between about 1:1 and 2:1.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. The indoor smoker of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the width ratio of the waste container height to the waste container width is about 1.5:1.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. The indoor smoker of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein a depth ratio is defined as a waste container depth to a waste container height, and wherein the depth ratio is between about 1.2:1 and 1.8:1.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. The indoor smoker of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein a bottom wall of the hopper defines a hopper angle relative to a horizontal direction, wherein the hopper angle is between about 30 degrees and 60 degrees.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. The indoor smoker of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein the hopper angle is about 40 degrees.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
