<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225404A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230711" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225404</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18007917</doc-number>
<date>20210603</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>GB</country>
<doc-number>2008359.8</doc-number>
<date>20200603</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>24</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>40</main-group>
<subgroup>42</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20200101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>24</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>40</main-group>
<subgroup>42</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="hvgpy80p3t325">A REFILL FOR AN INHALER PARTICULARLY A CANNABINOID INHALER</invention-title>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<orgname>OBG Consumer Reg Scientific Limited</orgname>
<address>
<city>Liverpool</city>
<country>GB</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>GB</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>YOUNG</last-name>
<first-name>Paul</first-name>
<address>
<city>Liverpool</city>
<country>GB</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/GB2021/051378</doc-number>
<date>20210603</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c12-date><date>20221202</date></us-371c12-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A refill for an inhaler, the refill including a cylinder with an axis and containing a pressurised inhalable composition. An outlet valve at one end has a hollow valve stem extending axially from the cylinder. A cap is fitted onto the cylinder at the outlet end and extends axially beyond the valve stem. The cap has an internal passage extending through the cap to allow access to the valve stem. The internal passage provides a guide wall to guide the inhaler onto the stem during the refill process.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="95.08mm" wi="128.86mm" file="US20230225404A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="216.15mm" wi="140.21mm" file="US20230225404A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="225.04mm" wi="151.47mm" file="US20230225404A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="221.83mm" wi="56.22mm" file="US20230225404A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="200.15mm" wi="60.37mm" file="US20230225404A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention relates to a refill for an inhaler, particularly a cannabinoid inhaler.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Cannabinoids have long been known for their therapeutic potential in pain relief, treatment of seizures, antiemesis et cetera. It is, however, a class of compounds whose usage has been associated with a great deal of debate owing to its psychoactive effects. It was not until the discovery of cannabinoid receptors (CB1 and CB2) and the isolation of individual cannabinoids such as THC (tetrahydrocannabinol), CBD (cannabidiol), CBN (Cannabinol), and THCV (Tetrahydrocannabivarin), that the psychoactive effects could be attributed primarily to compounds (like THC) with high affinities to the receptor CB1. Furthermore, it has been established that individual cannabinoids differ from one another in their affinities to receptors and certain cannabinoids, such as CBD, behave as CB1/CB2 antagonists, thereby blocking some actions of their agonists, such as THC.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">With on-going research, therapeutic applications of cannabinoids are becoming increasingly evident, resulting in legalisation of these compounds for medical purposes in a number of countries. The primary targets of research in this field are being associated with safe, rapid and/or effective delivery of cannabinoids.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">A number of ways of delivering cannabinoids are known in the art.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">For example, US2012/0304990 teaches the use of heating to vaporise a cannabis deposit. One drawback of this system is that there is only a small temperature differential between the temperature at which the cannabis will vaporise (180&#xb0; C. to 200&#xb0; C.) and the temperature at which toxins are produced (230&#xb0; C.).</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">A number of documents (for example WO03/055549, US6509005 and WO2004/000290) disclose the use of a metered dose inhaler. Such inhalers suffer from a number of drawbacks. Firstly, the metering chamber is relatively small, generally less than 100&#xb5;l resulting in delivery of fairly concentrated doses. Also, such devices require users to optimally co-ordinate actuation of the outlet valve and inhalation, failing which, dose delivery could be variable.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">A further common mechanism is the simple spray which is disclosed, for example, in WO02/064109 and US2006/135599 which are designed to provide a sublingual or buccal spray. Such a spray is currently being marketed by GW Pharmaceuticals under the Sativex (TM) brand. These sprays suffer from the possibility of non-uniform drug dose delivery owing to the flushing action of saliva. Further, they have a slower onset of action when compared with pulmonary delivery.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">A development of this idea was disclosed in WO2015/121673. This takes an inhaler which is based on a simulated cigarette and uses it to dispense cannabis.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The inhaler is based on a design of simulated cigarette which uses a pressurised reservoir and a breath operated valve. Suction on an inhaling end of the inhaler opens the breath operated valve such that the pressurised reservoir is able to dispense the formulation.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The inhaler is primarily designed as a simulated cigarette. Details of the breath operated valve are described in WO2009/001082, WO2010/073018, WO2011/015825, WO2011/015826, WO2014/033438, WO2014/033439, WO2014/155091 and WO2016/005728.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Additional details of the inhaler are provided in: WO2011/117580 and WO2014/155093</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Details of the manner in which the inhaler is tested and assembled are provided in WO2015/087045, WO2014/155095 and WO2016/046567.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The inhaler is designed to be refillable via a refill pack which is designed to have the shape and size of a cigarette pack. Details of the refill pack are provided in: WO2009/001078, WO2014/155092, WO2014/155090 and WO2014/155089</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">WO2015/121673 provides details of the composition required to dispense a cannabinoid based product from such an inhaler.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The above mentioned references provide a full description of the inhaler internal workings and the composition.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">A disclosure of an inhaler which has been modified in order to be suitable for dispensing a cannabinoid product is disclosed in WO 2019/073204. This takes the above described inhaler and encases it in an outer housing in order to create a larger inhaler which can more easily be handled by a user. The inhaler is packaged in a refill pack which fulfils a number of functions in that it houses a refill canister which is protected from dirt and damage during transportation and storage, and also provides guidance for the interface between the inhaler and the refill cannister during the refill operation. On the other hand, the refill housing is a relatively large plastic component which is disposable once the contents of the refill device are exhausted and which cannot easily be recycled.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The present invention addresses this concern while maintaining the key functionality of the refill housing of WO 2019/073204.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">According to the present invention, there is provided a refill for an inhaler according to claim 1.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Rather than providing a refill housing to fully enclose the refill and the inhaler, the present invention replaces this with a cap fitted onto the end of the refill cylinder. This uses a fraction of the material required for the housing in WO 2019/073204. The fact that the cap extends axially beyond the valve stem provides protection for the valve stem from damage and dirt during transportation and storage. The cap provides the possibility that a film can be applied, for example in the form of a sticker or a shrink fit across the cap in order to provide further protection and to provide a tamper evident feature.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Further, because the refill is a cylinder which is refilled by engagement with a cap on the top of the cylinder, the refill and inhaler are effectively refilled by pressing the two components together in a direction along the central axis of the refill. This provides a more robust refill arrangement as the user can grip the refill in one hand and the inhaler in the other hand and push them together in an end-to-end manner along the axis of the refill. This contrasts with WO 2009/073204 where the axis of the refill device is offset a significant distance from the centre of the refill housing making the refill operation more awkward, particularly for those with a limited dexterity in their hands.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The cap may be bonded to the cylinder. However, preferably, the cap is a snap fit onto the cylinder as this provides a simple and robust attachment. Further, preferably, a sticker surrounds both the cap and the cylinder to provide a more robust connection and to provide a tamper evident feature.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In WO 2019/073204, the refill end of the inhaler and the corresponding guide surface in the refill pack are circular so that the inhaler can be refilled in any angular orientation.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In the present case, the internal passage extending through the cap preferably has a non-circular cross-section. This allows the interface between the refill and the inhaler to be made larger than it is in WO 2019/073204. Further, the refill and inhaler cannot rotate relatively to one another when they are engaged during the refill process. Both of these features, coupled with the end-to-end axial arrangement set out above lead to a much more robust refilling process.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The internal passage preferably has an elongate generally oval shape. This fits well with the overall shape of the inhaler. The internal passage preferably has at least one inwardly protecting axially extending rib which can provide a location feature with a corresponding recess on the refill end of the inhaler. The internal passage may also be tapered to aid in the location of the inhaler in the internal passage.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The cross sectional area of the internal passage in a plane perpendicular to the axial direction is at least 30% and more preferably at least 40% of the cross sectional area of the cap in a plane perpendicular to the axial direction. This provides a large surface for the interface with the inhaler which provides for a robust refill and allows the inhaler to have a relatively large engaging end.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Preferably the valve stem is depressible axially to open the valve. This provides a robust refill operation.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The present invention may also extend to a combination of a refill according to a first aspect of the present invention and an inhaler, the inhaler having a housing with a refill end and an inhaling end, the inhaling end being dimensioned to fit within the internal passage in the refill, and the inhaling end being dimensioned so that it will not fit within the internal passage in the refill. This prevents the user from inadvertently trying to refill the inhaler in the incorrect orientation.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">An example of a refill container in accordance with the present invention, and an inhaler which can be used with the refill, will now be described with reference to the accompanying drawings, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a perspective view from one end of the inhaler from below;</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a perspective view from one end of the inhaler from above;</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a perspective view in the same orientation as <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> of an internal portion of the inhaler;</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is a cross-section through a medium plane at the inhaling end of the inhaler;</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is a perspective view from above of the refill;</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is a top view of the refill;</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> is perspective view from above of the cap; and</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> is a perspective view from below of the cap.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The internal workings of the inhaler device <b>1</b> are based on an inhaler core I shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> which is described in the PCT publications referred to above. This forms the inner core of the inhaler device. This is modified as described in WO2019/073204 to surround this inner core I with an outer housing <b>3</b> as described below.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">In general terms, the workings of the inhaler core I have not been modified and this will therefore not be described in great detail here.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">In broad terms, the inhaler core I comprises a reservoir <b>4</b> and a breath operated valve mechanism <b>5</b> which has a spring loaded member valve member <b>6</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>) which pinches a deformable tube <b>7</b> closed to close off access to the reservoir. The valve element <b>6</b> is biased closed by a spring <b>8</b>. A membrane <b>9</b> is in communication with an air flow path such that suction on the inhaling end <b>10</b> (opposite to refill end <b>14</b>) causes a change of pressure on the membrane which will lift the valve element <b>6</b> against the action of the spring <b>8</b>. Further details of this are given in the above references.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">One modification to the inhaler core I is illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>. The inhaler I is closed in the vicinity of the membrane <b>9</b> by a cap <b>15</b> which in the above mentioned references directly support the spring <b>8</b>. In the present case, however, a further component in the form of a bung <b>16</b> is inserted through an opening <b>17</b> in the cap and is sealed by an O ring <b>18</b>. This allows the cap <b>15</b> to be welded in place before the spring <b>8</b> is put in place and then retained by the bung <b>16</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">As is apparent, for example, from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> and <b>2</b></figref>, the outer housing <b>3</b> is made up of three separate portions, namely a mouthpiece casing <b>20</b>, a top casing <b>21</b> and a bottom casing <b>22</b> which are clipped together to form the outer housing. As can be seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>, an O-ring <b>23</b>  seals a flange <b>24</b> on the inhaler core to the mouthpiece casing <b>20</b>. This flange <b>24</b> represents a further modification of the inhaler I. A similar flange is present at the opposite end to the outer housing <b>3</b>. The mouthpiece casing <b>20</b> is also provided with a number of ribs <b>25</b> (only one of which is visible in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>) to prevent the bung <b>16</b> from being dislodged.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">As shown particularly in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> and <b>2</b></figref>, the outer housing <b>3</b> is provided with a number of ergonomic features to enhance the usability of the inhaler device <b>1</b> particularly for those with limited manual dexterity.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Thus, the outer housing <b>3</b> is provided with a significantly larger size than the inhaler core as can be seen, for example, from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> as well as <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> and <b>2</b></figref> in which the inhaler core I is visible at the inhaling <b>10</b> end. The inhaler is approximately 26 mm across in its widest position and is preferably approximately 20 mm deep at its widest position. This provides the relatively flat elongate configuration apparent from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> and <b>2</b></figref>. Recesses <b>30</b> are provided in the top and bottom surfaces of the outer housing <b>3</b>. This makes the inhaler device <b>1</b> easier to grip both during the inhaling process and as it is refilled. During inhaling, the user will grip the inhaler by placing their fingers on the top recess and their thumb against the bottom recess.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">All of the features described above are disclosed in WO 2019/073204. However, one significant difference in the inhaler is at the refill end <b>14</b>. At this end, the smooth generally flat nature of the outer housing <b>3</b> is preserved, rather than converging into a small circular refill end as in WO 2019/073204. At this end, at least one groove <b>31</b> extends axially from the refill end <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The refill will now be described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>5</b> to <b>8</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The refill comprises two components; namely a cylinder <b>40</b> and a cap <b>50</b>. The cylinder is a pressurised refill cylinder of the design which is well known in the art. The cylinder has an outlet valve at the top end and an outlet nozzle <b>41</b> via which the composition is dispensed when the outlet nozzle is depressed. The cylinder is a pressurised reservoir which is preferably pressurised by the composition comprising a propellant. The outlet valve may be a non-metered outlet valve, preferably of the type described in the above references related to the refill.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The cap <b>50</b> is provided with at least one lug <b>51</b> via which the cap is snap fitted onto a shoulder (not shown) at the top of the cylinder. The assembly of the cylinder <b>40</b> and cap <b>50</b> is then enclosed fully or partially by a sticker <b>60</b>, which further holds the two components together and can be printed with essential product information. The cap <b>50</b> cannot then be removed without first removing the sticker <b>60</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">As show in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>5</b> and <b>6</b></figref>, the cap <b>50</b> has internal passageway <b>51</b> extending fully through the cap such that it allows access to the valve stem <b>41</b> from above. The passageway <b>51</b> has a generally oval shape with a pair of inwardly extending ribs <b>52</b> which are complimentary to the grooves <b>31</b> on the inhaler.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">The lower end of the cap has a reduced diameter portion <b>53</b> defining a ridge <b>54</b> at its top end. When the cap <b>50</b> is on the cylinder <b>40</b>, the sticker <b>60</b> is applied to the cylinder <b>40</b> and the reduced diameter portion <b>53</b> abutting the ridge <b>54</b> to secure the two together and provide a smooth outer surface for the assembly as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">In order to refill the inhaler, the refill end <b>14</b> of the inhaler <b>1</b> is inserted into the cap <b>50</b>. The inhaling end <b>10</b> is shaped such that it cannot be inserted into the cap <b>50</b>. The inhaler <b>1</b> and refill have a narrow elongate configuration in the direction of engagement of the two components. The refill operation is therefore very stable. This is assisted by the fact that there is a large engagement area between two components caused by the relatively large size of the passage <b>51</b> and the fact that the two components cannot rotate with respect to one another. The exact manner by which the refill valve in the inhaler <b>1</b> interacts with the valve stem <b>41</b> is set out in the above references which provide details of the refill pack.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">While certain claims specify a cannabinoid inhaler and require an inhalable composition comprising a cannabinoid, all aspects of the invention can be used with any inhalable pharmaceutical composition.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A refill for an inhaler, the refill comprising a cylinder with an axis and containing a pressurised inhalable composition, and an outlet valve at one end, the outlet valve having a hollow valve stem extending axially from the cylinder; and a cap fitted onto the cylinder at the outlet end, the cap extending axially beyond the valve stem, the cap having an internal passage extending through the cap to allow access to the valve stem, the internal passage providing a guide wall to guide the inhaler, in use, onto the stem during the refill process.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. A refill according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the cap is a snap fit onto the cylinder.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. A refill according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein a film is applied across the top of the cap to cover the internal passage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. A refill according <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> further comprising a sticker surrounding both the cap and the cylinder.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. A refill according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the internal passage extending through the cap has a non-circular cross-section.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. A refill according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the internal passage preferably has an elongate shape.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. A refill according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the internal passage has at least one inwardly protecting axially extending rib to provide a location feature with a corresponding recess on the refill end of the inhaler.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. A refill according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the cross sectional area of the internal passage in a plane perpendicular to the axial direction is at least 30% of the cross sectional area of the cap in a plane perpendicular to the axial direction.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. A refill according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the cross sectional area of the internal passage in a plane perpendicular to the axial direction is at least 40% of the cross sectional area of the cap in a plane perpendicular to the axial direction.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. A refill according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the valve stem is depressible axially to open the valve.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. A refill according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> in combination with an inhaler, the inhaler having a housing with a refill end and an inhaling end, the inhaling end being dimensioned to fit within the internal passage in the refill, and the inhaling end being dimensioned so that it will not fit within the internal passage in the refill.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
