<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225587A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225587</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18155333</doc-number>
<date>20230117</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>10-2022-0006184</doc-number>
<date>20220114</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>005</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>00105</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>0057</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>00128</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>00154</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e61">DETACHABLE ENDOSCOPE</invention-title>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>TAEWOONG MEDICAL CO., LTD.</orgname>
<address>
<city>Gimpo-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>PARK</last-name>
<first-name>Sung Hwan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Seoul</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="01" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>JI</last-name>
<first-name>Hyun Soo</first-name>
<address>
<city>Seoul</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A detachable endoscope including: an insertion unit whose one end is to be inserted into a body; an operation unit coupled to another end of the insertion unit and operating the one end of the insertion unit to perform a bending motion using an operation module; and a detachment unit which detachably couples the operation unit and the insertion unit, and locks the insertion unit in a coupled state simultaneously when being coupled, so that the insertion unit is secured to the operation unit.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="121.58mm" wi="152.32mm" file="US20230225587A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="139.19mm" wi="154.35mm" file="US20230225587A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="157.06mm" wi="154.86mm" file="US20230225587A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="105.75mm" wi="160.61mm" file="US20230225587A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="181.61mm" wi="117.94mm" file="US20230225587A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="201.51mm" wi="164.51mm" file="US20230225587A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="200.24mm" wi="155.45mm" file="US20230225587A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="199.90mm" wi="159.94mm" file="US20230225587A1-20230720-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="193.04mm" wi="106.60mm" file="US20230225587A1-20230720-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="66.38mm" wi="85.34mm" file="US20230225587A1-20230720-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present application claims priority to Korean Patent Application No. 10-2022-0006184, filed Jan. 14, 2022, the entire contents of which is incorporated herein for all purposes by this reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">Field of the Invention</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates to a device, and more particularly to a detachable endoscope.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">Background Art</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">In general, a medical procedure using an endoscope is to insert an endoscope equipped with a camera and a medical procedure tool through a small hole without making a large incision in the body of a patient, and then proceed with the procedure while observing the affected part of the patient through the image taken by the endoscope in the body. In particular, the endoscopic procedure starting from laparoscopic surgery has advantages in that the incision region is smaller than that of laparotomy, so the scar region is also small, and there is little bleeding, which leads to the quick patient recovery after the procedure.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The conventional endoscopes are integrally constituted with an insertion part intended to be inserted into the human body and an operation part that operates the insertion part, and a plurality of channels and guides are embedded through the inside of each part. In particular, an image sensing device such as an expensive CCD is provided at the front end of the insertion part inserted into the body. Therefore, it is difficult to separate only the insertion part from the operation part and replace it with a new one. To overcome this problem, in line with the trend of strengthening the sanitary function of medical endoscopes, various types of detachable endoscopes are being used in which an insertion part intended to be inserted into the body and an operation part for operating the insertion part are connected to each other when being used, or separated from each other when being stored.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">However, in the conventional detachable endoscope having a structure in which the operation part and the insertion part are detachably coupled via the connection part, in order to separate the insertion part and the operation part from each other by releasing the engagement in the connection part after the endoscopic procedure, a pressing member such as a button must be provided in the connection part, and the engagement connection in the connection part must be released using this pressing member. Therefore, the structure of the connection part that detachably connects the operation part and the insertion part to each other becomes very complicated, and the manufacturing cost of the endoscope increases.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Further, the overall number of components provided in the connection part of the endoscope increases due to the engagement release button and accessory structures associated therewith additionally provided in the connection part. In the case of a mechanical malfunction of the engagement release button, the endoscope for a medical procedure cannot be used, while the cost required to maintain/repair the connection part increases.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">A technical problem to be addressed by the present disclosure is to provide a detachable endoscope that prevents internal contamination of the endoscope and allows easy replacement and cleaning of a part intended to be inserted into the human body by configuring the detachable endoscope such that the part can be secured simultaneously when being coupled.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Technical drawbacks, which the present disclosure is to address, are limited to the aforementioned ones, and unmentioned or other technical drawbacks may be clearly appreciated from the following detailed description by a person having ordinary skill in the art to which the present disclosure belongs.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In order to achieve the above technical objects, a detachable endoscope according to an embodiment of the present disclosure may include an insertion unit whose one end is to be inserted into a body; an operation unit coupled to another end of the insertion unit and operating the one end of the insertion unit to perform a bending motion using an operation module; and a detachment unit which detachably couples the operation unit and the insertion unit, and locks the insertion unit in a coupled state simultaneously when being coupled, so that the insertion unit is secured to the operation unit.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">According to an example of the present disclosure, the detachment unit may include a first detachment module disposed at one end of the operation unit and having an intermediate connection part to which a connection wire receiving a force from the operation module is connected; and a second detachment module disposed at the other end of the insertion unit, detachably coupled to the first detachment module, and having an insertion end connection part connected to an operation wire that transfers a force applied by the operation module to the one end of the insertion unit.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">According to an example of the present disclosure, the intermediate connection part may be provided with an intermediate connection body disposed rotatably around a longitudinal direction; an insertion groove formed concavely inward in a longitudinal direction at one end of the intermediate connection body and having a penetration part penetratingly formed in a direction perpendicular to the longitudinal direction; and a guide projection for guiding rotational motion of the intermediate connection body, and the insertion end connection part may be provided with an insertion end connection body extending in a longitudinal direction; and an engaging member protruding outward in a longitudinal direction from one end of the insertion end connection body.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">According to an example of the present disclosure, when the insertion unit and the operation unit are coupled, the engaging member may be inserted into the insertion groove, the engaging member being protrudingly formed in a length corresponding to the concave depth of the insertion groove.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">According to an example of the present disclosure, when the insertion unit and the operation unit are coupled, the insertion end connection part may press the intermediate connection part in a longitudinal direction in a state in which one end of an insertion end connection body is in contact with one end of the intermediate connection body.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">According to an example of the present disclosure, as the insertion end connection body rotates along the guide projection by the pressing of the intermediate connection part, the engaging member may be inserted into the penetration part to be in an engaged state.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">According to an example of the present disclosure, the intermediate connection part and the insertion end connection part may be arranged on a same line along a longitudinal direction to face each other, be coupled to each other, and operate integrally based on manipulation of the operation module.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In the detachable endoscope according to the embodiments of the present disclosure, the insertion unit intended to be inserted into the human body is configured to be detachable from the operation unit, so that the internal contamination of the endoscope can be prevented and parts can be easily replaced and cleaned. Additionally, in the course of coupling the insertion unit, one end of the insertion unit can be inserted into and pressed against one end of the operation unit, and at the same time, engaged, coupled, and locked therewith, without the use of a separate engaging or locking structure, thereby enabling simple and easy assembly and disassembly of the insertion unit.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The effects of the present disclosure are not limited to the aforementioned effects, but should be understood as including all effects that can be inferred from the configuration provided by the description or claims of the present application.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a perspective view showing a detachable endoscope according to an embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a perspective view illustrating a detachment unit which couples an insertion unit and an operation unit that are provided in a detachable endoscope according to an embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a perspective view showing a detachment unit provided in a detachable endoscope according to an embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is a perspective view showing a second detachment module included in a detachable endoscope according to an embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is a plan view showing a state before the insertion unit and the operation unit are coupled through the detachment unit according to an embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is a plan view showing a state in which the insertion unit and the operation unit are coupled through a detachment unit according to an embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>A</figref> is a perspective view showing a state before the intermediate connection part and the insertion end connection part provided in the detachable endoscope according to an embodiment of the present disclosure are coupled to each other. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>7</b>B and <b>7</b>C</figref> are perspective views showing states before the coupling of the intermediate connection part and the insertion end connection part is completed. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>D</figref> is a perspective view showing a state in which the intermediate connection part and the insertion end connection part are coupled.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b>A</figref> is a side view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>A</figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b>B</figref> is a side view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>B</figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b>C</figref> is a side view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>C</figref>, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b>D</figref> is a side view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>D</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Hereinafter, embodiments of the present disclosure will be described with reference to the accompanying drawings. However, the disclosure can be embodied in various different forms, and the scope of the disclosure should not be construed as being limited to the embodiments described herein. In the drawings, in order to describe clearly the disclosure, parts not related to the description are omitted, and like reference signs will be given to like constitutional elements throughout the specification.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">As used herein, &#x201c;connecting(or combining)&#x201d; a part with another part (or &#x201c;bring&#x201d; a part into contact or touch with another part) may refer to a case where they are &#x201c;indirectly connected&#x201d; to each other with other element intervening therebetween, as well as a case where they are &#x201c;directly connected&#x201d;. Further, when a part &#x201c;includes(or comprises)&#x201d; a component, it means not that the part excludes other component, but instead that the part may further include other component unless expressly stated to the contrary.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The terms used herein are used to merely describe specific embodiments, but are not intended to limit the disclosure. Singular expressions may include the meaning of plural expressions unless the context clearly indicates otherwise. The terms such as &#x201c;include (or comprise)&#x201d;, &#x201c;have (or be provided with)&#x201d;, and the like are intended to indicate that features, numbers, steps, operations, components, parts, or combinations thereof written in the following description exist, and thus should not be understood as that the possibility of existence or addition of one or more different features, numbers, steps, operations, components, parts, or combinations thereof is excluded in advance.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Hereinafter, embodiments of this disclosure will be described in detail with reference to the accompanying drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a perspective view showing a detachable endoscope according to an embodiment of the present disclosure. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a perspective view illustrating a detachment unit which couples an insertion unit and an operation unit that are provided in a detachable endoscope according to an embodiment of the present disclosure. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a perspective view showing a detachment unit provided in a detachable endoscope according to an embodiment of the present disclosure. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is a perspective view showing a second detachment module included in a detachable endoscope according to an embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> to <b>4</b></figref>, a detachable endoscope <b>10</b> may be a device for inspecting and performing medical procedures on organs inside a body. In this case, the detachable endoscope <b>10</b> may include an operation unit <b>100</b>, an insertion unit <b>200</b>, and a detachment unit <b>300</b>. Additionally, the detachable endoscope <b>10</b> may further include a joint unit <b>400</b>. The joint unit <b>400</b> is electrically connected to an endoscope control and management system (not shown), and hereinafter, the operation unit <b>100</b>, the insertion unit <b>200</b>, and the detachment unit <b>300</b> will be mainly described.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The operation unit <b>100</b> is a part that the user manipulates to control the operation of the insertion unit <b>200</b>, and may include an operation module H. In this case, the operation module H may include a lower operation part H<b>10</b> and an upper operation part H<b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">To one end (hereinafter, a first coupling end) of the operation unit <b>100</b>, the detachable insertion unit <b>200</b> can be selectively connected. In the state in which the insertion unit <b>200</b> is coupled, the user can rotate the lower operation part H<b>10</b> in left and right directions, so that the front end (hereinafter referred to as an insertion end) of the insertion unit <b>200</b> can be controlled to bend in up and down directions (direction A). Additionally, the user can control the insertion end of the insertion unit <b>200</b> to bend in left and right directions (direction B) by rotating the upper operation part H<b>20</b> in left and right directions.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The upper operation part H<b>20</b> may be provided with an upper sprocket (not shown), and an upper chain (not shown) meshed therewith, and the lower operation part H<b>10</b> may be provided with a lower sprocket (not shown) and a lower chain (not shown) meshed therewith. In this case, when the upper operation part H<b>20</b> and/or the lower operation part H<b>10</b> are/is selectively rotated by the user's manipulation, the upper sprocket and/or the lower sprocket rotate(s), and this rotational motion can be converted into reciprocating rectilinear motion by the upper chain and/or the lower chain meshed therewith.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Additionally, the upper chain and the lower chain may be connected to the inside of the insertion end of the insertion unit <b>200</b> via connection wires <b>101</b>, <b>102</b>, <b>103</b>, <b>104</b> and operation wires <b>201</b>, <b>202</b>, <b>203</b>, <b>204</b>, which will be described later. By the reciprocating rectilinear motion of the upper chain and/or the lower chain, the connection wires <b>101</b>, <b>102</b>, <b>103</b>, <b>104</b> and the operation wires <b>201</b>, <b>202</b>, <b>203</b>, <b>204</b> are selectively linearly moved, so that the insertion end of the insertion unit <b>200</b> connected to the operation wires <b>201</b>, <b>202</b>, <b>203</b>, <b>204</b> can bend in the up and down directions (direction A) or in the left and right directions (direction B). Meanwhile, the user can adjust the bending amount of the insertion end by appropriately changing the rotation angle of the lower operation part H<b>10</b> and/or the upper operation part H<b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Meanwhile, rotation of the upper sprocket and the lower sprocket may be made by the manual rotational manipulation of the user who holds the upper and lower operation parts H<b>20</b> and H<b>10</b> provided in the operation module H. However, the present disclosure is not limited to this, but each of the upper sprocket and the lower sprocket may also be constituted by connecting a rotational axle connected thereto with a driving means such as an electric motor, and using a separate remote control means for controlling the driving means.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">A part (i.e., the insertion end) of the insertion unit <b>200</b> may be inserted into the body during an endoscopic procedure. In this case, the insertion end of the insertion unit <b>200</b> may be an end among both ends of the insertion unit <b>200</b>, which is opposite to the end coupled to the operation unit <b>100</b> (hereinafter, referred to as a second coupling end). At the insertion end, an illuminating and photographing unit may be provided which has a light source for illuminating the inside of the body, and an image sensor for photographing the inside of the body.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The insertion end and its periphery of the insertion unit <b>200</b>, in one embodiment, may have a long and thin cylindrical shape with a hollow formed therein. At least this portion of the insertion unit <b>200</b> may be formed with a flexible material, so that the bending direction can be adjusted by the operation unit <b>100</b> as described above. In the insertion unit <b>200</b>, for example, a cover forming the outer surface of the insertion unit <b>200</b> may be formed with a flexible tube material such as a resin composition.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Meanwhile, the operation unit <b>100</b> may include a manipulation switch and a manipulation button for injecting or discharging liquid and gas used during an endoscopic procedure. A part (e.g., the second coupling end or its periphery) of the insertion unit <b>200</b> detachably coupled with the first coupling end of the operation unit <b>100</b> via the detachment unit <b>300</b> may be provided with an entrance through which a medical procedure tool such as an endoscopic procedure tool having a clip is protruded from or retracted into the insertion unit <b>200</b>, and with a cap for opening and closing the entrance.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">An air supply channel C<b>30</b> for supplying air, a water supply channel C<b>20</b> for supplying water, and a suction channel C<b>10</b> for sucking in water and air and discharging them to the outside may be provided on the cover provided at the first coupling end of the operation unit <b>100</b>. Additionally, the aforementioned cover may be provided with a terminal C<b>40</b> electrically connected to the illuminating and photographing unit provided at the insertion end of the insertion unit <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The detachment unit <b>300</b> may detachably connect the operation unit <b>100</b> and the insertion unit <b>200</b>. In this case, the detachment unit <b>300</b> may include a first detachment module <b>300</b><i>a </i>and a second detachment module <b>300</b><i>b </i>that are detachably coupled to each other, and by coupling or decoupling the first detachment module <b>300</b><i>a </i>and the second detachment module <b>300</b><i>b</i>, the operation unit <b>100</b> and the insertion unit <b>200</b> may be connected or separated.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The first detachment module <b>300</b><i>a </i>may be disposed to be inserted into the operation unit <b>100</b>, and may include a first module body <b>310</b> and an intermediate connection part. At this time, the intermediate connection part may include two pairs of intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b>, and connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b> provided on the intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b>, respectively. Meanwhile, hereinafter, the intermediate connection part will be denoted by reference numeral <b>320</b>, although this reference numeral is not shown in the drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The first module body <b>310</b> may be a housing in which a middle hollow is formed penetrating both ends along the longitudinal direction (Y axis direction). Covers covering the middle hollow may be coupled to both ends of the first module body <b>310</b>. In this case, the cover may be arranged on the same line with the middle hollow of the intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b> along the longitudinal direction (Y axis direction), and may have the through-holes <b>111</b>, <b>112</b>, <b>113</b>, <b>114</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>) formed for connection communicating with the middle hollow.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The intermediate connection part <b>320</b> may connect the operation module H and the insertion end connection part <b>340</b> to be described later via the connection wires <b>101</b>, <b>102</b>, <b>103</b>, and <b>104</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b> may have various shapes. For example, the intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b> may be bars having an elongated cylindrical shape. The intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b> may be inserted penetrating the middle hollow of the first module body <b>310</b>. In this case, the intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b> are inserted through the through-holes <b>111</b>, <b>112</b>, <b>113</b>, <b>114</b> for connection of the first module body <b>310</b> and the covers coupled to both ends thereof, and accordingly, both ends of the intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b> may be disposed at least partially outside the first module body <b>310</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, and <b>334</b> of the insertion end connection parts <b>340</b> may be detachably connected to the connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b>. The connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b> may be disposed at one ends of the intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b>, and these one ends of the intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b> may be ends among opposite ends of the intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b>, which face the insertion unit <b>200</b>. In this case, one ends of the connection wires <b>101</b>, <b>102</b>, <b>103</b>, and <b>104</b> may be connected to the other ends of the intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, <b>314</b>, and the other ends of the connection wires <b>101</b>, <b>102</b>, <b>103</b>, and <b>104</b> may be connected to upper chains or lower chains provided in the operation module H.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">In this case, as the user manipulates the operation module H, the rotational motion of the upper sprockets or the lower sprockets can be converted into reciprocating rectilinear motion by the upper chains or the lower chains, and subsequently, the connection wires <b>101</b>, <b>102</b>, <b>103</b>, and <b>104</b> connected to the upper chains or the lower chains may perform reciprocating rectilinear motion. Accordingly, the intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b> connected to the connection wires <b>101</b>, <b>102</b>, <b>103</b>, and <b>104</b>, and their connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b> may perform reciprocating rectilinear motion along a direction parallel to the longitudinal direction (Y axis direction).</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">The connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b> may be formed with a larger diameter than the outer diameter of the intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b>. At this time, between the connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b> and the connection wires <b>101</b>, <b>102</b>, <b>103</b>, and <b>104</b>, elastic members which the intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b> are inserted penetrating can be disposed. When the intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b> are pressed by the insertion end connection part <b>340</b> during the coupling process, the elastic members are compressed and deformed, and can generate an elastic restoring force for returning the intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b> to their original positions. The elastic member may be constituted with, for example, a coil spring.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">The connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b> may be provided with insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, and <b>324</b> into which the engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, and <b>334</b> are inserted when the insertion unit <b>200</b> and the operation unit <b>100</b> are coupled to each other, and guide projections T for guiding rotation of the intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, and <b>324</b> may be formed concavely in the longitudinal direction (e.g., &#x2212;Y axis direction) inward from the connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b>. The insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, and <b>324</b> may be provided with penetration parts N formed to penetrate through the connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b> in a direction (e.g., X axis direction) perpendicular to the longitudinal direction (Y axis direction). The insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, and <b>324</b> may be partially communicated with the outside through the penetration parts N. Additionally, the engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, and <b>334</b> can be in an engaged state and secured in the insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, and <b>324</b> by the penetration parts N.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The guide projections T<b>1</b>, T<b>2</b>, T<b>3</b>, and T<b>4</b> can guide the rotational motion of the intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b>. The guide projections T<b>1</b>, T<b>2</b>, T<b>3</b>, and T<b>4</b> may be formed to protrude toward the outside in the radial direction from the connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b> of the intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">When the insertion unit <b>200</b> and the operation unit <b>100</b> are coupled, and when the insertion end connection part <b>340</b> presses the connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b> in the &#x2018;pressing direction (&#x2212;Y axis direction)&#x2019; parallel to the longitudinal direction, the guide projections T<b>1</b>, T<b>2</b>, T<b>3</b>, and T<b>4</b> can move along guide slits G<b>1</b>, G<b>2</b>, G<b>3</b>, and G<b>4</b> formed in the first module body <b>310</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">The guide slits G<b>1</b>, G<b>2</b>, G<b>3</b>, and G<b>4</b> may include a &#x2018;curved line part&#x2019; that is curved and extended from one side of the first module body <b>310</b> to the other side thereof, and a &#x2018;straight line part&#x2019; connected to this curved line part and extending backward (&#x2212;Y axis direction) parallel to the longitudinal direction of the first module body <b>310</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">In this case, when the connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b> are pressed by the insertion end connection part <b>340</b>, the guide projections T<b>1</b>, T<b>2</b>, T<b>3</b>, and T<b>4</b> can be first rotated along the curved line part to guide the rotational motion of the intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b>. Then, when the connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b> are further pressed by the insertion end connection part <b>340</b>, the guide projections T<b>1</b>, T<b>2</b>, T<b>3</b>, and T<b>4</b> linearly can move along the straight line part to guide the intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b> to move along the pressing direction (&#x2212;Y axis direction).</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Meanwhile, the intermediate connection part <b>320</b> may include two pairs of intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b>, and for the convenience of description, the two pairs of intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b> and <b>314</b> will be referred to as the first intermediate connection body <b>311</b>, the second intermediate connection body <b>312</b>, the third intermediate connection body <b>313</b>, and the fourth intermediate connection body <b>314</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">In this case, two pairs of middle hollows penetrating both ends may be formed in the first module body <b>310</b> along the longitudinal direction (Y axis direction). The first, second, third, and fourth intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b> may be respectively inserted penetrating the two pairs of middle hollows.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">The first, second, third, and fourth intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b> may be arranged symmetrically with each other, within the first module body <b>310</b>, in the width direction (X axis direction) and/or in the height direction (Z axis direction).</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">Specifically, the first intermediate connection body <b>311</b> may be arranged symmetrically with the second intermediate connection body <b>312</b> in the width direction (X axis direction). At this time, the first intermediate connection body <b>311</b> may be arranged symmetrically with the third intermediate connection body <b>313</b> in the height direction (Z axis direction), and the third intermediate connection body <b>313</b> may be arranged symmetrically with the fourth intermediate connection body <b>314</b> in the width direction (X axis direction). Accordingly, the first intermediate connection body <b>311</b> and the second intermediate connection body <b>312</b> can be arranged side by side in a pair on the upper side inside the first module body <b>310</b>, and the third intermediate connection body <b>313</b> and the fourth intermediate connection body <b>314</b> can be arranged side by side in a pair on the lower side inside the first module body <b>310</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">Respective connection ends of the first, second, third, and fourth intermediate connection bodies <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, and <b>324</b>, that is, the first connection end E<b>1</b>, the second connection end E<b>2</b>, the third connection end E<b>3</b>, and the fourth connection end E<b>4</b> are inserted to penetrate the through-holes <b>111</b>, <b>112</b>, <b>113</b>, and <b>114</b> for connection provided in the cover, respectively, so that they can protrude outward toward the insertion unit <b>200</b> from the first module body <b>310</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">Additionally, the first connection wire <b>101</b>, the second connection wire <b>102</b>, the third connection wire <b>103</b>, or the fourth connection wire <b>104</b> may be connected to the other ends of the first, second, third, and fourth intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b>, respectively, opposite to the connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b>. In this case, each of the intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b> may be inserted penetrating the inside of the elastic member in the form of a coil spring.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">The second detachment module <b>300</b><i>b </i>may be arranged to be inserted into the insertion unit <b>200</b>, and may include a second module body <b>330</b> and an insertion end connecting part. At this time, the insertion end connection part may include the two pairs of insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b>, and the engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, <b>334</b> provided at the insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, <b>344</b>, respectively. Meanwhile, hereinafter, the insertion end connection part will be denoted by reference numeral <b>340</b>, although this reference numeral is not shown in the drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">The second module body <b>330</b> may be a housing having an insertion end hollow which penetrates both ends thereof along the longitudinal direction (Y axis direction).</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">The insertion end connection part <b>340</b> can transfer the force applied by the user's manipulation of the operation module H to the insertion end via the operation wires <b>201</b>, <b>202</b>, <b>203</b>, and <b>204</b>, so that the insertion end can bend.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">The insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b> may have a variety of shapes. For example, the insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b> may be bars having an elongate cylindrical shape. The insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b> may be inserted penetrating the insertion end hollow of the second module body <b>330</b>. At this time, both ends of the insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b> may be disposed at least partially outside the second module body <b>330</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">Each of the insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b> may have a rack gear part L<b>11</b>, L<b>12</b>, L<b>13</b>, or L<b>14</b> on its one surface. Each of the rack gear parts L<b>11</b>, L<b>12</b>, L<b>13</b>, and L<b>14</b> may be disposed on the surface among the surfaces of each of the insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b>, which faces the center of the second module body <b>330</b>, and the insertion end connection body <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b> may extend in the longitudinal direction (Y axis direction).</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">The engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, and <b>334</b> may be inserted into the aforementioned insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, and <b>324</b> of the connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b>, and may be detachably coupled thereto.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">The engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, and <b>334</b> may be disposed at one ends of the insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b>, and the one ends of the insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b> may be ends facing the operation unit <b>100</b>. In this case, one ends of the operation wires <b>201</b>, <b>202</b>, <b>203</b>, and <b>204</b> may be connected to the other ends of the insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b>, and the other ends of the operation wires <b>201</b>, <b>202</b>, <b>203</b>, and <b>204</b> may be connected to the inside of the insertion ends.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">Meanwhile, the insertion end connection parts <b>340</b> may include two pairs of insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b>. For the convenience of description, the two pairs of insertion end connection bodies will be referred to as the first insertion end connection body <b>341</b>, the second insertion end connection body <b>342</b>, the third insertion end connection body <b>343</b>, and the fourth insertion end connection body <b>344</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">In this case, the second module body <b>330</b> may be formed so as to have two pairs of insertion end hollows penetrating both ends along its longitudinal direction (Y axis direction). The first, second, third, and fourth insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b> may be respectively arranged to be inserted penetrating the two pairs of insertion end hollows.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">The first, second, third, and fourth insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b> may be arranged symmetrically with each other in the width direction (X axis direction) and/or the height direction (Z axis direction) in the second module body <b>330</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">Specifically, the first insertion end connection body <b>341</b> may be arranged symmetrically with the second insertion end connection body <b>342</b> in the width direction (X axis direction). Accordingly, the first rack gear part L<b>11</b> of the first insertion end connection body <b>341</b> and the second rack gear part L<b>12</b> of the second insertion end connection body <b>342</b> may be arranged to face each other. Additionally, the first insertion end connection body <b>341</b> may be arranged symmetrically with the third insertion end connection body <b>343</b> in the height direction (Z axis direction), and the third insertion end connection body <b>343</b> may be arranged symmetrically with the fourth insertion end connection body <b>344</b> in the width direction (X axis direction). Accordingly, the third rack gear part L<b>13</b> of the third insertion end connection body <b>343</b> and the fourth rack gear part L<b>14</b> of the fourth insertion end connection body <b>344</b> may be arranged to face each other. Accordingly, the first insertion end connection body <b>341</b> and the second insertion end connection body <b>342</b> can be arranged side by side in a pair on the upper side inside the second module body <b>330</b>, and the third insertion end connection body <b>343</b> and the fourth insertion end connection body <b>344</b> can be arranged side by side in a pair on the lower side inside the second module body <b>330</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">In the above-described case, the second module body <b>330</b> may be provided with a pinion gear part P which rotates around a rotational axle extending through and between the first insertion end connection body <b>341</b> and the second insertion end connection body <b>342</b>, and between the third insertion end connection body <b>343</b> and the fourth insertion end connection body <b>344</b>. In this case, the pinion gear part P may include a first pinion gear P<b>10</b> and a second pinion gear P<b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">The first pinion gear P<b>10</b> may be disposed between the first insertion end connection body <b>341</b> and the second insertion end connection body <b>342</b>, so that it can be meshed with the first rack gear part L<b>11</b> and the second rack gear part L<b>12</b> at the same time. In this meshed state, the first pinion gear P<b>10</b> may rotate around the first central axle part perpendicular to the longitudinal direction (Y axis direction) according to the user's manipulation of the operation module H.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">The second pinion gear P<b>20</b> may be disposed between the third insertion end connection body <b>343</b> and the fourth insertion end connection body <b>344</b>, so that it can be meshed with the third rack gear part L<b>13</b> and the fourth rack gear part L<b>14</b> at the same time. In this meshed state, the second pinion gear P<b>20</b> may rotate around the second central axle part perpendicular to the longitudinal direction (Y axis direction) according to the user's manipulation of the operation module H.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">The second central axle part may be disposed on the same line as the first central axle part, but may be configured to be separated from each other and independently rotatable. Accordingly, while the first pinion gear P<b>10</b> and the second pinion gear P<b>20</b> rotate around the first central axle part or the second central axle part, they can avoid interfering (or hindering) each other's rotational movements.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">The second module body <b>330</b> may have &#x2018;straight line guide slits G&#x2019; extending in the longitudinal direction (Y axis direction) on its upper and lower surfaces. The straight line guide slits G may be provided in a pair on the upper surface of the second module body <b>330</b> to face the first insertion end connection body <b>341</b> and the second insertion end connection body <b>342</b>, respectively, and may also be provided in a pair on the lower surface of the second module body <b>330</b> to face the third insertion end connection body <b>343</b> and the fourth insertion end connection body <b>344</b>, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">In this case, the first insertion end connection body <b>341</b> and the second insertion end connection body <b>342</b> may each be provided with &#x2018;guide protruding members r extending upward and inserted into the straight line guide slits G facing each other. And, the third insertion end connection body <b>343</b> and the fourth insertion end connection body <b>344</b> may each be provided with guide protruding members I extending downward and inserted into the straight line guide slits G facing each other. In this case, the guide protruding member I moves along the linear guide slit G, so that it can guide the reciprocating rectilinear motion of each connected insertion end connection body.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">At one end of each of the first, second, third, and fourth insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b>, the first engaging member <b>331</b>, the second engaging member <b>332</b>, the third engaging member <b>333</b>, or the fourth engaging member <b>334</b> may be provided. And, to the other end of each of the first, second, third, and fourth insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b>, the first operation wire <b>201</b>, the second operation wire <b>202</b>, the third operation wire <b>203</b>, or the fourth operation wire <b>204</b> may be connected.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is a plan view showing a state before the insertion unit and the operation unit are coupled through the detachment unit according to an embodiment of the present disclosure. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is a plan view showing a state in which the insertion unit and the operation unit are coupled through a detachment unit according to an embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>5</b> and <b>6</b></figref>, a method of arranging and combining the operation unit <b>100</b> and the insertion unit <b>200</b> may be as follows.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">First, the first coupling end of the operation unit <b>100</b> and the second coupling end of the insertion unit <b>200</b> may be disposed to face each other. As an example, before coupling, the first coupling end of the operation unit <b>100</b> may be in a &#x2018;parallel-aligned state&#x2019; with the second coupling end of the insertion unit <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">Here, when viewing the detachable endoscope <b>10</b> from above based on the Z axis of the drawing, the &#x2018;parallel-aligned state&#x2019; may mean a state in which the virtual first reference line M<b>1</b> connecting the first connection end E<b>1</b> and the second connection end E<b>2</b> [and connecting the third connection end E<b>3</b> and the fourth connection end E<b>4</b>] provided in the operation unit <b>100</b> is parallel to the virtual second reference line M<b>2</b> connecting one end of the first insertion end connection body <b>341</b> and one end of the second insertion end connection body <b>342</b> [and connecting one end of the third insertion end connection body <b>343</b> and one end of the fourth insertion end connection body <b>344</b>] provided in the insertion unit <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">Next, the operation unit <b>100</b> and the insertion unit <b>200</b> can be moved in a direction parallel to the longitudinal direction (Y axis direction) and approaching each other (hereinafter, referred to as a coupling direction). In this case, since the insertion unit <b>200</b> and the operation unit <b>100</b> are in a &#x2018;parallel-aligned state&#x2019;, the first engaging member <b>331</b> and the second engaging member <b>332</b> of the insertion unit <b>200</b> may be inserted into the first insertion groove <b>321</b> of the first connection end E<b>1</b> and the second insertion groove <b>322</b> of the second connection end E<b>2</b>, respectively, while at the same time maintaining a parallel state to each other. In addition, the third engaging member <b>333</b> and the fourth engaging member <b>334</b> of the insertion unit <b>200</b> may also be inserted into the third insertion groove <b>323</b> of the third connection end E<b>3</b> and the fourth insertion groove <b>324</b> of the fourth connection end E<b>4</b>, respectively, while at the same time maintaining a state parallel to each other, and to the first engaging member <b>331</b> and the second engaging member <b>332</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">In this case, as the operation unit <b>100</b> and the insertion unit <b>200</b> move in the coupling direction (Y axis direction), the engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, and <b>334</b> can be completely inserted into the insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, and <b>324</b>, and ends of the insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b> can contact the connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b> facing them. Accordingly, the first connection end E<b>1</b> and the second connection end E<b>2</b> [and the third connection end E<b>3</b> and the fourth connection end E<b>4</b>] may be arranged to pass a virtual third reference line M<b>3</b> together with one end of the first insertion end connection body <b>341</b> and one end of the second insertion end connection body <b>342</b> [and one end of the third insertion end connection body <b>343</b> and one end of the fourth insertion end connection body <b>344</b>].</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">Next, when the intermediate connection part <b>320</b> moves backward (in the &#x2212;Y axis direction) by the user's manipulation of the operation module H, the connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b> and the intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b> may move backward (&#x2212;Y axis direction) while rotating by the guide projections T<b>1</b>, T<b>2</b>, T<b>3</b>, and T<b>4</b> and the guide slits G<b>1</b>, G<b>2</b>, G<b>3</b>, and G<b>4</b>. With this, the engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, and <b>334</b> may be secured to one ends of the insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, and <b>324</b> in the engaged state, so that the insertion unit <b>200</b> and the operation unit <b>100</b> can be coupled with each other. In this regard, the specific combination method will be described in detail below.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">Meanwhile, as another embodiment, the first coupling end may be in &#x2018;a misaligned state&#x2019; with the second coupling end before the coupling. Here, the &#x2018;misaligned state&#x2019; may refer to a state in which, when the detachable endoscope <b>10</b> is viewed from above, one end of the first insertion end connection body <b>341</b> and one end of the second insertion end connection body <b>342</b> protrude at different distances, so that the first reference line M<b>1</b> and the second reference line M<b>2</b> are not parallel to each other and are inclined at a predetermined angle.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">This &#x2018;misaligned state&#x2019; may be a state in which some of the insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b> may protrude further toward the operation unit <b>100</b> than the rest of the insertion end connection bodies. For example, it may be a state in which one end of the first insertion end connection body <b>341</b> protrudes further toward the operation unit <b>100</b> than one end of the second insertion end connection body <b>342</b>, and the other insertion end connection bodies <b>343</b> and <b>344</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">Next, the operation unit <b>100</b> and the insertion unit <b>200</b> may be moved to approach each other in a direction parallel to the longitudinal direction (Y axis direction) (hereinafter, referred to as a coupling direction). At this time, since the insertion unit <b>200</b> and the operation unit <b>100</b> are in &#x2018;the misaligned state&#x2019;, the first engaging member <b>331</b> of the insertion unit <b>200</b> can begin to be inserted into the first insertion groove <b>321</b> of the first connection end E<b>1</b> earlier before the second engaging member <b>332</b> as well as the other engaging members <b>333</b> and <b>334</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">In this case, as the operation unit <b>100</b> and the insertion unit <b>200</b> move along the coupling direction, the first locking member <b>331</b> can be first fully inserted into the first insertion groove <b>321</b>, so that the one end of the first insertion end connection body <b>341</b> can come into contact with the first connection end E<b>1</b> facing the first insertion end connection body <b>341</b>. At this time, the second insertion end connection body <b>342</b> and the other insertion end connection bodies <b>343</b> and <b>344</b> may be in a non-contact state with the connection ends E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b> facing them, or in a state in which only a portion of the engaging member is inserted into the insertion groove.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">Next, the operation unit <b>100</b> and the insertion unit <b>200</b> move further in the coupling direction (Y axis direction), and the first intermediate connection part <b>320</b> in contact with the first insertion end connection body <b>341</b> is pressed, so that it can be moved backward (&#x2212;Y axis direction).</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">In this case, the other insertion end connection bodies <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b> may sequentially contact the connection ends E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b> facing them, respectively, based on the distances protruding toward the operation unit <b>100</b>. At the same time, as the respective connection ends are pressed, the elastic members provided in the intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b> can be compressed and deformed at the same time or at the different times, and the intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b> can be moved in the coupling direction (Y axis direction), respectively. Accordingly, all the elastic members can be pressed until they reach the &#x2018;same compression deformation state&#x2019;. Here, the same compression deformation state may refer to a state in which the elastic members have the same or similar compressed length and shape after their deformation.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">When all the elastic members are in the same compression deformation state, all the insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b> may come into contact with the facing connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b>, respectively. In this case, the first connection end E<b>1</b> and the second connection end E<b>2</b> [and the third connection end E<b>3</b> and the fourth connection end E<b>4</b>] are arranged to pass the virtual third reference line M<b>3</b> together with one end of the first insertion end connection body <b>341</b> and one end of the second insertion end connection body <b>342</b> [and one end of the third insertion end connection body <b>343</b> and one end of the fourth insertion end connection body <b>344</b>], and thus, the first coupling end of the operation unit <b>100</b> and the second coupling end of the insertion unit <b>200</b> can be in a &#x2018;parallel-aligned state&#x2019; as described above.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">Then, the operation unit <b>100</b> and the insertion unit <b>200</b> move further in the coupling direction, so that they can press the connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b> backward (i.e., &#x2212;Y axis direction) while maintaining contact with the insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b>. Accordingly, the intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b> connected to the connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b> are rotated by the guide projections T<b>1</b>, T<b>2</b>, T<b>3</b>, and T<b>4</b> and the guide slits G<b>1</b>, G<b>2</b>, G<b>3</b>, and G<b>4</b>, so that the engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, and <b>334</b> can be inserted into the insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, and <b>324</b>, and secured by being engaged with one ends of the insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, and <b>324</b>. Accordingly, the insertion unit <b>200</b> may be coupled to the operation unit <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>A</figref> is a perspective view showing a state before the intermediate connection part and the insertion end connection part provided in the detachable endoscope according to an embodiment of the present disclosure are coupled to each other. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>7</b>B and <b>7</b>C</figref> are perspective views showing states before the coupling of the intermediate connection part and the insertion end connection part is completed. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>D</figref> is a perspective view showing a state in which the intermediate connection part and the insertion end connection part are coupled.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>7</b>A to <b>7</b>D</figref>, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>8</b>A to <b>8</b>D</figref>, a method of coupling the insertion end connection part <b>340</b> to the intermediate connection part <b>320</b> may be as follows.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">First, as described above, before the coupling, the operation unit <b>100</b> and the insertion unit <b>200</b> are arranged to face each other, so that the intermediate connection part <b>320</b> and the insertion end connection part <b>340</b> may be arranged to face each other. At this time, in a state where the connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b> face the engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, and <b>334</b> each other, the intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b> may be arranged on the same line as the insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b> in the longitudinal direction (Y axis direction) (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>7</b>A and <b>8</b>A</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">Next, the operation unit <b>100</b> and the insertion unit <b>200</b> may be moved so as to come closer along the coupling direction. In this case, the engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, and <b>334</b> can be inserted into the insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, and <b>324</b> provided at the connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0098">At this time, the engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, and <b>334</b> may be provided with an &#x2018;engaging projection&#x2019; protrudingly formed toward the outer side of the radial direction of the engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, and <b>334</b> at their front ends. When the engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, and <b>334</b> are inserted into the insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, and <b>324</b>, the engaging projections may be accommodated in the insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, and <b>324</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>7</b>B and <b>8</b>B</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0099">Next, as the insertion unit <b>200</b> moves further along the coupling direction (Y axis direction), the front ends of the insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b> may come into contact with the connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0100">In this regard, the protruding distance r<b>1</b> of the engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, and <b>334</b> may be formed to be similar to (preferably, shorter in length than) the depth r<b>2</b> of the insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, and <b>324</b>. Accordingly, when the front ends of the insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b> come into contact with the connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b>, the front ends of the engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, and <b>334</b> can be in a non-contact state (i.e., a predetermined gap exists) with the inside of the insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, and <b>324</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0101">Next, the user may operate a locking part <b>200</b><i>a </i>provided at the second coupling end of the insertion unit <b>200</b> to couple and fix the insertion unit <b>200</b> to the operation unit <b>100</b>. As an example, the locking part <b>200</b><i>a </i>may be rotatably installed at the second coupling end, and the first coupling end of the operation unit <b>100</b> may be inserted into this locking unit <b>200</b><i>a</i>. In this case, as the user rotates the locking part <b>200</b><i>a </i>in one direction, the locking part <b>200</b><i>a </i>and the first coupling end may be coupled in a screw connection method and secured together.</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0102">In this regard, when the locking part <b>200</b><i>a </i>is rotated, the insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b> are further moved in the coupling direction (&#x2212;Y axis direction) in a state of being in contact with the connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b>, so that they can press the connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b> and the intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b> backward (&#x2212;Y axis direction). With this, the guide projections T<b>1</b>, T<b>2</b>, T<b>3</b>, and T<b>4</b> move backward (&#x2212;Y axis direction) while rotating along the &#x2018;curved line parts&#x2019; of the guide slits G<b>1</b>, G<b>2</b>, G<b>3</b>, and G<b>4</b>, and as a result, the connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b> and the intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b> can be rotated around the longitudinal direction (Y axis direction).</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0103">By this rotation, in a state where the engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, and <b>334</b> are accommodated in the insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, and <b>324</b>, the engaging projections protrude to the outside of the insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, and <b>324</b> through the penetration part N to be in a non-separable state (primary coupling state) (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>C</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0104">Next, in the primary coupling state, by the user's manipulation of the operation module H, the intermediate connection part <b>320</b> can be pulled backward (&#x2212;Y axis direction). In this case, the guide projections T<b>1</b>, T<b>2</b>, T<b>3</b>, and T<b>4</b> pass through the &#x2018;curved line parts&#x2019; of the guide slits G<b>1</b>, G<b>2</b>, G<b>3</b>, and G<b>4</b> and move backward (in the &#x2212;Y axis direction) along the &#x2018;straight line parts,&#x2019; and accordingly, the engaging projections of the engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, and <b>334</b> protruding outward through the penetration part N can be in the engaged state at the inner ends of the insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, and <b>324</b>. As a result, the intermediate connection part <b>320</b> and the insertion end connection part <b>340</b> may be coupled to become a non-separable state (secondary coupling state)(see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>D</figref>). Thereafter, in the &#x2018;secondary coupling state&#x2019;, by the user's manipulation of the operation module H, the intermediate connection part <b>320</b> and the insertion end connection part <b>340</b> can perform reciprocating rectilinear motion and operate integrally.</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0105">Meanwhile, when removal or replacement of the insertion unit <b>200</b> is required, the insertion unit <b>200</b> may be separated from the operation unit <b>100</b> by a process as follows.</p>
<p id="p-0107" num="0106">First, reference points (not shown) provided respectively on the first operation part H<b>10</b> and the second operation part H<b>20</b> may be aligned in a line. In this way, when the first and second operation parts H<b>10</b> and H<b>20</b> are aligned along the reference points, the operation unit <b>100</b> and the insertion unit <b>200</b> may again be in a &#x2018;parallel-aligned state&#x2019; as described above.</p>
<p id="p-0108" num="0107">Next, the locking state may be released by rotating the locking part <b>200</b><i>a </i>of the insertion unit <b>200</b> in a direction opposite to the locking direction. After the unlocking of the locking part <b>200</b><i>a </i>is completed, the user may separate the insertion unit <b>200</b> by moving it away from the operation unit <b>100</b> in a direction opposite to the coupling direction (Y axis direction). Thereafter, the replacement of the insertion unit <b>200</b> may be completed by coupling another insertion unit as a replacement to the operation unit <b>100</b> through the same or similar method as described above.</p>
<p id="p-0109" num="0108">Regarding the operation method of the detachable endoscope <b>10</b> as described above, when the insertion unit <b>200</b> and the operation unit <b>100</b> are assembled in the &#x2018;second coupled state&#x2019;, by the user's manipulation of the first operation part H<b>10</b> or the second operation part H<b>20</b>, the intermediate connection part <b>320</b> performs reciprocating rectilinear motion through the lower sprocket and the upper sprocket, and the lower chain and upper chain respectively connected thereto, and at this time, the insertion end connection part <b>340</b> can perform reciprocating rectilinear motion integrally with the intermediate connection part <b>320</b> while being coupled with it through the engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, and <b>334</b> and the insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, and <b>324</b>, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0110" num="0109">In this case, the first detachment module <b>300</b><i>a </i>may be connected to the operation module H through the lower sprocket and the upper sprocket rotated in forward/backward directions by the first and second operation parts H<b>10</b> and H<b>20</b>, the lower chain and the upper chain connected thereto to be wound around them, and the first, second, third and fourth connection wires <b>101</b>, <b>102</b>, <b>103</b> and <b>104</b> connected to both ends of the chains.</p>
<p id="p-0111" num="0110">The first and second connection wires <b>101</b> and <b>102</b> connected to both ends of the upper chain connected to the upper sprocket operate in linkage with the first and second operation wires <b>201</b> and <b>202</b> disposed side by side in a pair on the upper side of the inside of the insertion unit <b>200</b> based on the drawing, so that the first and second connection wires can bend the insertion end of the insertion unit <b>200</b> in the left and right directions (direction B).</p>
<p id="p-0112" num="0111">Contrarily, the third and fourth connection wires <b>103</b> and <b>104</b> connected to both ends of the lower chain connected to the lower sprocket to be wound around it operate in linkage with the third and fourth operation wires <b>203</b> and <b>204</b> disposed side by side in a pair on the lower side of the inside of the insertion unit <b>200</b> based on the drawing, so that the third and fourth connection wires can bend the insertion end of the insertion unit <b>200</b> in the up and down directions (direction A). However, the present disclosure is not limited to this, and bending manipulations in the up and down directions (direction A) and the left and right directions (direction B) may be reversed depending on the design of the detachable endoscope <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0113" num="0112">As described above, in the detachable endoscope <b>10</b> according to the embodiments of the present disclosure, the insertion unit <b>200</b> intended to be inserted into the human body is configured to be detachable from the operation unit <b>100</b>, so that the internal contamination of the endoscope <b>10</b> can be prevented and parts can be easily replaced and cleaned. Additionally, in the course of coupling the insertion unit <b>200</b>, one end of the insertion unit <b>200</b> can be inserted into and pressed against one end of the operation unit <b>100</b>, and at the same time, engaged, coupled, and locked therewith, without the use of a separate engaging or locking structure, thereby enabling simple and easy assembly and disassembly of the insertion unit <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0114" num="0113">The afore-mentioned description of the disclosure is just an example, and a person having ordinary skill in the art may understand that it can be easily modified into other specific configuration without changing the technical spirit or essential features of the disclosure. Accordingly, it should be understood that the embodiments described above are illustrative in every respect and not restrictive. For example, the respective components described as a singular form may be implemented in a distributed form, and likewise the respective components described as a distributed form may be implemented in a combined form.</p>
<p id="p-0115" num="0114">The scope of the present disclosure is represented by the following claims, and all modifications and changes derived from the meaning and scope of the claims and equivalent concepts thereof should be interpreted as being included in the scope of the present disclosure.</p>
<heading id="h-0008" level="1">REFERENCE SIGN LIST</heading>
<p id="p-0116" num="0000">
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0001-0001" num="0000">
    <ul id="ul0002" list-style="none">
        <li id="ul0002-0001" num="0115"><b>10</b>: Detachable endoscope</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0002" num="0116"><b>100</b>: Operation unit</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0003" num="0117"><b>200</b>: Insertion unit</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0004" num="0118"><b>300</b>: Detachment unit</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0005" num="0119"><b>300</b><i>a</i>: First detachment module</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0006" num="0120"><b>300</b><i>b</i>: Second detachment module</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0007" num="0121"><b>400</b>: Joint unit</li>
    </ul>
    </li>
</ul>
</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A detachable endoscope comprising:
<claim-text>an insertion unit whose one end is to be inserted into a body;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an operation unit coupled to another end of the insertion unit and operating the one end of the insertion unit to perform a bending motion using an operation module; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a detachment unit which detachably couples the operation unit and the insertion unit, and locks the insertion unit in a coupled state simultaneously when being coupled, so that the insertion unit is secured to the operation unit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The detachable endoscope of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the detachment unit includes:
<claim-text>a first detachment module disposed at one end of the operation unit and having an intermediate connection part to which a connection wire receiving a force from the operation module is connected; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second detachment module disposed at the other end of the insertion unit, detachably coupled to the first detachment module, and having an insertion end connection part connected to an operation wire that transfers a force applied by the operation module to the one end of the insertion unit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The detachable endoscope of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the intermediate connection part is provided with an intermediate connection body disposed rotatably around a longitudinal direction; an insertion groove formed concavely inward in a longitudinal direction at one end of the intermediate connection body and having a penetration part penetratingly formed in a direction perpendicular to the longitudinal direction; and
<claim-text>a guide projection for guiding rotational motion of the intermediate connection body, and wherein the insertion end connection part is provided with an insertion end connection body extending in a longitudinal direction; and an engaging member protruding outward in a longitudinal direction from one end of the insertion end connection body.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The detachable endoscope of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein when the insertion unit and the operation unit are coupled, the engaging member is inserted into the insertion groove, the engaging member being protrudingly formed in a length corresponding to the concave depth of the insertion groove.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The detachable endoscope of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein when the insertion unit and the operation unit are coupled, the insertion end connection part presses the intermediate connection part in a longitudinal direction in a state in which one end of an insertion end connection body is in contact with one end of the intermediate connection body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The detachable endoscope of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein as the insertion end connection body rotates along the guide projection by the pressing of the intermediate connection part, the engaging member is inserted into the penetration part to be in an engaged state.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The detachable endoscope of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the intermediate connection part and the insertion end connection part are arranged on a same line along a longitudinal direction to face each other, are coupled to each other, and operate integrally based on manipulation of the operation module.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
