<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225547A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225547</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18009447</doc-number>
<date>20210618</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="regional">
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>20181248.4</doc-number>
<date>20200619</date>
</priority-claim>
<priority-claim sequence="02" kind="national">
<country>IT</country>
<doc-number>102020000024139</doc-number>
<date>20201013</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>31</main-group>
<subgroup>44</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>31</main-group>
<subgroup>446</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e79">COFFEE MACHINE WITH AUTOMATIC LOCKING OF THE FILTER-HOLDER</invention-title>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>CARIMALI S.P.A.</orgname>
<address>
<city>Bergamo</city>
<country>IT</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>IT</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>DOGLINI MAJER</last-name>
<first-name>Andrea</first-name>
<address>
<city>Chignolo d'Isola</city>
<country>IT</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="01" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>IEMMA</last-name>
<first-name>Lorenzo</first-name>
<address>
<city>Chignolo d'Isola</city>
<country>IT</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="02" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>CERIANI</last-name>
<first-name>Allessandro</first-name>
<address>
<city>Chignolo d'Isola</city>
<country>IT</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>CARIMALI S.P.A.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Bergamo</city>
<country>IT</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/IB2021/055402</doc-number>
<date>20210618</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c12-date><date>20221209</date></us-371c12-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A coffee machine has a supporting body that delivers hot water for producing a beverage. A filter-holder is can be filled with a brewing material and releasably coupleable to the supporting body to receive hot water therefrom for brewing the brewing material to produce the beverage. A coupling device includes a first coupling part mounted on the supporting body and a second coupling part carried by the filter-holder. The coupling device is configured to tighten the filter-holder by a relative rotation of the first coupling part and the second coupling part. An automation device is configured to cause relative rotation of the first coupling part and the second coupling part. A user interface is configured to cause the coupling device to tight-couple and uncouple and/or a beverage delivery to start and stop in response to sensed actions or forces.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="188.98mm" wi="158.75mm" file="US20230225547A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="203.79mm" wi="169.33mm" file="US20230225547A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="244.52mm" wi="164.68mm" file="US20230225547A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="211.07mm" wi="171.37mm" file="US20230225547A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="228.01mm" wi="157.65mm" file="US20230225547A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="236.30mm" wi="180.17mm" file="US20230225547A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="221.66mm" wi="158.33mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225547A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="240.88mm" wi="128.19mm" file="US20230225547A1-20230720-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="209.13mm" wi="142.83mm" file="US20230225547A1-20230720-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="167.30mm" wi="169.16mm" file="US20230225547A1-20230720-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="214.97mm" wi="152.65mm" file="US20230225547A1-20230720-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="234.70mm" wi="163.66mm" file="US20230225547A1-20230720-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00012" num="00012">
<img id="EMI-D00012" he="226.82mm" wi="157.65mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225547A1-20230720-D00012.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00013" num="00013">
<img id="EMI-D00013" he="236.73mm" wi="129.29mm" file="US20230225547A1-20230720-D00013.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00014" num="00014">
<img id="EMI-D00014" he="219.37mm" wi="140.04mm" file="US20230225547A1-20230720-D00014.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00015" num="00015">
<img id="EMI-D00015" he="194.99mm" wi="166.03mm" file="US20230225547A1-20230720-D00015.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00016" num="00016">
<img id="EMI-D00016" he="217.68mm" wi="154.43mm" file="US20230225547A1-20230720-D00016.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00017" num="00017">
<img id="EMI-D00017" he="217.34mm" wi="153.16mm" file="US20230225547A1-20230720-D00017.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00018" num="00018">
<img id="EMI-D00018" he="220.81mm" wi="157.23mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225547A1-20230720-D00018.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00019" num="00019">
<img id="EMI-D00019" he="187.20mm" wi="157.14mm" file="US20230225547A1-20230720-D00019.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00020" num="00020">
<img id="EMI-D00020" he="233.60mm" wi="146.56mm" file="US20230225547A1-20230720-D00020.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a national stage application, filed under 35 U.S.C. &#xa7; 371, of International Patent Application No. PCT/162021/055402, filed on Jun. 18, 2021, which claims priority to European patent application no. 20181248.4 filed on Jun. 19, 2020 and Italian patent application no. 102020000024139 filed on Oct. 13, 2020, the entire to disclosures of all of which are incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="tail"?>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE DISCLOSURE</heading>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">1. Field of the Disclosure</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates to the field of machines for preparing coffee or similar beverages, and in particular it relates to a semi-automatic coffee machine for professional use in bars or for domestic use.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">2. Description of Related Art</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">As is well known, semi-automatic coffee machines comprise those machines in which a coffee beverage is largely made manually by an operator, while other operations are controlled automatically by an electronic control unit.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">A typical operation that has to be carried out manually is, for example, loading the ground coffee, which normally requires the operator to remove the so-called filter-holder from the machine to load a dose of loose ground coffee or a pod or a disposable capsule into the filter-holder, and then to fluidtight couple the filter-holder to an annular supporting body which forms an outlet of a hot water injection assembly of the coffee machine.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Another operation that is controlled directly by the operator, normally by means of a button, is the start and, vice versa, the stop of the beverage delivery. In some types of semi-automatic machines, the beverage delivery is stopped automatically, based on a setting of the &#x201c;length&#x201d; of the coffee to be delivered in the cup.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In general, the filter-holder is coupled to the annular supporting body by means of a bayonet coupling device formed of at least two radial fins carried by the filter-holder and a corresponding number of slots formed in the annular supporting body.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Each fin, or, alternatively, each slot, is partially delimited by an inclined plane, which, when the filter-holder is coupled to the annular supporting body and the fins are displaced along the respective slots, engages an abutment plane formed on the corresponding slot, or, respectively, on the corresponding fin, so as to cause an axial displacement of the filter-holder towards the annular supporting body and consequent fluid-tight coupling of a free edge of the filter-holder against a frontal seal carried by the annular supporting body.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">From the operator's point of view, coupling the filter-holder to the supporting annular body of the water injection assembly involves two sequential operations in order to bring the filter-holder first into an insertion configuration, in which the filter-holder is inserted in the annular body, and then into a tight coupling configuration, in which the filter-holder is tight-coupled onto the annular supporting body.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The insertion configuration is usually reached by vertically moving the filter-holder from bottom upwards so that the filter-holder is coupled frontally to the annular supporting body and the fins are aligned with corresponding slots. Typically, in the insertion configuration, the filter-holder is angularly offset (leftwards) from a frontal configuration with respect to the operator.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The tight coupling configuration is instead reached by rotating the filter-holder, typically by about 30&#xb0;-40&#xb0; and anticlockwise, starting from the insertion configuration, so as to move the fins along the slots until the free edge of the filter-holder is compressed against the frontal seal of the annular supporting body. Resultingly, in the tight coupling configuration the filter-holder is angularly offset from the insertion configuration and is typically placed frontally to the operator.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">EP 3 037 023 A1 discloses a connecting device for connecting a filter-holder of an espresso machine to a hot water dispensing group for producing a beverage. The filter-holder comprises a body, provided with a handle, with an inner cavity delimited by a cylindrical wall and defining a housing for a filter, to be loaded with ground coffee. The cavity is open at an end facing the dispensing group, is closed with a bottom wall at the opposite end, and is provided with a beverage dispensing opening formed in the bottom wall. The filter-holder further comprises a pair of diametrically opposed fins projecting radially from the side wall and extending circumferentially outside the cavity. The water dispensing group comprises an opening designed to accommodate the open end of the inner cavity of body of the filter-holder and a pair of helical guides extending around an axis orthogonal to the plane on which the filter-holder connects to the water dispensing group. The helical guides are arranged around the opening and are each designed to accommodate thereon, by means of a bayonet coupling, a corresponding fin of the pair of fins of the filter-holder. The connecting device comprises a plate-like element fixed to the water delivery group and provided with an opening aligned with the opening of the water dispensing group and with a tubular cavity, which is open at both axial ends and is aligned with the axial openings and in a distal position relative to the opening of the water dispensing group. The connecting device further comprises an annular element which is arranged inside the tubular cavity of the plate-like element so as to freely rotate around the longitudinal axis thereof. The pair of helical guides is formed on the internal wall of the annular element and motor means are provided to angularly displace the annular element so as to servo-assist the insertion of the filter-holder into the water delivery group.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE DISCLOSURE</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The Applicant has found that known coffee machines of the type described above have a number of drawbacks that are well known to the operators in the sector.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In particular, the Applicant has found that one of these drawbacks is represented by the fact that the mechanical seal between the filter-holder and the water outlet of the water injection group is totally dependent on the effectiveness of the tight coupling of the coupling device, which is left exclusively to the action of the operator, i.e., the extent to which the operator is able to compress the filter-holder against the annular supporting body when rotating it from the insertion configuration to the tight coupling configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">As is well known, this operation requires not only a certain technique on the part of the operator, but above all a considerable effort, which can be extremely onerous from a physical point of view when it has to be repeated hundreds or even thousands of times a day, as in the case of a bartender, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Moreover, the effort of tight coupling the filter-holder is not even the only one required to the operator, as the removal thereof also requires the operator to apply a not negligible force, at least in the first phase of the rotation in order to move the filter-holder away from the tight coupling configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The Applicant has also found that another of the drawbacks of known coffee machines of the type described above is represented by the fact that the activation of the various operating functions of the coffee machines requires various interactions of the operator with different elements of the coffee machines.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The aim of the present disclosure is to provide improvements to remedy the above-described drawbacks.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">According to the present disclosure, a coffee machine is provided, as claimed in the appended claims.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> shows, in perspective view and with parts removed for the sake of clarity, an embodiment of the coffee machine of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> shows, in exploded view, a detail of a water injection group of the coffee machine shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, and the filter-holder of the coffee machine in a disengagement configuration, in which filter-holder is disengaged from the water injection group.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> shows the detail shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> in an assembled configuration, and the filter-holder in the aforementioned disengagement configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> shows, with parts removed for the sake of clarity, the coffee machine shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> during insertion of the filter-holder in the water injection group.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>5</b> and <b>6</b></figref> show the filter-holder engaged with the water injection group in an initial uncoupled configuration and in a final tight-coupled configuration of the filter-holder and the water injection group, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> shows, in cross-section, the filter-holder and part of the water injection group arranged in the above-mentioned final tight-coupled configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> shows, in exploded view, a detail of the water injection group in a different embodiment of the coffee machine of the present disclosure and the filter-holder of the coffee machine in a disengagement configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref> shows the detail shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> in an assembled configuration and the filter-holder in the above-mentioned disengagement configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref> shows, with parts removed for the sake of clarity, the coffee machine shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> during insertion of the filter-holder on the water injection group.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>11</b> and <b>12</b></figref> show, in perspective view and, respectively, in a bottom view, the filter-holder shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref> engaged with the water injection group in an initial uncoupled configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>13</b> and <b>14</b></figref> show, in perspective view and, respectively, in bottom view, the filter-holder shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref> engaged with the water injection group in a final tight-coupled configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>15</b></figref> shows, in cross-section, the filter-holder and part of the water injection group arranged in the final tight-coupled configuration shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>14</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>16</b></figref> shows, in exploded view, a detail of the water injection group in a further different embodiment of the coffee machine of the present disclosure, and the filter-holder of the coffee machine in a disengagement configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>17</b></figref> shows the detail shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> in an assembled configuration and the filter-holder in the above-mentioned disengagement configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>18</b></figref> shows, with parts removed for the sake of clarity, the coffee machine shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>16</b></figref> during insertion of the filter-holder on the water injection group;</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>19</b> and <b>20</b></figref> show, in perspective view and, respectively, in bottom view, the filter-holder shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>18</b></figref> engaged with the water injection group in an initial uncoupled configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>21</b> and <b>22</b></figref> show, in perspective view and, respectively, in bottom view, the filter-holder shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>18</b></figref> engaged with the water injection group in a final tight-coupled configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>23</b></figref> shows, in cross-section, the filter-holder and part of the water injection group arranged in the final tight-coupled configuration shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>21</b> and <b>22</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>24</b></figref> shows, in perspective and with parts removed for the sake of clarity, a variant of the water injection group of the coffee machine of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>25</b>, <b>26</b> and <b>27</b></figref> show, in front view, three variants of a detail of the coffee machine of the present disclosure.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE DISCLOSURE</heading>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The present disclosure will now be described in detail with reference to the accompanying drawings to enable a skilled person to realize and use it. Various modifications to the embodiments presented shall be immediately clear to persons skilled in the art and the general principles disclosed herein could be applied to other embodiments and applications but without thereby departing from the scope of protection of the present disclosure as defined in the appended claims. Therefore, the present disclosure should not be considered limited to the embodiments described and shown, but should be granted the widest protective scope in accordance with the features described and claimed.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Where not otherwise defined, all the technical and scientific terms used herein have the same meaning commonly used by persons of ordinary skill in the field pertaining to the present disclosure. In the event of a conflict, this description, including the definitions provided, shall be binding. Furthermore, the examples are provided for illustrative purposes only and as such should not be considered limiting.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">In order to facilitate understanding of the embodiments described herein, reference will be made to some specific embodiments and a specific language will be used to describe them. The terminology used herein is for the purpose of describing only particular embodiments, and is not intended to limit the scope of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> shows and denotes as a whole with the reference numeral <b>1</b> a semi-automatic coffee machine commonly for professional use in bars or for domestic use.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The coffee machine <b>1</b> comprises a box-shaped frame <b>2</b>, which is delimited frontally, with respect to an operator, by a front wall <b>3</b>, and a plurality of components for the production of coffee which are supported by the frame <b>2</b> and comprising a boiler <b>4</b> for the production of hot water arranged inside the frame <b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">In a different embodiment, shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>24</b></figref>, the boiler <b>4</b> for the production of hot water is arranged outside the frame <b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The front wall <b>3</b> can be either an external wall of the coffee machine <b>1</b> or an internal wall of the coffee machine <b>1</b> in turn protected by an external casing (not shown) which completely or partially covers the frame <b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The boiler <b>4</b> comprises a hot water supply conduit <b>5</b>, an end portion of which extends within a supporting body <b>6</b> mounted to protrude from the front wall <b>3</b> and configured to be releasably engaged by a filter-holder <b>7</b>, which is designed to be filled with either loose ground coffee or a disposable coffee pod or capsule and to receive water from the supporting body <b>6</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">From the lower end of the front wall <b>3</b>, a drip tray <b>8</b> protrudes which is closed above by a grid <b>9</b> to support, in use, one or more cups underneath the filter holder <b>7</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">The filter-holder <b>7</b> comprises a cup <b>10</b> open at the top and a handle <b>11</b> extending radially from the cup <b>10</b> and designed to be gripped by an operator to couple and uncouple the cup <b>10</b> to/from the supporting body <b>6</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">The cup <b>10</b> is provided at the bottom with a conduit <b>12</b> for the delivery of the coffee beverage, to which a two-way delivery spout <b>13</b> can be connected, preferably removably, to allow the coffee beverage to be delivered in two cups at the same time.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The cup <b>10</b> houses internally a cup-shaped filter <b>14</b> which is designed to receive either loose ground coffee or a coffee pod or capsule. Preferably, the filter <b>14</b> is made of metallic material, conveniently stainless steel, and has a perforated bottom wall and a lateral wall ending with an edge <b>15</b> which is U-folded outwards and is arranged astride a free end edge of the cup <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The cup <b>10</b> has, close to its open end, a number of projections or fins <b>16</b>, which radially project outwardly from the cup <b>10</b> and define a portion of a coupling device <b>17</b>, of the type commonly referred to as a &#x201c;bayonet&#x201d;, designed to removably couple the cup <b>10</b>, and hence the filter-holder <b>7</b>, to the supporting body <b>6</b>. In the examples shown in the accompanying FIGS., the fins <b>16</b> are in number of three and are mutually equispaced around a longitudinal axis of the cup <b>10</b>. In variants not shown, the fins <b>16</b> could be in number of two or more than three.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">The fins <b>16</b> lie substantially on a horizontal plane perpendicular to the longitudinal axis of the cup <b>10</b> and are delimited at the bottom by respective inclined planes <b>18</b>, all of which have the same inclination and orientation relative to the lying plane of the fins <b>16</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">As shown in the accompanying FIGS., the supporting body <b>6</b> is generically cup-shaped, with a concavity facing downwards, and comprises a tubular lateral wall <b>19</b>, coaxial to a substantially vertical axis <b>20</b>, and a bottom wall, through which the aforementioned end portion of the hot water supply conduit <b>5</b> is formed.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">A hot water distribution shower <b>21</b> is mounted at the centre of the bottom wall, fluidically communicates with the hot water supply conduit <b>5</b>, and is surrounded by an annular cavity <b>22</b> coaxial to the axis <b>20</b> and housing a frontal seal <b>23</b> which, as will be described in more detail below, has the function of fluid-tight coupling the filter-holder <b>7</b> and the supporting body <b>6</b> when the coupling device <b>17</b> is tight-coupled.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Furthermore, a number of transverse projections <b>24</b> are associated with the supporting body <b>6</b>, which are arranged on the supporting body <b>6</b> so as to cooperate with the fins <b>16</b> when the filter-holder <b>7</b> is coupled to the supporting body <b>6</b>. The transverse projections <b>24</b> define, together with the fins <b>16</b>, the aforementioned coupling device <b>17</b>, of which they form a further portion.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">For this purpose, the transverse projections <b>24</b> are delimited at the top, i.e., towards the bottom wall of the supporting body <b>6</b>, by respective abutment planes <b>25</b>, which are coplanar to each other and perpendicular to the axis <b>20</b> and are configured to slidably engage with the inclined planes <b>18</b> in response to a relative rotation of the transverse projections <b>24</b> and the fins <b>16</b>, in the manner and forms described below, so as to cause an upward displacement of the filter-holder <b>7</b> and the compression of the latter against the supporting body <b>6</b>, resulting in a tight coupling of the coupling device <b>17</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">In particular, as will be further clarified in the following description, the coupling of the filter-holder <b>7</b> to the supporting body <b>6</b> comprises a first completely manual step during which the operator brings the cup <b>10</b> of the filter-holder <b>7</b> close to the supporting body <b>6</b> through a vertical upward movement in order to arrange the filter-holder <b>7</b> in an insertion configuration, in which the fins <b>16</b> are arranged in the free spaces between the transverse projections <b>24</b>, and the edge <b>15</b> of the filter <b>14</b> engages the cavity <b>22</b> and faces the, and preferably contacts the, frontal seal <b>23</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">Conveniently, in order to ease the correct positioning of the filter-holder <b>7</b> in the insertion configuration and to keep it stable in this configuration prior to tight coupling the coupling device <b>17</b>, a magnetic positioning device <b>26</b> is there is provided, which comprises a number of permanent magnets <b>27</b>, each fixed to a respective fin <b>16</b>, and a number of permanent magnets <b>28</b> mounted along the periphery of the bottom wall of the cup <b>10</b> in positions such that, when the filter-holder <b>7</b> is approached to the supporting body <b>6</b>, the permanent magnets <b>28</b> are facing corresponding permanent magnets <b>27</b> of the fins <b>16</b>. Preferably, the attractive force between the pairs of facing permanent magnets <b>27</b> and <b>28</b> is enough to hold the filter-holder <b>7</b> in the insertion configuration, even if the operator completely abandons the filter-holder <b>7</b> before the coupling device <b>17</b> is tight-coupled.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">The coupling of the filter-holder <b>7</b> to the supporting body <b>6</b> further comprises a second step during which the coupling device <b>17</b> is tight-coupled. In this step, the fins <b>16</b> and the projections <b>24</b> are relatively rotated and the engagement between the inclined planes <b>18</b> and the abutment planes <b>25</b> causes the filter-holder <b>7</b> to move from the insertion configuration to a tight coupling configuration, in which the filter-holder <b>7</b> is arranged at a higher level than in the insertion configuration and the edge <b>15</b> of the filter <b>14</b> is compressed against the frontal seal <b>23</b> so as to achieve a fluid-tight coupling with the latter.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">The coffee machine <b>1</b> further comprises an automation device <b>29</b> configured to automatically tight-couple and uncouple the coupling device <b>17</b> so as to relieve the operator of the physical effort associated with such operations.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">In this respect, it should be noted that, since the relative rotation of the fines <b>16</b> and the transverse projections <b>24</b> causes the coupling device <b>17</b> to be tight-coupled and uncoupled, there is no conceptual difference, but only an implementation difference, between a type of actuation of the coupling device <b>17</b>, in the following for descriptive convenience indicated as the first type of actuation, in which the transverse projections <b>24</b> rotate relative to the fins <b>16</b>, and a type of actuation of the coupling device <b>17</b>, in the following for descriptive convenience indicated as the second type of actuation, in which the fines <b>16</b> rotate relative to the transverse projections <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">The automation device <b>29</b> comprises a toothed ring nut <b>30</b> carried by the supporting body <b>6</b> and mounted to rotate around the axis <b>20</b>, and a drive device <b>31</b> operatively coupled to the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> to rotate it around the axis <b>20</b> and move it between a rest configuration, in which an operator is allowed to couple the filter-holder <b>7</b> to the supporting body <b>6</b> in order to arrange it in the insertion configuration, and an operating configuration, in which the filter-holder <b>7</b> is in the tight coupling configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">Depending on the type of actuation of the coupling device <b>17</b>, the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> rotates the transverse projections <b>24</b> relative to the fins <b>16</b>, or, vice versa, the fins <b>16</b> relative to the transverse projections <b>24</b> to tight-couple and uncouple the coupling device <b>17</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">In particular, in the first type of actuation shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>-<b>7</b></figref>, the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> is mounted integral with the transverse projections <b>24</b> to rotate them relative to the fins <b>16</b>, while in the second type of actuation (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>8</b>-<b>15</b> and <b>16</b>-<b>23</b></figref>), the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> is angularly coupled to the fins <b>16</b> to rotate them relative to the transverse projections <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">The toothed ring nut <b>30</b> comprises an external toothing <b>32</b> coaxial to the axis <b>20</b> and formed on an annular body <b>33</b> rotatably mounted on the tubular side wall <b>19</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">Preferably, the drive device <b>31</b> comprises an electric motor <b>34</b>, arranged in the frame <b>2</b>, and a gear transmission <b>35</b> designed to receive rotational motion from an output shaft of the electric motor <b>34</b> and transmit it, suitably reduced, to the ring nut <b>30</b>. Preferably, the output shaft of the electric motor <b>34</b> extends through the front wall <b>3</b> and the gear transmission <b>35</b> is arranged outside the frame <b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">In an embodiment not shown, the drive device <b>31</b> comprises a gear motor entirely housed in the frame <b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">In the following, the automation device <b>29</b> will be described in more detail with explicit reference to each one of the two aforementioned types of actuation of the coupling device <b>17</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">First Type of Actuation of the Coupling Device</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b> to <b>7</b></figref> show an embodiment of the coffee machine <b>1</b> operating according to the first type of actuation of the coupling device <b>17</b>, i.e., the type in which the transverse projections <b>24</b> rotate relative to the fins <b>16</b> and are rotated about the axis <b>20</b> by the toothed ring nut <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">In this embodiment, the toothed ring nut <b>30</b>, which is rotatably mounted on the tubular side wall <b>19</b>, substantially forms an extension of the tubular lateral wall <b>19</b> and brings integrally the transverse projections <b>24</b> close to its own free end edge.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b> and <b>3</b></figref>, the transverse projections <b>24</b> extend from an inner surface of the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> towards the axis <b>20</b>, are arranged with the respective abutment planes <b>25</b> facing the bottom wall of the supporting body <b>6</b>, and are evenly distributed around the axis <b>20</b> such that free spaces <b>36</b> of sufficient angular width are circumferentially defined therebetween in order to allow the fines <b>16</b> to pass through the free spaces <b>36</b> in a direction parallel to the axis <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">The supporting body <b>6</b> has a plurality of seats <b>37</b>, which are distributed around the seal <b>23</b> so as to be axially aligned with corresponding free spaces <b>36</b> when the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> is in the rest configuration, and are so sized as to each accommodate a respective fin <b>16</b> when the filter-holder <b>7</b> is in the insertion configuration (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">In order to attract the filter-holder <b>7</b> and then keep it stable in the insertion configuration, each seat <b>37</b> is provided with one of the aforementioned permanent magnets <b>28</b> of the positioning device <b>26</b> so as to cooperate, when the filter-holder <b>7</b> is approached to the supporting body <b>6</b>, with the permanent magnet <b>27</b> of the corresponding fin <b>16</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">Preferably, the seats <b>37</b> and, consequently, the toothed ring nut <b>30</b>, are arranged around the axis <b>20</b> so that, when the filter-holder <b>7</b> is in the insertion configuration, the handle <b>11</b> of the filter-holder <b>7</b> is arranged frontally to the operator and generally perpendicular with respect to the front wall <b>3</b> of the casing <b>2</b>. Since in the first type of actuation of the coupling device <b>17</b>, the fins <b>16</b> of the filter-holder do not rotate during the tight coupling of the coupling device <b>17</b>, but only undergo an axial upward displacement, the filter-holder <b>7</b> remains in the same frontal configuration relative to the operator even when it is in the tight coupling configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>5</b> and <b>6</b></figref> show how the coupling device <b>17</b> is tight-coupled by rotating the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> from the rest configuration, shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, to the operating configuration, shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">In the rest configuration of the toothed ring nut <b>30</b>, the filter-holder <b>7</b> is in the insertion configuration, in which the fins <b>16</b> engage the corresponding seats <b>37</b> and the edge <b>15</b> of the filter <b>14</b> engages the seal <b>23</b> frontally or is at least adjacent thereto.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">As is clearly shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>, in order to move the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> from the rest configuration to the operating configuration, the drive device <b>31</b> is operated to impart to the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> a rotation of such an extent as to cause the transverse projections <b>24</b> and the fins <b>16</b> to overlap, at least partially. During this rotation, the abutment planes <b>25</b> of the transverse projections <b>24</b> slide along the inclined planes <b>18</b> of the fins <b>16</b>, imparting an upward thrust to the latter, and thus to the entire filter-holder <b>7</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref>, at the end of the rotation of the toothed ring nut <b>30</b>, the filter-holder <b>7</b> is in the tight coupling configuration, in which the edge <b>15</b> of the filter <b>14</b> is compressed against the seal <b>23</b> so that the filter-holder <b>7</b> is fluid-tightly coupled to the supporting body <b>6</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">Second Type of Actuation of the Coupling Device</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>8</b> to <b>15</b></figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>16</b> to <b>23</b></figref> show respective embodiments of the coffee machine <b>1</b> operating according to the second type of actuation of the coupling device <b>17</b>, i.e., the type in which the fins <b>16</b> rotate relative to the transverse projections <b>24</b> and the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> is angularly coupled to the fins <b>16</b> to rotate them about the axis <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">In this embodiment, the transverse projections <b>24</b> are not carried by the toothed ring nut <b>30</b>, but are integral with the tubular lateral wall <b>19</b>. In particular, the transverse projections <b>24</b> are arranged along an end free edge of the tubular lateral wall <b>19</b>, extend towards the axis <b>20</b>, and the respective abutment planes <b>25</b> face the bottom wall of the supporting body <b>6</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">Also in this embodiment, the transverse projections <b>24</b> are evenly distributed around the axis <b>20</b> and circumferentially define therebetween free spaces <b>36</b> of sufficient angular width to allow the fins <b>16</b> to pass through the free spaces <b>36</b> in a direction parallel to the axis <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">In the sections corresponding to the free spaces <b>36</b>, around the seal <b>23</b>, the bottom wall of the supporting body <b>6</b> carries the permanent magnets <b>28</b> which, like in the previous embodiment, are designed to cooperate, when the filter-holder <b>7</b> is approached to the supporting body <b>6</b>, with the permanent magnets <b>27</b> carried by the corresponding fins <b>16</b> in order to attract and retain, or help to retain, the filter-holder <b>7</b> in the insertion configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">As mentioned above, in the second type of actuation of the coupling device <b>17</b>, the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> is angularly coupleable to the fins <b>16</b> and, hence, to the filter-holder <b>7</b>, such that the filter-holder <b>7</b> is rotated around the axis <b>20</b> when it is actuated by the drive device <b>31</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">The angular coupling between toothed ring nut <b>30</b> and filter-holder <b>7</b> is achieved when filter-holder <b>7</b> assumes the insertion configuration. Two examples of how this angular coupling can be achieved are given by the embodiments shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>8</b> to <b>15</b></figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>16</b> to <b>23</b></figref>, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">In the embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>8</b> to <b>15</b></figref>, the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> is provided with a fork <b>38</b> configured to be arranged astride the handle <b>11</b> of the filter-holder <b>7</b> when the latter is in the insertion configuration, thereby making the filter-holder <b>7</b> and the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> angularly integral.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>10</b>, <b>11</b> and <b>13</b></figref>, conveniently, the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> is mounted on the supporting body <b>6</b> so that, when the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> is in the rest configuration, the fork <b>38</b> is angularly offset from a central configuration facing the operator and, preferably, is to the left of the operator (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>10</b> and <b>11</b></figref>). Preferably, moreover, the rest configuration of the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> is chosen so that, after the rotation of the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> from the rest configuration to the operating configuration, the fork <b>38</b> and, hence, the handle <b>11</b> of the filter-holder <b>7</b>, is substantially in said central configuration in front of the operator (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>13</b></figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>12</b> and <b>14</b></figref> show how the coupling device <b>17</b> is tight coupled by rotating the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> from the rest configuration (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>12</b></figref>) to the operating configuration (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>14</b></figref>), and the corresponding rotation of the filter-holder <b>7</b> from the insertion configuration (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>12</b></figref>) to the tight coupling configuration (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>14</b></figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">In the insertion configuration of the filter-holder <b>7</b>, the handle <b>11</b> is inserted into the fork <b>38</b>, the fins <b>16</b> are arranged between the transverse projections <b>24</b> in corresponding free spaces <b>36</b>, and the edge <b>15</b> of the filter <b>14</b> engages the seal <b>23</b> frontally or is at least adjacent thereto.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">Operation of the drive device <b>31</b> causes the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> to rotate, dragging the filter-holder <b>7</b> with it and sliding the fins <b>16</b> on the transverse projections <b>24</b>, thus moving the filter-holder <b>7</b> upwards.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>15</b></figref>, at the end of the rotation of the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> and the filter-holder <b>7</b>, the latter is in the tight coupling configuration, in which the edge <b>15</b> of the filter <b>14</b> is compressed against the seal <b>23</b>, so that the filter-holder <b>7</b> is fluid-tightly coupled to the supporting body <b>6</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">In the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>16</b> to <b>23</b></figref>, the angular coupling between the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> and the filter-holder <b>7</b> is achieved by means of a seat or pocket <b>39</b> integral with the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> and configured to be engaged by one of the fins <b>16</b> of the filter-holder <b>7</b> when the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> is in the rest configuration and the filter-holder <b>7</b> is brought in the insertion configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">In particular, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>17</b></figref>, the pocket <b>39</b> is defined by two walls projecting from an inner surface of the toothed ring <b>30</b>, extends within one of the free spaces <b>36</b> between the transverse projections <b>24</b> and is so sized as to contain a fin <b>16</b> with relative precision.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">When the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> is in the rest configuration and the filter-holder <b>7</b> is inserted in the supporting body <b>6</b>, one of the fins <b>16</b> is inserted in the pocket <b>39</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>20</b></figref>) so as to constrain the filter-holder <b>7</b> to rotate together with the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> when the latter moves into the operating configuration. The rotation of the filter-holder <b>7</b> causes the fins <b>16</b> to engage the respective transverse projections <b>24</b>, so resulting in the tight coupling of the coupling device <b>17</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>22</b></figref>). In this regard, it is noted that in the shown example, the size of the pocket <b>39</b> is such that, during rotation of the filter-holder <b>7</b>, the pocket <b>39</b> would interfere with the transverse projection <b>24</b> intended to cooperate with the fin <b>16</b> inserted in the pocket <b>39</b>. Therefore, said transverse projection <b>24</b> is absent and the tight coupling of the coupling device <b>17</b> is effectively achieved by engaging the other fins with the respective transverse projections <b>24</b>. In a variant not shown, the pocket <b>39</b> is so sized and shaped as to allow it to be rotated despite the presence of the transverse projection <b>24</b> intended to cooperate with the fin <b>16</b> inserted in the pocket <b>39</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>18</b>, <b>19</b> and <b>21</b></figref>, the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> is conveniently mounted on the supporting body <b>6</b> so that, when the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> is in the rest configuration, it is possible to insert a fin <b>16</b> into the pocket <b>39</b> while keeping the handle <b>11</b> of the filter-holder <b>7</b> in a configuration angularly offset leftwards relative to a central configuration in front of the operator so that, after the rotation of the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> from the rest configuration to the operating configuration, the handle <b>11</b> is substantially in said central configuration in front of the operator.</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>23</b></figref>, at the end of the rotation of the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> and the filter-holder <b>7</b>, the latter is in the tight coupling configuration, in which the edge <b>15</b> of the filter <b>14</b> is compressed against the seal <b>23</b>, so that the filter-holder <b>7</b> is fluid-tightly coupled to the supporting body <b>6</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0098">Regardless of whether the coupling device <b>17</b> belongs to the first type or second type of actuation described above, the automation device <b>29</b> of the coffee machine <b>1</b> is configured, as mentioned above, to automatically tight-couple and uncouple the coupling device <b>17</b> so as to replace, or assist, the operator in performing such actions.</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0099">In order to implement such an automatism, which from a practical point of view requires the activation of the drive device <b>31</b> which rotates the toothed ring nut <b>30</b>, the automation device <b>29</b> comprises a user interface <b>40</b> operatively coupled to the drive device <b>31</b> and configured to allow an operator to cause the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> to rotate in both directions of rotation in order to tight-couple and uncouple the coupling device <b>17</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0100">In a basic embodiment not shown in the accompanying FIGS., the user interface <b>40</b> may comprise a simple button or rocker switch with two or more positions, or one or more touch keys, or a touch-sensitive panel capable of detecting simple touches or more complex gestures made by an operator.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0101">In a advanced embodiment shown in the accompanying FIGS., according to a different and independent aspect of the disclosure, the user interface <b>40</b> is configured to transform actions performed manually by an operator on the filter-holder <b>7</b> into corresponding electrical commands for the drive device <b>31</b>, such that the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> is rotated in opposite directions of rotation and for a given time.</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0102">In particular, the user interface <b>40</b> comprises:</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0103">an electronic sensory system <b>41</b> configured to sense actions by an operator on the handle <b>11</b> of the filter-holder <b>7</b> and output an electrical output indicative of the actions by an operator on the handle <b>11</b> of the filter-holder <b>7</b>, and</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0104">an electronic control unit <b>42</b> communicatively coupled with, in particular electrically connected to, the electronic sensory system <b>41</b> and the drive device <b>31</b> to receive the electrical output of the electronic sensory system <b>41</b> and to generate corresponding electrical commands for the drive device <b>31</b> based on the received electrical output, so as to cause the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> to rotate in opposite directions of rotation to tight-couple and uncouple the coupling device <b>17</b> in response to actions made by an operator on the filter-holder <b>7</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0105">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, the electronic sensory system <b>41</b> comprises a panel or plate <b>43</b>, which is mounted on the front wall <b>3</b> and supports the supporting body <b>6</b>, and one or more sensors <b>44</b> coupled to the plate <b>43</b> to sense forces applied to the plate <b>43</b> directly or indirectly through the filter-holder <b>7</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0107" num="0106">Conveniently, motion sensors <b>44</b> coupled to the plate <b>43</b> may be used as sensors <b>44</b> so as to sense (micro-)movements of the plate <b>43</b> caused by actions of an operator on the plate <b>43</b> either directly or indirectly, through the filter-holder <b>7</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0108" num="0107">The number, the technology and the arrangement of the motion sensors <b>44</b> are chosen such that they allow to sense (micro-)movements of the plate <b>43</b> caused by actions that are wished to be sensed of an operator on the plate <b>43</b> either directly or indirectly, through the filter-holder <b>7</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0109" num="0108">Conveniently, load cells <b>44</b> can be used as motion sensors <b>44</b>, which are explicitly referred to in this description without losing generality.</p>
<p id="p-0110" num="0109">Furthermore, since, by convention, the filter-holder of a coffee machine is rotated by an operator counterclockwise (rightwards with respect to the operator) to be locked on the supporting body and clockwise (leftwards with respect to the operator) to be unlocked, conveniently, the number, technology and the arrangement of the motion sensors are chosen such that they allow sensing (micro-)movements of the plate <b>43</b> caused by the force applied by the operator to the filter-holder <b>7</b> in order to rotate the latter anti-clockwise and clockwise.</p>
<p id="p-0111" num="0110">In this embodiment, the electronic control unit <b>42</b> is programmed to:</p>
<p id="p-0112" num="0111">determine, based on the electrical outputs of the load cells <b>44</b>, the movements of the plate <b>43</b> caused by the actions manually performed by an operator on the handle <b>11</b> of the filter-holder <b>7</b>, and</p>
<p id="p-0113" num="0112">generate electrical commands for the drive device <b>31</b> such that the latter causes the toothed ring <b>30</b> to rotate from the rest configuration to the operating configuration when the load cells <b>44</b> sense a movement of the plate <b>43</b> caused by a rightward (counterclockwise) thrust applied to the filter-holder <b>7</b> by the operator, and, conversely, from the operating configuration to the rest configuration when the load cells <b>44</b> sense a movement of the plate <b>43</b> caused by a leftward (clockwise) thrust applied to the filter-holder <b>7</b> by the operator.</p>
<p id="p-0114" num="0113">In the embodiment shown in the accompanying FIGS., the plate <b>43</b> has a rectangular shape and is delimited by a substantially horizontal lower and upper edges, and by two substantially vertical lateral edges. The lower and upper edges have respective extensions <b>43</b><i>a </i>projecting perpendicularly from the plate <b>43</b> outwards from the front wall <b>3</b> and arranged facing and contiguous with respective brackets <b>45</b> projecting from the lower and upper sides of a window in the front wall <b>3</b> in which the plate <b>43</b> is inserted.</p>
<p id="p-0115" num="0114">Preferably, each extension <b>43</b><i>a </i>is connected to the respective bracket <b>45</b> by means of a pin <b>46</b> arranged substantially in the centre of the bracket <b>45</b> and coaxial to the other pin <b>46</b> so as to define, with the latter, a vertical rotation axis <b>47</b>, about which the plate <b>43</b> may oscillate, in opposite directions, when the operator imparts a rightward or leftward thrust to the supporting group <b>6</b> through the filter-holder <b>7</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0116" num="0115">In order to sense the movement, i.e., the oscillation, of the plate <b>43</b>, the load cells <b>44</b> are arranged between the plate <b>43</b> and the front wall <b>3</b> at the lateral edges of the plate <b>43</b>, on the outside of the front wall <b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0117" num="0116">In any case, the embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>-<b>23</b></figref> is only an example of how many load cells <b>44</b> may be required and how they should be arranged with respect to the plate <b>43</b> and the front wall <b>3</b> in order to sense movements of the plate <b>43</b> in response to the rightward and leftward thrust imparted by an operator to the filter-holder <b>7</b> inserted in the supporting body <b>6</b>. The number, the configuration and the orientation of the load cells <b>44</b> depends in fact on the type of load cell used.</p>
<p id="p-0118" num="0117">Furthermore, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>25</b></figref>, the presence of the pin <b>46</b> is also optional since the number and the arrangement of the load cells <b>44</b> may be sufficient to give the plate <b>43</b> and the movements thereof sufficient stability.</p>
<p id="p-0119" num="0118">Finally, also the shape of the plate <b>43</b> shown in the accompanying FIGS. is purely for illustrative purposes and may be replaced by a mounting element of any shape and size as long as it is suitable to rigidly support the supporting body <b>6</b> and to allow the load cells <b>44</b> to be applied for sensing (micro-)movements of the plate <b>43</b> in response to a rightward and leftward thrust imparted by an operator to the filter-holder <b>7</b> inserted in the supporting body <b>6</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0120" num="0119">Depending on whether the coupling device <b>17</b> operates according to the first type or the second type of actuation, the tight coupling thereof, which, as mentioned above, is caused by the rotation of the toothed ring nut <b>30</b>, takes place either in a fully automatic mode, in which the rotation of the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> is exclusively controlled by the electronic control unit <b>42</b> through the drive device <b>31</b>, or, respectively, in a partially automatic mode, in which the rotation of the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> is carried out partly manually by the operator and partly automatically by the drive device <b>31</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0121" num="0120">In fact, in the first type of actuation, in which the filter-holder <b>7</b> is not rotated between the insertion configuration and the tight coupling configuration and the transverse projections <b>24</b> are carried by the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> to move relative to the fins <b>16</b>, the tight coupling of the coupling device <b>17</b> occurs in a completely automatic manner when an operator places the filter-holder <b>7</b> in the insertion configuration and imparts a rightward thrust (if the convention is followed, or leftwards) as if he wanted to rotate it to lock it, thus causing a movement (oscillation) of the plate <b>43</b>, corresponding electrical outputs of the load cells <b>44</b> and operation of the drive device <b>31</b>, consequently the rotation of the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> in the operating configuration, in response to an electrical command from the electronic control unit <b>42</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0122" num="0121">Conversely, a thrust in the opposite direction, in this case to the left, imparted by the operator to the filter-holder <b>7</b> as if he wanted to unlock it to remove it, causes an opposite movement of the plate <b>43</b> and consequently the rotation of the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> from the operating configuration to the rest configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0123" num="0122">On the other hand, in the second type of actuation, in which the filter-holder <b>7</b> is integral with the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> when the filter-holder <b>7</b> is in the insertion configuration and is rotated to move between the insertion configuration and the tight coupling configuration so as to cause the fins <b>16</b> to engage to, or disengage from, the transverse projections <b>24</b>, the tight coupling of the coupling device <b>17</b> takes place in a partially automatic manner, that is, it occurs in a manual &#x201c;servo-assisted&#x201d; manner.</p>
<p id="p-0124" num="0123">In particular, when the operator places the filter-holder <b>7</b> in the insertion configuration and imparts a rightward thrust (if the convention is followed, or leftwards), the filter-holder <b>7</b> actually starts rotating towards the tight coupling configuration but, at the same time, the load cells <b>44</b> senses a consequent thrust on the plate <b>43</b> and, consequently, the electronic control unit <b>42</b> activates the drive device <b>31</b> which rotates the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> into the operating configuration, thus completing the tight coupling of the coupling device <b>17</b> without the operator having to exert any more force on the filter-holder <b>7</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0125" num="0124">The uncoupling of the coupling device <b>17</b> is mainly automatic as the thrust imparted by the operator to the filter-holder <b>7</b> in the opposite direction, in this case to the left, does not have to be of such an extent as to overcome the tight coupling force, but it is sufficient that it is suitable for being sensed by the load cells <b>44</b> through the movement of the plate <b>43</b> so as to cause the rotation of the toothed ring nut <b>30</b> from the operating configuration to the rest configuration and, hene, the return of the filter-holder <b>7</b> to the insertion configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0126" num="0125">It goes without saying that the tight coupling and uncoupling of the coupling device <b>17</b> may be achieved by acting directly on the plate <b>43</b>, in particular by imparting thrusts directly on the plate <b>43</b>, on opposite sides of the supporting body <b>6</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0127" num="0126">Finally, in a preferred embodiment, the automation device <b>29</b> is configured to control not only the tight coupling and uncoupling of the coupling device <b>17</b>, but also to start and stop beverage delivery in response to appropriate actions manually performed by the operator on the handle <b>11</b> of the filter-holder <b>7</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0128" num="0127">Preferably, the delivery of the beverage is controlled similarly to that described above for the tight coupling of the coupling device <b>17</b> and, in particular, is carried out by means of load cells <b>44</b> which are mounted between the plate <b>43</b> and the front wall <b>3</b> to sense a movement of the plate <b>43</b> in directions that are different from the movements caused by the thrusts imparted to the filter-holder <b>7</b> to and from the tight coupling configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0129" num="0128">The load cells <b>44</b> provided for this purpose may be the same as those intended to sense the movements of the plate <b>43</b> when tight coupling and uncoupling the coupling device <b>17</b>, or may be distinct from those intended to sense the movements of the plate <b>43</b> when tight coupling and uncoupling the coupling device <b>17</b> and arranged in appropriate positions with respect to the plate <b>34</b>. For the sake of simplicity, in the accompanying FIGS. all load cells <b>44</b> are shown with the same reference number, regardless of the type of movement they are intended to sense.</p>
<p id="p-0130" num="0129">In a preferred embodiment, the command to start and stop the beverage delivery is imparted by the operator by exerting on the handle <b>11</b> of the filter-holder <b>7</b>, when the latter is arranged in the tight coupling configuration, an upward and, respectively, a downward thrust. Since the filter-holder <b>7</b> is integrally coupled to the supporting body <b>6</b>, the thrust imparted to the filter-holder <b>7</b> is transmitted to the plate <b>43</b> and is sensed by the load cells <b>44</b>, whose electrical outputs cause the electronic control unit <b>42</b> to control the start or stop of a pump (not shown) that supplies water to the boiler <b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0131" num="0130">In a different embodiment, the command to start and stop the beverage delivery may be given by the operator by applying to the handle <b>11</b> of the filter-holder <b>7</b>, when the latter is arranged in the tight coupling configuration, a torque tending to rotate the handle rightwards and, respectively, leftwards.</p>
<p id="p-0132" num="0131"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>25</b>, <b>26</b> and <b>27</b></figref> show examples of possible arrangements of the load cells <b>44</b> in order to sense the movements of the plate <b>43</b> caused by a thrust on the filter-holder <b>7</b> rightwards/leftwards and/or upwards/downwards.</p>
<p id="p-0133" num="0132">In particular, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>25</b></figref> shows a situation in which the thrusts on the filter-holder <b>7</b> rightwards/leftwards and/or upwards/downwards are sensed by the same pair of load cells <b>44</b> arranged at the smaller sides of the plate <b>43</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0134" num="0133"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>26</b></figref> shows both the situation in which the thrusts on the filter-holder <b>7</b> rightwards/leftwards and/or upwards/downwards are sensed by the same pair of load cells <b>44</b> (shown in a continuous line) arranged at the larger sides of the plate <b>43</b>, and the situation in which the thrusts on the filter-holder <b>7</b> rightwards/leftwards are sensed by a first pair of load cells <b>44</b> (shown in a dashed line) arranged at the smaller sides of the plate <b>43</b>, while the thrusts on the filter-holder <b>7</b> upwards/downwards are sensed by a second pair of load cells <b>44</b> (shown in a continuous line) arranged at the larger sides of the plate <b>43</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0135" num="0134">In the end, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>27</b></figref> shows the situation in which the thrusts on the filter-holder <b>7</b> rightwards/leftwards and/or upwards/downwards are sensed by four load cells <b>44</b> arranged near the four vertices of the plate <b>43</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0136" num="0135">Similarly to what has been said for the tight coupling and uncoupling of the coupling device <b>17</b>, in a basic embodiment, also for the command to start and stop the beverage delivery the user interface <b>40</b> may comprise a simple button or a rocker switch with two or more positions, or a pair of touch keys, or even a touch-sensitive panel capable of sensing simple touches or a more complex gesture made by the operator.</p>
<p id="p-0137" num="0136">It follows from the foregoing that the user interface <b>40</b> according to the advanced embodiment may be of a type capable of controlling both the tight coupling/uncoupling of the coupling device <b>17</b> and the start/stop of beverage delivery in response to actions made by an operator on the filter-holder <b>7</b>, or of a type capable of controlling only one of the tight coupling/uncoupling of the coupling device <b>17</b> and the start/stop of beverage delivery.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A coffee machine comprising:
<claim-text>a supporting body that delivers hot water for producing a beverage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a filter-holder that is fillable with a brewing material and is releasably coupleable to the supporting body to receive the hot water therefrom for brewing the brewing material to produce the beverage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a coupling device comprising a first coupling part mounted on and integral with the supporting body and a second coupling part carried by the filter-holder,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the coupling device is configured to cause the filter-holder to be tight-coupled in a tight-coupling configuration to the supporting body starting from an insertion configuration in which the filter-holder is loosely inserted to the supporting body by a relative rotation of the first coupling part and the second coupling part; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an automation device configured to cause the first coupling part and the second coupling part to relatively rotate at least partially automatically;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a motorised member of the automation device operable to relatively rotate the first coupling part and the second coupling part about an axis of the supporting body and in opposite rotational directions,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the motorised member comprises a ring nut rotatably mounted on the supporting body to rotate about the axis and coupleable to the filter-holder when the filter-holder is in the insertion configuration to become angularly integral with the filter-holder, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the ring nut is operable to rotate the second coupling part relative to the first coupling part to move the filter-holder between the insertion configuration to the tight-coupling configuration.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The coffee machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the ring nut comprises a seat configured to be engageable, when the filter-holder is in the insertion configuration, by a part of the filter-holder to cause the filter-holder and the ring nut to become angularly integral.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The coffee machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the seat is defined by a fork integral with the ring nut and the seat is configured to be arrangeable astride a handle of the filter-holder when the filter-holder is in the insertion configuration to cause the filter-holder and the ring nut to become angularly integral.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The coffee machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the seat is defined by a pocket integral with the ring nut and the seat is configured to be engageable by the second coupling part of the filter-holder when the filter-holder is in the insertion configuration so as to cause the filter-holder and the ring nut to become angularly integral.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. A coffee machine comprising:
<claim-text>a supporting body configured to deliver hot water for producing a beverage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a filter-holder fillable with a brewing material and configured to be releasably coupleable to the supporting body to receive hot water therefrom for brewing the brewing material to produce the beverage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a coupling device comprising a first coupling part mounted on the supporting body and a second coupling part carried by the filter-holder;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the coupling device is configured to cause the filter-holder to assume a tight-coupling configuration in which the filter-holder is tight-coupled to the supporting body starting from an insertion configuration in which the filter-holder is inserted loosely in the supporting body as a result of a relative rotation of the first coupling part and the second coupling part; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an automation device configured to cause the first coupling part and the second coupling part to relatively rotate at least partially automatically,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the automation device comprises a motorised member operable to relatively rotate the first coupling part and the second coupling part about an axis of the supporting body in opposite rotations directions,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the motorised member comprises a ring nut rotatably mounted on the supporting body to rotate about the axis and carry the first coupling part,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the ring nut is operable to rotate the first coupling part relative to the second coupling part to cause the filter-holder to assume the tight-coupling configuration completely automatically starting from the insertion configuration and vice versa, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>where the ring nut is angularly oriented around the axis to allow the filter-holder to be manually arrangeable in the insertion configuration by an upward movement of the filter-holder exclusively along the axis towards the supporting body.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The coffee machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the supporting body is shaped to cooperate with the second coupling part when the filter-holder is in the insertion configuration to substantially prevent the filter-holder from rotating about the axis during rotation of the ring nut, so-as to assume one and the same configuration relative to an operator both in the insertion configuration and in the tight coupling configuration.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The coffee machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the ring nut is angularly oriented around the axis so that in both the insertion configuration and in the tight-coupling configuration the filter-holder assumes, relative to an operator, a frontal configuration in which a handle of the filter-holder is arranged frontally relative to the operator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The coffee machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising,
<claim-text>a magnetic positioning device configured to ease positioning of the filter-holder the insertion configuration when approached to the supporting body,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the positioning device comprises one or more first magnetic elements associated with the supporting body and one or more second magnetic elements associated with the second coupling part, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first magnetic elements are arranged to cooperate magnetically with the second magnetic elements when the filter-holder is in, or is about to assume, the insertion configuration.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The coffee machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the filter-holder comprises a cup-shaped body having a bottom wall and an open end delimited by an edge, and the supporting body comprises a brewing hot water outlet and a seal surrounding the brewing hot water outlet,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first coupling part comprises a number of first projections and the second coupling part comprises a number of second projections,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second projections are arranged on the filter-holder to fail to interfere with the first projections when the filter-holder is in the insertion configuration and to slidably cooperate with the first projections during relative rotation of the first coupling part and the second coupling part</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first projections and the second projections are so shaped as to cause, during the relative rotation, the filter-holder and the supporting body to move one towards the other so that, in the tight-coupling configuration, the edge of the filter-holder is fluid-tightly pressed against the seal, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first magnetic elements are arranged on the bottom wall of the cup-shaped body, between the first projections, and the second magnetic elements are carried by respective fins in positions such that, when the filter-holder is approached to the supporting body, the first magnetic elements face corresponding second magnetic elements</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. A coffee machine comprising:
<claim-text>a supporting body designed to deliver hot water for producing a beverage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a filter-holder configured to be fillable with a brewing material and to be releasably coupleable to the supporting body to receive the hot water for brewing the brewing material and producing the beverage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a coupling device comprising a first coupling part mounted on the supporting body and a second coupling part carried by the filter-holder;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the coupling device is configured to cause the filter holder to assume a tight-coupling configuration in which the filter-holder is tight-coupled to the supporting body: starting from an insertion configuration in which the filter-holder is inserted loosely in the supporting body, as a result of a relative movement of the first coupling part and the second coupling part;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an automation device configured to cause the first coupling part and the second coupling part to relatively move at least partially automatically; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a positioning device designed to ease positioning of the filter-holder the insertion configuration</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the positioning device is a magnetic positioning device comprising one or more first magnetic elements associated with the supporting body and one or more second magnetic elements associated with the second coupling part, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first magnetic elements are so arranged as to cooperate magnetically with the second magnetic elements when the filter-holder is in, or is about to assume, the insertion configuration.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The coffee machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the filter-holder comprises a cup-shaped body having a bottom wall and an open end delimited by an edge, and the supporting body comprises a brewing hot water outlet and a seal surrounding the brewing hot water outlet,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first coupling part comprises a number of first projections, and the second coupling part comprises a number of second projections,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second projections are arranged on the filter-holder so as to fail to interfere with the first projections when the filter-holder is in the insertion configuration and to slidably cooperate with the first projections during the-relative rotation of the first coupling part and the second coupling part,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first projections and the second projections are shaped to cause, during the relative rotation, the filter-holder and the supporting body to move one towards the other so that in the tight-coupling configuration the edge of the filter-holder is fluid-tightly pressed against the seal, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first magnetic elements are arranged on the bottom wall of the cup-shaped body between the first projections and the second magnetic elements are carried by respective fins in positions such that, when the filter-holder is approached to the supporting body, the first magnetic elements face corresponding second magnetic elements</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The coffee machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the automation device comprises a motorised member operable to relatively rotate the first coupling part and the second coupling part about an axis of the supporting body and in opposite rotation directions, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first coupling part is integral with the supporting body and the motorised member comprises a ring nut rotatably mounted on the supporting body to rotate about the axis and configured to be coupleable to the filter-holder when the filter-holder is in the insertion configuration to become angularly integral with the filter-holder, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the ring nut is operable to rotate the second coupling part relative to the first coupling part to move the filter-holder from the insertion configuration to the tight coupling configuration, and vice versa.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. The coffee machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the ring nut comprises a seat configured to be engageable, when the filter holder is in the insertion configuration, by a part of the filter-holder to cause the filter-holder and the ring nut to become angularly integral.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The coffee machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the seat is defined by a fork integral with the ring nut and the seat is configured to be arrangeable astride a handle of the filter-holder when the filter-holder, is in the insertion configuration to cause the filter-holder and the ring nut to become angularly integral.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. The coffee machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the seat is defined by a pocket integral with the ring nut and configured to be engageable by the second coupling part of the filter-holder when the filter-holder is in the insertion configuration to cause the filter-holder and the ring nut to become angularly integral.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. The coffee machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the automation device comprises a motorised member operable to relatively rotate the first coupling part and the second coupling part about an axis of the supporting body and in opposite rotation directions,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the motorised member comprises a ring nut, which is rotatably mounted on the supporting body to rotate about the axis and carries the first coupling part,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the ring nut is operable to rotate the first coupling part relative to the second coupling part so as to cause the filter-holder to assume the tight-coupling configuration completely automatically starting from the insertion configuration, and vice versa, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the ring nut is angularly oriented around the axis to allow the filter-holder to be manually arrangeable in the insertion configuration by an upward movement of the filter-holder exclusively along the axis towards the supporting body.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. The coffee machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the supporting body is shaped to cooperate with the second coupling part when the filter-holder is in the insertion configuration to substantially prevent the filter-holder from rotating about the axis during rotation of the ring nut to assume one and the same configuration relative to an operator in both the insertion configuration and in the tight coupling configuration.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. The coffee machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the ring nut is angularly oriented around the axis so that in both the insertion configuration and in the tight-coupling configuration the filter-holder assumes, relative to an operator, a frontal configuration, in which a handle of the filter-holder is arranged frontally relative to the operator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. The coffee machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the ring nut has a toothing, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the automation device comprises an electric actuator and a gear transmission to kinematically couple the electric actuator and the ring nut.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. The coffee machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein, in the tight-coupling configuration, the filter-holder and the supporting body are fluid-tightly coupled.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text><b>21</b>. The coffee machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a frame on which the supporting body is mounted;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the automation device further comprises a user interface configured to sense an action by a user on the filter-holder or a force applied to the frame by a user, either directly or indirectly through the filter-holder, and to cause the coupling device to tight-couple and uncouple in response to sensed action or forces.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text><b>22</b>. The coffee machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00021">claim 21</claim-ref>, wherein the user interface is configured to sense either action by a user on the filter-holder selected from the group consisting of: rightward, leftward, upward, and downward, or a force applied directly by a user on an area of the frame.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text><b>23</b>. The coffee machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00022">claim 22</claim-ref>, wherein the user interface is further configured to sense either an action by a user on the filter-holder that is either rightward and leftward or upward and downward, or a force applied directly by a user on areas of the frame on opposite sides of the supporting body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024" num="00024">
<claim-text><b>24</b>. The coffee machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00021">claim 21</claim-ref>, wherein the user interface is further configured to cause beverage delivery to start and stop in response to a sensed action or force.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025" num="00025">
<claim-text><b>25</b>. The coffee machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00021">claim 21</claim-ref>, wherein the user interface is further configured to deliver hot water to the filter-holder to start and stop in response to a sensed action or force.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026" num="00026">
<claim-text><b>26</b>. The coffee machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00021">claim 21</claim-ref>, wherein the user interface is further configured to sense rightward, leftward, upward, and downward actions by a user on the filter-holder and to cause the coupling device to tight couple and uncouple in response to sensed rightward and leftward actions, and the beverage delivery to start and stop in response to sensed upward and downward actions, or vice versa.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027" num="00027">
<claim-text><b>27</b>. The coffee machine of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00021">claim 21</claim-ref>, wherein the user interface comprises:
<claim-text>an electronic sensory system configured to sense an action by a user on the filter-holder or a force applied to the frame by a user either directly or indirectly through the filter-holder, and responsively output an electrical output indicative of a sensed action or force; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an electronic control unit communicatively coupled to the electronic sensory system to receive the electrical output and to output electrical commands for the automation device based on the electrical output of the electronic sensory system to cause the coupling device to tight-couple and uncouple.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
