<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225472A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225472</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17928964</doc-number>
<date>20210420</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>17</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>2020209977395</doc-number>
<date>20200603</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>45</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>45</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>0054</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>45</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>2011</main-group>
<subgroup>003</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e61">FOLDABLE BAG</invention-title>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Li</last-name>
<first-name>Jiecong</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="01" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Shenzhen Lemore Marketing Consultancy Co.,Ltd</orgname>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Huang</last-name>
<first-name>Chenglan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/CN2021/088427</doc-number>
<date>20210420</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c12-date><date>20221201</date></us-371c12-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The present utility model discloses a foldable bag which comprises a first sheet, a second sheet and a third sheet, an accommodating cavity with an opening is enclosed by the first sheet and the second sheet, the third sheet extends from the second sheet and is rotatable to at least partially cover the opening, the first sheet has two corresponding first sides and second sides, the first sheet is provided with a first folding line, a second folding line and a third folding line. The foldable bag can not only contain mobile devices, but also provide support.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="75.01mm" wi="140.55mm" file="US20230225472A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="210.23mm" wi="142.58mm" file="US20230225472A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="223.69mm" wi="160.95mm" file="US20230225472A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="219.20mm" wi="156.04mm" file="US20230225472A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="235.88mm" wi="94.91mm" file="US20230225472A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present utility model belongs to the field of containing bags, and in particular, relates to a foldable bag.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Bags currently available usually have a fixed structure and cannot be transformed structurally, and they have no function of supporting mobile devices and cannot adjust the angle of support. Thus, the user of the bag cannot put a mobile device supported (such as a notebook computer and a tablet computer) on the bag in a form convenient for the user to operate.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Therefore, how to transform the bag into a supporting structure of which the supporting angle is adjustable is the technical problem to be solved by those skilled in the art.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">A technical problem mainly solved by the present utility model is to provide a foldable bag, which solves the problem that the bag in the prior art cannot be structurally transformed into a supporting structure.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">To solve the above technical problem, a technical solution adopted by the present utility model is to provide a foldable bag, the foldable bag comprises a first sheet, a second sheet and a third sheet, an accommodating cavity with an opening is enclosed by the first sheet and the second sheet, the accommodating cavity is configured to accommodate a mobile device, the third sheet extends from the second sheet and is rotatable to at least partially cover the opening, the first sheet has two corresponding first sides and second sides, both the first sheet and the second sheet have a plurality of folding lines, and the plurality of folding lines include:</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">a first folding line, being arranged on the first sheet, the beginning and the end of which are respectively adjacent to the corresponding second sides, wherein the first folding line is parallel to the first side;</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">a second folding line, being arranged on the first sheet and extending obliquely from the beginning of the first folding line to the adjacent first side;</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">a third folding line, being arranged on the first sheet and extending obliquely from the end of the first folding line to the adjacent first side;</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">a fourth folding line and a fifth folding line, both being arranged on the second sheet, respectively corresponding to the second folding line and the third folding line, and being folded through the plurality of folding lines to form a three-dimensional supporting structure.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In another embodiment of the foldable bag according to the present utility model, the third sheet is provided with a sixth folding line, which divides the third sheet into a first supporting part and a second supporting part, and the first supporting part and the second supporting part are bendable along the sixth folding line.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In another embodiment of the foldable bag according to the present utility model, the third sheet is in the form of a trapezoid whose side length gradually decreases from the joint of the third sheet and the second sheet toward the extension direction of the free end.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In another embodiment of the foldable bag according to the present utility model, the included angle formed by the second folding line and the first folding line is the same as the included angle formed by the third folding line and the first folding line.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In another embodiment of the foldable bag according to the present utility model, the included angle formed by the second folding line and the first folding line and the included angle formed by the third folding line and the first folding line range from 30&#xb0; to 60&#xb0;.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In another embodiment of the foldable bag according to the present utility model, a first area enclosed by the first folding line, the second folding line and the third folding line is provided with a first magnet, the first supporting part is provided with a second magnet, and the first magnet and the second magnet are mutually attracted.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In another embodiment of the foldable bag according to the present utility model, the second sheet is provided thereon with a soft leather which is expandable outward from the inside of the accommodating cavity.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In another embodiment of the foldable bag according to the present utility model, the first side away from the opening is provided with a barrier for blocking the mobile device from sliding off the foldable bag.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In another embodiment of the foldable bag according to the present utility model, the second sheet and the third sheet are an integrally formed structure.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In another embodiment of the foldable bag according to the present utility model, the materials of the first sheet, the second sheet and the third sheet are flexible materials.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Beneficial effects of the present utility model are as follows: the present utility model discloses a foldable bag, which can be folded and transformed along folding lines arranged on the body of the bag and thus transformed into a supporting structure for supporting mobile devices.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a schematic view illustrating an unfolded and untransformed state in an embodiment of a foldable bag according to the present utility model.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a front schematic view in another embodiment of the foldable bag according to the present utility model.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a back schematic view in another embodiment of the foldable bag according to the present utility model.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is a schematic view of a first supporting form in another embodiment of the foldable bag according to the present utility model.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is a schematic view of the first supporting form in another embodiment of the foldable bag according to the present utility model.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is a schematic view of a second supporting form in another embodiment of the foldable bag according to the present utility model.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> is a schematic view illustrating the use state in the first supporting form in another embodiment of the foldable bag according to the present utility model.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> is a schematic view illustrating the use state in the second supporting form in another embodiment of the foldable bag according to the present utility model.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">To facilitate the understanding of the present utility model, the present utility model will be explained in more detail hereinafter with reference to attached drawings and specific embodiments. Preferred embodiments of the present utility model are given in the attached drawings. However, the present utility model can be implemented in many different forms and is not limited to the embodiments described in this specification. On the contrary, these embodiments are provided to make the understanding of the disclosure of the present utility model more thorough and comprehensive.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">It shall be noted that, unless otherwise defined, all technical and scientific terms used in this specification have the same meanings as those commonly understood by those skilled in the art of the present utility model. Terms used in the specification of the present utility model are only for the purpose of describing specific embodiments, and are not intended to limit the present utility model.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, the foldable bag comprises a first sheet <b>1</b>, a second sheet <b>2</b> and a third sheet <b>3</b>, an accommodating cavity <b>4</b> with an opening is enclosed by the first sheet <b>1</b> and the second sheet <b>2</b>, the accommodating cavity <b>4</b> is configured to accommodate a mobile device, the third sheet <b>3</b> extends from the second sheet <b>2</b> and is rotatable to at least partially cover the opening, the first sheet <b>1</b> has two corresponding first sides <b>11</b> and second sides <b>12</b>, both the first sheet <b>1</b> and the second sheet <b>2</b> have a plurality of folding lines, and the plurality of folding lines include:</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">a first folding line Z<b>1</b>, being arranged on the first sheet <b>1</b>, the beginning Z<b>11</b> and the end Z<b>12</b> of which are respectively adjacent to the corresponding second sides <b>12</b>, wherein the first folding line Z<b>1</b> is parallel to the first side <b>11</b>;</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">a second folding line Z<b>2</b>, being arranged on the first sheet <b>1</b> and extending obliquely from the beginning Z<b>11</b> of the first folding line Z<b>1</b> to the adjacent first side <b>11</b>;</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">a third folding line Z<b>3</b>, being arranged on the first sheet <b>1</b> and extending obliquely from the end Z<b>12</b> of the first folding line Z<b>1</b> to the adjacent first side <b>11</b>;</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">a fourth folding line Z<b>4</b> and a fifth folding line Z<b>5</b>, both being arranged on the second sheet <b>2</b>, respectively corresponding to the second folding line Z<b>2</b> and the third folding line Z<b>3</b>, and being folded through the plurality of folding lines to form a three-dimensional supporting structure.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The mobile device may be a notebook computer or a tablet computer or the like, the shapes of the first sheet <b>1</b> and the second sheet <b>2</b> are preferably rectangular, but they may also be other shapes.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Preferably, referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, the side of the second sheet <b>2</b> at the side of the opening is a third side <b>13</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">More preferably, the fourth folding line Z<b>4</b> extends obliquely to the third side <b>13</b> from the second side <b>12</b> adjacent thereto, the fifth folding line Z<b>5</b> extends obliquely to the third side <b>13</b> from the second side <b>12</b> adjacent thereto, the second sheet <b>2</b> is provided thereon with a seventh folding line Z<b>7</b> parallel to the first folding line Z<b>1</b>, the beginning of the seventh folding line Z<b>7</b> is connected to the fifth folding line Z<b>5</b>, and the end of the seventh folding line Z<b>7</b> is connected to the fourth folding line Z<b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Preferably, the included angle formed by the second folding line Z<b>2</b> and the first folding line Z<b>1</b> is the same as the included angle formed by the third folding line Z<b>3</b> and the first folding line Z<b>1</b>, and the included angle formed by the seventh folding line Z<b>7</b> and the fourth folding line Z<b>4</b> is the same as the included angle formed by the seventh folding line Z<b>7</b> and the fifth folding line Z<b>5</b>. This form ensures that the foldable bag can have symmetry when folded along the above folding lines, so that the mobile device can be stably placed on the foldable bag that has been transformed and folded without lateral sliding or overturning.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Preferably, the included angle formed by the second folding line Z<b>2</b> and the first folding line Z<b>1</b> and the included angle formed by the third folding line Z<b>3</b> and the first folding line Z<b>1</b> range from 30&#xb0; to 60&#xb0;, and within this range of angles, the foldable bag can be correspondingly transformed and folded into supporting structures with different angles to meet the requirements of different supporting heights.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Preferably, referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the third sheet <b>3</b> is provided with a sixth folding line Z<b>6</b>, which divides the third sheet <b>3</b> into a first supporting part <b>31</b> and a second supporting part <b>32</b>, and the first supporting part <b>31</b> and the second supporting part <b>32</b> are bendable along the sixth folding line Z<b>6</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Preferably, referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the third sheet <b>3</b> is in the form of a trapezoid whose side length gradually decreases from the joint of the third sheet <b>3</b> and the second sheet <b>2</b> toward the extension direction of the free end, and more preferably, the shape of the third sheet <b>3</b> can not only be a trapezoid, but also be a semicircle or an ellipse; that is, any shape of which the width gradually decreases from the joint of the third sheet <b>3</b> and the second sheet <b>2</b> toward the extension direction of the free end is possible.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Preferably, referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, a first area Y<b>1</b> enclosed by the first folding line Z<b>1</b>, the second folding line Z<b>2</b> and the third folding line Z<b>3</b> is provided with a first magnet, the first supporting part <b>31</b> is provided with a second magnet, and the first magnet and the second magnet are mutually attracted. On the one hand, the first magnet and the second magnet are arranged so that when the foldable bag is unopened as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, the third sheet <b>3</b> can be tightly attached to the first sheet <b>1</b>, and the opening can be well covered to prevent the mobile device in the foldable bag from falling off; and on the other hand, the first magnet and the second magnet are arranged so that the first supporting part <b>31</b> can be tightly attached and attracted to the inner side of the first area Y<b>1</b> of the first sheet <b>1</b> during the subsequent folding and transformation (another supporting form of the foldable bag as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>), and thus the first supporting part <b>31</b> of the third sheet <b>3</b> can stably support the first sheet <b>1</b>, thereby achieving the purpose of stably supporting the mobile device placed on the first sheet <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Preferably, referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref>, the first side <b>11</b> away from the opening is provided with a barrier T<b>1</b> for blocking the mobile device from sliding off the foldable bag, and the barrier T<b>1</b> has two forms. When the foldable bag is not transformed and folded, the barrier T<b>1</b> is attached to the first sheet <b>1</b>; and when the foldable bag is transformed and folded, the barrier T<b>1</b> can be lifted from the first sheet <b>1</b>, and a notch formed by the lifting operation faces the opening so that when the mobile device is placed on the foldable bag, the lower end of the mobile device can be stuck in the notch or abut against the notch to prevent the mobile device from slipping off</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref>, the foldable bag is folded along the first folding line Z<b>1</b>, the second folding line Z<b>2</b>, the third folding line Z<b>3</b>, the fourth folding line Z<b>4</b> and the fifth folding line Z<b>5</b>, and is transformed into a first supporting form as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>. In the first supporting form, the first area Y<b>1</b> of the first sheet <b>1</b> is tilted, and the second and fourth folding lines Z<b>2</b> and Z<b>4</b> as well as the third and fifth folding lines Z<b>3</b> and Z<b>5</b> divide the second side <b>12</b> into two parts which include a first side part <b>121</b> and a second side part <b>122</b>, wherein the first side part <b>121</b> is close to the opening, and the first side part <b>121</b> is bent toward the inside of the foldable bag; a third supporting part P<b>1</b> is enclosed by the fourth folding line Z<b>4</b>, the fifth folding line Z<b>5</b>, the first side part <b>121</b> and the third side <b>13</b>, and the third supporting part P<b>1</b> is located on the horizontal plane; a fourth supporting part L<b>1</b> is enclosed by the first side part <b>121</b>, the second folding line Z<b>2</b>, the third folding line Z<b>3</b> and the first side <b>11</b> adjacent to the second folding line Z<b>2</b> and the third folding line Z<b>3</b>, the third supporting part P<b>1</b> and the fourth supporting part L <b>1</b> constitute the supporting framework of the first supporting form of the foldable bag, and the third supporting part P<b>1</b> serves as the supporting base of the fourth supporting part L<b>1</b>, thereby enhancing the supporting strength of the foldable bag.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Preferably, the included angle formed by the plane where the fourth supporting part L<b>1</b> is located and the plane where the third supporting part P<b>1</b> is located ranges from 80&#xb0; to 100&#xb0;, and in this embodiment, the included angle formed by the plane where the fourth supporting part L<b>1</b> is located and the plane where the third supporting part P<b>1</b> is located is 95&#xb0;. The included angle formed is close to a vertical angle of 90&#xb0;, which makes the supporting more stable.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Preferably, the first supporting form may be further divided into two branch forms, which include a first branch form and a second branch form. In the first branch form as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>, the first supporting part <b>31</b> of the third sheet <b>3</b> extends into the accommodating cavity <b>4</b> by being bent, and this form reduces the area occupied by the foldable bag and improves the space utilization rate, so that the foldable bag is suitable for use on a horizontal plane or desktop with a small area; while in the second branch form as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, the third sheet <b>3</b> is opened and laid flat on the horizontal plane, and this form can facilitate the user to quickly open and close the opening so that the mobile device can be quickly placed into or taken out of the foldable bag, thereby improving the efficiency of storage, transformation and folding of the foldable bag, and saving time.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref>, the foldable bag is folded along the first folding line Z<b>1</b>, the second folding line Z<b>2</b>, the third folding line Z<b>3</b>, the fourth folding line Z<b>4</b>, the fifth folding line Z<b>5</b>, and the sixth folding line Z<b>6</b>, and is transformed into a second supporting form as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>. The second supporting form is similar to the first supporting form, except that the first supporting part <b>31</b> is closely attached to and supports the inner side of the first area Y<b>1</b> of the first sheet <b>1</b>; the included angle formed by the plane where the third supporting part P<b>1</b> is located and the plane where the fourth supporting part L<b>1</b> is located is an acute angle, and the included angle is obviously smaller than the included angle formed by the plane where the third supporting part P<b>1</b> is located and the plane where the fourth supporting part L<b>1</b> is located in the first supporting form; the first side part <b>121</b> in the second supporting form is not bent towards the inner side of the foldable bag as deep as the first side part <b>121</b> in the first supporting form; that is, when the second supporting form is viewed in the direction of the view shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the first side part <b>121</b> does not extend beyond the fourth folding line Z<b>4</b> or the fifth folding line Z<b>5</b>; however, when the first supporting form is viewed in the direction of the view shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the first side part <b>121</b> obviously extends beyond the fourth folding line Z<b>4</b> and the fifth folding line Z<b>5</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">When the first supporting form is compared to the second supporting form, the included angle formed by the plane where the fourth supporting part L<b>1</b> is located and the plane where the third supporting part P<b>1</b> is located is closer to 90&#xb0; in the first supporting form, so the first area Y<b>1</b> is tilted higher and the supporting angle is higher, and thus the first supporting form is a high-angle supporting form, and the second supporting form is a low-angle supporting form.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Preferably, referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>, the second sheet <b>2</b> is provided thereon with a soft leather <b>5</b> which is expandable outward from the inside of the accommodating cavity <b>4</b>. With arrangement of the soft leather <b>5</b>, some small articles, such as a mouse and a charger, can be placed in the foldable bag at a position corresponding to the soft leather <b>5</b>. Because the soft leather <b>5</b> can be expanded and deformed, the accommodating volume of the foldable bag can be increased, and the foldable bag will not be damaged when many articles are placed in the foldable bag.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Preferably, the second sheet <b>2</b> and the third sheet <b>3</b> are an integrally formed structure, which can enhance the connection strength between the second sheet <b>2</b> and the third sheet <b>3</b>, and prevent the connection position of the third sheet <b>3</b> and the second sheet <b>2</b> from being worn or broken by repeatedly bending the connection position of the third sheet <b>3</b> and the second sheet <b>2</b>, thereby prolonging the service life of the third sheet <b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">Preferably, the materials of the first sheet <b>1</b>, the second sheet <b>2</b> and the third sheet <b>3</b> are flexible materials, such as plastic, elastic metal sheets and leather products or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Preferably, the inner surface of the accommodating cavity <b>4</b> of the foldable bag is provided with an inner bag, which can accommodate articles with a smaller volume.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">Based on the above embodiments, the present utility model discloses a foldable bag, which comprises a first sheet, a second sheet and a third sheet, an accommodating cavity with an opening is enclosed by the first sheet and the second sheet, the accommodating cavity is configured to accommodate a mobile device, the third sheet extends from the second sheet and is rotatable to at least partially cover the opening, the first sheet has two corresponding first sides and second sides, both the first sheet and the second sheet have a plurality of folding lines, the plurality of folding lines include: a first folding line, being arranged on the first sheet, the beginning and the end of which are respectively adjacent to the corresponding second sides, wherein the first folding line is parallel to the first side; a second folding line, being arranged on the first sheet and extending obliquely from the beginning of the first folding line to the adjacent first side; a third folding line, being arranged on the first sheet and extending obliquely from the end of the first folding line to the adjacent first side; a fourth folding line and a fifth folding line, both being arranged on the second sheet, respectively corresponding to the second folding line and the third folding line, and being folded through the plurality of folding lines to form a three-dimensional supporting structure. The foldable bag can not only carry mobile devices, but also be folded and transformed into a supporting structure.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">What described above are only embodiments of the present utility model, and thus are not intended to limit the patent scope of the present utility model; any equivalent structural changes made by using the contents of the specification and the attached drawings of the present utility model, or direct or indirect application in other related technical fields, are included in the scope claimed in the present utility model.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. foldable bag, being characterized in that, the foldable bag comprising a first sheet, a second sheet and a third sheet, an accommodating cavity with an opening being enclosed by the first sheet and the second sheet, the accommodating cavity being configured to accommodate a mobile device, the third sheet extending from the second sheet and being rotatable to at least partially cover the opening, the first sheet having two corresponding first sides and second sides, both the first sheet and the second sheet having a plurality of folding lines, the plurality of folding lines including:
<claim-text>a first folding line, being arranged on the first sheet, the beginning and the end of which are respectively adjacent to the corresponding second sides, wherein the first folding line is parallel to the first side;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second folding line, being arranged on the first sheet and extending obliquely from the beginning of the first folding line to the adjacent first side;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third folding line, being arranged on the first sheet and extending obliquely from the end of the first folding line to the adjacent first side;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fourth folding line and a fifth folding line, both being arranged on the second sheet, respectively corresponding to the second folding line and the third folding line, and being folded through the plurality of folding lines to form a three-dimensional supporting structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The foldable bag according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, being characterized in that, the third sheet is provided with a sixth folding line, which divides the third sheet into a first supporting part and a second supporting part, and the first supporting part and the second supporting part are bendable along the sixth folding line.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. he foldable bag according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, being characterized in that, the third sheet is in the form of a trapezoid whose side length gradually decreases from the joint of the third sheet and the second sheet toward the extension direction of the free end.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The foldable bag according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, being characterized in that, the included angle formed by the second folding line and the first folding line is the same as the included angle formed by the third folding line and the first folding line.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The foldable bag according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, being characterized in that, the included angle formed by the second folding line and the first folding line and the included angle formed by the third folding line and the first folding line range from 30&#xb0; to 60&#xb0;.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The foldable bag according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, being characterized in that, a first area enclosed by the first folding line, the second folding line and the third folding line is provided with a first magnet, the first supporting part is provided with a second magnet, and the first magnet and the second magnet are mutually attracted.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The foldable bag according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, being characterized in that, the second sheet is provided thereon with a soft leather which is expandable outward from the inside of the accommodating cavity.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The foldable bag according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, being characterized in that, the first side away from the opening is provided with a barrier for blocking the mobile device from sliding off the foldable bag.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The foldable bag according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, being characterized in that, the second sheet and the third sheet are an integrally formed structure.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The foldable bag according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, being characterized in that, the materials of the first sheet, the second sheet and the third sheet are flexible materials.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
