<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225513A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230711" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225513</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17577534</doc-number>
<date>20220118</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>17</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>40</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>402</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="pmmydbfwqu6bt">CHAIR BACK ADJUSTMENT SYSTEM</invention-title>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>ALLSEATING CORPORATION</orgname>
<address>
<city>Mississauga</city>
<country>CA</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CA</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>NEIL</last-name>
<first-name>Gary</first-name>
<address>
<city>Mississauga</city>
<country>CA</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="01" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>PAESANO</last-name>
<first-name>Marco</first-name>
<address>
<city>Oakville</city>
<country>CA</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="02" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>NICOLL</last-name>
<first-name>David</first-name>
<address>
<city>Mississauga</city>
<country>CA</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A back adjustment system for a chair having a frame that includes a top end and bottom end. The back adjustment system may further include a chair back having a first end and a second end. The first end of the chair back may be mounted solely to the top end of the frame of the chair and also includes an adjusting means, which may be mounted at the bottom end of the frame. The adjusting means may allow for engagement between the bottom end of the frame and the second end of the chair back. The adjusting means may be adapted to telescopically engage between the bottom end of the frame and the second end of the chair back thereby solely moving the second end of the chair back from a retracted position to an extended position.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="217.34mm" wi="184.40mm" file="US20230225513A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="229.62mm" wi="169.50mm" file="US20230225513A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="210.82mm" wi="143.76mm" file="US20230225513A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="205.91mm" wi="119.63mm" file="US20230225513A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="217.85mm" wi="160.19mm" file="US20230225513A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="217.85mm" wi="160.19mm" file="US20230225513A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="207.18mm" wi="160.53mm" file="US20230225513A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="207.18mm" wi="160.53mm" file="US20230225513A1-20230720-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="208.45mm" wi="141.39mm" file="US20230225513A1-20230720-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="223.86mm" wi="159.85mm" file="US20230225513A1-20230720-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="219.79mm" wi="171.37mm" file="US20230225513A1-20230720-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading level="1" id="h-0001">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This invention relates in general to adjustment mechanisms for chairs and more particularly a back adjustment system for a chair and more specifically the movement of a chair back.</p>
<heading level="1" id="h-0002">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">There are wide variety of office chairs that have been designed to be more ergonomic and provide a variety of different functions and adjustments. These adjustments are typically in relation to height of the chair seat or arm positioning, and more specifically chair back support for the spine and the back, which are susceptible to the harmful effects of a prolonged sitting position. In general, chair have included adjustments to the height of the chair back itself so that the spinal support can be adjusted relative to the height of the individual. Other adjustment mechanisms have focused on adjusting the depth of spinal support, which can be accomplished by adjusting the chair back itself. Many of the adjustment mechanisms include complex arrangements and require the user to reach under the chair seat and do not provide an easy accessible adjustment mechanism or steady support.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">A back adjustment system for chair back that focuses on the chair back, which is easy for the individual to adjust, maintains the ergonomics of the chair back, provides improved spinal support, allows for support along a horizontal plane by adjusting the entire chair back is desirable.</p>
<heading level="1" id="h-0003">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">An object of one aspect of the present invention is to provide a chair back adjustment system.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In accordance with one aspect of the present invention there is provided a back adjustment system for a chair having a frame that includes a top end and bottom end. The back adjustment system may further include a chair back having a first end and a second end. The first end of the chair back may be mounted solely to the top end of the frame of the chair.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The back adjustment system for a chair may further include an adjusting means, which may be mounted at the bottom end of the frame. The adjusting means may allow for engagement between the bottom end of the frame and the second end of the chair back. The adjusting means may be adapted to telescopically engage between the bottom end of the frame and the second end of the chair back thereby solely moving the second end of the chair back from a retracted position to an extended position.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Preferably, the adjusting means may further include a ratchet assembly that extends from the mid point of the bottom end of the frame outwards along a horizontal plane. The ratchet assembly may allow for the second end of the chair back to move outwards away from the frame.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Conveniently, the adjusting mechanism may include a adjustment mechanism which may be actuated by a least one push button positioned on the second end on the chair back.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading level="1" id="h-0004">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">A detailed description of the preferred embodiment is provided herein below by way of example only and with reference to the following drawings, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a perspective view and illustrates a back adjustment system for a chair in accordance with the preferred embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> in a back perspective view, illustrates the back adjustment system for a chair of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> in a top view, illustrates the back adjustment system for a chair of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b><i>a</i></figref> in a cross sectional view along the lines 4-4, illustrates the back adjustment system for a chair of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b><i>b</i></figref> in a cross sectional view along the lines 4-4, illustrates the back adjustment system for a chair of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b><i>c</i></figref> in a cross sectional view along the lines 4-4, illustrates the back adjustment system for a chair of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b><i>d</i></figref> in a cross sectional view along the lines 4-4, illustrates the back adjustment system for a chair of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> in a front perspective view, illustrates the back adjustment system for a chair of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> in a back perspective view, illustrates the back adjustment system for a chair of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b><i>a</i></figref> in a side view, illustrates the back adjustment system for a chair of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b><i>b</i></figref> in a side view, illustrates the back adjustment system for a chair of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In the drawings, preferred embodiments of the invention are illustrated by way of example. It is to be expressly understood that the description and drawings are only for the purpose of illustration and as an aid to understanding, and are not intended as a definition of the limits of the invention.</p>
<heading level="1" id="h-0005">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> to <b>7</b><i>b</i></figref>, there is illustrated a back adjustment system <b>10</b> for a chair <b>12</b> in accordance with a preferred embodiment of the present invention. The back adjustment system <b>10</b> for a chair <b>12</b> includes a frame <b>14</b> including a top end <b>16</b> and bottom end <b>18</b> and a chair back <b>20</b> having a first end <b>22</b> and a second end <b>24</b> where the first end <b>22</b> of the chair <b>20</b> back is mounted solely to the top end <b>16</b> of the frame <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">An adjusting means <b>26</b> may be mounted at the bottom end <b>18</b> of the frame <b>14</b> for engagement between the bottom end <b>18</b> of the frame <b>14</b> and the second end <b>24</b> of the chair back <b>20</b>. The adjusting means <b>26</b> may be adapted to telescopically engage between the bottom end <b>18</b> of the frame <b>14</b> and the second end <b>24</b> of the chair back <b>20</b>. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>7</b><i>a</i> and <b>7</b><i>b</i></figref>, this configuration may allow for the sole movement of the second end <b>24</b> of the chair back <b>20</b> from a retracted position <b>28</b> to an extended position <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The frame <b>14</b> may be configured to mirror the shape of the chair back <b>20</b> whereby the frame <b>14</b> is not visible when positioned in front of the chair <b>12</b>. The frame <b>14</b> may be made from a variety of materials including metal and plastic, by way of example only.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The chair back <b>20</b> may be configured into a variety of shapes that provide support for a user when seated in the chair <b>12</b>. In particular, the top end <b>22</b> of the chair back <b>20</b> securely engages with the top end <b>16</b> of the frame <b>14</b>. More specifically the chair back <b>20</b> and the frame <b>14</b> only engage with one another directly at the top end <b>22</b> of the chair back <b>20</b>. The secure engagement between the top end <b>22</b> of the chair back <b>20</b> and top end <b>16</b> of the frame <b>14</b> occurs with the aid of fasteners and or adhesives, while allowing flexibility and movement in the chair back <b>20</b> itself at its second end <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">More specifically the chair back <b>20</b> can flex along its horizontal and vertical plane or in an angular pivoting motion thereby providing varying support for the user in the chair <b>12</b>. The chair back <b>20</b> may further include a lumbar zone <b>40</b> that moves with the chair back to provide support to user in various positions. The chair back <b>20</b> may further include a covering, such as an upholstered covering or mesh covering, by way of example only.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>3</b> to <b>5</b></figref>, the adjusting means <b>26</b> may be positioned at a mid point <b>32</b> on the bottom end <b>18</b> of the frame <b>14</b>. The adjusting means <b>26</b> may further include a ratchet assembly <b>38</b> that extends from the mid point <b>32</b> of the bottom end <b>18</b> of the frame <b>14</b> outwards along a horizontal plane. More specifically the ratchet assembly <b>38</b> has a first end <b>40</b> and second end <b>42</b>. The first end <b>40</b> is mounted to the mid point <b>32</b> of the bottom end <b>18</b> of the frame <b>14</b> and the second end <b>42</b> of the ratchet assembly <b>38</b> is mounted to the second end <b>24</b> of the chair back <b>20</b>. When the adjusting means <b>26</b> is engaged and the ratchet assembly <b>38</b> extends outwards, the second end <b>42</b> of the ratchet assembly <b>38</b> moves the second end <b>24</b> of the chair back <b>20</b> outwards away from the frame <b>14</b>. The ratchet assembly <b>38</b> may have pre-determined steps that provide pre-determined positions for the chair back&#x2019;s <b>20</b> movement. The pre-determined positions reflect increasing movement of the chair back <b>20</b> away from the frame <b>14</b>, thereby providing increasing back support to the user.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> the adjusting means <b>26</b> may further include an adjustment mechanism <b>34</b>. The adjustment mechanism <b>34</b> may include at least one push button assembly <b>36</b> positioned at the second end <b>42</b> of the ratchet assembly <b>38</b> and adapted to engage the second end <b>24</b> on the chair back <b>20</b>. Conveniently a second push button assembly <b>36</b> may be included to allow for easy access to the adjusting means <b>26</b> for the adjustment of the chair back <b>20</b> from either side of the chair <b>12</b> by the user. When engaged, the push button assembly <b>36</b> releases the ratchet assembly <b>38</b> and the user can position the chair back <b>20</b> in the desired position. When the push button assembly is disengaged by the user and the ratchet assembly <b>38</b> re-engages and the chair back <b>20</b> is locked into the desired position.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Other variations and modifications of the invention are possible. All such modifications or variations are believed to be within the sphere and scope of the invention as defined by the claims appended hereto.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>I claim:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A back adjustment system for a chair comprising:
<claim-text>(a) a frame including a top end and bottom end;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) a chair back having a first end and a second end, the first end of the chair back is mounted solely to the top end of the frame; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) an adjusting means mounted at the bottom end of the frame for engagement between the bottom end of the frame and the second end of the chair back; 
<claim-text>wherein the adjusting means is adapted to telescopically engage between the bottom end of the frame and the second end of the chair back thereby solely moving the second end of the chair back from a retracted position to an extended position.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. A back adjustment system for a chair as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the adjusting means further comprises a ratchet assembly.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. A back adjustment system for a chair as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref> wherein the ratchet assembly is mounted to a mid point at the bottom end of the frame and a second end of the ratchet assembly is mounted to the second end of the chair back.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. A back adjustment system for a chair as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref> wherein the ratchet assembly further includes pre-determined steps for securing the chair back in a specified position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. A back adjustment system for a chair as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the adjusting means further comprises an adjustment mechanism.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. A back adjustment system for a chair as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref> wherein the adjustment mechanism is actuated by a least one push button positioned on the second end on the chair back.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. A back adjustment system for a chair as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref> wherein the adjusting means further comprises a ratchet assembly.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. A back adjustment system for a chair as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref> wherein the ratchet assembly is mounted to a mid point at the bottom end of the frame and a second end of the ratchet assembly is mounted to the second end of the chair back.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. A back adjustment system for a chair as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref> wherein the ratchet assembly further includes pre-determined steps for securing the chair back in a specified position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. A back adjustment system for a chair as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref> wherein the adjusting means moves the chair back in horizontal and vertical planes and in an angular pivoting motion.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
