<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225344A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225344</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17579645</doc-number>
<date>20220120</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>17</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>23</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>152</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>23</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>19</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>65</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>85</main-group>
<subgroup>34</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>65</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>81</main-group>
<subgroup>20</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>23</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>152</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20160801</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>23</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>19</main-group>
<subgroup>03</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>B</section>
<class>65</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>85</main-group>
<subgroup>34</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>B</section>
<class>65</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>81</main-group>
<subgroup>2069</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>23</class>
<subclass>V</subclass>
<main-group>2002</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">SYSTEM AND METHOD OF ACCELERATED INDIVIDUAL BANANA RIPENING</invention-title>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Pollack</last-name>
<first-name>Alex J.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Panama City Beach</city>
<state>FL</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Pollack</last-name>
<first-name>Alex J.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Panama City Beach</city>
<state>FL</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A system that includes a plurality of banana containers is provided. Each banana container has a first container end to receive an unpeeled banana and a second container end. The system includes a gas dispensing regulator connected to a plurality of banana containers. The gas dispensing regulator includes a plurality of gas meters having a one-to-one correspondence with the plurality of banana containers. A corresponding meter is connected to the second container end of a corresponding banana container to dispense a corresponding amount of ripening gas into the corresponding banana container. The system can limit the pressure of the ripening gas in the banana container using the closing device to vary the ripening rate of the bananas. This can avoid spoiling the taste of the bananas.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="168.66mm" wi="129.37mm" file="US20230225344A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="185.34mm" wi="131.40mm" file="US20230225344A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="70.44mm" wi="102.87mm" file="US20230225344A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="76.71mm" wi="92.88mm" file="US20230225344A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="68.50mm" wi="100.75mm" file="US20230225344A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="147.07mm" wi="134.45mm" file="US20230225344A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="147.07mm" wi="145.12mm" file="US20230225344A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This disclosure relates generally to systems and methods for controlled ripening of fresh fruits and especially bananas, where the rate of ripening is directed to selectively ripening individual bananas.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Currently bananas when bought from the grocer, whether bought in hands of 4, 6 or 8 bananas, all may be unripe together making them uneatable. Later when they reach the stage of ripening, they ripen all at the same time, usually leading to having too many ripe bananas at the same time. Very often, overripe bananas are discarded in the trash which results in wasted money. Depending on the number of bananas available at the grocer, banana hands may include hands in a barely ripe stage, from which to select. Still all the bananas in a hand will ripen at the same time.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The banana changes color in stages of ripening. The color of a banana at each stage may be used to determine the fiber to sugar content. The underripe stage has the highest fiber and lowest sugar content as compared to the overripe stage which has the highest sugar content and lowest fiber. For example, green bananas are considered underripe and can have the lowest sugar content. The next stage is when a banana is yellow. At this stage, the banana is high in fiber and has a low sugar content. During this stage, the banana is yellow and is ripe with high antioxidant and fiber content, which is the preferred stage for consumption. The next stage, the banana is very ripe. At the very ripe stage, the banana has yellow, but is covered with brown spots. So as noted, the yellow stage is the best for consumption, but without intervention, all bananas of a hand will reach this stage simultaneously, possibly leading to waste.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Therefore, there is a need for an improved system of ripening bananas, so that they reach the yellow stage of ripeness consecutively, not simultaneously.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Embodiments include a system and method of ripening bananas to vary a rate of ripening of the bananas.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">An aspect of the embodiments includes a system that includes a plurality of banana containers. Each banana container has a first container end to receive an unpeeled banana and a second container end. The system includes a gas generator including a gas dispensing regulator, the gas regulator is connected with the plurality of banana containers. The gas dispensing regulator includes a plurality of gas metering devices having a one-to-one correspondence with the plurality of banana containers. A corresponding meter is connected to the second container end of a corresponding banana container to dispense a corresponding amount of ripening gas into the corresponding banana container.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Another aspect of the embodiments includes a method that comprises housing, in a plurality of banana containers, unpeeled bananas. Each banana container has a first container end to receive an unpeeled banana and a second container end. The method includes dispensing, by a gas generator connected to the plurality of banana containers, a ripening gas into corresponding banana containers at different flow rates. The gas generator including a plurality of gas meters having a one-to-one correspondence with the plurality of banana containers, a corresponding meter connected to the second container end of the corresponding banana container.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">A more particular description briefly stated above will be rendered by reference to specific embodiments thereof that are illustrated in the appended drawings. Understanding that these drawings depict only typical embodiments and are not therefore to be considered to be limiting of its scope, the embodiments will be described and explained with additional specificity and detail through the use of the accompanying drawings in which:</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> illustrates a controlled banana ripening system according to embodiments herein;</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> illustrates a cap for the gas generator compartment of the system of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> illustrates an end view of the gas dispensing regulator of the system of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> illustrates an end view of the banana container cinching closure device of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> illustrates a side view of the system with a banana loaded in a banana container, with the end closure tightened; and</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> illustrates a flowchart of ripening a hand of bananas.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Embodiments are described herein with reference to the attached figures wherein like reference numerals are used throughout the figures to designate similar or equivalent elements. The figures are not drawn to scale and they are provided merely to illustrate aspects disclosed herein. Several disclosed aspects are described below with reference to non-limiting example applications for illustration. It should be understood that numerous specific details, relationships, and methods are set forth to provide a full understanding of the embodiments disclosed herein. One having ordinary skill in the relevant art, however, will readily recognize that the disclosed embodiments can be practiced without one or more of the specific details or with other methods. In other instances, well-known structures or operations are not shown in detail to avoid obscuring aspects disclosed herein. The embodiments are not limited by the illustrated ordering of acts or events, as some acts may occur in different orders and/or concurrently with other acts or events. Furthermore, not all illustrated acts or events are required to implement a methodology in accordance with the embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Notwithstanding that the numerical ranges and parameters setting forth the broad scope are approximations, the numerical values set forth in specific non-limiting examples are reported as precisely as possible. Any numerical value, however, inherently contains certain errors necessarily resulting from the standard deviation found in their respective testing measurements. Moreover, all ranges disclosed herein are to be understood to encompass any and all sub-ranges subsumed therein. For example, a range of &#x201c;less than 10&#x201d; can include any and all sub-ranges between (and including) the minimum value of zero and the maximum value of 10, that is, any and all sub-ranges having a minimum value of equal to or greater than zero and a maximum value of equal to or less than 10, e.g., 1 to 4.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The terms &#x201c;front,&#x201d; &#x201c;back,&#x201d; &#x201c;rear&#x201d; or &#x201c;side&#x201d; are relative terms and used for a frame of reference when describing the components. For example, the &#x201c;front&#x201d; may be the &#x201c;back.&#x201d; The &#x201c;side&#x201d; may be the right side, left side, a front side, or a rear side. The &#x201c;side&#x201d; may be a &#x201c;front&#x201d; or a &#x201c;back.&#x201d;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The inventor has determined that by varying a ripening treatment applied to fruit such as bananas, a consumer can vary the ripening of one or more individual bananas to be ripe on different days. The ripening treatment may include varying at least one of the exposure level and pressure of ethylene gas to accelerate the ripening of the bananas at different rates.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The controlled banana ripening system, as described herein, allows a consumer to selectively induce a certain level of ethylene gas and retain a certain concentration of ethylene gas applied to the skin of a banana to control the ripening of a banana or pair of bananas.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The controlled banana ripening system varies the ripening of a banana through variations in the thickness of a banana container, to retain a specific concentration of ethylene gas within the banana container, for example. By achieving a variation in one or more of the pressure, amount, and concentrations of ethylene gas, within in different containers, the system controls the ripening of the banana in each container at different rates and not simultaneously.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">For example, the consumer can buy a hand of green bananas and ripening each banana sequentially or on different days by storing green bananas in the banana ripening system, resulting in the treated bananas becoming ripe sequentially, approximately on different days. However, most bananas that are sold in grocers are already exposed to an amount of ethylene gas to begin a ripening process.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Additionally, the consumer can buy an amount of partially ripen bananas and ripening each unripen banana sequentially or on different days by storing of the unripen bananas in the banana ripening system, resulting in the treated bananas becoming ripe sequentially, approximately on different days.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The banana ripening system <b>100</b> will be described in relation to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>-<b>5</b></figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> illustrates a controlled banana ripening system according to embodiments herein. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> illustrates a cap device <b>110</b> of the gas generator compartment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> illustrates an end view of the gas dispensing regulator of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> illustrates an end view of the banana container cinching closure of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> illustrates a side view of the system <b>100</b> with a banana loaded in a banana container.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> the system <b>100</b> may include a plurality of banana containers <b>130</b>, each container <b>130</b> has a first container end <b>134</b> to receive an unpeeled banana <b>5</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>) and a second container end <b>136</b>. In this example, the number of banana container <b>130</b> is six denoted by <b>130</b><sup>1</sup>, <b>130</b><sup>2</sup>, <b>130</b><sup>3</sup>, <b>130</b><sup>4</sup>, <b>130</b><sup>5 </sup>and <b>130</b><sup>6</sup>. The system may have any number of banana containers greater than one. The number of sleeves may be 2-8, for example. Each container is configured to receive therein an unpeeled banana, as best seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>. The banana may be a green banana.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The banana container <b>130</b> comprises a housing <b>132</b> having the first container end <b>134</b> and the second container end <b>136</b> and a wall thickness to surround skin of the unpeeled banana between the first container end <b>134</b> and the second container end <b>136</b>. The housing <b>132</b> of the container <b>130</b> may include polyethylene material, a polymer material or other material that is semi-permeable to ethylene gas (C2H4). The thickness and density of material of the container <b>130</b> allows the ethylene to be retained at different concentration levels causing the bananas to ripen at different rates in the container.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The second container end <b>136</b> of the housing <b>132</b> may have a narrowed end compared to the diameter of the housing <b>132</b>. The first container end <b>134</b> of the housing may be sinched closed with a closing device <b>140</b>. The banana is configured to be placed in the housing <b>132</b> by opening the first container end <b>134</b> large enough to receive the size of the banana. The housing <b>132</b> may be flexible.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">In some embodiments, the plurality of banana containers <b>130</b> may include a first pair of banana containers <b>130</b><sup>1</sup>, <b>130</b><sup>2 </sup>having a first housing wall thickness, a second pair of banana containers <b>130</b><sup>3</sup>, <b>130</b><sup>4 </sup>having a second housing wall thickness less than the first housing wall thickness, and a third pair of banana containers <b>130</b><sup>5</sup>, <b>130</b><sup>6 </sup>having a third housing wall thickness less than the second housing wall thickness, ranging from 2-6 mil.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Referring also to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>, the banana container may include a closing device <b>140</b> coupled to the first container end of the housing. The closing device <b>140</b> may be made of a resilient band with the ability to lock, via lock or fastener <b>445</b>, the closing device <b>140</b> around the banana, forming a seal around the neck of the banana finger. In the case of a banana finger, the closing device <b>140</b> may close the first container end around the neck of the banana.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The banana container <b>130</b> may be in the shape of a banana sleeve for receiving a banana without bruising or harming the skin of the banana. In another embodiment, the container <b>130</b> may be of a shape and size to hold more than a single banana. As a non-limiting example, the consumer may wish to use the banana container <b>130</b> to ripen two bananas at a same rate where the other containers may already contain other bananas.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The system <b>100</b> may include a gas generator <b>101</b> including a gas dispensing regulator <b>102</b>, the gas dispensing regulator <b>102</b> is connected with the plurality of banana containers <b>130</b>. The gas generator <b>101</b> includes a housing <b>120</b> having an interior compartment <b>104</b> for placement of material for the creation of ethylene gas, for example. The gas dispensing regulator <b>102</b> may be connected or integrated into the housing <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The gas dispensing regulator <b>102</b> may include a plurality of gas meters <b>301</b>-<b>306</b>, having a one-to-one correspondence with the banana containers <b>130</b><sup>1</sup>-<b>130</b><sup>6</sup>. A corresponding meter <b>301</b>-<b>306</b> is connected to the second container end <b>136</b> of a corresponding banana container <b>130</b> to dispense a corresponding amount of ripening gas into the corresponding banana container <b>130</b> from the compartment <b>104</b> of the housing <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The gas generator <b>101</b> may include a removable cap device <b>110</b> that may be used to open and close the compartment <b>104</b>. The cap device <b>110</b> to be connected to a first compartment end <b>106</b> of housing <b>120</b>, the first compartment end is configured to be a capped end. The housing <b>120</b> also includes a second compartment end <b>108</b> opposite the first compartment end. The gas dispensing regulator <b>102</b> is connected to integrated with the second compartment end <b>108</b> to form a gas regulating end <b>108</b>. The removable cap device <b>110</b> can be selectively removed from the first compartment end <b>106</b> to replenish the gas generating material (or tablet T) in the compartment <b>104</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the removable cap device <b>110</b> may include a cap body <b>202</b> having a hole <b>204</b> in a bottom end <b>204</b>. The interior walls of the cap body <b>202</b> includes threads <b>206</b> for opening and closing the compartment <b>104</b>. As can be appreciated, other closing mechanism may be used, such as Snap-on caps, hinge lids or the like. The housing <b>120</b> may be tubular with a cap on one end and a gas regulator on the other end, in which a tablet T of ethylene (gas) generating material can be placed. When the tablet comes into contact with a minimum level of moisture, it begins to generate ethylene gas. The moisture may come from the air or by using a small piece of moist material such as a paper towel or other material.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, the gas dispensing regulator <b>102</b> may include a substrate <b>320</b> at the second compartment end <b>108</b> of the compartment <b>104</b>. The substrate <b>320</b> includes the plurality of gas meters <b>301</b>-<b>306</b>, which dispense a ripening gas into the corresponding banana containers <b>130</b><sup>3</sup>-<b>130</b><sup>4</sup>, simultaneously, but at different dispensing rates. By way of non-limiting example, the plurality of gas meters <b>301</b>-<b>306</b> include a first pair of gas meters <b>301</b>-<b>302</b> to dispense a first corresponding amount of the ripening gas into the first pair of banana containers <b>130</b><sup>1</sup>-<b>130</b><sup>2</sup>, simultaneously; a second pair of gas meters <b>303</b>-<b>304</b> to dispense a second corresponding amount of the ripening gas into the second pair of banana containers <b>130</b><sup>3</sup>-<b>130</b><sup>4</sup>, simultaneously, and a third pair of gas meters <b>305</b>-<b>306</b> to dispense a third corresponding amount of the ripening gas into the third pair of banana containers <b>130</b><sup>5</sup>-<b>130</b><sup>6</sup>, simultaneously. The second corresponding amount of ripening gas is less than the first corresponding amount. The third corresponding amount is less than the second corresponding amount. For illustrative purposes, the first pair of meters are coupled in a one-to-one correspondence to the first pair of banana containers <b>130</b><sup>1</sup>-<b>130</b><sup>2</sup>. Each meter (i.e., meter <b>301</b>) includes a plurality of orifices through which a fluid, air, or ethylene gas (C2H4) flows into the corresponding one banana container (i.e., container <b>130</b><sup>1</sup>). By way of non-limiting example, the number of orifices in the first pair of gas meters <b>301</b>-<b>302</b> is greater than the number of orifices of the second pair of gas meters <b>303</b>-<b>304</b> and the third pair of gas meters <b>305</b>-<b>306</b>. The orifice diameter of each orifice is essentially the same. In other embodiments, the orifice size can change so that the rate of dispensing the gas can vary.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">In other embodiments, the number of orifices may be the same, but the diameter of the orifice may vary to vary the rate of gas flow through the meter and into the corresponding container.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The system <b>100</b> provides for the treatment (exposing to a process) of up to three sets of bananas pairs, which are individually and uniquely treated to arrive at different ripening levels and schedules. In some embodiments, two people may want to have a ripened banana on the same day. This system <b>100</b> allows two bananas to be ripened simultaneously.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">In other embodiments, the user may place banana in alternate banana housings to delay the ripening of the banana using the same system <b>100</b> based on the thickness of the banana container and the meter flow of the ripening gas. Still further, a user may vary the placement of the banana in the banana housing according to their own eating choices.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Although the embodiment shown includes pairs of banana containers with the same wall thickness, alternately each banana container may have a different wall thickness. In such an embodiment, the first container may have the thickest wall thickness and the last banana container would have the thinnest wall thickness.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Still further, the flow rates of the meters can be varied so that each meter has a different rate as compared to the next meter in the series.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, a corresponding banana container houses a corresponding one banana finger of a hand of bananas. The ripening rate is controlled by the plurality of banana containers having varying wall thicknesses such that the wall thicknesses and the rate at which the corresponding amount of the ripening gas is dispensed to a respective banana container are varied to control the ripening rate of the unpeeled banana. For example, the thicker the wall thickness of the banana container the faster the ripening rate. The slower the rate of dispensing of the ripening gas into the banana container, the slower the rate of ripening. Both of these parameters can be controlled to sequentially ripen a banana either through acceleration or delayed ripening as compared to the ripening rate that occurs naturally in air.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">In some embodiments, varying the molecular density of the polyethylene film, for example from low-density polyethylene (LDPE) to high-density polyethylene (HDPE), the level of ethylene gas can also be controlled. Therefore, the permeability is controlled by a combination of polyethylene density and thickness, to achieve the ideal permeability for each set of banana containers.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The inventor has determined that storage of green bananas in the system for one day (minimum 24 hours) results in bananas being ripened sequentially, on different days. The system <b>100</b> allows consumers to ripen bananas at different speeds to achieve the goal of bananas from the same bunch being ripe, on different days.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The system may include a device that generates ethylene gas (capsule or material that contains an ethylene generator at a particular moisture level) at a low concentration. A tablet of ethylene generating material is placed in the compartment and the moisture from the connected bananas in their compartments is sufficient to react and generate ethylene gas. A secondary alternative material also may be use, that is wetted on the surface, prior to insertion into the compartment, starting the gas generating reaction that then feeds the ethylene gas into three pairs of banana containers at different rates and concentrations.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">System <b>100</b> provides a means to introduce different amounts of ethylene gas to individual sets of bananas (such as banana sleeves of various thicknesses). System <b>100</b> provides a consumer the ability to vary the acceleration of ripening of bananas to achieve the goal of bananas from the same bunch being ripe, on different days.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> illustrates a flowchart of a method <b>600</b> for ripening a number of bananas. A method <b>600</b> for treating bananas to control the ripening of such bananas will now be described. The method <b>600</b> may include housing in a plurality of banana containers unpeeled bananas, each banana container having a first container end to receive an unpeeled banana and a second container end, at <b>602</b>. The method <b>600</b> may include, dispensing by a gas generator connected to the plurality of banana containers, a ripening gas into corresponding banana containers at different flow rates, at <b>604</b>. The gas generator including a gas dispensing regulator that may include a plurality of gas meters having a one-to-one correspondence with the plurality of banana containers, a corresponding meter connected to the second container end of the corresponding banana container.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Since each banana container <b>130</b> includes a housing <b>132</b> having the first container end <b>134</b> and the second container end <b>136</b> and a wall thickness to surround skin of the unpeeled banana between the first container end and the second container end, the method may include varying a rate of ripening based on the wall thickness of each banana container.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Since the plurality of banana containers <b>130</b> may include pairs of banana containers, each banana container of the pair has the same wall thickness and each pair of banana containers have a different wall thickness than another pair of banana containers, then the method may include varying the rate of ripening of the fresh (green) bananas in pairs.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">Since the plurality of gas meters <b>301</b>-<b>306</b> may be in pairs, the method may include varying the rate of ripening based on the wall thickness of each banana container in the pairs of banana containers and the dispensed amount of the ripening gas from the gas meter pairs.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">The method may include dispensing an amount of ethylene gas by the gas generator, the ethylene gas being the ripening gas.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Since each banana container <b>130</b> may include a closing device <b>140</b> coupled to the first container end of the banana container <b>130</b> to control pressure of the ripening gas in the banana container, then the method may include controlling or limiting the pressure of the ripening gas in the banana container <b>130</b> using the closing device <b>140</b> to vary the ripening rate of the bananas.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The method may also include removing the cap device <b>110</b> from the first compartment end <b>106</b>. Then, the method may include adding a gas generating material (or tablet T) to the compartment <b>104</b>. The method may include activating the gas generating material (or tablet T) in the compartment <b>104</b> to generate the ripening gas, and placing the cap device <b>110</b> on the first compartment end <b>106</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Although the embodiments herein are directed to bananas, including green bananas, the system may be applied to other fresh fruit where additional ripening may be desired and can be accomplished to a ripening gas.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">The terminology used herein is for the purpose of describing particular embodiments only and is not intended to be limiting. As used herein, the singular forms &#x201c;a,&#x201d; &#x201c;an,&#x201d; and &#x201c;the&#x201d; are intended to include the plural forms as well, unless the context clearly indicates otherwise. Furthermore, to the extent that the terms &#x201c;including,&#x201d; &#x201c;includes,&#x201d; &#x201c;having,&#x201d; &#x201c;has,&#x201d; &#x201c;with,&#x201d; or variants thereof are used in either the detailed description and/or the claims, such terms are intended to be inclusive in a manner similar to the term &#x201c;comprising.&#x201d; Moreover, unless specifically stated, any use of the terms first, second, etc., does not denote any order or importance, but rather the terms first, second, etc., are used to distinguish one element from another.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">Unless otherwise defined, all terms (including technical and scientific terms) used herein have the same meaning as commonly understood by one of ordinary skill in the art to which embodiments of the invention belongs. It will be further understood that terms, such as those defined in commonly used dictionaries, should be interpreted as having a meaning that is consistent with their meaning in the context of the relevant art and will not be interpreted in an idealized or overly formal sense unless expressly so defined herein.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">While various disclosed embodiments have been described above, it should be understood that they have been presented by way of example only, and not limitation. Numerous changes, omissions and/or additions to the subject matter disclosed herein can be made in accordance with the embodiments disclosed herein without departing from the spirit or scope of the embodiments. Also, equivalents may be substituted for elements thereof without departing from the spirit and scope of the embodiments. In addition, while a particular feature may have been disclosed with respect to only one of several implementations, such feature may be combined with one or more other features of the other implementations as may be desired and advantageous for any given or particular application. Furthermore, many modifications may be made to adapt a particular situation or material to the teachings of the embodiments without departing from the scope thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">Further, the purpose of the foregoing Abstract is to enable the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office and the public generally and especially the scientists, engineers and practitioners in the relevant art(s) who are not familiar with patent or legal terms or phraseology, to determine quickly from a cursory inspection the nature and essence of this technical disclosure. The Abstract is not intended to be limiting as to the scope of the present disclosure in any way.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Therefore, the breadth and scope of the subject matter provided herein should not be limited by any of the above explicitly described embodiments. Rather, the scope of the embodiments should be defined in accordance with the following claims and their equivalents.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A system comprising:
<claim-text>a plurality of banana containers, each banana container having a first container end to receive an unpeeled banana and a second container end; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a gas generator including a gas dispensing regulator connected to the plurality of banana containers to dispense a ripening gas into corresponding banana containers at different flow rates, the gas dispensing regulator including a plurality of gas meters having a one-to-one correspondence with the plurality of banana containers, a corresponding meter connected to the second container end of a corresponding banana container to dispense a corresponding amount of the ripening gas into the corresponding banana container to ripen the unpeeled banana in the corresponding banana container in response to the corresponding amount of the ripening gas.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the gas generator further comprises:
<claim-text>a compartment having a first compartment end and a second compartment end; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a removable cap device coupled to the first compartment end to selectively replenish the ripening gas in the compartment,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the gas dispensing regulator is connected at the second compartment end opposite the first compartment end of the compartment, the gas dispensing regulator including the plurality of gas meters.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein each banana container comprises a housing having the first container end and the second container end and a wall thickness to surround skin of the unpeeled banana between the first container end and the second container end.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of banana containers comprises pairs of banana containers, each banana container of the pair having equal wall thicknesses and each pair of banana containers having a different wall thickness than another pair of banana containers.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of banana containers comprises:
<claim-text>a first pair of banana containers having a first housing wall thickness;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second pair of banana containers having a second housing wall thickness less than the first housing wall thickness; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third pair of banana containers having a third housing wall thickness less than the second housing wall thickness.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of gas meters comprises:
<claim-text>a first pair of gas meters dispensing a first corresponding amount of the ripening gas into the first pair of banana containers, simultaneously;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second pair of gas meters dispensing a second corresponding amount of the ripening gas into the second pair of banana containers, simultaneously, the second corresponding amount being less than the first corresponding amount; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third pair of gas meters dispensing a third corresponding amount of the ripening gas into the third pair of banana containers, simultaneously, the third corresponding amount being less than the second corresponding amount.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the unpeeled banana is an unripe banana.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of banana containers having varying wall thicknesses such that the wall thicknesses and a rate at which the corresponding amount of the ripening gas are dispensed to a respective banana container controls the ripening rate of the unpeeled banana.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein each banana container further comprising a closing device coupled to the first container end of the banana container to control a pressure of the ripening gas in the banana container.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of banana containers comprise polyethylene material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. A method comprising:
<claim-text>housing, in a plurality of banana containers, unpeeled bananas, each banana container having a first container end to receive an unpeeled banana and a second container end;</claim-text>
<claim-text>dispensing, by a gas generator connected to the plurality of banana containers, a ripening gas into corresponding banana containers at different flow rates, the gas generator including a plurality of gas meters having a one-to-one correspondence with the plurality of banana containers, a corresponding meter connected to the second container end of a corresponding banana container to dispense a corresponding amount of ripening gas into the corresponding banana container; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>ripening each unpeeled banana in each corresponding banana container in response to the corresponding amount of the ripening gas dispensed.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the gas generator comprises:
<claim-text>a compartment having a first compartment end and a second compartment end, gas dispensing regulator at the second compartment end, the gas dispensing regulator including the plurality of gas meters, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a removable cap device coupled to the first compartment end to selectively replenish the ripening gas in the compartment; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the method further comprising:
<claim-text>removing the cap device from the first compartment end,</claim-text>
<claim-text>adding a gas generating material to the compartment,</claim-text>
<claim-text>activating the gas generating material in the compartment to generate the ripening gas, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>placing the cap device on the first compartment end.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein each banana container comprises a housing having the first container end and the second container end and a wall thickness to surround skin of the unpeeled banana between the first container end and the second container end; and the method further comprising:
<claim-text>varying a rate of ripening based on the wall thickness of each banana container.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of banana containers comprises pairs of banana containers, each banana container of the pair having equal wall thicknesses and each pair of banana containers having a different wall thickness than another pair of banana containers; and
<claim-text>the method further comprising:
<claim-text>varying the rate of ripening of banana pairs.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of banana containers comprises:
<claim-text>a first pair of banana containers having a first housing wall thickness;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second pair of banana containers having a second housing wall thickness less than the first housing wall thickness; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third pair of banana containers having a third housing wall thickness less than the second housing wall thickness.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of gas meters comprises:
<claim-text>a first pair of gas meters dispensing a first corresponding amount of the ripening gas into the first pair of banana containers, simultaneously,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second pair of gas meters dispensing a second corresponding amount of the ripening gas into the second pair of banana containers, simultaneously, the second corresponding amount being less than the first corresponding amount, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third pair of gas meters dispensing a third corresponding amount of the ripening gas into the third pair of banana containers, simultaneously, the third corresponding amount being less than the second corresponding amount; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the method further comprising:
<claim-text>varying the rate of ripening based on the wall thickness of each banana container in the pairs of banana containers and an amount of the dispensed ripening gas from the gas meter pairs.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the unpeeled banana is an unripe banana.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the dispensing of the ripening gas includes dispensing an amount of ethylene gas, the ethylene gas being the ripening gas.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein each banana container further comprising a closing device coupled to the first container end of the banana container to control pressure of the ripening gas in the banana container; and
<claim-text>the method further comprising:
<claim-text>limiting pressure of the ripening gas in the banana container using the closing device to vary a ripening rate of the bananas.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of banana containers comprise polyethylene material.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
