<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225427A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225427</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18042186</doc-number>
<date>20220907</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>2300</main-group>
<subgroup>33</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>2600</main-group>
<subgroup>10</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>2400</main-group>
<subgroup>38</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>2300</main-group>
<subgroup>22</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">MULTI-LAYER SWIMWEAR FITMENT APPARATUS</invention-title>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>63261086</doc-number>
<date>20210910</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Klabunde</last-name>
<first-name>Karena</first-name>
<address>
<city>Raleigh</city>
<state>NC</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Klabunde</last-name>
<first-name>Karena</first-name>
<address>
<city>Raleigh</city>
<state>NC</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/US22/76031</doc-number>
<date>20220907</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c12-date><date>20230217</date></us-371c12-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Apparatus and associated methods relate to a garment having adjustable closure modules to reduce unwanted exposure. In an illustrative example, a continuous one-piece swimsuit may include at least one distributed tension closure system (DTCS) at each side of the swimsuit. The DTCS, for example, may include an elastic layer disposed underneath a longitudinally adjustable tension member coupled to opposing lateral edges of the DTCS. For example, when the swimsuit is donned by a wearer and lengths of the adjustable tension members are individually adjusted to a corresponding desired tension, each adjustable tension members urges the opposing lateral edges together by the corresponding desired tension such that an aperture of the hip openings is adjusted to reduce unwanted exposure of a body of the wearer. Various embodiments may advantageously provide modest fittings while maintaining a substantially smooth layer fitting comfortably to the wearer.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="215.05mm" wi="130.56mm" file="US20230225427A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="202.86mm" wi="173.65mm" file="US20230225427A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="230.89mm" wi="132.59mm" file="US20230225427A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="221.66mm" wi="128.10mm" file="US20230225427A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="208.62mm" wi="104.82mm" file="US20230225427A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims the benefit of U.S. Provisional Application Serial No. 63/261,086, titled &#x201c;Multi-layer Swimwear Fitment Apparatus,&#x201d; filed by Karena Klabunde, on Sep. 10, 2021.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">This application incorporates the entire contents of the foregoing application(s) herein by reference.</p>
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="tail"?>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Various embodiments relate generally to textile and garments.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Clothing is part of daily lives of any human society. Normally, clothing is made of cloth or fabric that is woven from a filament (e.g., yarn, thread). In modern days, clothing may be made with non-woven materials. There are different ways of creating clothes out of cloth. For example, one approach is simply draping the cloth and wrapping the cloth around a body. Some notable examples of this may be the dhoti for men and the sari for women in the Indian subcontinent, the Scottish kilt, and the Japanese sarong. This kind of clothing may simply be tied up or fixated with pins or belts to hold the garments in place (kilt and sarong). Since the cloth is not cut and sewn, people of various sizes can wear the same garment. Another approach involves measuring, cutting, and sewing the cloth by hand or with a sewing machine. Sometimes the cloth is cut according to a sewing pattern, and the garment is further adjusted by a tailor to fit the wearer's measurements.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">People make different clothes for different purposes. One such example includes sportswear and/or activewear that is specific for sporting or outdoor activity purposes. Exemplary sportswear garments include, for example, tracksuits, shorts, t-shirts, polo shirts, swimsuits, wet suits for diving or surfing, ski suits, and leotards for gymnastics. Sportswear may be designed with a wearer's comfort and/or performance in mind. For example, gymnastics clothing may use easily deformable fabric for easy movement. For example, apparels for long distance running may be designed to keep the wearer in good comfort by offering good moisture wicking properties to enable sweat to transfer from the inside to the outside for the garment. Clothing for outdoor sports in the winter or snow sports may use breathable fabrics with insulative properties. Women's swimsuits include one-piece, bikinis, or thongs.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Apparatus and associated methods relate to a garment having adjustable closure modules to reduce unwanted exposure. In an illustrative example, a continuous one-piece swimsuit may include at least one distributed tension closure system (DTCS) at each side of the swimsuit. The DTCS, for example, may include an elastic layer disposed underneath a longitudinally adjustable tension member coupled to opposing lateral edges of the DTCS. For example, when the swimsuit is donned by a wearer and lengths of the adjustable tension members are individually adjusted to a corresponding desired tension, each adjustable tension members may urge the opposing lateral edges together by the corresponding desired tension such that an aperture of the hip openings is adjusted to reduce unwanted exposure of a body of the wearer. Various embodiments may advantageously provide modest fittings while maintaining a substantially smooth layer fitting comfortably to the wearer.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The DTCS may be used to advantageously fit wearers with distributed tension to enhance comfortability and aesthetic value. In an illustrative example, the DTCS may be embedded or integrated in a swimsuit. The swimsuit may, for example, include a DTCS substantially extending from under a wearer's arm to a user's hip. The swimsuit, for example, may include two designated tension openings at each side of the garment, one near the hip and another underarm of the wearer. In some implementations, a wearer may adjust the openings by applying tension at the closure cord and hold the width of the opening using the stopper during use. The wearer may cover the DTCS with a covering layer by, for example, zipping the covering layer. Various embodiments may advantageously improve the wearer's comfort by preventing abrasion and pinching.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The details of various embodiments are set forth in the accompanying drawings and the description below. Other features and advantages will be apparent from the description and drawings, and from the claims.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>B</figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref>, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>D</figref> depict exemplary distributed tension closure garments (DTCGs) in an illustrative use-case scenario.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a flowchart to illustrate an exemplary method for fitting a piece of garment using a distributed tension closure system (DTCS).</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> depicts an exemplary DTCG with a drawstring and a stopper adjuster.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Like reference symbols in the various drawings indicate like elements.</p>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF ILLUSTRATIVE EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>B</figref> depict exemplary distributed tension closure garments (DTCGs <b>100</b>) in an illustrative use-case scenario. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A-<b>1</b>C</figref>, the DTCG <b>100</b> is made with, among other accessories and/or fabric, a shell fabric <b>105</b> and two distributed tension closure systems (DTCS) <b>110</b>, one at each side of the DTCG <b>100</b>. In the depicted example, the DTCS <b>110</b> is located around the hip area of the DTCG <b>100</b>. For example, the DTCS <b>110</b> may extend from a leg opening of the DTCG <b>100</b> longitudinally towards an underarm portion of the DTCG <b>100</b>. The DTCS <b>110</b> includes a lining panel <b>115</b>, a tension distribution layer <b>120</b>, and a covering layer <b>125</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The DTCG <b>100</b> is, in this example, a swimsuit. In various embodiments, the DTCG <b>100</b> may be worn by children for swimming. In this example, the DTCG <b>100</b> is made mostly with the shell fabric <b>105</b>. For example, the shell fabric may include elastic materials. Exemplary elastic materials that may include the shell fabric include, by way of example and not limitation, Nylon (polyamides), elastane, polyester, or some combination thereof. In some implementations, the shell fabric <b>105</b> may include materials used for swimsuits. In this example, the shell fabric <b>105</b> is combined with the DTCS <b>110</b>. In some embodiments, a user (e.g., child) who wears the DTCG <b>100</b> may advantageously benefit from the combination of the shell fabric <b>105</b> and the DTCS <b>110</b> comfortably and adjustably fitting the body of the child at one or both of the two designed openings, underarm and around the hip.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In the DTCS <b>110</b>, the lining panel <b>115</b> may be made, for example, with material with highly elastic properties. In some implementations, the lining panel <b>115</b> may stay substantially flat without wadding in both open state and fitted state of the closure due to the elasticity of the panel <b>115</b>. In some implementations, the lining panel may be constructed of a 4-way stretchable fabric. In some examples, compositions of the lining panel <b>115</b> may include elastane, spandex, or other elastic fibers. In some examples, the lining panel <b>115</b> may also be durable and chlorine resistant. Because of the flat surface and, thus, in some examples, substantially evenly distributed pressure on a wearer's skin, the lining panel <b>115</b> may advantageously improve the wearer's comfort by preventing abrasion and pinching.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The tension distribution layer <b>120</b> includes a closure cord <b>130</b> and a stopper <b>135</b>. For example, the closure cord <b>130</b> may be a zig-zagged drawstring. In other examples, the closure cord <b>130</b> may be an elastic tape. In other examples, the closure cord <b>130</b> may be a chain that is made with plastic, metal, and/or a natural material. The closure cord <b>130</b> joins two opposing edges <b>140</b>. The two opposing edges <b>140</b>, for example, may be part of the shell fabric <b>105</b>. In other examples, the opposing edges <b>140</b> may be formed by other material independent of the shell fabric <b>105</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In various embodiments, the closure cord <b>130</b> may be arranged to join the two opposing edges <b>140</b> in a way that the tension between the opposing edges <b>140</b> are substantially evenly distributed. As an illustrative example, the closure cord <b>130</b> may be pulled to urge the opposing edges <b>140</b> closer together, thereby fitting the designated area to the size of the wearer. In this example, the designated areas for fitting are around the hip (e.g., a leg opening) and under the arm (armhole) of the area, where the two DTCS <b>110</b> are substantially located. For example, the closure cord <b>130</b> may be adjustable to the wearer's specific physiological structure by having a distributed tension along the body contour. Accordingly, the shell fabric <b>105</b> may, for example, be advantageously fitted to a user's specific body structure.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">As depicted, for example, a tension (T) may be applied to the closure cord <b>130</b>. The tension may be (substantially) evenly distributed along the entire cord. Accordingly, the closure cord <b>130</b> may apply a force (F) to each point of engagement (e.g., via a grommet and/or eyelet) with the tension distribution layer <b>120</b>. Such embodiments may, for example, enable a user to apply a substantially evenly distributed force that may be advantageously applied quickly and/or easily. The evenly distributed force may, for example, advantageously enhance user comfort. The evenly distributed force may, for example, advantageously eliminate tight spots and/or loose spots due to garment contour misalignment with body contour.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">As an illustrative example without limitation, the lining panel <b>115</b> may be coupled with the tension distribution layer <b>120</b> and/or the shell fabric <b>105</b> by thread sewing (e.g., overlock seam, double stitching), taping, bonding, or some combination thereof. When a wearer fits the DTCG <b>100</b> by tightening the closure cord <b>130</b>, in some implementations, the tension between the closure cord <b>130</b> and the body of the wearer may be substantially evenly distributed along the body contour of the wearer due to the highly elastic nature of the lining panel <b>115</b>. For example, the tension may be distributed evenly via the surface of the lining panel <b>115</b>. In some embodiments the lining panel <b>115</b> may, for example, assist the shell fabric <b>105</b> in distributing the tension. In some embodiments the closure may be coupled to the lining panel <b>115</b> directly. In various embodiments, the distributed tension may advantageously prevent uncomfortable tight spots and/or immodest or unsightly loose spots.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The stopper <b>135</b> is, in the depicted example, coupled with the closure cord <b>130</b>. For example, the wearer may use the stopper <b>135</b> to control the tension applied to the closure cord <b>130</b> and therefore hold the width of the opening between the opposing edges <b>140</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In some implementations, the DTCG <b>100</b> may be a continuous garment. For example, the DTCG <b>100</b> may be produced as a seamless garment. The DTCG <b>100</b>, for example, may be produced by combining a few fabric panels (sewn, bonded) together to form a continuous garment. In various implementations, the opposing edges <b>140</b> may be joined at a middle portion between a hem at the DTCS <b>110</b> and the underarm portion of the DTCG <b>100</b>. In some examples, the middle portion may provide reference for smoothing crinkling of fabric at the hem after tension adjustment.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">As shown, the DTCS <b>110</b> is triangular shaped. For example, the triangulated DTCS <b>110</b> may include a downward tension force at the DTCS <b>110</b>. For example, the downward force may reduce crinkle effect at the DTCG <b>100</b> and improve comfortability of the wearer.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In some implementations, the DTCG <b>100</b> may advantageously decrease gapping between two sizes (e.g., a 25 to a 26). For example, a child wearing the DTCG <b>100</b> may use the DTCS <b>110</b> to adjust or remove a gap at a leg opening without tightening the DTCG <b>100</b> at other parts of the DTCG <b>100</b>. As an illustrative example, the DTCS <b>110</b> may provide an adjustable range of substantially about 0.5-1 inch of gap at the leg opening.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Layering on top of the opposing edges <b>140</b>, the covering layer <b>125</b> includes a first edge <b>145</b> and a second edge <b>150</b>. In this example, the first edge <b>145</b> and the second edge <b>150</b> can be releasably coupled together by a fastener. For example, the fastener may be a zipper, a set of Velcro tape, one or more snap buttons, a magnetic fasteners pair, one or more hook buttons, or other fastening mechanisms. In a fastened state, the covering layer <b>125</b> covers the tension distribution layer <b>120</b> and the lining panel <b>115</b> in the depicted example. When the covering layer <b>125</b> is unfasten, in this example, the tension distribution layer <b>120</b> is revealed and the closure cord <b>130</b> is available for adjustment.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In some implementations, the covering layer <b>125</b> may, in the fastened state, advantageously protect the tension distribution layer <b>120</b> from being inadvertently or unintentionally operated during use. For example, the covering layer <b>125</b> may protect the tension distribution layer <b>120</b> from external objects snagging on the closure cord <b>130</b> during use. In some implementations, the covering layer <b>125</b> may conceal the tension distribution layer <b>120</b> and the lining panel <b>115</b> to provide aesthetic value to the DTCG <b>100</b>. For example, the covering layer <b>125</b> may be solid colored or printed with patterns or other artwork (e.g., by digital printer) to offer aesthetic value.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">In various embodiments, the DTCS <b>110</b> that includes the covering layer <b>125</b>, the tension distribution layer <b>120</b> with the closure cord <b>130</b> and the stopper <b>135</b>, and the lining panel <b>115</b> may be used to advantageously fit wearers with distributed tension to enhance comfortability and aesthetic value.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>D</figref>, a continuous swimsuit <b>160</b> includes an upper DTCS <b>165</b> and a lower DTCS <b>170</b>. For example, the continuous swimsuit <b>160</b> may include the upper DTCS <b>165</b> and the lower DTCS <b>170</b> at each side of the continuous swimsuit <b>160</b>. The upper DTCS <b>165</b> extends longitudinally from an underarm opening towards a hip portion of the continuous swimsuit <b>160</b>. The lower DTCS <b>170</b> extends longitudinally from a leg opening towards an underarm portion of the continuous swimsuit <b>160</b>. In this example, the DTCS <b>165</b>, <b>170</b> includes an elastic layer <b>175</b> disposed underneath a tension adjustment cord <b>180</b>. For example, the elastic layer <b>175</b> may separate the tension adjustment cord <b>180</b> to a body of a wearer. As shown the tension adjustment cords <b>180</b> are coupled to engagement points <b>185</b><i>a, </i><b>185</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">In operation, the continuous swimsuit <b>160</b> may be fitted by tightening the tension adjustment cords <b>180</b>. For example, the tension adjustment cords <b>180</b> may be longitudinally adjustable. For example, the tension adjustable cords <b>180</b> may be adjusted in length so that an arm aperture <b>190</b> and a leg aperture <b>195</b> may be individually adjusted. In this example, after a desired tension is obtained, the tension adjustment cords <b>180</b> may be tied into a knot to fix the desired tension at the engagement points <b>185</b><i>a </i>and <b>185</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">In various implementations, the tension adjustment cords <b>180</b> may urge opposing lateral edges together by the corresponding desired tension. In some examples, the apertures <b>190</b>, <b>195</b> may advantageously be adjusted to reduce exposure of a body of a wearer. The elastic layer <b>175</b> may, for example, be advantageously stretchable so that bunching or crinkling of the elastic layer <b>175</b> is substantially mitigated to improve comfort of the wearer.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a flowchart to illustrate an exemplary method <b>200</b> for fitting a piece of garment using a distributed tension closure system. In one example, the piece of garment may be a swimsuit. For example, the distributed tension closure system may be the DTCS <b>110</b> as described in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The method <b>200</b> starts when a user or a wearer puts on the garment with a distributed tension closure system at each designated tension area in step <b>205</b>. For example, the garment may have designated tension areas at the hip and under arm on both left and right side of the garment.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Next, tension is adjusted at one or more DTCS using a distributed tension closure layer of the DTCS in step <b>210</b>. For example, the user may adjust the closure cord <b>130</b> to tighten or loosen the tension as described in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>. As a result, for example, the dimension of the designated areas may be adjusted to fit the user.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">In step <b>215</b>, it is determined whether the garment is fitted properly at the designated areas. For example, it may be determined that the garment is fitted properly based on substantially absence of uncomfortable tight spots and/or immodest or unsightly loose spots at hip opening or underarm of a wearer.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">If it is determined that the garment is not fitted properly at one or more designated areas, then the step <b>210</b> is executed. If it is determined that the garment is fitted properly at one or more designated areas, then, in an optional step <b>220</b>, the distributed tension closure layer of the DTCS is covered and the method <b>200</b> ends. For example, a covering layer with two edges may be fastened to cover the distributed closure layer for concealing the closure layer.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Other embodiments of the DTCS may be constructed to fit various garment designs. In some implementations, the DTCS may be a continuous closure area on each side, from underarm to hip. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> depicts an exemplary DTCG <b>300</b> with a drawstring and a stopper adjuster. In this example, an elastic drawstring <b>305</b> is disposed within a tunnel <b>310</b> of a DTCS <b>315</b>. As shown, the elastic drawstring <b>305</b> may be coupled to lateral opposing edges <b>320</b>, <b>325</b>. For example, the elastic drawstring <b>305</b> may be coupled to the lateral opposing edges <b>320</b>, <b>325</b> by bonding. The elastic drawstring <b>305</b> may be coupled to the lateral opposing edges <b>320</b>, <b>325</b> by, for example, reinforcement stitching (e.g., bartack stitching, double stitching). Each of the elastic drawstrings <b>305</b> is coupled to a stopper <b>330</b>. To adjust an aperture <b>335</b>, a wearer may, for example, adjust a relative position of the stopper <b>330</b> at the elastic drawstring <b>305</b>. For example, the elastic drawstring <b>305</b> may urge the lateral opposing edges <b>320</b>, <b>325</b> closer when more of the elastic drawstring <b>305</b> is pulled out from the tunnel <b>310</b>. In this example, the DTCS <b>315</b> includes an elastic layer <b>340</b> to distribute tension evenly between the lateral opposing edges <b>320</b>, <b>325</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In various embodiments a DTCS may, for example, be provided in gymnastic clothing (e.g., a gymnasium suit). In various embodiments a DTCS may, for example, be provided in underclothing. In various embodiments a DTCS may, for example, be provided in outer garments. In various embodiments a DTCS may, for example, be provided in active wear and/or protective wear (e.g., ski suit, jumpsuit, overalls, coveralls).</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">In various embodiments a DTCS may, for example, be disposed on a front of a garment. A DTCS may, by way of example and not limitation, be disposed on a rear of a garment.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Although various embodiments have been described with reference to the figures, other embodiments are possible. In some implementations, a DTCS may be manufactured as a modulated accessory or fastening part. For example, the DTCS may include a fastening mechanism or otherwise be easily integrated with the rest of the garment. For example, the DTCS may include flaps or other mechanisms for combination (e.g., for sewn on and/or taped together) with shell fabric of the garment. In some embodiments, this may advantageously reduce cost for designing, developing, and/or producing a garment using the DTCS.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Although an exemplary system has been described with reference to the figures, other implementations may be deployed in other industrial, scientific, medical, commercial, and/or residential applications. For example, the DTCS may be applicable to garments that need to be fitted to avoid immodest sightings (e.g., gymnastics, wet suit/dry suit for surfing and diving, dance/ballet uniforms).</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">In an illustrative aspect, a garment may include a continuous garment body (e.g., <b>100</b>) and, two pairs of adjustable closure modules (e.g., <b>110</b>), each pair at a side of the garment body. For example, each adjustable closure modules may include a hip module (e.g., <b>170</b>) extending longitudinally from a hem of one side of a leg opening towards an armhole of the one side, and an underarm module (e.g., <b>165</b>) extending longitudinally from under the armhole of one side of an arm opening towards the one side of a hip portion of the garment body. For example, each of the adjustable closure modules may include an elastic layer (e.g., <b>115</b>) disposed underneath a tension adjustable layer. The tension adjustable layer may, for example, include a longitudinally adjustable tension member (e.g., <b>130</b>) coupled to opposing lateral edges (e.g., <b>140</b>) of the adjustable closure modules. For example, when the garment is donned by a wearer and a length of the adjustable tension members of each of the adjustable closure modules are individually adjusted to a corresponding desired tension, each adjustable tension members, for example, may urge the opposing lateral edges together by the corresponding desired tension such that an aperture (e.g., <b>190</b>) of the corresponding openings the garment body may be fitted to reduce exposure of a body of the wearer. For example, the elastic layer may maintain a substantially smooth layer separating the body from the corresponding adjustable tension member.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The continuous garment body may be a one-piece swimsuit. The continuous garment body may be a gymnasium suit. The elastic layer may, for example, include a 4-way stretchable fabric. The elastic layer may include polyamides. The tension member, for example, may include a closure cord and a stopper. For example, the closure cord is coupled to the lateral edges by inserting through a plurality of points of engagement at each side of the lateral edges. For example, upon a corresponding desired tension being fixed with the stopper, the tension exerted at each of the plurality of points of engagement may be substantially evenly distributed such that abrasion and pinching are substantially mitigated. For example, the tension member may include an elastic drawstring and a stopper. The elastic drawstring may be coupled to the lateral edges by a reinforcement stitch. For example, an opening of the aperture of a corresponding hip opening may be reduced between 0 inch and 1.5 inch after the length of the adjustable tension members is adjusted.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">In an illustrative aspect, a garment may include a continuous garment body (e.g., <b>100</b>), and two adjustable closure modules (e.g., <b>110</b>). For example, each of the adjustable closure modules may be disposed at a side of the garment body and extending longitudinally from an opening towards a middle portion of the garment body of the one side. For example, each of the adjustable closure modules may include an elastic layer (e.g., <b>115</b>) and means for adjusting an aperture (e.g., <b>190</b>) of the opening (e.g., <b>130</b>). For example, the aperture adjusting means may be coupled to opposing lateral edges (e.g., <b>140</b>) of the adjustable closure module. For example, when the garment is donned by a wearer and the aperture adjusting means are individually operated, each of the aperture adjusting means may urge opposing lateral edges together. For example, an aperture of a corresponding opening of the garment body may be fitted to reduce exposure of a body of the wearer. For example, the elastic layer may maintain a substantially smooth layer separating the body from the corresponding aperture adjusting means.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">A number of implementations have been described. Nevertheless, it will be understood that various modifications may be made. For example, advantageous results may be achieved if the steps of the disclosed techniques were performed in a different sequence, or if components of the disclosed systems were combined in a different manner, or if the components were supplemented with other components. Accordingly, other implementations are contemplated within the scope of the following claims.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A garment comprising:
<claim-text>a continuous garment body; and,</claim-text>
<claim-text>two pairs of adjustable closure modules, each pair at a side of the garment body and comprising:
<claim-text>a hip module extending longitudinally from a hem of one side of a leg opening towards an armhole of the one side; and,</claim-text>
<claim-text>an underarm module extending longitudinally from under the armhole of one side of an arm opening towards the one side of a hip portion of the garment body,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein:
<claim-text>each of the adjustable closure modules comprises an elastic layer disposed underneath a tension adjustable layer, and the tension adjustable layer comprises a longitudinally adjustable tension member coupled to opposing lateral edges of the adjustable closure modules such that,</claim-text>
<claim-text>when the garment is donned by a wearer and a length of the adjustable tension members of each of the adjustable closure modules are individually adjusted to a corresponding desired tension,</claim-text>
<claim-text>then each adjustable tension members urges the opposing lateral edges together by the corresponding desired tension such that an aperture of the corresponding openings the garment body is fitted to reduce exposure of a body of the wearer, and,</claim-text>
<claim-text>each elastic layer maintains a substantially smooth layer separating the body from the corresponding adjustable tension member.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the continuous garment body is a one-piece swimsuit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the continuous garment body is a gymnasium suit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the elastic layer comprising a 4-way stretchable fabric.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the elastic layer comprising polyamides.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the tension member comprises a closure cord and a stopper, wherein the closure cord is coupled to the lateral edges by inserting through a plurality of points of engagement at each side of the lateral edges.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein, upon a corresponding desired tension being fixed with the stopper, the tension exerted at each of the plurality of points of engagement is substantially evenly distributed such that abrasion and pinching are substantially mitigated.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the tension member comprises an elastic drawstring and a stopper, wherein the elastic drawstring is coupled to the lateral edges by a reinforcement stitch.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein an opening of the aperture of a corresponding hip opening is reduced between 0 inch and 1.5 inch after the length of the adjustable tension members is adjusted.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. A garment comprising:
<claim-text>a continuous garment body; and,</claim-text>
<claim-text>two adjustable closure modules, each of the adjustable closure modules being disposed at a side of the garment body and extending longitudinally from a hem of one side of a leg opening towards an armhole of the one side, and each of the adjustable closure modules comprising an elastic layer disposed underneath a tension adjustable layer,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein:
<claim-text>the tension adjustable layer comprises a longitudinally adjustable tension member coupled to opposing lateral edges of the adjustable closure modules such that,</claim-text>
<claim-text>when the garment is donned by a wearer and a length of the adjustable tension members of each of the adjustable closure modules are individually adjusted to a corresponding desired tension,</claim-text>
<claim-text>then each adjustable tension members urges the opposing lateral edges together by the corresponding desired tension such that an aperture of a leg opening on each side of the garment body is fitted to reduce exposure of a body of the wearer, and,</claim-text>
<claim-text>each elastic layer maintains a substantially smooth layer separating the body from the corresponding adjustable tension member.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, further comprising two adjustable closure modules, each under the armhole of one side of the garment body and extending longitudinally towards the corresponding leg opening such that apertures of the armholes are independently adjustable to avoid exposure of an upper body of the wearer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the continuous garment body is a one-piece swimsuit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. The garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the continuous garment body is a gymnasium suit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the elastic layer comprising a 4-way stretchable fabric.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. The garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the elastic layer comprising polyamides.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. The garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the tension member comprises a closure cord and a stopper, wherein the closure cord is coupled to the lateral edges by inserting through a plurality of points of engagement at each side of the lateral edges.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. The garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein, upon a corresponding desired tension is fixed with the stopper, the tension exerted at each of the plurality of points of engagement is substantially evenly distributed such that abrasion and pinching are substantially mitigated.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. The garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the tension member comprises an elastic drawstring and a stopper, wherein the elastic drawstring is coupled to the lateral edges by a reinforcement stitch.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. The garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein an opening of the aperture of a corresponding hip opening is reduced by up to 1.5 inches after the length of the adjustable tension members is adjusted.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. (canceled)</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
