<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225448A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225448</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17648197</doc-number>
<date>20220118</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>17</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>43</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>32</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>02</class>
<subclass>N</subclass>
<main-group>2</main-group>
<subgroup>18</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>43</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>32</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>H</section>
<class>02</class>
<subclass>N</subclass>
<main-group>2</main-group>
<subgroup>186</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Power Generating and Gait Assisting Footwear Article</invention-title>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>City University of Hong Kong</orgname>
<address>
<city>Hong Kong</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>YANG</last-name>
<first-name>Zhengbao</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hong Kong</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="01" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>PAN</last-name>
<first-name>Qiqi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hong Kong</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The present invention provides a device for improving energy economy and wearing comfort of a power generating, gait assisting footwear article while maintaining normal gait pattern during human locomotion. The device includes a motion conversion mechanism to convert linear reciprocating moment exerted on the device during heel strike/up into a series of rotations; a rotation acceleration module to increase the speed of rotations before being transformed into electric current by a generator. The device also includes a power management module and energy storage element(s) for energy storage and power supply to the footwear article or external electronics.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="67.31mm" wi="158.75mm" file="US20230225448A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="67.82mm" wi="132.33mm" file="US20230225448A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="81.11mm" wi="167.30mm" file="US20230225448A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="79.59mm" wi="111.08mm" file="US20230225448A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="103.38mm" wi="169.93mm" file="US20230225448A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="79.76mm" wi="147.40mm" file="US20230225448A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="207.09mm" wi="159.85mm" file="US20230225448A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention relates to an integrated device for footwear article to generate power while having gait assisting function.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">In a fast-changing and evolving manner of human lifestyle, incorporation of multi-functions into a footwear has become a trend, especially incorporating elements involving energy economy, which has drawn many attentions from users, footwear developers/manufacturers, and researchers in the relevant field. Some of them have proposed various paradigms to reduce energy expenditure such as spring-based structures or soft and elastic materials which have become a mainstream of conventional human augmented-locomotion assistant devices with energy harvesting protocols on harnessing biochemical energy during walking.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">For harvesting biochemical energy during walking, some major energy conversion mechanisms include utilizing electromagnetic, triboelectric and/or piezoelectric effect(s) of human locomotion during walking. For example, U.S. Pat. No. 8,970,054 provided an electromagnetic energy harvester with a displacement-amplified mechanism to harvest and also increase the power generated by an electric generator configured to be driven by a downward movement of a heel plate during a heel strike phase of walking.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">U.S. Pat. No. 8,716,877 provided a generator module having at least an elastic generator affixed to the leg shank of a wearer to harvest the energy generated from ankle joint motion. This device is limited by the ankle joint motion of the wearer in terms of change in angular motion of the ankle joint. From a different perspective, the generator affixed to the wearer limits the ankle motion and/or affects the comfort of the wearer.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">U.S. Pat. No. 9,057,361 provided a biomechanical energy harvester for harnessing energy from the motion of one or more joints with an electromagnetic effect. Several sensors were coupled in that harvester to serve as a clutch for determining the mutualistic and non-mutualistic conditions.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">For the biomechanical energy harvesters using piezoelectric effect, different configurations have been employed in the existing devices for capturing energy generated from different motions. For example, Shenck et al. (2001) used a flexible piezoelectric foil stave to harness sole-bending energy while a reinforced PZT dimorph was used to capture heel-strike energy.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Fan et al. (2017) provided a shoe-mounted piezoelectric energy harvester having a rotor combined with a bimorph PZT cantilever beam, and permanent magnets being attached at the free ends of the beam to harness the kinetic energy associated with foot strike motions, where the bimorphs were excited by movements of a steel ball coupled to the beam along its sleeve during the foot strike motions.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">US 2006/0021261 provided a piezoelectric energy harvester within a cavity of a sole member which captures the power generated from the deformation of a curved bimorph during a touchdown moment.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In addition, a number of studies on different energy conversation elements applied in footwear or exoskeleton show that these elements can reduce energy or metabolic cost by about 4% to 8% (Hoogkamer et al., 2017; Simpson et al., 2019; Collins et al., 2015).</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Gait assisting is another element that many people would like to have in their footwear. With such a surging market demand, a lot of wearable exoskeletons or exosuits have been recently developed with both energy harvesting and gait assisting functions, which can be generally divided into passive (for example, in US 2013/0281895, U.S. Pat. Nos. 8,053,914 and 7,956,476) and active (for example, in U.S. Pat. Nos. 10,326,312, 9,918,515 and 11,044,968) mechanisms.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In terms of reducing muscle force, U.S. Pat. No. 9,282,783 provided gait assisting shoes that can utilize parallel function of the Achilles' tendons through an integration of force-carrying mechanisms to manage forces and energies associated with dorsiflexion and plantar flexion; a sandal-like sole made of a resilient, elastic, springy material was provided in U.S. Pat. No. 7,290,358, which aids in the natural walking action by alternately compressing and releasing, adding energy to the step, thereby aiding walking while wearing ski boots; a similar design was employed in a walking support of a boot in US 2011/0302808, where soft materials were used to enhance wearer's comfort.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">However, none of those prior arts has a simple, integrated design to couple various profiles including shock absorbing, energy harvesting and gait assisting into a single device. Moreover, none of them could generate sufficient power for high energy demand electronics, but only generated power of less than one Watt since most of them are limited by the size, weight and/or structure of the device. Some of them require attachment or affixation to certain part of one or both limbs that may limit the motion of the corresponding joint(s) and affect normal gait pattern.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Therefore, there is a need for an integrated device including all the afore-mentioned features/functions while the disadvantages and problems described above in the prior arts could be at least diminished or substantially eliminated.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Accordingly, provided herein is a simple, lightweight, and integrated walking assistive device for improving energy economy, shock absorption, wearing comfort of an article of footwear while maintaining normal gait pattern during human locomotion.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In a first aspect, the prevent invention provides a device including:</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">a motion conversion module including an impact force absorbing and resilient member; and one or more guided members being attached to the impact force absorbing resilient member;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">a rotation acceleration module comprising a plurality of rotatable members and communicating with the motion conversion module;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">an electrical energy generator communicating with the rotation acceleration module; and</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">a frame accommodating the motion conversion module, rotation acceleration module and electrical energy generator,</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">wherein the motion conversion module is vertically extended from a horizontal section of the frame forming a sleeve,</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">the sleeve is internally threaded;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">at least one of the guided members is configured to move along the internally threaded sleeve when the impact force absorbing resilient member moves vertically along the sleeve due to a heel strike or up motion of the wearer's foot;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">the one or more guided members, upon moving along the internally threaded sleeve, drive(s) at least one of the rotatable members of the rotation acceleration module to rotate, thereby subsequently driving the remaining rotatable members of the rotation acceleration module;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">the electrical energy generator transforms rotational energy of the rotatable members of the rotation acceleration module into electric energy to be stored in an energy storage element and/or supplied to other parts of the article of the footwear and external electronics.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In one embodiment, the impact force absorbing and resilient member is a spring with one end attached to a top end of the sleeve and an opposite end attached to a first guided member.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">In one embodiment, the first guided member attached to the spring is disc-like. It includes a plurality of teeth disposed at a periphery thereof such that the first guided member is capable to move along the internally threaded sleeve.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">In an exemplary embodiment, the first guided member is engaged with a second guided member such that when the first guided member moves along the internally threaded sleeve, the second guided member is driven to rotate either clockwise or counterclockwise.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">In one embodiment, the second guided member is rod-like with one end attached to the first guided member and an opposite end attached to a first rotatable member of the rotation acceleration module such that when the second guided member rotates due to vertical displacement of the first guided member along the internally threaded sleeve, the first rotatable member is driven to rotate.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">In the first aspect, the one or more rotatable members of the rotation acceleration module is/are preferably gears having the same or different size and/or number of teeth with each other, and is/are driven by rotation of the first rotatable member.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">In one embodiment, more than one of the gears are arranged in hierarchy to minimize the size of the rotation acceleration module in the frame. At least two of the gears in different size and number of teeth form a pair of gears to interact with another pair of gears such that an initial rotational speed by the rotation of the first rotatable member is increased through the interactions among different pairs of gears in the rotation acceleration module.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The electrical energy generator of the present device can be selected from an electromagnetic generator and is activated by the rotation of the gear that is disposed most proximally to the electrical energy generator.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">In one embodiment, the electromagnetic generator is connected to a power management module including one or more rectifiers to convert alternating current generated by the electromagnetic generator into direct current.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The power management module further includes voltage converter to regulate the direct current level to be output to the energy storage element, other parts of the article of footwear, and/or external electronics.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The rotational speed of the most proximal gear to the electrical energy generator is adjustable by adjusting one or both of a helical pitch and a twist angle of the internal threads of the sleeve in the motion conversion module, and/or adjusting a frequency up-conversion ratio between each of the gears of the same pair in the rotation acceleration module.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">A second aspect of the present invention provides a power generating and gait assisting article of footwear including the device of the first aspect or any embodiments thereof described hereinafter, a power management circuit; and one or more energy storage elements.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In an exemplary embodiment, the footwear article of the second aspect includes a first hollow space at a heel section of the article for disposing the present device and a second hollow space in the middle of an insole of the article for disposing the power management circuit and the one or more energy storage elements.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The footwear article is selected from boots, shoes, or high-heeled footwear.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">A third aspect of the present invention provides a method for improving energy harvesting and shock absorbing efficiencies of an article of footwear including:</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">providing a first hollow space at a heel section and a second hollow space in the middle of an insole of the article of footwear;</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">incorporating the device of the first aspect or described hereinafter into the first hollow space; and</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">incorporating a power management circuit and one or more energy storage elements into the second hollow space.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">There is also provided in the present invention a power generating and gait assisting article of footwear fabricated according to the method of the third aspect or described hereinafter.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">This summary is provided to introduce a selection of concepts in a simplified form that are further described below in the Detailed Description. This Summary is not intended to identify key features or essential features of the claimed subject matter, nor is it intended to be used as an aid in determining the scope of the claimed subject matter. Other aspects of the present invention are disclosed as illustrated by the embodiments hereinafter.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The appended drawings, where like reference numerals refer to identical or functionally similar elements, contain figures of certain embodiments to further illustrate and clarify the above and other aspects, advantages and features of the present invention. It will be appreciated that these drawings depict embodiments of the invention and are not intended to limit its scope. The invention will be described and explained with additional specificity and detail through the use of the accompanying drawings in which:</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> shows an isometric view of the present device according to an embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> schematically depicts the working principle of the present device and how it imparts shock absorbing, gait assisting and energy harvesting properties to an article of footwear;</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> schematically depicts communications between a generator, a gearbox and a spring of the present device according to certain embodiments of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> schematically depicts power generation by the present device over a gait cycle when being applied to an article of footwear according to an embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> shows a circuitry diagram of power management of the present device according to an embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref> shows images of an article of footwear with the present device according to an embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>B</figref> shows test results of different performances of the present device according to the embodiment as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Skilled artisans will appreciate that elements/features shown in the figures are illustrated for simplicity and clarity and have not necessarily been depicted to scale.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">It will be apparent to those skilled in the art that modifications, including additions and/or substitutions, may be made without departing from the scope and spirit of the invention. Specific details may be omitted so as not to obscure the invention; however, the disclosure is written to enable one skilled in the art to practice the teachings herein without undue experimentation.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">The present invention applies a unique two-stage frequency-up conversion mechanism to the integrated, walking assistive device for naturally harnessing collisional energy during the touch-down moment of an associated article of footwear during human walking in order to enhance the energy economy and gait pattern thereof together with improvement in wearing comfort.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Turning into <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, the major components of the present device according to an exemplary embodiment are shown from an isometric view, including a generator <b>101</b>, a frame <b>102</b>, a gearbox <b>103</b>, a spring <b>104</b>, and a sleeve <b>105</b>. It should be understood that auxiliary components, detail and/or variations of the major components, and/or connections between different components of the present device may be omitted from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> for simplicity of illustration.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, the present device as shown is embedded into a heel section of shoes, for example, within or adjacent to a cushion pad of an article of footwear. The sleeve <b>105</b> is connected to the cushion pad of the footwear article. The generator <b>101</b> is embedded into a base of the frame <b>102</b> to save a vertical space therein for accommodating other major components, in particular, the gearbox <b>103</b> which is attached on to the base of the frame <b>102</b>. The gearbox <b>103</b> includes a plurality of gears in connection with one or more guided members forming communication between the sleeve <b>105</b>, the gearbox <b>103</b>, and the generator <b>101</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">In this example, the gearbox <b>103</b> is secured on the base of the frame <b>102</b> with an adhesive. However, it is possible to secure the gearbox <b>103</b> on the base of the frame <b>102</b> with other available means/methods. To balance between wearing comfort and power output performance, a working displacement of the sleeve <b>105</b> in vertical direction is set to be about 3.5 cm in this example.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">To minimize frictional loss and wear arising from an engagement between the internal threads of the sleeve <b>105</b> and a guided disc with teeth (not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>) driven by gears of the gearbox <b>103</b>, lubricant such as grease may be applied to a space between the internal threads and the guided disc so that when the guided disc rotates around the internally threaded surface of the sleeve, the teeth of the guided disc are allowed to move more smoothly.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">In certain embodiments, the frame <b>102</b> and the sleeve <b>105</b> can be made of flexible, elastic, and lightweight materials such as resins and be fabricated by 3D printing to improve the flexibility, elasticity, and wearing comfort of the footwear article incorporated with the present device. The present device is embedded into a cavity of the heel section of the footwear article so not to cause any uncomfortableness to the wearer. The frame <b>102</b> is also configured to limit the horizontal movement of the outer profile of the sleeve <b>105</b>. Due to the materials used to fabricate the components and the number of the components to form the present device, the weight and volume thereof can be significantly reduced. In one embodiment, the weight of the present device can be reduced to about 100 g or lower. In another embodiment, the volume of the present device can be reduced to about 118 cm<sup>3 </sup>or lower.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">Turning into <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the schematic diagram on the left panel depicts how collisional energy is harvested by the present device in an article of footwear, for example, in a boot (on the right panel). As shown on the left panel of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a close-up isometric view of the sleeve <b>105</b> accommodating the spring <b>104</b> of the present device, where two parallel guided rods <b>201</b> are provided in the sleeve <b>105</b> to connect the gearbox <b>103</b> (not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>) and a guided disc <b>204</b>. One end of the spring <b>104</b> is attached on to a surface of the guided disc <b>204</b> while an opposite end of the spring <b>104</b> is attached to a lower surface of the sleeve top <b>203</b>. The sleeve <b>105</b> including an upper surface of the sleeve top <b>203</b> is embedded inside an insole of the footwear article to enhance the wearing comfort. The guided disc <b>204</b> includes a plurality of teeth <b>205</b> at the periphery thereof so that the guided disc <b>204</b> is capable to rotate along the internal threads <b>202</b> of the sleeve <b>105</b>, thereby converting a linear reciprocating motion into rotation of the guided disc <b>204</b> along the internal threads <b>202</b> in accordance with a designated pitch and twist angle (&#x3b8;) of the sleeve <b>105</b> during a heel strike/heel up moment which triggers a vertical or substantially vertical movement of the spring <b>104</b>. This configuration limits the movement direction and range of the motion conversion mechanism without sacrificing normal gait pattern such as step length, width and frequency, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">Provided on the right panel of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is an exemplary embodiment of a footwear article, for example, a boot, incorporated with the present device and illustration of how the linear reciprocating motion is transformed into electric current and then stored in the footwear article. In that exemplary embodiment, a power management circuit (PMC) <b>206</b> is provided in the middle of the sole of the boot <b>208</b> for receiving power (in a form of alternating current) generated by the generator <b>101</b> and convert thereof into electricity that can be ultimately stored into one or more energy storage modules <b>207</b> which is disposed under an arch section of the boot <b>208</b>. The PMC <b>206</b> mainly includes AC-DC converter, impedance matching circuit, and capacitors, and signal indicators, which are collectively for converting an alternating current received from the generator <b>101</b> into direct current at a proper voltage level which can be stored by the storage module(s) and/or be used directly to supply power to other parts of the footwear article and/or other electronics. Detailed circuitry diagram of an exemplary embodiment of the PMC is depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> and descriptions hereinafter.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">Turning into <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, the gearbox <b>103</b> and corresponding connections with the generator <b>101</b> and the motion conversion mechanism in the sleeve <b>105</b> are depicted. The rotation of the guided disc <b>204</b> along the internally threaded sleeve <b>104</b> due to the linear reciprocating moment exerted on the sleeve top <b>203</b> as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> drives guided rods <b>201</b> to rotate, with one end fixed to the guided disc <b>204</b> and an opposite end fixed to a gear plate <b>304</b>. Two parallel rods' design will be more stable to transmit strong torque compared with a single one. The gear plate <b>304</b> turns the rest of the gears (<b>301</b>, <b>302</b>, <b>303</b>, <b>305</b>, <b>306</b>). In order to reduce the size of the gearbox <b>103</b>, the gears in this example are arranged in hierarchy and in pairs, that is, gears <b>301</b> and <b>302</b> form a pair; gears <b>303</b> and <b>306</b> form another pair; gears <b>304</b> and <b>305</b> form a third pair. When gear <b>304</b> turns, it drives its corresponding gear <b>305</b> which is concentrically connected to a gear of a second hierarchical pair, gear <b>306</b>, such that gear <b>306</b> will also be driven, accordingly, thereby driving a corresponding gear <b>303</b> to turn, etc. Thus, the heel strike force exerted on the sleeve <b>105</b> is transformed into rotation through the motion conversion mechanism within the sleeve <b>105</b>, and the rotational speed of the guided member of the motion conversion mechanism is increased along this hierarchy of gears in the gearbox <b>103</b> until gear <b>301</b> which is connected to the generator <b>101</b>. This hierarchical arrangement of gears in the gearbox <b>103</b> can ensure a substantially full transformation of the heel strike force exerted on the sleeve top <b>203</b> by the wearer during walking into a high-speed rotation of the generator <b>101</b>, in order to result in a high power output while the normal gait pattern and wearing comfort are not sacrificed. Power output of the present device can be adjusted by adjusting the frequency up-conversion ratio among different pairs of gears. Relationship between the power output of the present device and frequency up-conversion ratio of different gears will be further elaborated hereinafter.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">Turning into <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>, how the linear motion of heel strike is converted into energy and how the level of power output can be adjusted in the present device are schematically depicted. Taking one gait cycle as an example, the spring <b>104</b> during the early and mid stance phase is compressed by the heel strike force exerted on the sleeve top <b>203</b> to force the attached guided disc <b>204</b> in the presence of a number of teeth <b>205</b> at its periphery to move downwards along the internal threaded line <b>202</b>. In this example, the guided disc <b>204</b> with the teeth <b>205</b> rotates clockwise along the internal threaded line <b>202</b>. The rotation of guided disc <b>204</b> drives the attached guided rods <b>201</b> and the gear <b>305</b> attached thereto to rotate in the same circular direction. Once the gear <b>305</b> is driven to rotate, the corresponding gear <b>304</b> of the same pair and other lower hierarchical pairs of gears in the gearbox <b>103</b> will be driven to rotate in order to eventually drive the generator <b>101</b>. The spring <b>104</b> disposed in the sleeve <b>105</b> also serves to absorb at least partially the impact force of the touchdown moment to protect the heel against excessive load.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">During the terminal stance phase, the compressed spring <b>104</b> is released while a restoring force is provided for the heel up moment, thus assisting contraction of soleus and gastrocnemius muscles. Meanwhile, the restoring force also drives the guided members (guided disc and rods) to rotate counterclockwise in order to eventually drive the generator <b>101</b> for power generation when the sleeve top returns to its initial position. Therefore, the heel strike energy is fully captured by the vertical and circular movements of the corresponding mechanical parts of the motion-energy conversation mechanism within the sleeve of the present invention during stance phase of each gait cycle while the heel section is protected against excessive load by the spring.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">The speed of rotation of the guided members within the sleeve to exert the first frequency up conversion can be adjusted by adjusting the magnitude of the pitch of the internal thread line and/or the twist angle. The smaller the magnitude of each pitch is, or the larger the twist angle is, the higher is the speed of rotation of the guided members within the sleeve.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">During each gait cycle, the speed of the initial rotation of the most proximal gear to the guided rods, gear <b>305</b>, is increased by the gears of the gearbox <b>103</b> before the generator <b>101</b> is driven. The afore-mentioned hierarchical arrangement of gears enables a second frequency up conversion. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>, moduli and the number of teeth of each pair of gears (Z<sub>11</sub>, Z<sub>12</sub>; Z<sub>21</sub>, Z<sub>22</sub>; Z<sub>31</sub>, Z<sub>32</sub>) can be adjusted to optimize the final speed of rotation of the most proximal gear, gear <b>301</b>, to the generator <b>101</b>. The frequency up conversion ratio (K) for each pair of gears of the gearbox <b>103</b> is represented by the following equation:</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0000">
<maths id="MATH-US-00001" num="00001">
<math overflow="scroll">
 <mrow>
  <mi>K</mi>
  <mo>=</mo>
  <mrow>
   <munderover>
    <mo>&#x220f;</mo>
    <mrow>
     <mi>i</mi>
     <mo>=</mo>
     <mn>1</mn>
    </mrow>
    <mn>3</mn>
   </munderover>
   <mfrac>
    <msub>
     <mi>Z</mi>
     <mrow>
      <mi>i</mi>
      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
      <mn>1</mn>
     </mrow>
    </msub>
    <msub>
     <mi>Z</mi>
     <mrow>
      <mi>i</mi>
      <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
      <mn>2</mn>
     </mrow>
    </msub>
   </mfrac>
  </mrow>
 </mrow>
</math>
</maths>
</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0000">In this example, i=1, 2, or 3.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0067">It should be understood that the number of gears of the gearbox, hierarchical arrangement thereof, and/or the frequency up conversion ratio is/are adjustable in order to optimize the rotational speed of the most proximal gear with respect to the generator <b>101</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0068">Turning into <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, the generator <b>101</b> includes or is connected to one or more rectifiers for converting AC into DC current. The generator <b>101</b> can be one or more electromagnetic generators being rectifier circuits for AC-DC conversion. The generator <b>101</b> can be connected to a power management circuit (PMC), such as the PMC shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, where it includes, but not limited to, rectifiers, voltage converter, and capacitors, and signal indicators. For example, TD1410 module shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is used to manage the DC output at a proper voltage level for the following energy storage element. The PMC can further include or be connected to an energy storage element such as supercapacitors and rechargeable batteries. The energy stored in such an energy storage element can be used to supply power to other electronics of the same footwear article or to other portable electronics including, but not limited to, smartphones, sensors, display/screen, and wireless communication modules. Since most of the circuits in the PMC do not occupy a lot of space (except some sensors/indicators), and therefore they can all be installed in the heel section of the footwear article, or simply within the frame of the present device. In a preferred embodiment, the PMC is incorporated into the frame of the present device to reduce the overall size of the device, and by which it can save cost on extra installation.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0069">Turning into <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref>, it shows a footwear article, which is a boot <b>600</b>, with hollow heel section <b>601</b> and hollow insole <b>602</b>. For simplicity of illustration, the sleeve <b>105</b> and frame <b>102</b> of the present device are separated from the generator <b>101</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref>. The power management circuit (PMC) <b>206</b> and energy storage element <b>207</b> are electrically connected to the generator <b>101</b> in this example. In an exemplary embodiment, the frame <b>102</b> and sleeve <b>105</b> are made of flexible, elastic, and lightweight materials, such as acrylonitrile-butadiene-styrene (ABS), to reduce the overall weight and enhance the wearing comfort, and the materials selected are preferably 3D printable. All the major components (<b>101</b>, <b>102</b>, <b>103</b>, <b>104</b>, <b>105</b>) of the present device are embedded into the hollow heel section <b>601</b> while the PMC <b>206</b> and energy storage element <b>207</b> are embedded into the hollow insole <b>602</b> of the boot <b>600</b>. From a bottom view of the boot <b>600</b>, part of the frame <b>102</b> and the sleeve <b>203</b> can be visualized, while the PMC <b>206</b> and energy storage element <b>207</b> are fully embedded into the insole <b>602</b> so that they cannot be visualized from this view.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0070"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>B</figref> shows different performance test results of the boot <b>600</b> incorporated with the present device. Shock absorbing performance of the boot <b>600</b> is verified by about 15.4% reduction in peak pressure between a normal (inactive) state and active state of the present device. Gait assisting performance is verified by measuring the change in average muscle activity of two main calf muscles, gastrocnemius and soleus muscles, with or without the activation of the present device. The results (bar chart in the middle of the lower panel) suggest that the present device reduces the muscle activity of gastrocnemius and soleus muscles by about 4.95% and about 4.35%, respectively, compared to those measured under inactive state of the device. In terms of the energy harvesting performance, under excitation by stride frequency of about 1.1 Hz, the present device is capable to generate a maximum voltage of about 13 V and a peak power of 3.8 Watts, provided that the pitch is 10 mm with a 45-degree twist angle, and the up conversion ratio of the gear box is 65. The dimension of the frame <b>102</b> of the device in this example is 55 mm (L)&#xd7;35 mm (W)&#xd7;25 mm (H), or in an total volume of about 118 cm<sup>3 </sup>(including the volume of the frame <b>102</b> and the sleeve <b>105</b>), and a total mass of about <b>101</b> grams. A subsequent measurement (results are not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>B</figref>) on power output from a pair of the boots <b>600</b> both incorporated with the same configuration of the present device shows that the boots can generate over 7 Watts of peak power collectively.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0071">Although the invention has been described in terms of certain embodiments, other embodiments apparent to those of ordinary skill in the art are also within the scope of this invention. Accordingly, the scope of the invention is intended to be defined only by the claims which follow.</p>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">INDUSTRIAL APPLICABILITY</heading>
<p id="p-0075" num="0072">The structure of present invention is simple, and can be easily assembled, thus the manufacturing cost could be minimized. The present invention is also easy to be scaled up, thus is suitable for large-scale industrialization. The reasonable size and weight of the present device makes it easy to fit into substantially all types of footwear. Adjustable voltage output by varying different parameters of the mechanical parts of the present device also provides flexibility and simplicity for meeting different requirements and performance expectations of footwear articles.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00001" nb-file="US20230225448A1-20230720-M00001.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00001" he="8.13mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US20230225448A1-20230720-M00001.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A device for improving energy harvesting, gait assisting and shock absorbing efficiencies while maintaining normal gait pattern of a wearer of an article of footwear during locomotion, the device comprising:
<claim-text>a motion conversion module comprising an impact force absorbing and resilient member;</claim-text>
<claim-text>and one or more guided members being attached to the impact force absorbing resilient member;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a rotation acceleration module comprising a plurality of rotatable members and communicating with the motion conversion module;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an electrical energy generator communicating with the rotation acceleration module; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a frame accommodating the motion conversion module, rotation acceleration module and electrical energy generator,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the motion conversion module being vertically extended from a horizontal section of the frame forming a sleeve, wherein the sleeve is internally threaded,</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one of the guided members being configured to move along the internally threaded sleeve when the impact force absorbing resilient member moves vertically along the sleeve due to a heel strike or up motion of the wearer's foot,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the one or more guided members, upon moving along the internally threaded sleeve, driving at least one of a plurality of rotatable members of the rotation acceleration module to rotate, thereby subsequently driving the remaining rotatable members of the rotation acceleration module;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the electrical energy generator transforming rotational energy of the rotatable members of the rotation acceleration module into electric energy to be stored in an energy storage element and/or supplied to other parts of the article of the footwear and external electronics.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the impact force absorbing and resilient member is a spring with one end attached to a top end of the sleeve and an opposite end attached to a first guided member.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the first guided member attached to the spring is disc-like and comprises a plurality of teeth disposed at a periphery thereof such that the first guided member is capable to move along the internally threaded sleeve.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the first guided member is engaged with a second guided member such that when the first guided member moves along the internally threaded sleeve, the second guided member is driven to rotate either clockwise or counterclockwise.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the second guided member is rod-like with one end attached to the first guided member and an opposite end attached to a first rotatable member of the rotation acceleration module such that when the second guided member rotates due to vertical displacement of the first guided member along the internally threaded sleeve, the first rotatable member is driven to rotate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein one or more rotatable members of the rotation acceleration module is/are gears having the same or different size and/or number of teeth with each other, and is/are driven by rotation of the first rotatable member.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein more than one of the gears are arranged in hierarchy and at least two of the gears in different size and number of teeth form a pair of gears to interact with another pair of gears such that an initial rotational speed by the rotation of the first rotatable member is increased through the interactions among different pairs of gears in the rotation acceleration module.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the electrical energy generator is selected from an electromagnetic generator and is activated by the rotation of the gear that is disposed most proximally to the electrical energy generator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the electromagnetic generator is connected to a power management module comprising one or more rectifiers to convert alternating current generated by the electromagnetic generator into direct current.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the power management module further comprises voltage converter to regulate the direct current level to be output to the energy storage element, other parts of the article of footwear, and/or external electronics.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the rotational speed of the most proximal gear to the electrical energy generator is adjustable by adjusting one or both of a helical pitch and a twist angle of the internal threads of the sleeve in the motion conversion module, and/or adjusting a frequency up-conversion ratio between each of the gears of the same pair in the rotation acceleration module.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein within a space between the teeth of the first guided member and a path of the internal threads of the sleeve along which the first guided member moves within the sleeve is added with a lubricant to smoothen the path that the teeth of the first guided member travel.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. A power generating and gait assisting article of footwear comprising:
<claim-text>the device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a power management circuit; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>one or more energy storage elements.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The article of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, further comprises a first hollow space at a heel section of the article for disposing the device and a second hollow space in the middle of an insole of the article for disposing the power management circuit and the one or more energy storage elements.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. The article of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref> being selected from boots, shoes, or high-heeled footwear.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. A method for improving energy harvesting and shock absorbing efficiencies of an article of footwear comprising:
<claim-text>providing a first hollow space at a heel section and a second hollow space in the middle of an insole of the article of footwear;</claim-text>
<claim-text>incorporating the device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> into the first hollow space; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>incorporating a power management circuit and one or more energy storage elements into the second hollow space.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. A power generating and gait assisting article of footwear fabricated according to the method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
