<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225590A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225590</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17871814</doc-number>
<date>20220722</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>17</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>303</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>50</main-group>
<subgroup>30</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>0014</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>00135</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>303</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20160201</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>50</main-group>
<subgroup>30</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>00142</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>00103</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">APPLICATOR FOR A SPECULUM ACCESSORY SLEEVE AND USE THEREOF</invention-title>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>16661748</doc-number>
<date>20191023</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11395577</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17871814</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation>
<division>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>15588439</doc-number>
<date>20170505</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>10456016</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>16661748</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</division>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>CEEK Women's Health, Inc.</orgname>
<address>
<city>Portland</city>
<state>OR</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lalli</last-name>
<first-name>Maria</first-name>
<address>
<city>Portland</city>
<state>OR</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="01" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Freissler</last-name>
<first-name>Christian</first-name>
<address>
<city>Portland</city>
<state>OR</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="02" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lee</last-name>
<first-name>Katie</first-name>
<address>
<city>Portland</city>
<state>OR</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="03" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Peppersack</last-name>
<first-name>Ute</first-name>
<address>
<city>Cologne</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An applicator for positioning a sleeve accessory on a medical speculum, and a method for using the applicator, is provided. The applicator has a flat, oblong shape with a distal end and a proximal end, the proximal end being broader than the distal end. The distal end of the applicator includes a first prong and a second prong. At least a portion of the distal end of the applicator is configured to slide into a lumen of a sleeve accessory to facilitate positioning of the sleeve accessory on a medical speculum.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="125.22mm" wi="158.75mm" file="US20230225590A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="220.56mm" wi="103.12mm" file="US20230225590A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="239.86mm" wi="121.24mm" file="US20230225590A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="100.75mm" wi="107.53mm" file="US20230225590A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="189.40mm" wi="142.24mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225590A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="239.44mm" wi="147.57mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225590A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="205.66mm" wi="152.15mm" file="US20230225590A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="135.72mm" wi="153.59mm" file="US20230225590A1-20230720-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="194.39mm" wi="150.03mm" file="US20230225590A1-20230720-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims the benefit of and priority to, and is a continuation of, U.S. Non-Provisional application Ser. No. 16/661,748, filed on Oct. 23, 2019, which is a division of, U.S. Non-Provisional application Ser. No. 15/588,439, filed May 5, 2017, now U.S. Pat. No. 10,456,016, which is incorporated herein by reference in its entirety.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates generally to the field of a medical speculum, and more particularly to an applicator for applying a sleeve to a medical speculum.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">A speculum is a medical tool used to provide visualization into a body cavity. Speculums or specula are traditionally used for viewing and accessing the vaginal cavity for gynecology patients. The traditional speculum consists of two blades with a hinge and a handle. The blades are inserted into the body cavity in a closed position, and separated by squeezing two pieces of the handle together or applying force to a lever attached to the handle, thereby dilating the vagina and providing visualization of and accessibility to the vagina, the cervix, and surrounding areas. Once opened, the speculum can be locked in an open position, e.g., by using a screw-based mechanism so an operator (e.g., physician, nurse, mid-wife, etc.) does not need to continue squeezing the pieces of the handle or the lever during the inspection. The operator can then proceed with inspecting the vagina, conducting a Pap smear, or any other medical procedures that may need to be provided.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The double blade design of speculum devices has been in use since the 1800s, and few changes have been made to the original design. The biggest changes with the double-blade design have been changes in the material from metal to plastic and the addition of internal lighting on some models of the speculum so that the operator does not have to rely on external lighting to gain a clear view of the vagina and the cervix.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">There are drawbacks with the traditional two blade design. For one, tissue can enter between the blades once they are opened inside the vaginal cavity, a common occurrence that providers characterize as &#x201c;side wall encroachment.&#x201d; Women, especially obese women, women with multiple vaginal births, or those with vaginal laxity, may have extra tissue in the side walls of the vagina that may fall into the space between the two blades once opened. This can cause problems for operators, particularly in providing clear visualization of the vagina and cervix, which potentially limits the effectiveness of the procedure. Furthermore, with all patients, when trying to close the speculum blades, tissue and/or pubic hair may become pinched between the blades. Pinching is extremely painful for patients and difficult for the operator to avoid without removing the speculum in an open position, which causes significant discomfort to the patients as well. There are no satisfactory solutions for these problems, resulting in tremendous patient discomfort with the entire speculum experience.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In an attempt to limit sidewall encroachment and allow for better visualization of the vaginal walls and cervix, operators may attempt to place condoms or portions of medical gloves over the speculum. This is an unsatisfactory and ineffective approach as condoms and gloves were not designed to support the internal pressure of the vaginal walls, but to be as thin as possible. Furthermore, using these solutions can result in both condoms and glove fingers, or torn portions of them, being left behind in the vaginal cavity following removal of the speculum. Alternatively, operators may choose to use larger speculums to provide a larger viewing/accessing window to compensate for tissue entering the side of the speculum between the blades. However, increasing the size of the speculum can provide discomfort to patients. Moreover, while there are now different sizes of speculums offered for an examination, it can be hard to determine the correct size for a patient as the size of the patient does not necessarily correlate with the size of the speculum that should be used.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">An additional drawback to the traditional speculum design is that speculums are traditionally made of metal, though some made with disposable plastic have been increasing in use. When the speculum is made of metal, it can feel cold to the patient upon entry to the vaginal cavity, especially in comparison to the internal temperatures of the body, which can result in discomfort for the patient during the procedure. This may result in the patient tensing up and making the procedure more painful. Even when made of plastic, the design of the speculum is generally the same as the traditional design (but for some differences that may exist in the locking mechanisms, wall thicknesses, consistencies between the types of plastic, etc.), meaning that even plastic speculums may face some of the same drawbacks as traditional speculums.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Embodiments herein generally relate to applicators for accessories to improve speculum devices, components of the same, and methods of making and using the same. The accessories overcome many drawbacks of existing speculum devices, and the applicators enable practitioners to easily position the accessories on speculum devices for use during a medical procedure. In one aspect, an applicator is provided for easy positioning of a sleeve accessory, either on an existing speculum design or an updated speculum design, to cover an insertion portion of the speculum.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">One embodiment relates to an applicator for positioning a sleeve accessory on a medical speculum. The applicator has a flat, oblong shape with a distal end and a proximal end, the proximal end being broader than the distal end. Additionally, the distal end includes a first prong and a second prong. At least a portion of the distal end of the applicator is configured to slide into a lumen of a sleeve accessory to facilitate positioning of the sleeve accessory on a medical speculum.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Another embodiment relates to a method for positioning a sleeve accessory on a medical speculum. The method includes providing a medical speculum with a pair of bills, providing a sleeve accessory having a cylindrical sleeve body defining a lumen, and providing an applicator having a flat, oblong shape with a distal end and a proximal end, the proximal end being broader than the distal end. The distal end of the applicator includes a first prong and a second prong. The first prong and the second prong are configured to be folded into a first pocket and a second pocket, respectively, the first pocket and the second pocket configured to receive the bills of the medical speculum. The method further includes positioning the lumen of the sleeve accessory about the distal end of the applicator, sliding the bills of the speculum between the first pocket and the second pocket of the applicator to position the bills of the speculum in the lumen of the sleeve accessory; and removing the applicator from the lumen of the sleeve accessory.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Another embodiment relates to a kit. The kit includes a sleeve accessory having a cylindrical sleeve body defining a lumen, wherein the sleeve accessory is configured to be positioned on an insertion portion of a medical speculum, and an applicator having a flat, oblong shape with a distal end and a proximal end, the proximal end being broader than the distal end. The distal end includes a first prong and a second prong. The applicator is configured to slide, by the distal end of the applicator, at least partially into the lumen of the sleeve accessory to facilitate positioning of the sleeve accessory on the insertion portion of the medical speculum.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a side perspective view of a medical speculum on which a sleeve accessory according to various embodiments can be used.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a side view of the medical speculum of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a side perspective view of a sleeve accessory positioned on a medical speculum, according to an example embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is a side view of a sleeve accessory positioned on a medical speculum, according to an example embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is a side perspective view of a sleeve accessory positioned on a medical speculum in an open position, according to an example embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b>A and <b>6</b>B</figref> are bottom views of an applicator for a sleeve accessory, according to an example embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>C</figref> is a top view of the applicator of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b>A and <b>6</b>B</figref> positioned in a sleeve accessory, according to an example embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>A</figref> is a side view of the applicator of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b>A-<b>6</b>C</figref> being used to position a sleeve accessory on a medical speculum, according to an example embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>B</figref> is a top perspective view of the applicator of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b>A-<b>6</b>C</figref> being used to position a sleeve accessory on a medical speculum, according to an example embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>C</figref> is a side view of the applicator of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b>A-<b>6</b>C</figref> being used to position a sleeve accessory on a medical speculum, according to an example embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>D</figref> is a top perspective view of the applicator of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b>A-<b>6</b>C</figref> being used to position a sleeve accessory on a medical speculum, according to an example embodiment.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In the following detailed description, reference is made to the accompanying drawings, which form a part of the present disclosure. In the drawings, similar symbols typically identify similar components, unless context dictates otherwise. The illustrative embodiments described in the detailed description, drawings, and claims are not meant to be limiting. The detailed description is intended as a description of exemplary embodiments and is not intended to represent the only embodiments which may be practiced. The term &#x201c;exemplary,&#x201d; as used herein, means &#x201c;serving as an example, instance, or illustration,&#x201d; and should not necessarily be construed as preferred or advantageous over other embodiments. Other embodiments may be utilized, and other changes may be made, without departing from the spirit or scope of the subject matter presented herein. It will be readily understood that the aspects of the present disclosure, as generally described herein and illustrated in the Figures, can be arranged, substituted, combined, and designed in a wide variety of different configurations, all of which are explicitly contemplated by and form part of this disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Referring to the Figures generally, an applicator for a sleeve accessory, or modifier sleeve, for a medical speculum is shown. The sleeve accessory may be used on any traditional speculum or any new or updated speculum design, including speculums that may be specifically designed for use with the sleeve accessory according to the present embodiments. The sleeve has an expandable body portion and is configured to be removably attached to an insertion portion of a speculum. In certain uses, a practitioner may be able to select a speculum with a narrower profile than the practitioner would regularly select because the sleeve reduces some of the previously described shortcomings of the traditional speculum design, for example, the problem of vaginal side wall tissue falling into the user's line of sight during use. The applicator is then used by the practitioner to easily and quickly position the sleeve accessory onto the bills of a speculum with minimal direct handling of the sleeve.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, a two-blade speculum is shown according to certain traditional designs. As shown, the speculum <b>200</b> has an upper bill <b>203</b> and a lower bill <b>205</b>, a handle <b>207</b>, and a lever <b>209</b>. The upper bill <b>203</b> and the lower bill <b>205</b> together comprise an elongated insertion portion <b>211</b>. The insertion portion <b>211</b>, which is expandable as described herein, may be inserted into the vaginal cavity of a female patient. During insertion, the upper bill <b>203</b> and the lower bill <b>205</b> are in a closed position, wherein there is a minimal amount of space between the two bills. Once inserted and in order to dilate the vaginal cavity, the bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b> are separated into an open position by pressing the lever <b>209</b> towards the handle <b>207</b>. In accordance with typical speculum designs, the speculum <b>200</b> may be made of any sturdy biomaterial including metals and plastics.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, a side view of speculum <b>200</b> is shown. The upper bill <b>203</b> and the lower bill <b>205</b> may be configured in such a way that when in the closed position, the upper bill <b>203</b> and the lower bill <b>205</b> are wider near the handle <b>207</b> than near a body or end of the insertion portion <b>211</b>, i.e., the bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b> distend quickly to create somewhat of a cone shape near the handle <b>207</b>, as shown in the side view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>. The bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b> may maintain a constant shape after the cone, forming the elongated insertion portion <b>211</b>. The upper bill <b>203</b> and the lower bill <b>205</b> of the elongated insertion portion <b>211</b> may have a uniform width or diameter as the bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b> extend away from the handle <b>207</b>. In other embodiments, the proximal portion of the bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b> near the handle <b>207</b> may be up to two times wider than the distal end of the bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">At a distal end of the elongated insertion portion <b>211</b>, away from the proximal handle <b>207</b>, the bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b> may be rounded (e.g., the bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b> may each be rounded, the ends of bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b> closed together may form a rounded end, etc.). A rounded end may provide more comfort to a patient while receiving the speculum <b>200</b> in a cavity. The bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b> may also be configured such that when in the closed position, the ends the bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b> do not abut one another, creating a gap which helps to prevent tissue from becoming lodged in between the bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b>. In one embodiment, the bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b> may be of the same length such that when the bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b> are closed, they form a smooth, continuous end to the insertion portion <b>211</b>. Alternatively, in another embodiment, one of the bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b> may be longer than the other, such that when the bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b> are in the closed position, the longer bill juts out from beneath or above the other bill.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the handle <b>207</b> includes an upper portion and a lower portion. The upper portion of the handle <b>207</b> is coupled to bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b>. The lower portion provides a location for the user to hold the speculum <b>200</b>. Coupled to the handle <b>207</b> is the lever <b>209</b>. The lever <b>209</b> includes a mechanism for opening and closing bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b>. While the lever <b>209</b> is shown to be coupled to the upper portion of the handle <b>207</b>, the lever <b>209</b> may be coupled to the handle <b>207</b> at any location. In some embodiments, the speculum <b>200</b> may also include a mechanism for locking the bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b> into an open position.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">As described herein, using a sleeve accessory, such as sleeve accessory <b>301</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, with a medical speculum, such as speculum <b>200</b>, may overcome the previously described shortcomings of the traditional speculum in a variety of ways. First, the sleeve may be made of a rubber or other soft material that is warmer than the traditional metal speculum bills. As such, inserting a speculum with a sleeve accessory attached may be less shocking, and thus more comfortable, to a patient than a bare metal speculum. The material may be at least substantially transparent to allow for good visualization of the vaginal cavity through the speculum with attached sleeve. Furthermore, a slimmer profile speculum can be utilized because of the sleeve (e.g., because the sleeve allows for improved visualization such that a larger speculum is not necessary), which provides better comfort for the patient during the procedure, examination, or surgery involving the speculum. The sleeve moreover allows the speculum to be removed in a closed position while preventing the pinching of either tissues or pubic hair during the process, significantly improving patient comfort while reducing patient anxiety. Importantly, the sleeve also provides the side wall support between the upper bill and the lower bill of the speculum that allows the practitioner better and less impeded visualization into the vagina and cervix. When used during an electrosurgery, the sleeve accessory may additionally provide insulation to protect the vaginal walls of a patient during the electrosurgery procedure. Accordingly, using a sleeve accessory with a medical speculum may provide a number of benefits to the patient. Because of this, it would also be advantageous to practitioners to have an applicator tool to help them in quickly and correctly positioning a sleeve accessory on a medical speculum. A sleeve accessory may be the same or similar to those described in U.S. patent application Ser. No. 15/393,041 filed Dec. 28, 2016, which is incorporated by reference herein in its entirety.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Though specific reference is made in this specification to the elements or features of speculum <b>200</b>, it is understood that the accessory or modifier elements described herein, as well as any applicators for the accessory or modifier elements described herein, may be used with any speculum having an elongated and expandable insertion portion, such as any two-blade speculum design. The features herein used to describe speculum <b>200</b> may also be present on any other speculum on which the accessory or modifier elements described herein may be used.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">In one aspect, a practitioner may use a sleeve accessory adapted to be used with a speculum, such as speculum <b>200</b>, as follows. First, a user positions a sleeve accessory on an insertion portion of a speculum, such as insertion portion <b>211</b> on speculum <b>200</b>, while the speculum is in a closed position. In exemplary embodiments, the user positions the sleeve accessory on the insertion portion by using an applicator tool, such as the applicators described herein, which aids the practitioner in quickly and correctly positioning the sleeve accessory on the insertion portion of the speculum. The user then inserts the speculum with the attached sleeve accessory into a patient's vagina. The user sets the speculum to the open position, thereby separating bills of the insertion portion and stretching the sleeve accessory. Next, the user performs a medical procedure on the patient using the speculum in the open position. The medical procedure may be any obstetric or gynecological procedure, such as an examination of the vaginal cavity, a Pap smear, an insertion or removal of an intrauterine device (IUD), an insemination, a sexually transmitted infection (STI) testing, a tissue collection, a biopsy, or an electrosurgery. After the user completes the medical procedure, the user closes the speculum and removes the speculum from the patient. Finally, the user removes the sleeve accessory from the speculum (e.g., by rolling the sleeve accessory off, by using a removal device, etc.).</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>3</b>-<b>5</b></figref> show examples of a sleeve accessory to be used with a speculum. The sleeve accessory may be the same or similar to those described in U.S. patent application Ser. No. 15/393,041 filed Dec. 28, 2016, which is incorporated by reference herein in its entirety. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> depicts a sleeve accessory <b>301</b> on the elongated insertion portion <b>211</b> of speculum <b>200</b>. As shown, the sleeve <b>301</b> is configured to be positioned on the elongated insertion portion <b>211</b>, to surround or enclose both bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b>, while the bills are in a closed position. In some embodiments, the sleeve <b>301</b> has a cylindrical sleeve body. By &#x201c;cylindrical&#x201d; it is meant that the sleeve body has a continuous, longitudinal shape that surrounds a hollow area (e.g., a lumen or hollow sleeve channel) within an inner wall or surface of the cylinder. The cylindrical sleeve body is not limited to a circular cylinder and may instead have a cross-sectional shape that is a square, a rectangle, a circle, an oval, a triangle, and so on. In the embodiment shown, the sleeve <b>301</b> has a cylindrical shape with a proximal opening through which the insertion portion <b>211</b> can be inserted. In the embodiment shown, the shape of the sleeve <b>301</b> substantially matches the shape of the bills, or may be in another shape, on which the sleeve <b>301</b> is being positioned. As such, the cylindrical body of the sleeve <b>301</b> may have a uniform width or diameter between a distal end of the sleeve body and a proximal end of the sleeve body while the sleeve <b>301</b> is in an un-stretched or unexpanded state, to match a uniform width or diameter of the bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b> extending away from the handle <b>207</b>. In one embodiment, the uniform diameter of the cylindrical body of the sleeve <b>301</b> may range between 0.25 inches and 3.0 inches. In other embodiments, the sleeve <b>301</b> may comprise a different natural shape than the shape of the bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b>, and may also have a non-uniform width or diameter ranging between 0.25 and 3.0 inches when in an un-stretched or unexpanded state.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The sleeve <b>301</b> may be made of one or more compliant or partially compliant materials, such as latex, vinyl, natural and synthetic rubbers, silicone, nylon, polyethylene, polyurethane, polypropylene, and non-degradable or degradable elastomers. In preferred embodiments, the sleeve <b>301</b> may be made of a polyisoprene (PI), a polyurethane (PU), a thermoplastic polyurethane (TPU), a styrene copolymer (SBS), and/or a thermoplastic elastomer (TPE). The material of the sleeve <b>301</b> may range from completely transparent to translucent or frosty to opaque. Alternatively, the sleeve <b>301</b> may include a finish that ranges from completely transparent to translucent or frosty to opaque. Different finishes may be used for different types of gynecological examinations or procedures. For example, a thicker and/or more opaque sleeve may be used for a surgical procedure, such as an electrosurgery, while a thinner and/or more clear sleeve may be used for a gynecological examination or procedure.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The sleeve <b>301</b> or a portion of the sleeve <b>301</b> may optionally be coated with one or more bioactive or therapeutic agents, lubricants, or surface finishes. Examples of suitable bioactive or therapeutic agents include, but are not limited to, hormonal and non-hormonal contraceptive agents, cancer screening agents, vaginal spermicides, vaginal microbicides, antibacterial agents, antifungal agents, antiviral agents, anti-HIV agents, and cancer treatment agents, or combinations thereof The bioactive or therapeutic agents may be in any suitable formulation that may be applied to the surface of a vaginal speculum, such as a liquid, gel and powder.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">In some embodiments, lubricants may be applied to at least a portion of an inner surface of the sleeve <b>301</b> and/or to an outer surface of the sleeve <b>301</b>. When applied to the inner surface of the sleeve <b>301</b>, the lubricant may, e.g., aid in positioning the sleeve <b>301</b> on the insertion portion <b>211</b>. When applied to an outer surface of the sleeve, the lubricant may, e.g., help the speculum <b>200</b> with the attached sleeve <b>301</b> be more easily inserted into the patient. In other embodiments, the lubricant on the interior surface and/or exterior surface of the sleeve <b>301</b> may instead be, or may be combined with, a powder applied to the sleeve <b>301</b> or a surface texture finished into a material of the sleeve <b>301</b>. The powder and/or surface texture may likewise, e.g., aid the user in positioning the sleeve <b>301</b> on the insertion portion <b>211</b>, help the speculum <b>200</b> with the attached sleeve <b>301</b> be more easily inserted into the patient, and so on. In various embodiments, the sleeve <b>301</b> may come with lubricant and/or powder pre-applied, the sleeve <b>301</b> may come in a kit with lubricant and/or powder included for the user to apply to the sleeve <b>301</b>, the sleeve <b>301</b> may come with instructions that recommend types or brands of lubricants and/or powders for the user to apply to create the beneficial effects discussed above, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, once positioned on the insertion portion <b>211</b>, the sleeve <b>301</b> surrounds the bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b> and preferably has a snug fit around bill <b>203</b> and <b>205</b>. As such, sleeve <b>301</b> should not move along the bills <b>203</b> or <b>205</b> during insertion into the vagina or during a medical examination, procedure, or surgery being conducted on the vaginal or surrounding tissues. The sleeve <b>301</b> may additionally include ribbed details <b>310</b> that help the sleeve <b>301</b> remain securely fastened onto the insertion portion <b>211</b>. In one embodiment, the ribbed details may be limited to a portion of the sleeve <b>301</b> secured to the smaller, narrower, distal end of the insertion portion <b>211</b>. In other embodiments, the ribbed details may, additionally or alternatively, be limited to a portion of the sleeve <b>301</b> secured to the larger, proximal end of the insertion portion <b>211</b> near the handle <b>207</b>, or be distributed throughout the length of the sleeve <b>301</b>. In some embodiments, the ribbed details may instead be, or may be combined with, texture differences or lubrication differences provided on an inner surface of the sleeve <b>301</b> and/or gripping elements (e.g., such as flanges <b>505</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>) positioned on an inner surface of the sleeve <b>301</b> that may help the sleeve <b>301</b> remain securely fastened onto the insertion portion <b>211</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The proximal opening of the sleeve <b>301</b>, as well as a distal opening included in some embodiments of the sleeve <b>301</b>, may have a ridged finish, shown as end ring <b>307</b>. The ridged finish may be provided to give the user a ridge to aid the user in positioning the sleeve <b>301</b> on the insertion portion <b>211</b>, to finish the end of the sleeve <b>301</b> so that the end of the sleeve <b>301</b> is less easily ripped or otherwise damaged, to provide additional tension to adhere the sleeve <b>301</b> to the insertion portion <b>211</b>, and so on. The ridged finish may be provided as an end ring <b>307</b>, which may be a rolled bead edge (i.e., similar to a condom) or may be formed from an encapsulated ring (i.e., a ring that is rolled into the end of the sleeve <b>301</b> and cured). In other embodiments, the ridged finish may be provided as a dip in the material of the sleeve <b>301</b>, a secondary dip in another polymer material (e.g., of a different thickness, durometer, color, etc.) attached to the sleeve <b>301</b>, an otherwise attached or adhered secondary material that finishes the opening(s), and so on.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> illustrates another embodiment of a sleeve accessory for a medical speculum, shown as sleeve <b>501</b>. Sleeve <b>501</b> is designed similarly to sleeve <b>301</b>, with a cylindrical sleeve body configured to be slid over an insertion portion of a speculum, such as insertion portion <b>211</b> of speculum <b>200</b>. Sleeve <b>501</b> may have many of the same features as described above with respect to sleeve <b>301</b>, such as an end ring <b>507</b>. Sleeve <b>501</b> also includes flanges <b>505</b> to help the sleeve remain securely fastened onto the insertion portion <b>211</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>, similar to sleeve <b>301</b>, the cylindrical body of sleeve <b>501</b> has an open proximal end and an open distal end. However, in some embodiments, a sleeve accessory may instead have a closed distal end (e.g., the sleeve <b>501</b> may wrap around the distal end of the bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b> so as to enclose the top portion of the bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b>, or extend up to the distal end of the bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b>). In these embodiments, the sleeve accessory may further include a small hole or aperture (not shown) in the closed, distal end of the sleeve accessory, which may allow for visualization, tissue sampling, etc. through the otherwise closed distal end. Additionally, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>, the distal end of the sleeve <b>501</b> nearly reaches the distal end of the bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b>. However, in other embodiments, a sleeve accessory may not reach the end of the bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b> when the sleeve accessory is positioned on the bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b> or may extend past the end of the bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> illustrates a sleeve accessory, shown as sleeve <b>601</b>, positioned on speculum <b>200</b>. Sleeve <b>601</b> is configured similarly to sleeves <b>301</b> and <b>501</b> discussed above, with a cylindrical sleeve body surrounding a lumen configured to receive an insertion portion of a speculum, such as insertion portion <b>211</b> of speculum <b>200</b>, and open proximal and distal ends framed by end rings <b>607</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, once positioned on the speculum <b>200</b>, when a force is applied to the lever <b>209</b> and the bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b> of the speculum <b>200</b> separate, the sleeve <b>601</b> expands from a first state to a second state (i.e., from an unexpanded state to an expanded state). When the bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b> separate, the sleeve <b>601</b> may stretch to accommodate the increase in distance between bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b>. Beneficially, the expansion of the sleeve <b>601</b> provides side wall retention for tissue encroachment from the side walls of the vagina, allowing the user to maintain an uninterrupted view of the vaginal cavity and cervix while viewing the vaginal cavity and cervix through the speculum <b>200</b>. The expansion of the sleeve <b>601</b> also works to prevent vaginal tissue or pubic hair from entering the opening between the bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b>, as the bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b> may cause pinching of the tissue or pubic hair that is painful for the patient when the bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b> are returned to the closed position at the conclusion of the procedure, examination, or surgery. Additionally, when the bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b> are closed, the sleeve <b>601</b> may return to its original state (e.g., the first state).</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b>A-<b>6</b>C</figref> illustrate an applicator <b>700</b> for a sleeve accessory (e.g., sleeve accessory <b>301</b>, <b>501</b>, and/or <b>601</b>), according to one embodiment. The applicator <b>700</b> is used by a practitioner to facilitate the positioning of a sleeve accessory onto a medical speculum, such as speculum <b>200</b>. A bottom view of the applicator <b>700</b> is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b>A and <b>6</b>B</figref>. As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref>, according to one embodiment, the applicator <b>700</b> is flat and roughly oblong, with a broader proximal end <b>702</b> and a narrower distal end <b>704</b>. The proximal end includes a tab <b>706</b> that may be pulled away from the main body of the applicator <b>700</b>, while the distal end <b>704</b> splits into a first prong <b>708</b> and a second prong <b>710</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The applicator <b>700</b> further includes a first flap <b>712</b> and a second flap <b>714</b> formed into the sides of the applicator <b>700</b>, where the first flap <b>712</b> is configured to fold at a first fold line <b>716</b> and the second flap <b>714</b> is configured to fold at a second fold line <b>718</b>, as shown by the arrows of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>B</figref> illustrates the applicator <b>700</b> with the first flap <b>712</b> folded over the first fold line <b>716</b> and the second flap <b>714</b> folded over the second fold line <b>718</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>B</figref>, when the flaps <b>712</b> and <b>714</b> are folded over, the first flap <b>712</b> forms a first pocket <b>720</b> within the first prong <b>708</b> and the second flap <b>714</b> forms a second pocket <b>722</b> within the second prong <b>710</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The applicator <b>700</b> may be made of a stiff, noncompliant or minimally compliant material or of a flexible, more compliant material. Thus, the applicator <b>700</b> may be made of paper, cardboard, paperboard, or corrugated fiberboard. Alternatively, the applicator <b>700</b> may be made of natural or synthetic rubbers or of a plastic, such as latex, vinyl, silicone, polyethene, polyurethane, polypropylene, polycarbonate, or non-degradable or degradable elastomers. In some embodiments, the applicator <b>700</b> may be designed for a single use and be disposable. In other embodiments, the applicator <b>700</b> may be designed to be reusable (e.g., be designed to be sterilizable for reuse).</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">A top view of the applicator <b>700</b> positioned within a sleeve accessory, shown as sleeve <b>801</b>, is illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>C</figref>. The sleeve <b>801</b> is designed similarly to sleeves <b>301</b>, <b>401</b>, <b>501</b>, and <b>601</b>, with a cylindrical sleeve body configured to be slid over an insertion portion of a speculum, such as insertion portion <b>211</b> of speculum <b>200</b>. The sleeve <b>801</b> further includes an open proximal end <b>802</b> framed by an end ring <b>807</b> and an open distal end <b>804</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">However, other embodiments of sleeve <b>801</b> may include a closed distal end, one or more gripping elements (e.g., similar to ribbed details <b>310</b> or flanges <b>505</b>), one or more coatings, one or more surface finishes, and so on, as described above with respect to sleeves <b>301</b>, <b>501</b>, and <b>601</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>C</figref>, the applicator <b>700</b> is positioned within the sleeve <b>801</b>. In an exemplary embodiment, the applicator <b>700</b> and the sleeve <b>801</b> are packaged together with the applicator <b>700</b> pre-inserted into the sleeve <b>801</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>C</figref>. However, in other embodiments, a user may need to slide or otherwise position the applicator <b>700</b> into the sleeve <b>801</b>. In various embodiments, as shown, the applicator <b>700</b> is designed such that the oblong shape of the applicator <b>700</b>, with the broader proximal end <b>702</b> narrowing to the distal end <b>704</b>, fits the shape of the sleeve <b>801</b>, which may also narrow from the broader proximal end <b>802</b> to the narrower distal end <b>804</b>. Accordingly, the applicator <b>700</b> may be easily positioned within the sleeve <b>801</b> until the prongs <b>708</b> and <b>710</b> abut the walls of the sleeve <b>801</b>. In some embodiments, the prongs <b>708</b> and <b>710</b> may create friction between the applicator <b>700</b> and walls of the sleeve <b>801</b> such that there is at least some resistance to the applicator <b>700</b> being slid out from the sleeve <b>801</b>. Additionally, the tab <b>706</b> is configured to be tucked over the top edge (e.g., over the end ring <b>807</b>) of the proximal end <b>802</b> of the sleeve <b>801</b> once the applicator <b>700</b> has been slid into the sleeve <b>801</b>. Thus, the tab <b>706</b> and/or the resistance created by friction between the prongs <b>708</b> and <b>710</b> and the walls of the sleeve <b>801</b> may prevent the applicator <b>700</b> from inadvertently sliding out of the sleeve <b>801</b>. Instead, once the applicator <b>700</b> is inserted into the sleeve <b>801</b>, at least a small force may need to be applied to remove the applicator <b>700</b> from the sleeve <b>801</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Additionally, the prongs <b>708</b> and <b>710</b> are configured such that when the applicator <b>700</b> is inserted into the sleeve <b>801</b>, the prongs <b>708</b> and <b>710</b> hold the interior of the sleeve <b>801</b> at least partially open. In this way, the prongs <b>708</b> and <b>710</b> allow a user to easily slide an insertion portion of a medical speculum into the interior of sleeve <b>801</b>. Furthermore, the prongs <b>708</b> and <b>710</b> are spaced apart such that the space between the first fold line <b>716</b> and the second fold line <b>718</b> are at least as wide as the insertion portion of the medical speculum. As such, the insertion portion may be slid in between the prongs <b>708</b> and <b>710</b> and through the pockets <b>720</b> and <b>722</b> formed in the prongs <b>708</b> and <b>710</b>. Thus, the prongs <b>708</b> and <b>710</b> of the applicator <b>700</b> may guide the insertion portion of the medical speculum into the lumen of sleeve <b>801</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>C</figref>, in some embodiments, the distal ends <b>704</b> of the prongs <b>708</b> and <b>710</b> may not reach the distal end <b>804</b> of the sleeve <b>801</b>. However, in other embodiments, the applicator <b>700</b> may be configured such that the ends of the prongs <b>708</b> and <b>710</b> meet the distal end <b>804</b> of the sleeve <b>801</b>, or the applicator <b>700</b> may be configured such that the ends of the prongs <b>708</b> and <b>710</b> extend past the distal end <b>804</b> of the sleeve <b>801</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>7</b>A-<b>7</b>D</figref> illustrate a process of using the applicator <b>700</b> to position the sleeve <b>801</b> on a medical speculum, such as speculum <b>200</b>. First, the user removes an applicator <b>700</b> and a sleeve <b>801</b> from packaging intended to keep the sleeve <b>801</b> sterile. In exemplary embodiments, the applicator <b>700</b> and the sleeve <b>801</b> are packaged together with the applicator <b>700</b> pre-inserted into the sleeve <b>801</b> (e.g., as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>C</figref>). In such embodiments the user may, for example, remove the applicator <b>700</b> and sleeve <b>801</b> combination from the packaging by grasping the broad, proximal end <b>702</b> of the applicator and pulling the applicator <b>700</b> and sleeve <b>801</b> combination from the packaging. In this way, the user may remove the applicator <b>700</b> and sleeve <b>801</b> from the packaging without directly handling the sleeve <b>801</b>, which may help keep the sleeve <b>801</b> sterile. However, in other embodiments, the applicator <b>700</b> and the sleeve <b>801</b> may be packaged in separate packaging or may be packaged together but without the applicator <b>700</b> pre-inserted into the sleeve <b>801</b>. In such embodiments, the user may remove the applicator <b>700</b> and the sleeve <b>801</b> from the packaging and insert the applicator <b>700</b> (e.g., by the distal end <b>704</b> of the applicator <b>700</b>) at least partially into the sleeve <b>801</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>C</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">With the applicator <b>700</b> positioned in the sleeve <b>801</b>, the prongs <b>708</b> and <b>710</b> of the applicator <b>700</b> hold the interior of the sleeve <b>801</b> at least partially open. Further, the applicator <b>700</b> should not inadvertently slide out of the sleeve <b>801</b> once inserted into the sleeve <b>801</b>. Thus, the user then grasps the applicator <b>700</b> by the broad, proximal end <b>702</b>, thereby holding the sleeve <b>801</b>. Next, holding the speculum <b>200</b> by the handle <b>207</b>, the user inserts the insertion portion <b>211</b> of the speculum <b>200</b> into the lumen of the sleeve <b>801</b> through the proximal end <b>802</b> of the sleeve <b>801</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>7</b>A and <b>7</b>B</figref> illustrate the insertion portion <b>211</b> of the speculum <b>200</b> being inserted into the sleeve <b>801</b>, with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>A</figref> showing a side view of the speculum <b>200</b> being inserted into the sleeve <b>801</b> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>B</figref> showing a top perspective view of the speculum <b>200</b> being inserted into the sleeve <b>801</b>. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>7</b>A and <b>7</b>B</figref>, the speculum <b>200</b> is inserted by pushing the sliding the speculum <b>200</b> into the sleeve <b>801</b> in the direction of the arrows shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>7</b>A and <b>7</b>B</figref>. Further, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>7</b>A and <b>7</b>B</figref>, the applicator <b>700</b> is designed such that the insertion portion <b>211</b> may be inserted in between the prongs <b>708</b> and <b>710</b> and through the pockets <b>720</b> and <b>722</b> created by the prongs <b>708</b> and <b>710</b>, such that the flaps <b>712</b> and <b>714</b> envelop the sides of the bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b> once speculum <b>200</b> is inserted.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Once the insertion portion <b>211</b> has been inserted into the lumen of the sleeve <b>801</b>, the user grasps the proximal end <b>702</b> of the applicator <b>700</b> and, still holding the speculum <b>200</b> by the handle <b>207</b>, pulls the applicator <b>700</b> out from the lumen of the sleeve <b>801</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>7</b>C and <b>7</b>D</figref> illustrate the applicator <b>700</b> being removed from the sleeve <b>801</b>, with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>C</figref> showing a side view of the speculum <b>200</b> with the applicator <b>700</b> being removed and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>D</figref> showing a top perspective view of the speculum <b>200</b> with the applicator <b>700</b> being removed. The applicator <b>700</b> is removed in the direction of the arrows shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>7</b>C and <b>7</b>D</figref>. As discussed above, once inserted into the sleeve <b>801</b>, friction may exist between the prongs <b>708</b> and <b>710</b> of the applicator <b>700</b> and the walls of the sleeve <b>801</b>. Thus, when the applicator <b>700</b> is removed from the sleeve <b>801</b>, this friction may pull the sleeve <b>801</b> more fully and more securely onto the insertion portion <b>211</b> of the speculum <b>200</b>. For example, by comparing <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>7</b>A and <b>7</b>B</figref> with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>7</b>C and <b>7</b>D</figref>, one can see that the act of pulling the applicator <b>700</b> out from the sleeve <b>801</b> has caused the distal end <b>804</b> of the sleeve <b>801</b> to be pulled past the distal ends of the bills <b>203</b> and <b>205</b>. The user continues to pull the applicator <b>700</b> until it is completely removed from the sleeve <b>801</b>, at which point the sleeve <b>801</b> is fully positioned on the insertion portion <b>211</b> of the speculum <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">In some embodiments, an applicator (e.g., applicator <b>700</b>), a sleeve accessory (e.g., sleeve accessory <b>301</b>, <b>501</b>, <b>601</b>, or <b>801</b>), and/or a medical speculum (e.g., speculum <b>200</b>) may be provided in a kit form. In one embodiment, the kit may include one applicator, one accessory sleeve, and/or one speculum. In another embodiment, the kit may include a plurality of speculums of varying lengths and widths and of varying expansion capabilities (i.e., capable of opening the bills in different ways, to different opening lengths, etc.), one or more sleeves configured to fit the plurality of speculums, and one or more applicators configured to fit the one or more sleeves and position the one or more sleeves on the one or more speculums. In yet another embodiment, the kit may further include accessories related to the needs of the examination procedure, for example, an IUD insertion device, a disposable electrosurgery tool, etc. In yet another embodiment, a plurality of applicators can be provided loosely in a large package or box.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">The foregoing description details certain embodiments of the systems, devices, and methods disclosed herein. It will be appreciated, however, that no matter how detailed the foregoing appears in text, the devices and methods can be practiced in many ways. As is also stated above, it should be noted that the use of particular terminology when describing certain features or aspects of the technology should not be taken to imply that the terminology is being re-defined herein to be restricted to including any specific characteristics of the features or aspects of the technology with which that terminology is associated. The scope of the disclosure should therefore be construed in accordance with the appended claims and any equivalents thereof</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">It will be appreciated by those skilled in the art that various modifications and changes may be made without departing from the scope of the described technology. Such modifications and changes are intended to fall within the scope of the embodiments, as defined by the appended claims. It will also be appreciated by those of skill in the art that parts included in one embodiment are interchangeable with other embodiments; one or more parts from a depicted embodiment can be included with other depicted embodiments in any combination. For example, any of the various components described herein and/or depicted in the Figures may be combined, interchanged or excluded from other embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">With respect to the use of any plural and/or singular terms herein, those having skill in the art can translate from the plural to the singular and/or from the singular to the plural as is appropriate to the context and/or application. The various singular/plural permutations may be expressly set forth herein for sake of clarity.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">It will be understood by those within the art that, in general, terms used herein, and especially in the appended claims are generally intended as &#x201c;open&#x201d; terms (e.g., the term &#x201c;including&#x201d; should be interpreted as &#x201c;including but not limited to,&#x201d; the terms &#x201c;comprising&#x201d; and &#x201c;having&#x201d; should, respectively, be interpreted as &#x201c;comprising at least&#x201d; and &#x201c;having at least,&#x201d; the term &#x201c;includes&#x201d; should be interpreted as &#x201c;includes but is not limited to,&#x201d; etc.). It will be further understood by those within the art that if a specific number of an introduced claim recitation is intended, such an intent will be explicitly recited in the claim, and in the absence of such recitation no such intent is present. For example, as an aid to understanding, the following appended claims may contain usage of the introductory phrases &#x201c;at least one&#x201d; and &#x201c;one or more&#x201d; to introduce claim recitations. However, the use of such phrases should not be construed to imply that the introduction of a claim recitation by the indefinite articles &#x201c;a&#x201d; or &#x201c;an&#x201d; limits any particular claim containing such introduced claim recitation to embodiments containing only one such recitation, even when the same claim includes the introductory phrases &#x201c;one or more&#x201d; or &#x201c;at least one&#x201d; and indefinite articles such as &#x201c;a&#x201d; or &#x201c;an.&#x201d; In general, &#x201c;a&#x201d; and/or &#x201c;an&#x201d; should be interpreted to mean &#x201c;at least one&#x201d; or &#x201c;one or more&#x201d;; the same holds true for the use of definite articles used to introduce claim recitations.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">Furthermore, in those instances where a convention analogous to &#x201c;at least one of A, B, and C, etc.&#x201d; is used, in general, such a construction is intended in the sense one having skill in the art would understand the convention (e.g., &#x201c;a system having at least one of A, B, and C&#x201d; would include but not be limited to systems that have A alone, B alone, C alone, A and B together, A and C together, B and C together, and/or A, B, and C together, etc.). In those instances where a convention analogous to &#x201c;at least one of A, B, or C, etc.&#x201d; is used, in general, such a construction is intended in the sense one having skill in the art would understand the convention (e.g., &#x201c;a system having at least one of A, B, or C&#x201d; would include but not be limited to systems that have A alone, B alone, C alone, A and B together, A and C together, B and C together, and/or A, B, and C together, etc.). It will be further understood by those within the art that virtually any disjunctive word and/or phrase presenting two or more alternative terms, whether in the description, claims, or drawings, should be understood to contemplate the possibilities of including one of the terms, either of the terms, or both terms. For example, the phrase &#x201c;A or B&#x201d; will be understood to include the possibilities of &#x201c;A&#x201d; or &#x201c;B&#x201d; or &#x201c;A and B.&#x201d;</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">The technology disclosed herein has numerous applications and while particular embodiments of the technology have been described in detail, it will be apparent to those skilled in the art that the disclosed embodiments may be modified given the design considerations discussed herein. Therefore, the foregoing description is to be considered exemplary rather than limiting, and the true scope of the invention is that defined in the following claims.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A method for positioning a sleeve accessory on a medical speculum, comprising:
<claim-text>providing a medical speculum having an insertion portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>providing a sleeve accessory having a cylindrical sleeve body defining a lumen, and an applicator within the lumen of the sleeve accessory, the applicator having the distal end and a proximal end, the proximal end being broader than the distal end, the distal end of the applicator comprising a first prong and a second prong, the first prong and the second prong folded into a first pocket and a second pocket, respectively; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>sliding the insertion portion of the medical speculum between the first pocket and the second pocket of the applicator to position the insertion portion of the medical speculum in the lumen of the sleeve accessory.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising removing the applicator from the lumen of the sleeve accessory.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein removing the applicator from the lumen of the sleeve accessory pulls the sleeve accessory further onto a plurality of bills of the insertion portion of the medical speculum.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein sliding the portion of the distal end of the applicator into the lumen of the sleeve accessory comprises sliding the portion of the distal end of the applicator into the lumen of the sleeve accessory until at least one of the first prong and the second prong abut walls of the sleeve body of the sleeve accessory.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first pocket and the second pocket are configured to receive the speculum and thereby guide the medical speculum into the lumen of the sleeve accessory.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first prong and the second prong of the applicator are spaced apart such that, once the applicator has been slid at least partially into the lumen of the sleeve accessory, the first prong and the second prong abut inner walls of the sleeve accessory.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising tucking a proximal end of the sleeve accessory under a tab, the proximal end of the applicator comprising the tab.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the insertion portion of the medical speculum comprises a plurality of bills.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the applicator is made of a paper or a cardboard material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the sleeve accessory is made of latex, vinyl, natural rubber, synthetic rubber, silicone, nylon, polyethylene, polyurethane, polypropylene, non-degradable elastomer, or degradable elastomer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising disposing of the applicator after removing the applicator from the lumen of the sleeve accessory.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising disposing of the sleeve accessory.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
