<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225610A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225610</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18008429</doc-number>
<date>20210604</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>032</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>16</class>
<subclass>H</subclass>
<main-group>10</main-group>
<subgroup>60</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>032</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>005</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20180101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>G</section>
<class>16</class>
<subclass>H</subclass>
<main-group>10</main-group>
<subgroup>60</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">APPARATUS FOR TESTING AGE-RELATED MACULAR DEGENERATION AND METHOD OF USING THE SAME</invention-title>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>63037669</doc-number>
<date>20200611</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>THE REGENTS OF THE UNIVERSITY OF MICHIGAN</orgname>
<address>
<city>Ann Arbor</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lutz</last-name>
<first-name>Jacob</first-name>
<address>
<city>Ann Arbor</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="01" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Muthanna</last-name>
<first-name>Vichal Palandira</first-name>
<address>
<city>Ann Arbor</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="02" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Yu</last-name>
<first-name>Andrew</first-name>
<address>
<city>Ann Arbor</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="03" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Russo</last-name>
<first-name>Mario</first-name>
<address>
<city>Cambridge</city>
<state>MA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="04" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Sun</last-name>
<first-name>Rachel</first-name>
<address>
<city>Ann Arbor</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="05" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Paulus</last-name>
<first-name>Yannis</first-name>
<address>
<city>Ann Arbor</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/US21/35927</doc-number>
<date>20210604</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c12-date><date>20221205</date></us-371c12-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A portable ocular screening device for tracking macular degeneration having a portable body including a graduated focusing mechanism including an inner chamber. The apparatus also includes a monocular eyepiece disposed on the graduated focusing mechanism and a display screen and a processor disposed within the inner chamber. Additionally, a method of monitoring macular degeneration includes providing a monocular screening device having a display screen disposed within a body of the screening device. The method further includes displaying an image and also providing a prompt in response to the display of the image. Subsequently, the method includes receiving a response via an input device, the response indicative of a user's perception of the image and evaluating the response to determine if the response indicates a user accurately perceived the first image.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="81.03mm" wi="158.75mm" file="US20230225610A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="228.35mm" wi="124.80mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225610A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="229.02mm" wi="107.36mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225610A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="190.08mm" wi="155.28mm" file="US20230225610A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="239.10mm" wi="111.76mm" file="US20230225610A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="235.63mm" wi="126.75mm" file="US20230225610A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application relates generally to apparatus and techniques for testing for degenerative eye disease, and more particularly, to apparatus for testing age-related macular degeneration and methods of using the same.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Age-related macular degeneration is a degenerative disease of the eye affecting the retina. Additionally, age-related macular degeneration is the leading cause of adult blindness in industrialized countries and currently affects approximately <b>190</b> million people worldwide. When left untreated, age-related macular degeneration causes central vision loss. However, there is a narrow window of time when treatment can be administered to prevent the progression of age-related macular degeneration to adult blindness.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Age-related macular degeneration is classified in two distinct stages: The first stage is dry age-related macular degeneration. The second stage is wet age related macular degeneration. The transition from dry age-related macular degeneration to wet age-related macular degeneration can happen spontaneously. Wet age-related macular degeneration is responsible for more than 80% of severe vision loss when not treated within one to two weeks following the transition from dry to wet age-related macular degeneration.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Various techniques exist for evaluating the progression of age-related macular degeneration. The current standard of care for treating age-related macular degeneration involves periodic physician assessments. However frequent visitations are untenable due to the high costs and burdens of extensive physician visits. Yet, due to the spontaneous nature of the transition from dry to wet age-related macular degeneration, infrequent evaluations could result in extensive vision loss.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a perspective view of a portable ocular screening device of a first embodiment of the present disclosure for testing age-related macular degeneration and measuring a transition between dry and wet age-related macular degeneration;</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is an exploded view of the example portable ocular screening device of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a perspective view of a second embodiment of a portable ocular screening device of the present disclosure for testing age-related macular degeneration, having a single actuatable interface component;</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is a perspective view of third embodiment of a portable ocular screening device of the present disclosure for testing age-related macular degeneration, having a toggle-button interface component;</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b><i>a </i></figref>is a plan view of a display including a graphical user interface of the portable ocular screening device for initiating a screening test;</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b><i>b </i></figref>is a plan view of a display including a graphical user interface displaying a test image for user evaluation;</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b><i>c </i></figref>is a plan view of a display including a graphical user interface displaying a request for a response from the user based on the user's observation of the test image;</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b><i>a </i></figref>is a plan view of a test image graphic of a distorted circle; and</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b><i>b </i></figref>is a plan view of a test image graphic of a perfect circle.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The current standard of care, that requires patients to regularly meet with physicians for observation of age-related macular degeneration, is burdensome and insufficient given the spontaneity of the ocular degeneration. The gap in the medical care requires an affordable and effective remote monitoring solution to track the progression from dry to wet age-related macular degeneration. Such a remote monitoring system would increase patient agency in monitoring their own retinal health while also decreasing the burden on the healthcare system and making doctor visits more efficient and profitable.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">To overcome the burden on the healthcare system and provide improved patient agency, the present invention involves a portable ocular monitoring device for monitoring age-related macular degeneration. This portable ocular monitoring device is a handheld monocular screening device usable by patients in their own homes at regular intervals (e.g., daily, semiweekly, or weekly). Preferably, the patient will use of the portable ocular monitoring device on a daily basis. As a result, the device is able to track the progression from dry to wet age-related macular degeneration.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The retina test of the present invention relies on the concept of shape discrimination hyperacuity (SDH). SDH is a measure of a person's ability to detect sinusoidal deformations from circularity. Wet age-related macular degeneration affects the ability to identify distortions in common shapes. Patients who have wet age-related macular degeneration can be identified based on their minimum distortion-detection threshold (MDDT). In order to test a patient's MDDT, the patient is shown a series of circle-like images, some perfectly circular and some distorted to be non-circular. After each image is displayed the user is asked whether the image was a perfect circle. The accuracy of the responses is a measure of the user's MDDT.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The patient's MDDT data is collected and stored over a sequence of trials and statistically analyzed to determine a change in a patient condition. For example, a patient with lowering MDDT scores may be indicative of a transition from dry to wet age-related macular degeneration. As the portable ocular monitoring device relies on stored data over a series of trials, the more regular and consisted the trials, the more accurate the results. In some examples, the data on the patient's MDDT scores can influence future circle-like images to provide distorted, non-circular images that will best evaluate a patients MDDT. By adjusting the distortion of the circle-like images, the portable ocular monitoring device can converge on a user's MDDT during a single test, and longitudinally over several weeks and months.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Additionally, the portable ocular monitoring device is designed as a monocular monitoring device. The device is designed to test only one eye at a time so that each eye can be tested individually, and if the eyes are degenerating asymmetrically the better eye does not compensate for the degenerating eye.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The present invention of the portable ocular monitoring device is capable of (1) remotely and accurately identifying the transition of dry age-related macular degeneration to wet age-related macular degeneration; (2) being readily incorporated into the daily routine of the user/patient; and (3) effectively reducing the burden, on the patient and the healthcare system, of expensive and repetitive appointments with physicians, including retina specialists.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a perspective view of a first embodiment of a portable ocular screening device <b>100</b> of the present disclosure for testing age-related macular degeneration and measuring a transition between dry and wet age-related macular degeneration. The portable ocular screening device <b>100</b> includes a portable body <b>110</b>. Additionally, connected on a first end of the portable body <b>110</b> is a graduated focusing mechanism <b>112</b> having an inner chamber <b>114</b> (not shown). Opposite the first end of the portable body <b>110</b>, the portable body <b>110</b> is connected to a cap <b>116</b>. The portable body <b>110</b> of the portable ocular screening device <b>100</b> is designed to be lightweight and sized to be handheld.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Connected to the graduated focusing mechanism <b>112</b>, the portable ocular screening device <b>100</b> includes a monocular eyepiece <b>120</b>. The monocular eyepiece <b>120</b> allows a patient to look into the inner chamber <b>114</b> with only one eye. Disposed in the inner chamber is a display screen (discussed in greater detail below). As discussed above, the monocular eyepiece <b>120</b> is designed to accommodate only one eye so the patient can only test one eye at a time. As a result, the monocular eyepiece prevents a second eye from compensating for any degeneration in the first eye and skewing the test results for the first eye. Testing each eye separately also permits identification of asymmetric macular degeneration.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In some embodiments within the scope of the present disclosure, the monocular eyepiece <b>120</b> includes a magnification lens <b>122</b> surrounded by foam padding <b>124</b> for patient comfort. In some embodiments, the magnification lens <b>122</b> is a 22 millimeter (mm) biconcave lens that generates a 10&#xd7; (10 times) magnification. In other embodiments, the magnification may be greater or lesser, depending on the patient and/or the display used in the inner chamber <b>114</b>. Additionally, the graduated focusing mechanism <b>112</b> can be adjusted to focus the magnification lens <b>122</b> on the display disposed in the inner chamber <b>114</b>. For example, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> the graduated focusing mechanism <b>112</b> includes helical grooves that both allow the graduated focusing mechanism <b>112</b> to be secured to the portable body <b>110</b> and twisted to adjust the distance between the magnification lens <b>122</b> and the display. In other embodiments, the graduated focusing mechanism can be adjusted and secured by any known means. The adjustment of the graduated focusing mechanism allows patients with different visual acuities to focus on the screen based on their personal needs.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Additionally disposed on the portable body <b>110</b> of the example portable ocular screening device <b>100</b> are manually actuatable interface components. As further illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, the manual actuatable interface components include a first button <b>130</b> and a second button <b>132</b>. The first button <b>130</b> and the second button <b>132</b> are illustrated as protruding from the portable body <b>110</b>. However, in other examples, the first button <b>130</b> and the second button <b>132</b> may be flush with the portable body <b>110</b>, or even recessed into the portable body <b>110</b>. The patient, when looking through the monocular eyepiece <b>120</b> can control the portable ocular screening device <b>100</b> by using the first button <b>130</b> and the second button <b>132</b> in response to prompts on the display disposed in the inner chamber <b>114</b>. In other embodiments, the manually actuatable interface components may be more or fewer buttons, switches, toggles, knobs, directional pads (D-pad), thumbsticks, or other suitable interfaces.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is an exploded view <b>200</b> of the embodiment of the portable ocular screening device <b>100</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>. When assembled, the components of the exploded view <b>200</b> form the portable ocular screening device <b>100</b>, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>. As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the portable ocular screening device <b>100</b> includes a display <b>210</b> disposed in the inner chamber <b>114</b>. The display <b>210</b> is typically a 1.5 inch display. In other examples, the display can be larger or small than 1.5 inches. The display can be, for example, an organic light-emitting diode (OLED). In other examples, the display could be a quantum light-emitting diode (QLED), Micro light-emitting diode (MicroLED), liquid crystal display (LCD), or other displays able to fit within the inner chamber <b>114</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Additionally included in the inner chamber <b>114</b> is the processor <b>212</b>. The processor may be a single-board computer (e.g., a Raspberry Pi 3) or may be a more complex system. In the example of the portable ocular screening device <b>100</b>, the processor <b>212</b> controls the display <b>210</b> and receives inputs from the manual actuatable interface components (e.g., first button <b>130</b> and second button <b>132</b>). Additionally, the processor <b>212</b> is able to process the responses from the patient to measure a patients MDDT. After the processor <b>212</b> processes responses, the processor stores responses and MDDT scores in a memory (not shown) disposed in the portable ocular screening device.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The example portable ocular screening device <b>100</b> additionally includes an additional cavity <b>220</b> in the portable body <b>110</b>. The cavity <b>220</b> is covered by cap <b>116</b> which can be removed from the portable body <b>110</b> to provide access to the cavity <b>220</b>. The cavity <b>220</b> can include a battery power source (not shown) for powering the display <b>210</b> and the processor <b>212</b>. The cavity can additionally include access to the processor <b>212</b> and interfaces (not shown) for connection to external computer systems, external power sources for charging batteries, or other interface components.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a perspective view of a second embodiment of a portable ocular screening device <b>300</b> for testing age-related macular degeneration having a single actuatable interface component. In the embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, the portable ocular screening device <b>300</b> also includes a portable body <b>310</b> and a monocular eyepiece <b>320</b>. In contrast to the portable ocular screening device <b>100</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> and <b>2</b></figref>, the portable ocular screening device <b>300</b> includes a single manual actuatable interface component instead of the example first button <b>130</b> and second button <b>132</b>. The single button <b>330</b> is the only manual actuatable interface component of the portable ocular screening device <b>300</b>. A single button <b>330</b> may be beneficial to avoid confusion on the part of the user as to which actuatable interface component to manipulate in response to a prompt seen on a graphical user interface of a display of the portable ocular screening device <b>300</b> during use.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is a perspective view of a third embodiment of a portable ocular screening device <b>400</b> for testing age-related macular degeneration, having a toggle-button interface component. The portable ocular screening device <b>400</b> also includes a portable body <b>410</b> with a monocular eyepiece <b>420</b>. However, the portable ocular screening device <b>400</b> includes a toggle-button <b>430</b>. This toggle-button <b>430</b> serves as the manual actuatable interface component, and can, in some examples, be both pivoted to move a cursor on a display and depressed similar to a button. In some examples the pivoting of the toggle-button is limited to movement in only a first and second direction, or alternatively, the toggle-button may be one that can be moved in any direction.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The manual actuatable interface components of the embodiments of the portable ocular screening devices illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> (i.e., first button <b>130</b> and second button <b>132</b>), <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> (i.e., single button <b>330</b>), and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> (i.e., toggle-button <b>430</b>) are examples of manual actuatable interface components. Any comparable button or toggle is considered as useable with the portable ocular screening device of the present invention. Additionally, any combination of buttons or toggles is considered within the scope of with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b><i>a </i></figref>is a plan view of a display <b>500</b> presenting an example graphical user interface <b>510</b> of the portable ocular screening device <b>100</b> for initiating a screening test. By way of the graphical user interface <b>510</b>, a patient is prompted to choose one of two options. The first option <b>512</b> is to initiate an exam (as indicated by the selectable &#x201c;Start&#x201d; prompt). By way of example only, the first option <b>512</b> may be shaded with a first color associated with the first button <b>130</b>. As a result, the patient can associate the selection of the first option <b>512</b> with the operation of the first button <b>130</b> based on the similarity of the color. Additionally, the graphical user interface <b>510</b> includes a second option <b>514</b>. In some examples, the second option is shaded with a second color associated with the second button <b>132</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">In alternative examples, the patient can utilize a toggle. In such an example, the first option <b>512</b> can be selected by moving a toggle in a first direction. Accordingly, the second option can be selected by moving the toggle in a second direction. Additional user interface options are also considered including using a single button and preset timed periods for selecting options via the single button.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b><i>b </i></figref>is a plan view of the display <b>500</b> presenting an example graphical user interface <b>520</b> including a test image <b>522</b> for user evaluation. In the example of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b><i>b</i></figref>, the test image <b>522</b> is an image of a distorted circle with a fixation point <b>524</b> located centrally on the display <b>500</b>. In other examples, the test image <b>522</b> may be an image of a perfect circle instead of a distorted circle. The test image is displayed for a preset period of time. The test image <b>522</b> is displayed for 0.5 seconds. In other examples, the test image <b>522</b> may be displayed for more time (e.g., approximately 2 seconds) or less time (e.g., approximately 0.1 second).</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b><i>c </i></figref>is the display <b>500</b> presenting an example graphical user interface <b>530</b> requesting a response from the patient based on the test image <b>522</b>. In the example graphical user interface <b>530</b>, the request is, &#x201c;Was that a perfect circle?&#x201d; Accordingly, the patient may select a first response <b>532</b> of &#x201c;Yes,&#x201d; or a second response <b>534</b> of &#x201c;No.&#x201d; In some examples, the first response <b>532</b> may be shaded with a first color associated with the first button <b>130</b> and the second response <b>534</b> may be shaded with a second color associated with the second button <b>132</b>. However, the response may be selected differently based on the manual actuatable interface components on the portable ocular screening device.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The selected response is processed by the processor <b>212</b> and stored in memory. In the example of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>5</b><i>b </i>and <b>5</b><i>c</i></figref>, a patient selecting the second response <b>534</b> would improve their MDDT score while a patient selecting the first response <b>532</b> would decrease their MDDT score, because the test image <b>522</b> was not a perfect circle. After selection of a response, the process repeats and another test image is displayed to the patient for the same preset period of time as the test image <b>522</b>. If a user accurately identifies a distorted, non-circular image, the processor may provide a less distorted, non-circular image to evaluate the patients minimum distortion-detection threshold (MDDT). Alternatively, if a patient incorrectly identifies a distorted, non-circular image, the processor may provide a more distorted, non-circular image. By adjusting the distortion of the circular image, the processor can converge upon the patient's MDDT and accurately calculate a shape discrimination hyperacuity (SDH) value for the patient for the test.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Each of the selected responses is processed by the processor <b>212</b> and stored in memory. The processor <b>212</b> is also able to, from the collection of responses, calculate a trend based on a plurality of the patient's MDDT and SDH scores, and thus, measure progression of dry to wet age-related macular degeneration.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">After the processor has collected sufficient information on a first eye (e.g., has converged on an SDH score), the processor will indicate, by way of the graphical user interface and/or by an audible signal, and/or by a light or other indicator on the surface of the portable ocular screening device, that the user should begin a test of a second eye. The testing of the second eye will progress in the same manner as the first eye, but only the second eye will be able to see into the portable ocular screening device <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b><i>a </i></figref>illustrates an example test image graphic <b>602</b> of a distorted circle <b>604</b> on a graphical user interface <b>600</b>. In other examples, the distorted circle could be more distorted or less distorted than shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b><i>a</i></figref>. In the example of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b><i>a</i></figref>, the example test image graphic <b>602</b> includes a fixation point <b>606</b> located centrally in the graphical user interface <b>600</b>. The fixation point <b>606</b> is a pair of perpendicular lines, however the fixation point <b>606</b> could be a dot, small circle, or other shape centered in the graphical user interface <b>600</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b><i>b </i></figref>illustrates an example test image graphic <b>612</b> of a perfect circle <b>614</b> on a graphical user interface <b>610</b>. In the example of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b><i>b</i></figref>, the example test image graphic <b>612</b> includes a fixation point <b>616</b> located centrally in the graphical user interface <b>610</b>. The fixation point <b>616</b> is a pair of perpendicular lines, however the fixation point <b>616</b> could be a dot, small circle, or other shape centered in the graphical user interface <b>610</b>. Additionally, the fixation point <b>616</b> could be different from the fixation point <b>606</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b><i>a</i></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b><i>a </i>and <b>6</b><i>b</i></figref>, the graphical user interfaces <b>600</b> and <b>610</b> are shown with a black background and the fixation points <b>606</b> and <b>616</b>, the distorted circle <b>604</b>, and the perfect circle <b>614</b> are shown in white. This contrast reduces eye strain, however other color schemes and contrasts are also considered within the scope of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">While various embodiments have been described herein, modifications can be made thereto that are still considered within the scope of the appended claims.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A portable ocular screening device comprising:
<claim-text>a portable body including a graduated focusing mechanism including an inner chamber;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a monocular eyepiece disposed on the graduated focusing mechanism;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a display screen disposed within the inner chamber; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a processor positioned within the inner chamber.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The portable ocular screening device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further including a power source disposed in the portable body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The portable ocular screening device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further including a manually actuatable interface component.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The portable ocular screening device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the manually actuatable interface component is a mechanical interface selected from the group consisting of a depressible button, a pair of depressible buttons, a toggle-button, a switch, a directional pad, and a knob.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The portable ocular screening device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the processor is electronically connected to the display screen and the power source and responsive to actuation of the manually actuatable interface component.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The portable ocular screening device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the monocular eyepiece includes a magnification lens.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The portable ocular screening device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the graduated focusing mechanism adjusts a distance between the magnification lens and the display screen.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. A method of monitoring vision acuity related to macular degeneration, comprising:
<claim-text>providing a portable monocular screening device having a display screen disposed within a body of the monocular screening device;</claim-text>
<claim-text>displaying, via the display screen, a first image;</claim-text>
<claim-text>providing, via the display screen, a first prompt in response to the display of the first image;</claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving a first response via an input device on the portable monocular screening device, the response indicative of a user's perception of the first image; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>evaluating the first response to determine if the first response indicates a user accurately perceived the first image.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The method of monitoring vision acuity of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, further including:
<claim-text>displaying, via the display screen, a second image, different from the first image;</claim-text>
<claim-text>providing, via the display screen, a second prompt in response to the display of the second image;</claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving a first response via the input device on the portable monocular screening device, the response indicative of the user's perception of the second image; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>evaluating the first response and the second response to determine if the first response and the second response are consistent with responses indicative of the user having macular degeneration.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The method of monitoring vision acuity of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, further including generating a metric measuring a shape discrimination hyperacuity value based on evaluating at least the first response and the second response.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The method of monitoring vision acuity of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein in displaying the first and second images, the first image is one of an image of a circle or a distorted image of a circle and the second image is the other of the image of the circle or the distorted image.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The method of monitoring vision acuity of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, further including the portable monocular screening device providing additional images and collecting additional responses until a shape-discrimination hyperacuity threshold is established.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. The method of monitoring vision acuity of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, further including prompting a user to test a second eye.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The method of monitoring vision acuity of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, further including storing the first response in a memory located in the portable monocular screening device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. The method of monitoring vision acuity of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, further including storing the first response in an external memory.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
