<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225303A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230615" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225303</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18189481</doc-number>
<date>20230324</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>67</main-group>
<subgroup>033</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>29</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>67</main-group>
<subgroup>033</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>29</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>2227</main-group>
<subgroup>706</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>Q</subclass>
<main-group>50</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="azmiy7vjyu12o">VOLUMETRIC PUPAE DISPENSER</invention-title>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>16872788</doc-number>
<date>20200512</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11647738</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18189481</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>62854396</doc-number>
<date>20190530</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Verily Life Sciences LLC</orgname>
<address>
<city>South San Francisco</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Metlitz</last-name>
<first-name>Matthew</first-name>
<address>
<city>Menlo Park</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="01" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Massaro</last-name>
<first-name>Peter</first-name>
<address>
<city>San Carlos</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Verily Life Sciences LLC</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>South San Francisco</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A device comprises a dispenser assembly comprising a frame having a first surface and a second surface. The frame defines a pathway, an inlet opening in the first surface of the frame and a drain opening in the second surface of the frame. The inlet opening and the drain opening may provide access to the pathway. The device also includes a moveable member having at least one bore oriented perpendicular to the pathway. The moveable member may be translatable within the pathway between a first position and a second position.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="119.72mm" wi="193.38mm" file="US20230225303A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="192.79mm" wi="150.54mm" file="US20230225303A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="199.98mm" wi="161.12mm" file="US20230225303A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="194.14mm" wi="163.49mm" file="US20230225303A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="220.05mm" wi="148.42mm" file="US20230225303A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="230.04mm" wi="146.30mm" file="US20230225303A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="218.19mm" wi="140.72mm" file="US20230225303A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="145.54mm" wi="160.10mm" file="US20230225303A1-20230720-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="192.36mm" wi="106.34mm" file="US20230225303A1-20230720-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="192.28mm" wi="116.59mm" file="US20230225303A1-20230720-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="lead"?>
<heading level="1" id="h-0001">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a continuation of U.S. Pat. Application No. 16/872,788, titled &#x201c;Volumetric Pupae Dispenser&#x201d; filed on May 12, 2020, which claims priority to U.S. Provisional Pat. Application No. 62/854,396, titled &#x201c;Volumetric Pupae Dispenser&#x201d; filed on May 30, 2019, the entireties of each which are hereby incorporated by reference.</p>
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="tail"?>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading level="1" id="h-0002">FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates generally to the mass-rearing of insects. More specifically, but not by way of limitation, this disclosure relates to devices and methods for dispensing insect pupae.</p>
<heading level="1" id="h-0003">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Insect pupae in a mass-rearing environment, such as a sterile insect technique (SIT) program, involves rearing large numbers of insects from eggs and may involve releasing them into the wild. Maintaining an effective rearing program can be difficult, including maintaining a high yield and detecting problems during the rearing process. For example, clean environments and effective feeding routines may be of significant importance, as well as safe handling of the insects during the rearing process.</p>
<heading level="1" id="h-0004">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Various examples are described for devices and methods for dispensing insect pupae. One example device includes a dispenser assembly comprising: a frame having a first surface and a second surface opposite the first surface, wherein the frame defines: a pathway to enable movement of a movable member within the frame, an inlet opening in the first surface of the frame, the inlet opening providing access to the pathway, and a drain opening in the second surface of the frame, the drain opening providing access to the pathway, wherein the frame further comprises a filter overlaying the drain opening; and a moveable member translatable within the pathway between a first position and a second position, the movable member defining at least one bore oriented perpendicular to the pathway, wherein: when the movable member is at the first position, the bore is aligned with the inlet opening; and a reservoir container coupled to the dispenser assembly, the reservoir container defining a dispensing opening at a first end of the reservoir container, the dispensing opening aligned with the inlet opening of the frame.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">One example method includes providing a device comprising: a dispenser assembly comprising: a frame having a first surface and a second surface opposite the first surface, wherein the frame defines: a pathway to enable movement of a movable member within the frame, an inlet opening in the first surface of the frame, the inlet opening providing access to the pathway, and a drain opening in the second surface of the frame, the drain opening providing access to the pathway, wherein the frame further comprises a filter overlaying the drain opening; a moveable member translatable within the pathway between a first position and a second position, the movable member defining at least one bore oriented perpendicular to the pathway, wherein: when the movable member is at the first position, the bore is aligned with the inlet opening, and a reservoir container coupled to the dispenser assembly, the reservoir container defining a dispensing opening at a first end of the reservoir container, the dispensing opening aligned with the inlet opening of the frame; receiving a mixture of a liquid and a plurality of insect pupae or insect larvae into the reservoir container; straining the mixture using the filter overlaying the drain opening; moving the moveable member between the first position and the second position using an actuator; and outputting the plurality of insect pupae or insect larvae from the bore.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">These illustrative examples are mentioned not to limit or define the scope of this disclosure, but rather to provide examples to aid understanding thereof. Illustrative examples are discussed in the Detailed Description, which provides further description. Advantages offered by various examples may be further understood by examining this specification.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading level="1" id="h-0005">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The accompanying drawings, which are incorporated into and constitute a part of this specification, illustrate one or more certain examples and, together with the description of the example, serve to explain the principles and implementations of the certain examples.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>-<b>7</b></figref> show example devices for dispensing insect pupae according to this disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> shows a flowchart for an example method for dispensing insect pupae according to this disclosure; and</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref> shows an example computing device for dispensing insect pupae according to this disclosure.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading level="1" id="h-0006">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Examples are described herein in the context of devices and methods for dispensing insect pupae. Those of ordinary skill in the art will realize that the following description is illustrative only and is not intended to be in any way limiting. Reference will now be made in detail to implementations of examples as illustrated in the accompanying drawings. The same reference indicators will be used throughout the drawings and the following description to refer to the same or like items.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In the interest of clarity, not all of the routine features of the examples described herein are shown and described. It will, of course, be appreciated that in the development of any such actual implementation, numerous implementation-specific decisions must be made in order to achieve the developer&#x2019;s specific goals, such as compliance with application- and business-related constraints, and that these specific goals will vary from one implementation to another and from one developer to another.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">When mass rearing insects, it is important to dose the correct number of pupae into a container to ensure the maximization of the mating and egg production process. As such, there needs to be an accurate method for counting the insect pupae. However, manual methods of dosing and counting insect pupae can be very time and labor intensive. Particularly, counting and dispensing known amounts of pupae by manually counting the individual pupa, e.g., using a pipette, is extremely time consuming and tedious. Counting and dispensing known amounts of pupae by transferring the pupae into containers and estimating the number inside the container can result in an inaccurate count and still requires a significant amount of labor.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">When mass rearing insects, it may be desirable to dispense a dose of insect pupae (or simply &#x201c;pupae&#x201d;) without the need for manual counting and measurement by a user. Examples according to this disclosure can provide for the dispensing of insect pupae through the use of a semi-automated or fully automated device and method. While the examples and description below describe the dispensing of insect pupae, insect larvae or any other life-stage of an insect may be dispensed as described below.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In an illustrative example, a mixture of mosquito pupae and the liquid (e.g., water) that the pupae are being carried in are introduced into a pupae dosing device. A dose refers to a substantially consistent quantity of pupae taken from a population of pupae. Thus, this example pupae dosing device will obtain, over multiple iterations, a substantially constant number of pupae from a pupae population and dispense them, such as into individual containers per dose.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">This example device includes a reservoir that collects the pupae and the liquid, a moveable member with a bore extending through the moveable member that aligns with a dispensing opening in the reservoir. The device also includes a filter (e.g., mesh) located underneath the bore, while the moveable member&#x2019;s bore is aligned with the reservoir&#x2019;s opening, that permits the liquid to drain from the bore while holding the pupae within the bore. The device also defines an output opening at a different location than the filter. The moveable member moves back and forth between the two locations to receive the pupae and liquid from the reservoir, drain the fluid through the filter, and then dispense the pupae through the output opening.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The reservoir holds the mosquito pupae and the liquid and allows liquid and pupae to exit through its opening, when the bore in the moveable member is aligned with it. The mosquito pupae and the liquid flow through the dispensing opening and into the bore in the moveable member. As the mosquito pupae and the liquid flow into the bore, the liquid continues to flow through the filter and drains from the bore while the mosquito pupae are caught and contained in the bore. The liquid will drain until a saturation point occurs where the pupae fill substantially the entire volume of the bore, thereby clogging any holes in the filter. When the device reaches this saturation point, the number of pupae within the bore is substantially fixed based on the size of the bore.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In this example, after the device reaches the saturation point, an actuator moves the moveable member along a pathway until the bore is aligned with the output opening. A solid portion of the moveable member that does not have a bore extending through it will then block the opening in the reservoir so that any of the pupae and/or liquid remaining in the reservoir are not able to flow out of the reservoir.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The actuator moves the moveable member until the bore is aligned with the output opening. At which time, gravity, a water rinse, or both will cause the pupae to fall through the output opening and into a container positioned underneath the output opening to catch the pupae. Once the pupae are dispensed from the bore, the actuator will move the moveable member back to the original position where the bore is aligned with the reservoir&#x2019;s drain. The process is then repeated to dispense another dose of mosquito pupae.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">By using this pupae dosing device, each dose of pupae has substantially the same number of pupae based on the bore size selected for the moveable member. By using such a technique, the dispensing system provides a more accurate and consistent count of the pupae than when an individual would manually measure the pupae using a cup. In addition, the device operates much more quickly than manual pupae dispensing. Thus the pupae dosing device provides a faster, more accurate, and less labor-intensive method for dosing the pupae than by manually counting the individual pupae using a pipette. Incorporating the actuator into the pupae dosing device permits the device to be partially or fully automated in order to reduce or eliminate the need for human operation of the pupae dosing device.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">This illustrative example is given to introduce the reader to the general subject matter discussed herein and the disclosure is not limited to this example. The following sections describe various additional non-limiting examples and examples of systems and methods for dispensing insect pupae.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> shows an example device <b>100</b> for dispensing insect pupae. In this example, the device <b>100</b> is made out of homopolymer acetal (e.g., Delrin&#xae;); however, it may be made out of any suitable material or materials such as copolymer acetal, acrylic, metal, plastic, etc. The device <b>100</b> includes a dispenser assembly <b>102</b> and a reservoir container <b>104</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The dispenser assembly <b>102</b> includes a frame <b>106</b> and a moveable member <b>108</b> that translates within a pathway <b>110</b> defined in the frame. The frame <b>106</b> has a first surface <b>106</b><i>a</i> and a second surface <b>106</b><i>b</i> where the second surface <b>106</b><i>b</i> is located opposite the first surface <b>106</b><i>a</i>. In some examples, the first surface <b>106</b><i>a</i> and the second surface <b>106</b><i>b</i> form a top surface and a bottom surface of the frame <b>106</b>. The first surface <b>106</b><i>a</i> may be connected to the second surface <b>106</b><i>b</i> at a single location, e.g., as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>, or at multiple locations, e.g., as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>-<b>3</b></figref>, which may form a side piece or side pieces of the frame <b>106</b>. Additionally, the first surface <b>106</b><i>a</i> may be completely separate from the second surface <b>106</b><i>b</i>. In some examples, the frame is defined by a single piece of material that has been molded, extruded, machined, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">In this example, the frame <b>106</b> defines a pathway <b>110</b> between the first surface <b>106</b><i>a</i> and the second surface <b>106</b><i>b</i> and several openings, which include an inlet opening <b>112</b>, a drain opening <b>114</b>, and an output opening <b>116</b>. The inlet opening <b>112</b> is defined in the first surface <b>106</b><i>a</i>, while the drain opening <b>114</b> and the output opening <b>116</b> are defined in the second surface <b>106</b><i>b</i>. The inlet opening <b>112</b>, the drain opening <b>114</b>, and the output opening <b>116</b> all provide access to the pathway <b>110</b> through the frame <b>106</b>. In this example, the inlet opening <b>112</b> and the drain opening <b>114</b> are aligned across the pathway <b>110</b>. In other examples, however, the inlet opening <b>112</b> and the drain opening <b>114</b> may be misaligned across the pathway <b>110</b> or not aligned at all. Such configurations may provide an alternate way to pre-define the bore <b>120</b> to hold a fixed number of pupae and an amount of liquid. Additionally, in this example, the first surface <b>106</b><i>a</i> defines a rinse opening <b>126</b> that aligns with the output opening <b>116</b>, though the rinse opening <b>126</b> may be positioned to only partially align with the output opening <b>116</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In this example, the frame <b>106</b> also includes a filter <b>118</b> that overlays the drain opening <b>114</b> to allow water to exit the bore <b>120</b>, while retaining the pupae. The filter <b>118</b>, according to different examples, may be permanently coupled to the drain opening <b>114</b>, removably coupled to the drain opening <b>114</b>, pivotally coupled to the drain opening <b>114</b>, or coupled to the drain opening <b>114</b> in any other suitable manner. Additionally, the filter <b>118</b> may be placed in or over the drain opening <b>114</b>  without being physically coupled to the drain opening <b>114</b> at all. The filter <b>118</b> may be made from a mesh material or any other suitable material capable of draining a liquid while catching the insect pupae.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The pathway <b>110</b> is sized to fit the moveable member <b>108</b> while permitting the moveable member <b>108</b> to move along the pathway <b>110</b>. In this example, the moveable member <b>108</b> is a sliding block. However, the moveable member <b>108</b> may be any suitable shape for moving through the pathway <b>110</b>. The moveable member <b>108</b> defines at least one bore <b>120</b> that is oriented perpendicular to the pathway <b>110</b>. The bore <b>120</b> extends through the entire height of the moveable member <b>108</b>. In some examples, the bore <b>120</b> may define any suitable volume to permit the dosing of the insect pupae. For example, the bore <b>120</b> may define a volume of five milliliters, ten milliliters, or fifteen milliliters. As such, the bore <b>120</b> will hold a predetermined number of insect pupae based on the volume of the bore <b>120</b>. Additionally, the bore <b>120</b> may be any suitable shape for collecting a dose of pupae including cylindrical, rectangular, pyramidal, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The moveable member <b>108</b> may translate between a first position and a second position in order to create a dosing of the pupae. When the moveable member <b>108</b> is in the first position, as is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, the bore <b>120</b> is aligned with the inlet opening <b>112</b>. When the moveable member <b>108</b> is in the second position, as is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the bore <b>120</b> is aligned with the output opening <b>116</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> shows an example device <b>200</b> for dispensing insect pupae. In this example, the device <b>200</b> includes similar elements, such as a dispenser assembly <b>202</b> that includes a frame <b>206</b> and a moveable member <b>208</b>, and a reservoir container <b>204</b>, as described above in relation to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>. Here, the insect pupae have collected and been contained in the bore <b>220</b> until the pupae fill substantially the entire volume of the bore <b>220</b>. The moveable member <b>208</b> has moved to the second position so that the device <b>200</b> may output the pupae through the output opening <b>216</b>. In some examples, when the moveable member <b>208</b> is in the second position, the solid portion of the moveable member <b>208</b> blocks the inlet opening <b>212</b> to prevent the mixture from flowing out of the reservoir container <b>204</b>, such as is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Referring back to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, the bore <b>120</b> is be aligned with both the inlet opening <b>112</b> and the drain opening <b>114</b> when the moveable member <b>108</b> is in the first position. Additionally, the moveable member <b>108</b> may be configured to translate between additional positions besides the first position and the second position, e.g., a third position, a fourth position, etc. For example, if the drain opening <b>114</b> is not aligned with the inlet opening <b>112</b>, and instead is defined in the second surface <b>106</b><i>b</i> at a third position between the inlet opening <b>112</b> and the output opening <b>116</b>, the movable member <b>108</b> stops at the third position so that the bore <b>120</b> is aligned with the drain opening <b>114</b> to drain liquid from the bore <b>120</b> before proceeding to align with the output opening <b>116</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The dispenser assembly <b>102</b> also includes an actuator <b>128</b> that causes the moveable member <b>108</b> to move within the pathway <b>110</b>. In some examples, the actuator <b>128</b> may be a hydraulic actuator, a pneumatic actuator, an electrical actuator, or any other suitable actuator that is capable of causing the moveable member <b>108</b> to move. In some examples, the actuator <b>128</b> may be coupled to the moveable member <b>108</b>. For example, the actuator <b>128</b> may be screwed to the moveable member <b>108</b>, bolted to the moveable member <b>108</b>, adhered to the moveable member <b>108</b>, or coupled to the actuator <b>128</b> using any other suitable attachment means.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">In this example, the reservoir container <b>104</b> is coupled to the first surface <b>106</b><i>a</i> of the dispenser assembly <b>102</b>. In some examples, the reservoir container <b>104</b> may be coupled to only the first surface <b>106</b><i>a</i>, to only the second surface <b>106</b><i>b</i>, or to both the first surface <b>106</b><i>a</i> and <b>106</b><i>b</i>. The reservoir container <b>104</b> is removably coupled to the dispenser assembly <b>102</b> using at least one detachable connector <b>130</b> such as a magnet, a screw, a bolt, a clamp, a snap-fit design, a friction-fit design, or any other suitable means for removably attaching the reservoir container <b>104</b> to the dispenser assembly <b>102</b>. By removably attaching the reservoir container <b>104</b> to the dispenser assembly <b>102</b>, a user may easily remove the reservoir container <b>104</b> from the dispenser assembly <b>102</b> in order to clean or replace the reservoir container <b>104</b>. In some examples, the reservoir container <b>104</b> may be permanently coupled to the dispenser assembly <b>102</b>. For example, the reservoir container <b>104</b> may be formed with the dispenser assembly <b>102</b> from a single piece of material.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">In some examples, the reservoir container <b>104</b> also defines a dispensing opening <b>122</b> located at a first end of the reservoir container <b>104</b> and an intake opening <b>124</b>. The dispensing opening <b>122</b> is aligned with the inlet opening <b>112</b>. In this example, the intake opening <b>124</b> is located at an end of the reservoir container <b>104</b> opposite the first end; however, the intake opening <b>124</b> may be located at any end of the reservoir container <b>104</b>. The reservoir container <b>104</b> is shaped to guide the pupae and the liquid towards the dispensing opening <b>122</b>. For example, the reservoir container <b>104</b> may be shaped as a funnel, as may be seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, as an inverted trapezoid, as may be seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, as a ramp, or as any other suitable shape that is able to assist in guiding the pupae and the liquid to the dispensing opening <b>122</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">In some examples, the device <b>100</b> is part of a system that incorporates various other features into the device <b>100</b>. For example, the device <b>100</b> may be positioned so that the mixture is dispensed into the reservoir container <b>104</b> via a pipe and/or so that the insect pupae are output through the output opening and into a pipe, as is discussed below in reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Additionally, various rinsing mechanisms may be incorporated into the system to help with cleaning the device <b>100</b> or dosing the pupae. The rinsing mechanisms may use a liquid, e.g., water or pressurized water, or a gas, e.g. air or pressurized air, to remove pupae or debris from various elements of the device <b>100</b>. In some examples, the rinsing mechanisms may include hoses, nozzles, fans, pumps, or any other suitable device capable of outputting the water or air used to rinse the device <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">For example, a container rinsing mechanism <b>138</b> is permanently or removably attached to the reservoir container <b>104</b>. However, in some examples, the container rinsing mechanism <b>138</b> may be positioned separate from the reservoir container <b>104</b>. The container rinsing mechanism <b>138</b>, such as a spout, spigot, nozzle, etc. may receive and spray water or blow air from a source into the reservoir container <b>104</b> to rinse and assist in guiding the pupae towards the dispensing opening <b>122</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In this example, a filter rinsing mechanism <b>140</b> is positioned adjacent to the drain opening <b>114</b> so that the filter rinsing mechanism <b>140</b>, such as a spout, spigot, nozzle, etc. may receive and spray water or blow air from a source through the filter <b>118</b> in order to rinse the filter <b>118</b> and remove any pupae or debris that may be stuck in the filter <b>118</b>. The filter rinsing mechanism <b>140</b> may be used when the moveable member <b>108</b> is not in the first position or when there is no pupae or liquid in the reservoir container <b>104</b>. In this example, the output opening rinsing mechanism <b>142</b> is positioned adjacent to or above the rinse opening <b>126</b> so that the output opening rinsing mechanism <b>142</b> such as a spout, spigot, nozzle, etc. may receive and spray water or blow air from a source through the bore <b>120</b> when the moveable member <b>108</b> is in the second position to assist with outputting the pupae from the bore <b>120</b> through the output opening <b>116</b>. Additionally, the output opening rinsing mechanism <b>142</b> may be used while the moveable member <b>108</b> is not in the second position in order to clean the output opening of any debris or remaining pupae.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> shows another example device <b>300</b> for dispensing insect pupae. In this example, the device <b>300</b> includes the same features as were discussed above in reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>. The device <b>300</b> includes a dispenser assembly <b>302</b> that includes a frame <b>306</b> and a moveable member <b>308</b>, a reservoir container <b>304</b>, and an actuator <b>328</b>. In this example, the device <b>300</b> includes features in addition to those shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> to assist with dispensing insect pupae. Some of these features include, for example, an intake pipe <b>332</b> and an output pipe <b>334</b>. The intake pipe <b>332</b> is positioned to dispense the mixture of the insect pupae and the liquid into the reservoir container <b>304</b>. In some examples, the intake pipe <b>332</b> may be coupled to the reservoir container <b>304</b> or may be positioned adjacent to the reservoir container <b>304</b>. While the intake pipe <b>332</b> is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> as positioned above the reservoir container <b>304</b>, the intake pipe <b>332</b> may be positioned along any edge of the reservoir container <b>304</b>. In other examples, the intake pipe <b>332</b> may be coupled directly to the first surface <b>306</b><i>a</i> and aligned with the inlet opening <b>312</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The output pipe <b>334</b> is positioned to accept the insect pupae that are dispensed from the bore <b>320</b> through the output opening <b>316</b>. In some examples, the output pipe <b>334</b> may be coupled to second surface <b>306</b><i>b</i> of the frame <b>306</b> or may be positioned adjacent to the second surface <b>206</b><i>b</i>. The addition of the intake pipe <b>332</b> and/or the output pipe <b>334</b> enables the device <b>300</b> to be incorporated into a partially or fully automated insect mass rearing system. For example, the intake pipe <b>332</b>  may carry the mixture of insect pupae and liquid from an upstream collection area to the device <b>300</b> without requiring a user to manually dispense the mixture into the reservoir container <b>304</b>. The output pipe <b>334</b> may then carry the dosed pupae on to another area such as a sex sorting or mating location where specific, known quantities of insect pupae are required to make devices at those locations function properly.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">In this example, the device <b>300</b> includes and/or is controlled by a computing device <b>336</b> communicatively coupled to the actuator <b>328</b>, where the computing device <b>336</b> may control various features of the device <b>300</b>. For example, the computing device <b>336</b> may control the actuator <b>328</b> that moves moveable member <b>308</b> between positions. In some examples, the computing device <b>336</b> may be communicatively coupled to the actuator <b>328</b> via a wired interface <b>338</b>, such as Ethernet, USB, IEEE 1394, or a wireless interface, such as IEEE 802.11, Bluetooth, or radio interfaces for accessing cellular telephone networks (e.g., transceiver/antenna for accessing a CDMA, GSM, UMTS, or other mobile communications network(s)). While <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> only depicts a single computing device <b>336</b>, it should be appreciated that multiple computing devices <b>336</b> may be employed to apportion various processing tasks. Thus, some examples may split processing amongst multiple computing devices <b>336</b> to distribute processing requirements. In some examples, the computing device <b>336</b> may be integrated into the actuator <b>328</b>, coupled to the device <b>300</b>, or completely separate from the device <b>300</b>. In some examples, a single computing device may control multiple dispensing devices <b>300</b>. Further details relating to specifics of the computing device <b>336</b> are discussed below in relation to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> shows another example of the moveable member <b>408</b> that may be included in the example device <b>400</b> for dispensing insect pupae. In this example, the moveable member <b>408</b> includes the same features as were discussed above in reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>. For example, the moveable member <b>408</b> defines a bore <b>420</b> extending from a first surface of the moveable member <b>408</b> to a second surface of the moveable member <b>408</b>. Additionally in this example, the bore <b>420</b> includes at least one wall made out of the same material (e.g., mesh) as the filter <b>118</b> described in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>. Including mesh walls for the bore <b>420</b> may be beneficial in some examples because the greater the surface area of the bore that is made of mesh, the more accurate the count and measurement of the insect pupae may be. This is because the liquid of the mixture may be output through the entire height of the mesh wall even as the pupae begin to clog the lower portion of the mesh wall.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> shows another example of the moveable member <b>508</b> that may be included in the example device <b>500</b> for measuring and dispensing insect pupae. In this example, the moveable member <b>508</b> includes the same features as were discussed above in reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>. Here, the moveable member <b>508</b> is shaped as a rotatable disc. The disc shaped moveable member <b>508</b> includes at least one bore <b>520</b>. The at least one bore <b>520</b> may be made of solid walls or may be made of mesh walls as described above in reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>. In some examples, the actuator <b>528</b> may be coupled to the moveable member <b>508</b>. For example, the actuator <b>528</b> may be coupled to or embedded into a central location of the disc shaped moveable member <b>508</b>, as is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>. In other examples, the actuator <b>528</b> may be coupled to an outer surface of the disc shaped moveable member <b>508</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> shows another example device <b>600</b> for measuring and dispensing insect pupae. In this example, the device <b>600</b> includes similar features as were discussed above in reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>. The device <b>600</b> includes a dispenser assembly <b>602</b> that includes a frame <b>606</b> and a moveable member <b>608</b>, a reservoir container <b>604</b>, and an actuator <b>628</b>. Here, the moveable member <b>608</b> is shaped as a rotatable disc and defines at least two bores <b>620</b> as described above in reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> and the first surface <b>606</b><i>a</i> and the second surface <b>606</b><i>b</i> are only connected at a single location. The actuator <b>628</b> is coupled to an interior location in the moveable member <b>608</b> and causes the disc shaped moveable member <b>608</b> to rotate and move within the pathway <b>610</b>. The bores <b>620</b> may be distributed around the disc shaped moveable member <b>608</b> so that a first bore <b>620</b> is be aligned with the inlet opening <b>612</b> and the drain opening <b>614</b> at the same time that a second bore <b>620</b> is aligned with the output opening <b>616</b>. This allows for the simultaneous straining of the mixture in the first bore <b>620</b> and outputting of the strained pupae from the second bore <b>620</b>, which results in a faster dosing of the pupae. In some examples, there may be multiple sets of reservoir containers <b>604</b>, filters <b>618</b>, and openings <b>612</b>, <b>614</b>, <b>616</b>, and <b>622</b> that allows for simultaneous dosing to occur in a single device <b>600</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">In some examples, the moveable member <b>608</b> may be removed from the device <b>600</b> and a second moveable member <b>608</b> may be interchangeable with the removed moveable member <b>608</b>. The two moveable members <b>608</b> may be different shapes or have different sized bores. For example, the disc shaped moveable member <b>608</b> may be interchangeable with the sliding block shaped movable member <b>108</b> discussed above in reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>. Interchanging the moveable member <b>608</b> with a second moveable member <b>608</b> of a different shape may include interchanging the actuator <b>628</b> used to move the moveable member <b>608</b> because the actuator <b>628</b> used to move the disc shaped moveable member <b>608</b> may be a different type of actuator <b>628</b> than the actuator <b>128</b> used to move the sliding block shaped moveable member <b>108</b>. Additionally, the moveable member <b>608</b> may be interchangeable with a second moveable member <b>680</b> that includes at least one different sized bore <b>620</b>. Having interchangeable moveable members <b>608</b> with different sized bores <b>620</b> permits a user to adjust the doses of the insect pupae being created by the device <b>600</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> shows another example device <b>700</b> for dispensing insect pupae. In the example shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref>, the device <b>700</b> includes similar features as were discussed above in reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>. For example, the device <b>700</b> includes a dispenser assembly <b>702</b> that includes a moveable member <b>708</b>, a reservoir container <b>704</b>, and an actuator <b>728</b>. However, here, the reservoir container <b>704</b> is coupled to or positioned adjacent to the moveable member <b>708</b>. Thus, the mixture of the insect pupae and the liquid flow directly from the reservoir container <b>704</b>, through the dispensing opening <b>722</b> in the reservoir container <b>704</b>, and into the bore <b>720</b>. The filter <b>718</b> is pivotally coupled to the moveable member <b>708</b> and capable of controlling when the insect pupae are contained in the bore <b>720</b> and when the pupae are released from the bore <b>720</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">For example, when the moveable member <b>708</b> is in the first position (the bore <b>720</b> is aligned with the dispensing opening <b>722</b>), the filter <b>718</b> will completely cover the lower portion of the bore <b>720</b> in order to permit the liquid to be output through the filter <b>718</b> while containing the pupae in the bore <b>720</b>. When the moveable member <b>708</b> is in the second position (i.e., the solid portion of the moveable member <b>708</b> is aligned with the dispensing opening <b>722</b>), the filter <b>718</b> may rotate so that the pupae may be output from the bore <b>720</b>. When the filter <b>718</b> is not covering the lower portion of the bore <b>720</b> while the moveable member <b>708</b> is in the second position, either gravity or the use of water or air will cause the pupae to slide out of the bore <b>720</b> and into a container, an output pipe, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> shows an example method <b>800</b> for dispensing insect pupae according to this disclosure. The example method <b>800</b> will be discussed with respect to the device <b>100</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>. However, it should be appreciated that any suitable system for dispensing insect pupae may be employed, such as that shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>-<b>7</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">At block <b>810</b>, a device <b>100</b> for dispensing insect pupae is provided. Here, the device <b>100</b> includes a dispenser assembly <b>102</b>, which includes a frame <b>106</b> and a moveable member <b>108</b> defining at least one bore <b>120</b>, a reservoir container <b>104</b>, and an actuator <b>128</b> as discussed above. The frame <b>106</b> has a first surface <b>106</b><i>a</i> and a second surface <b>106</b><i>b</i> opposite the first surface that define a pathway <b>110</b> where the moveable member <b>108</b> is located and may move through. The frame <b>106</b> defines various openings, including an inlet opening <b>112</b>, a drain opening <b>114</b>, an output opening <b>116</b>, and a rinse opening <b>126</b>, in the first surface <b>106</b><i>a</i> and the second surface <b>106</b><i>b</i> that provide access to the pathway <b>110</b>. The frame may also include a filter <b>118</b> that is positioned to overlay the drain opening <b>114</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">At block <b>812</b>, a mixture of insect pupae and a liquid, such as water, is received into the reservoir container <b>104</b> of the device <b>100</b>. In some examples, the mixture may be received into the reservoir container <b>104</b> from a user manually dispensing the mixture into the reservoir container <b>104</b>. In other examples, the mixture may be received into the reservoir container <b>104</b> from a pipe, such as the intake pipe <b>332</b> discussed above in reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> positioned to dispense the mixture directly into the reservoir container <b>104</b>, or any other suitable type of upstream source that does not require manual action by a user.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">At block <b>814</b>, the mixture is strained using the filter <b>118</b> that overlays the drain opening <b>114</b>. After the mixture is received into the reservoir container <b>104</b>, the mixture is guided toward and through the dispensing opening <b>122</b> and the inlet opening <b>112</b> until the mixture reaches the bore <b>120</b> due to the shape of the reservoir container <b>104</b> and the gravitational forces acting on the mixture. Additionally, the reservoir container <b>104</b> may be rinsed with a liquid or gas, as discussed above in reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, to assist with guiding the mixture towards the bore <b>120</b>. In some examples, the bore <b>120</b> is not aligned with both the inlet opening <b>112</b> and the drain opening <b>114</b> at the same time. Instead the mixture flows into the bore <b>120</b> and the moveable member translates through the pathway <b>110</b> so that the bore <b>120</b> is aligned with the drain opening <b>114</b> and the filter <b>118</b> to strain the mixture.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">In some examples, the straining of the mixture occurs when the liquid is output through the filter <b>118</b> overlaying the drain opening <b>114</b> while the plurality of pupae are contained in the bore. The mesh material that the filter <b>118</b> is made out of is designed to permit liquid to pass through the openings in the mesh while holding the pupae in the bore <b>120</b>. As more of the liquid is output through the filter <b>118</b>, more pupae will fill the bore <b>120</b> until the bore <b>120</b> reaches a point of saturation where the pupae occupy substantially the entire volume of the bore <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">At block <b>816</b>, the moveable member <b>108</b> is moved from a first position to a second position. In some examples, the moveable member <b>108</b> is moved using an actuator <b>128</b>. As discussed above, the actuator may be coupled to the moveable member <b>108</b> or positioned adjacent to the moveable member <b>108</b> and may take any suitable form that is capable of causing the moveable member <b>108</b> to move (e.g., a hydraulic actuator, a pneumatic actuator, etc.). Additionally, the computing device <b>336</b>, as discussed in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, may be used to activate the actuator <b>128</b> and move the moveable member <b>108</b>. While the computing device <b>336</b> is discussed in relation to the linear actuator <b>328</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, the computing device <b>336</b> may be used to activate any actuator incorporated into the device <b>100</b>, including the disc shaped moveable member <b>508</b>, <b>608</b> discussed in relation to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>5</b> and <b>6</b></figref>. In other examples, the moveable member <b>108</b> may be moved manually.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">As discussed above, the moveable member <b>108</b> is in the first position when the bore <b>120</b> is aligned with the inlet opening <b>112</b>. This alignment permits the mixture to flow from the reservoir container <b>104</b> into the bore <b>120</b>. Here, the bore <b>120</b> is also aligned with the drain opening <b>114</b> in the first position, which permits the liquid to be output through the filter <b>118</b> overlaying the drain opening <b>114</b> at the same time as more of the mixture is flowing into the bore <b>120</b>. However, in some embodiments, the drain opening <b>114</b> may be misaligned or not aligned at all with the drain opening <b>114</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">When the moveable member <b>108</b> is in the second position, the bore <b>120</b> is aligned with the output opening <b>116</b> and the inlet opening <b>112</b> is blocked by a solid portion of the moveable member <b>108</b>. This solid portion prevents any more of the mixture from flowing out of the reservoir container <b>104</b> until to bore <b>120</b> is once again positioned underneath the inlet opening <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">In other examples, there may be no inlet opening <b>112</b> or drain opening <b>114</b> in the device, as is described above in reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref>. Thus, the moveable member <b>108</b> is in the first position when the bore <b>120</b> is aligned with the dispensing opening <b>722</b> and is in the second position when the bore <b>120</b> is not aligned with the dispensing opening <b>722</b> such that the dispensing opening <b>722</b> is blocked by a solid portion of the moveable member <b>108</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">At block <b>818</b>, the plurality of insect pupae contained in the bore <b>120</b> are output from the bore <b>120</b> through the output opening <b>116</b>. In some examples, the insect pupae may be output solely due to the gravitational forces acting on them. In other examples, a liquid, such as water, may be introduced to rinse the bore <b>120</b> to ensure that all the pupae are output from the bore.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref> shows an example computing device <b>900</b> suitable for use in example devices or methods for dispensing insect pupae according to this disclosure. The example computing device <b>900</b> includes a processor <b>910</b> which is in communication with the memory <b>920</b> and other components of the computing device <b>900</b> using one or more communications buses <b>902</b>. The processor <b>910</b> executes processor-executable instructions stored in the memory <b>920</b> to assist with dispensing insect pupae, such as instructions for part or all of the example method <b>800</b> described above with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">In some examples, the processor <b>910</b> is part of a computerized control system for the device <b>100</b>. The processor <b>910</b> may receive an actuator signal from the actuator <b>128</b> and determine a current position of the moveable member <b>108</b> based on the actuator signal. For example, the actuator signal may indicate that the actuator <b>128</b> is in a first position, a second position, or any other position. In other examples, the processor <b>910</b> may receive a sensor signal from a sensor <b>960</b> and determine a current position of the moveable member <b>108</b> based on the sensor signal. While the sensor <b>960</b> is shown as an integral element of computing device <b>900</b>, the sensor <b>960</b> may be separate from and communicatively coupled to the computing device <b>900</b>. The processor <b>910</b> may then transmit a movement signal to the actuator <b>128</b> based on the determined current position and the actuator <b>128</b> may be configured to move based on the movement signal.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">The computing device <b>900</b>, in this example, also includes one or more user input devices <b>950</b>, such as a keyboard, mouse, touchscreen, microphone, etc., to accept user input. The computing device <b>900</b> also includes a display <b>940</b> to provide visual output to a user.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">The computing device <b>900</b> also includes a communications interface <b>930</b>. In some examples, the communications interface <b>930</b> may enable communications using one or more networks, including a local area network (&#x201c;LAN&#x201d;); wide area network (&#x201c;WAN&#x201d;), such as the Internet; metropolitan area network (&#x201c;MAN&#x201d;); point-to-point or peer-to-peer connection; etc. Communication with other devices may be accomplished using any suitable networking protocol. For example, one suitable networking protocol may include the Internet Protocol (&#x201c;IP&#x201d;), Transmission Control Protocol (&#x201c;TCP&#x201d;), User Datagram Protocol (&#x201c;UDP&#x201d;), or combinations thereof, such as TCP/IP or UDP/IP.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">While some examples of methods and devices herein are described in terms of software executing on various machines, the methods and devices may also be implemented as specifically-configured hardware, such as field-programmable gate array (FPGA) specifically to execute the various methods. For example, examples can be implemented in digital electronic circuitry, or in computer hardware, firmware, software, or in a combination thereof. In one example, a device may include a processor or processors. The processor includes a computer-readable medium, such as a random access memory (RAM) coupled to the processor. The processor executes computer-executable program instructions stored in memory, such as executing one or more computer programs. Such processors may include a microprocessor, a digital signal processor (DSP), an application-specific integrated circuit (ASIC), field programmable gate arrays (FPGAs), and state machines. Such processors may further include programmable electronic devices such as PLCs, programmable interrupt controllers (PICs), programmable logic devices (PLDs), programmable read-only memories (PROMs), electronically programmable read-only memories (EPROMs or EEPROMs), or other similar devices.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">Such processors may include, or may be in communication with, media, for example computer-readable storage media, that may store instructions that, when executed by the processor, can cause the processor to perform the steps described herein as carried out, or assisted, by a processor. Examples of computer-readable media may include, but are not limited to, an electronic, optical, magnetic, or other storage device capable of providing a processor, such as the processor in a web server, with computer-readable instructions. Other examples of media include, but are not limited to, a floppy disk, CD-ROM, magnetic disk, memory chip, ROM, RAM, ASIC, configured processor, all optical media, all magnetic tape or other magnetic media, or any other medium from which a computer processor can read. The processor, and the processing, described may be in one or more structures, and may be dispersed through one or more structures. The processor may include code for carrying out one or more of the methods (or parts of methods) described herein.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">The foregoing description of some examples has been presented only for the purpose of illustration and description and is not intended to be exhaustive or to limit the disclosure to the precise forms disclosed. Numerous modifications and adaptations thereof will be apparent to those skilled in the art without departing from the spirit and scope of the disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">Reference herein to an example or implementation means that a particular feature, structure, operation, or other characteristic described in connection with the example may be included in at least one implementation of the disclosure. The disclosure is not restricted to the particular examples or implementations described as such. The appearance of the phrases &#x201c;in one example,&#x201d; &#x201c;in an example,&#x201d; &#x201c;in one implementation,&#x201d; or &#x201c;in an implementation,&#x201d; or variations of the same in various places in the specification does not necessarily refer to the same example or implementation. Any particular feature, structure, operation, or other characteristic described in this specification in relation to one example or implementation may be combined with other features, structures, operations, or other characteristics described in respect of any other example or implementation.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">Use herein of the word &#x201c;or&#x201d; is intended to cover inclusive and exclusive OR conditions. In other words, A or B or C includes any or all of the following alternative combinations as appropriate for a particular usage: A alone; B alone; C alone; A and B only; A and C only; B and C only; and A and B and C.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>That which is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A device for dosing a plurality of insect pupae or insect larvae comprising:
<claim-text>a dispenser assembly comprising:
<claim-text>a frame having a first surface and a second surface opposite the first surface, wherein the frame defines:
<claim-text>a pathway;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an inlet opening in the first surface of the frame, the inlet opening providing access to the pathway; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a drain opening in the second surface of the frame, the drain opening providing access to the pathway; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a moveable member having at least one bore oriented perpendicular to the pathway, wherein the moveable member is translatable within the pathway between a first position and a second position.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one bore is aligned with both the inlet opening and the drain opening at the first position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one bore is aligned with the drain opening at a third position of the moveable member between the first position and the second position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a reservoir container coupled to dispenser assembly.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the frame further defines an output opening in the second surface of the frame, the output opening providing access to the pathway, and wherein the at least one bore is aligned with the output opening at the second position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a reservoir container coupled to the dispenser assembly, wherein the reservoir container defines an intake opening and is shaped to guide a mixture of a liquid and insects to the inlet opening.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, further comprising a pipe positioned to dispense the mixture into the reservoir container.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the reservoir container is shaped like a funnel.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the reservoir container is removably coupled to the dispenser assembly using at least one of magnets, screws, bolts, clamps, a snap-fit design, or a friction-fit design.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the moveable member is at least one of a sliding block or a rotatable disc, and the rotatable disc defines a plurality of bores extending through the rotatable disc.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the moveable member is translatable using an actuator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one bore is sized to hold a predetermined number of insect pupae or insect larvae.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one bore comprises at least one mesh wall.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the moveable member is interchangeable with a second moveable member, wherein the at least one bore of the second moveable member is a different size than the at least one bore of the moveable member.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. A method comprising:
<claim-text>providing a device comprising:
<claim-text>a dispenser assembly comprising:
<claim-text>a frame having a first surface and a second surface opposite the first surface, wherein the frame defines:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pathway;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an inlet opening in the first surface of the frame, the inlet opening providing access to the pathway; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a drain opening in the second surface of the frame, the drain opening providing access to the pathway; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a moveable member having at least one bore oriented perpendicular to the pathway, wherein the moveable member is translatable within the pathway between a first position and a second position; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>dispensing portions of insects from the dispensing assembly by cyclically translating the moveable member between the first position and the second position.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. An insect pupae dosing system comprising:
<claim-text>a dosing device comprising:
<claim-text>a dispenser assembly comprising:
<claim-text>a frame having a first surface and a second surface opposite the first surface, wherein the frame defines:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pathway;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an inlet opening in the first surface of the frame, the inlet opening providing access to the pathway;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a drain opening in the second surface of the frame, the drain opening providing access to the pathway; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an output opening in the second surface of the frame, the output opening providing access to the pathway; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a moveable member having at least one bore oriented perpendicular to the pathway, wherein the moveable member is translatable within the pathway between a first position and a second position.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the dosing device further comprises a reservoir container coupled to the dispensing assembly, wherein the reservoir container is shaped to guide a mixture of insects to the inlet opening.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, further comprising a container rinsing mechanism configured to rinse the reservoir container with a rinsing liquid to assist with guiding insects of the mixture of insect to the inlet opening.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one bore is aligned with both the inlet opening and the drain opening at the first position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein a rinse opening is defined in the first surface, and wherein the at least one bore is aligned with both the rinse opening and the output opening at the second position.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
