<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225570A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225570</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18125759</doc-number>
<date>20230324</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>10</main-group>
<subgroup>38</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>11</main-group>
<subgroup>14</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>10</main-group>
<subgroup>38</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>G</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>11</main-group>
<subgroup>14</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>2010</main-group>
<subgroup>389</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">SYSTEMS AND METHODS FOR PRODUCT LEVEL TRACKING OF SHEET PRODUCT ROLLS</invention-title>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17065807</doc-number>
<date>20201008</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11617478</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18125759</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>63039061</doc-number>
<date>20200615</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>62912751</doc-number>
<date>20191009</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>GPCP IP Holdings LLC</orgname>
<address>
<city>Atlanta</city>
<state>GA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Murphy</last-name>
<first-name>David Warren</first-name>
<address>
<city>Neenah</city>
<state>WI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="01" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Robertson</last-name>
<first-name>Timothy Andrew</first-name>
<address>
<city>Appleton</city>
<state>WI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="02" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Swanson</last-name>
<first-name>Kevin Michael</first-name>
<address>
<city>Larsen</city>
<state>WI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="03" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Goltz</last-name>
<first-name>Ryan Anthony</first-name>
<address>
<city>Neenah</city>
<state>WI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Systems, devices, and methods for providing a sheet product dispenser with automated product level tracking functionality are provided herein. Various product level sensors are disclosed herein including a product level sensor configured to emit a signal toward an outer circumference of a sheet product roll on a spindle extending along a longitudinal axis and to receive a reflected signal. The product level sensor is positioned a radial distance away from the spindle and aimed to emit the signal in a direction that is not parallel and not perpendicular to the longitudinal axis. The product level sensor detects a parameter of the reflected signal corresponding to the distance between the product level sensor and the sheet product roll. Other example embodiments include mechanical product level sensors. Various communication protocols may be employed to limit transmission of data to conserve battery life while still maintaining desired communication functionality.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="89.15mm" wi="158.75mm" file="US20230225570A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="201.51mm" wi="123.53mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225570A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="175.18mm" wi="132.59mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225570A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="193.89mm" wi="128.44mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225570A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="201.93mm" wi="134.37mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225570A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="217.09mm" wi="97.03mm" file="US20230225570A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="121.67mm" wi="130.30mm" file="US20230225570A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="202.18mm" wi="120.40mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225570A1-20230720-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="224.71mm" wi="129.29mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225570A1-20230720-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="234.19mm" wi="123.78mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225570A1-20230720-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="222.33mm" wi="161.21mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225570A1-20230720-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="249.09mm" wi="127.00mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225570A1-20230720-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00012" num="00012">
<img id="EMI-D00012" he="220.30mm" wi="124.21mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225570A1-20230720-D00012.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00013" num="00013">
<img id="EMI-D00013" he="244.01mm" wi="128.69mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225570A1-20230720-D00013.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00014" num="00014">
<img id="EMI-D00014" he="206.33mm" wi="101.35mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225570A1-20230720-D00014.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00015" num="00015">
<img id="EMI-D00015" he="249.17mm" wi="113.62mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225570A1-20230720-D00015.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00016" num="00016">
<img id="EMI-D00016" he="204.30mm" wi="103.89mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225570A1-20230720-D00016.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00017" num="00017">
<img id="EMI-D00017" he="210.90mm" wi="128.19mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225570A1-20230720-D00017.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00018" num="00018">
<img id="EMI-D00018" he="232.07mm" wi="112.52mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225570A1-20230720-D00018.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00019" num="00019">
<img id="EMI-D00019" he="152.48mm" wi="123.78mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225570A1-20230720-D00019.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a continuation of and claims priority to U.S. application Ser. No. 17/065,807, entitled &#x201c;Systems and Method for Product Level Tracking of Sheet Product Rolls&#x201d;, filed Oct. 8, 2020, which claims priority to U.S. Provisional Application No. 63/039,061, entitled &#x201c;Systems and Methods for Product Level Tracking of Sheet Product Rolls&#x201d;, filed Jun. 15, 2020, and U.S. Provisional Application No. 62/912,751, entitled &#x201c;Systems and Methods for Inventory Tracking of Sheet Product Rolls&#x201d;, filed Oct. 9, 2019; each of which is incorporated herein by reference in its entirety.</p>
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="tail"?>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Example embodiments of the present invention generally relate to systems and methods for product level tracking of sheet product on a sheet product roll, and more particularly, for providing, e.g., retrofitting, sheet product dispensers with systems for automatic tracking of the quantity of sheet product remaining on the roll.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Conventional sheet product dispensers (e.g., paper towel dispensers and tissue dispensers) provide on-demand sheet product to a user from a supply of sheet product stored within the dispenser, such as in roll form. Rolls of sheet product, however, contain a limited quantity of sheet product such that the dispenser must be inspected regularly to determine whether the quantity of product remaining on a roll is sufficiently depleted such that the roll needs to be replaced. In commercial buildings containing many restrooms, for example, frequently checking the tissue paper dispenser in each stall of each restroom may be a time-consuming process for a maintainer (e.g., a janitor), and further, may result in an unnecessary roll change despite an adequate quantity of tissue paper remaining on the roll at the current time if a new supply would likely be needed prior to the next scheduled inspection. Further, it is difficult to maintain an accurate inventory count, such as for an entire building.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Though various &#x201c;smart&#x201d; sheet product dispenser systems have been developed to provide alerts as to the sheet product level and/or remaining inventory, sometimes, the costs associated with removing a conventional sheet product dispenser and replacing with such a &#x201c;smart&#x201d; system may be prohibitive. Further, some such &#x201c;smart&#x201d; systems require significant battery usage and, thus, may require frequent battery changes. Further, some sensor technology used in various &#x201c;smart&#x201d; systems may be improved upon.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Example embodiments of the present invention provide sheet product roll dispensers having sheet product level tracking functionality and systems and methods incorporating the same. For example, some embodiments of the present invention enable sheet product level tracking functionality to be added to a dispenser for dispensing sheet product from a roll without having to remove and/or replace the previously-installed dispenser. In accordance with various aspects, embodiments of the system may include a processor, a product level sensor, and a wireless communications module that are configured to be coupled to a conventional dispenser, for example, such as while the dispenser is mounted on a restroom wall or other structure (e.g., a stall partition). Upon being coupled to a dispenser, a processor associated with the product level sensor may determine, based on signals from the product level sensor, the quantity of sheet product remaining on the roll and, if appropriate, cause the wireless communications module to transmit a message to a remote computing device to indicate that a roll refill is needed. In various embodiments, systems for tracking (and communicating) the quantity of sheet product remaining on a roll may be configured to be powered by one or more batteries, for example, in order to avoid having to plug in or hard wire the dispenser system to an external power source. The product level sensor can have a variety of configurations in accordance with the present teachings. For example, in some embodiments, the systems and methods described herein utilize mechanical product level sensors that require only a limited energy supply, while the processor may restrict wireless transmissions to only certain events (e.g., when the sheet product inventory and/or battery power is low, when the roll has been replaced, etc.) and/or only at certain, pre-defined intervals in an effort to increase battery life. Additionally or alternatively, the systems and methods described herein may utilize a proximity product level sensor for indicating a distance between a portion of the product level sensor and the sheet product on the roll, which can be used to determine the quantity of sheet product remaining on the sheet product roll, for example, as the product level decreases. In various related aspects, the proximity product level sensor may be activated and/or wireless transmissions may be enabled upon the occurrence of only certain events and/or only at certain, pre-defined intervals in an effort to increase battery life.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In various aspects, embodiments of the invention may provide a sheet product roll dispenser having a product level sensor for indicating the quantity of sheet product remaining on a sheet product roll on a spindle extending along a longitudinal axis, wherein the sheet product roll is rotatably mounted within the dispenser. The product level sensor is configured to emit a signal toward an outer circumference of the sheet product roll and to receive a reflected signal therefrom. The product level sensor is positioned a radial distance away from the spindle and aimed to emit the signal in a direction that is not parallel and not perpendicular to the longitudinal axis. The product level sensor detects a parameter of the reflected signal corresponding to the distance between the product level sensor and the sheet product roll (e.g., illuminance, time-of-flight, phase shift). A processor, communicatively coupled to the product level sensor, may be configured to determine the quantity of sheet product remaining on the sheet product roll based on the parameter of the reflected signal. In various example embodiments, the processor may be coupled to the dispenser and the dispenser may further include a wireless communications module that transmits a message to a remote computing device to indicate that a refill is needed, for example, depending on the quantity of sheet product remaining on the sheet product roll as determined by the processor based on the parameter of the reflected signal.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In various additional or alternative aspects, embodiments of the invention may provide a sheet product roll dispenser having a product level sensor configured to generate a signal indicative of the distance to the circumferential perimeter of the sheet product roll from at least a portion of the product level sensor. In various aspects, the product level sensor can comprise an electromagnetic (EMR) source (e.g., a source of visible, IR, UV light, acoustic energy, etc.) directed toward the circumference of the sheet product roll rotatably mounted in the dispenser, with the central axis of the EMR source being neither parallel to the rotational axis of the roll nor perpendicular to the circumference of the sheet product roll, thereby increasing the resolution of the sensor signal as otherwise described herein. Some embodiments may include a wireless communications module that transmits a message to a remote computing device to indicate that a refill is needed, for example, based on the signal indicative of distance as detected by the product level sensor.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Some additional embodiments include apparatuses, systems, and methods including various example embodiments, such as described herein.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In an example embodiment of the present invention a sheet product roll dispenser is provided. The sheet product roll dispenser comprises a housing sized to at least partially contain a sheet product roll. The sheet product roll dispenser includes a spindle coupled to the housing and extending along a longitudinal axis. The spindle is configured to receive the sheet product roll. The sheet product roll dispenser further includes a product level sensor configured to emit a signal toward an outer circumference of the sheet product roll installed on the spindle and to receive a reflected signal therefrom. The product level sensor is positioned a radial distance away from the spindle and aimed to emit the signal in a direction that is not parallel to the longitudinal axis and not perpendicular to the longitudinal axis. The product level sensor detects a parameter of the reflected signal corresponding to the distance between the product level sensor and the sheet product roll. The sheet product roll dispenser further includes a processor configured to determine the quantity of sheet product remaining on the sheet product roll based on the parameter of the reflected signal.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In some embodiments, the sheet product roll dispenser further comprises a communications module configured to transmit product level data to a remote computing device for notifying a user regarding the quantity of sheet product on the sheet product roll, wherein the product level data is indicative of the quantity of sheet product remaining on the sheet product roll. In some embodiments, the notification to the user occurs upon a determination that the quantity of sheet product on the sheet product roll is depleted below a threshold quantity. In some embodiments, a first notification to the user occurs upon a determination that the quantity of sheet product on the sheet product roll is depleted below a first threshold quantity and a second notification to the user occurs upon a second determination that the quantity of sheet product on the sheet product roll is depleted below a second threshold quantity, wherein the first threshold quantity is greater than the second threshold quantity. In some embodiments, the first threshold quantity corresponds to when the reflected signal changes from being reflected off a side surface of the sheet product roll to being reflected off the outer circumference of the sheet product roll. In some embodiments, the processor is configured to determine the quantity of sheet product remaining at intervals, and wherein the duration between the intervals is reduced when the quantity of sheet product roll is below the first threshold quantity. In some embodiments, the duration between the intervals is further reduced when the quantity of sheet product roll is below the second threshold quantity.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In some embodiments, the sheet product roll dispenser further comprises a housing at least partially containing the product level sensor, the communications module, and at least one electrically conductive contact, wherein the housing is configured to be coupled to the sheet product dispenser between an inner surface of the sheet product dispenser and a side of the sheet product roll mounted on the spindle within the sheet product dispenser. In some embodiments, the housing comprises an outer plate, an inner plate, and sidewall extending therebetween, wherein the inner plate comprises one or more optical windows configured to allow the signal to be transmitted and received therethrough.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In some embodiments, the parameter of the reflected signal comprises one of time-of-flight, phase shift, shape, or illuminance.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In some embodiments, the product level sensor comprises an emitter configured to emit the signal such that a central axis of the emitted signal exhibits an angle in a range of about 15 degrees to about 75 degrees relative to the longitudinal axis of the spindle. In some embodiments, the angle is in a range of about 40 degrees to about 50 degrees.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In some embodiments, the processor is configured to limit transmissions initiated by the communications module until the detection of at least one high priority event. In some embodiments, the at least one high priority event is one of an event requiring service at the dispenser and an event of service being provided at the dispenser. In some embodiments, the event requiring service at the dispenser is selected from the group consisting of the processor determining that the quantity of sheet product on the sheet product roll is depleted below a threshold quantity, a charge remaining on one or more batteries coupled to the at least one electrically conductive contact being below a threshold level, and a detection of a fault. In some embodiments, the event of service being provided at the dispenser is selected from the group consisting of the processor determining that the quantity of sheet product on the sheet product roll is refilled above a threshold quantity and the replacement of one or more batteries.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In some embodiments, the processor is configured to limit transmissions initiated by the communications module to pre-defined intervals until the detection of at least one high priority event.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In another example embodiment, a system for providing automatic product level tracking functionality to a sheet product roll dispenser is provided. The system comprises a product level sensor configured to emit a signal toward an outer circumference of a sheet product roll on a spindle extending along a longitudinal axis and to receive a reflected signal therefrom. The sheet product roll is rotatably mounted on the spindle. The product level sensor is positioned a radial distance away from the spindle and aimed to emit the signal in a direction that is not parallel to the longitudinal axis and not perpendicular to the longitudinal axis. The product level sensor detects a parameter of the reflected signal corresponding to the distance between the product level sensor and the sheet product roll. The system further includes a processor configured to determine the quantity of sheet product remaining on the sheet product roll based on the parameter of the reflected signal. The system further includes a communications module configured to transmit product level data to a remote computing device for notifying a user regarding the quantity of sheet product on the sheet product roll. The product level data is indicative of the quantity of sheet product remaining on the sheet product roll. The system further includes an electrically conductive contact configured to be in contact with a terminal of one or more batteries for providing electrical power to at least one of the product level sensor, the processor, and the communications module. The product level sensor, the processor, the communications module, and the at least one electrically conductive contact are configured to be coupled to the sheet product roll dispenser.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In some embodiments, the system is configured to be coupled to the sheet product roll dispenser while the sheet product roll dispenser is installed on one of a wall or a structure such that the sheet product roll dispenser is retrofitted.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In yet another example embodiment, a system for providing automatic product level tracking functionality to a sheet product roll dispenser is provided. The system comprises a housing comprising a product level sensor configured to emit a signal toward an outer circumference of a sheet product roll on a spindle extending along a longitudinal axis and to receive a reflected signal therefrom. The sheet product roll is rotatably installed on the spindle and defines a first side surface, a second side surface, and the outer circumference extending therebetween. The product level sensor is positioned a radial distance away from the spindle and an axial distance away from the first side surface such that the product level sensor is positioned outside of a volume extending between a first plane corresponding to the first side surface and a second plane corresponding to the second side surface. The product level sensor is configured to emit the signal at a non-zero angle with respect to the longitudinal axis. The product level sensor detects a parameter of the reflected signal corresponding to the distance between the product level sensor and the sheet product roll. The housing further includes a processor configured to determine the quantity of sheet product remaining on the sheet product roll based on the parameter of the reflected signal. The housing further includes a communications module configured to transmit product level data to a remote computing device for notifying a user regarding the quantity of sheet product on the sheet product roll, wherein the product level data is indicative of the quantity of sheet product remaining on the sheet product roll. The housing further includes an electrically conductive contact configured to be in contact with a terminal of one or more batteries for providing electrical power to at least one of the product level sensor, the processor, and the communications module. The housing further includes one or more mounting features configured to enable coupling the housing to the sheet product roll dispenser.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In yet another example embodiment, a system for providing product level tracking functionality to a sheet product roll dispenser is provided. The system comprises a product level sensor comprising a source of electromagnetic radiation and a detector for detecting the electromagnetic radiation reflected from a circumference of a sheet product roll rotatably mounted within the dispenser around a spindle extending along a longitudinal axis. The source is configured to emit the electromagnetic radiation toward the sheet product roll along a central axis that is not parallel to the longitudinal axis and not perpendicular to the longitudinal axis. The product level sensor is configured to generate a signal indicative of the distance from at least a portion of the product level sensor to the sheet product roll. The system further includes a processor configured to determine the quantity of sheet product remaining on the sheet product roll based on the signal from the product level sensor. The system further includes a communications module configured to transmit product level data to a remote computing device for notifying a user regarding the quantity of sheet product on the sheet product roll, wherein the product level data is indicative of the quantity of sheet product remaining on the sheet product roll installed on the spindle. The system further includes an electrically conductive contact configured to be in contact with a terminal of one or more batteries for providing electrical power to at least one of the product level sensor, the processor, and the communications module. The product level sensor, the processor, the communications module, and the at least one electrically conductive contact are configured to be coupled to the sheet product roll dispenser.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">In yet another example embodiment, a system for adding automatic product level tracking functionality to a sheet product roll dispenser is provided. The system comprises a product level sensor configured to move from a first position to a second position when a quantity of sheet product on a sheet product roll mounted within the sheet product dispenser is depleted below a threshold quantity. The system further includes a processor configured to determine an instance in which the product level sensor moves to the second position. The system further includes a communications module configured to transmit product level data to a remote computing device for notifying a user upon the processor determining that the product level sensor moved to the second position, wherein the product level data is indicative of the quantity of sheet product on the sheet product roll. The system further includes an electrically conductive contact configured to be in contact with a terminal of one or more batteries for providing electrical power to at least one of the product level sensor, the processor, and the communications module. The product level sensor, the processor, the communications module, and the at least one electrically conductive contact are configured to be coupled to the sheet product roll dispenser.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In some embodiments, the system is configured to be coupled to the sheet product roll dispenser while the sheet product roll dispenser is installed on one of a wall or a partition such that the sheet product roll dispenser is retrofitted with the system.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In some embodiments, the product level sensor is biased to be in the second position.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In some embodiments, movement of the product level sensor from the first position to the second position is configured to close a circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">In some embodiments, the sheet product roll comprises a central bore extending along a longitudinal axis from a first side to a second side, and wherein at least a portion of the product level sensor is configured to be disposed in contact with the first side of the sheet product roll when in the first position. In some embodiments, the system further comprises a housing at least partially containing the product level sensor, the processor, the communications module, and the at least one electrically conductive contact, wherein the housing is configured to be coupled to the sheet product dispenser between an inner surface of the sheet product dispenser and the first side of the sheet product roll mounted on a spindle within the sheet product dispenser. In some embodiments, the housing comprises an outer plate, an inner plate, and sidewall extending therebetween, the inner plate defining an opening through which at least a portion of the product level sensor extends to be disposed in contact with the first side of the sheet product roll. In some embodiments, each of the inner and outer plate comprises a bore through which the spindle engages a spindle-receiving cavity on the inner surface of the sheet product dispenser. In some embodiments, the housing comprises a spindle receiving cavity for engaging the spindle.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In some embodiments, the product level sensor is a first product level sensor and is mounted so as to contact the first side of the sheet product roll when in the first position at a first radial distance from the central bore, wherein the threshold quantity is a first threshold quantity. The system further includes a second product level sensor that is configured to move from a first position to a second position when a quantity of sheet product on the sheet product roll mounted within the sheet product dispenser is depleted below a second threshold quantity. The second product level sensor is mounted so as to contact the first side of the sheet product roll when in the first position at a second radial distance from the central bore. The second radial distance is smaller than the first radial distance. The second threshold quantity is smaller than the first threshold quantity.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">In some embodiments, when the product level sensor is in the first position, the processor is configured to limit transmissions initiated by the communications module until the switch is moved to the second position.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">In some embodiments, the processor is configured to limit transmissions initiated by the communications module until the detection of at least one high priority event. In some embodiments, the at least one high priority event is one of an event requiring service at the dispenser and an event of service being provided at the dispenser.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">In some embodiments, the processor is configured to limit transmissions initiated by the communications module to pre-defined intervals until the detection of at least one high priority event. In some embodiments, the pre-defined interval is at most about an hour. In some embodiments, the pre-defined interval is at most about 24 hours. In some embodiments, the transmissions by the communications module at the pre-defined intervals comprises product level data and battery state data.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">In some embodiments, the processor is configured to determine an instance in which the product level sensor moves from the second position to the first position. The communications module is configured to transmit second product level data to the remote computing device for notifying the user upon the processor determining that the product level sensor moved to the first position.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">In yet another example embodiment, an apparatus for adding automatic product level tracking functionality to a sheet product roll dispenser is provided. The apparatus comprises a housing configured to be coupled to the sheet product roll dispenser. The housing at least partially contains a product level sensor configured to move from a first position to a second position when a quantity of sheet product on a sheet product roll mounted within the sheet product dispenser is depleted below a threshold quantity. The housing further includes a processor configured to determine an instance in which the product level sensor moves to the second position. The housing further includes a communications module configured to transmit product level data to a remote computing device for notifying a user upon the processor determining that the product level sensor moved to the second position. The product level data is indicative of the quantity of sheet product on the sheet product roll. The housing further includes an electrically conductive contact configured to be in contact with a terminal of one or more batteries for providing electrical power to the product level sensor, the processor, and the communications module. The housing further includes one or more mounting features configured to enable coupling of the housing to the sheet product dispenser.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">In some embodiments, the housing is configured to be coupled, via the one or more mounting features, to the sheet product roll dispenser while the sheet product roll dispenser is installed on one of a wall or a partition such that the sheet product roll dispenser is retrofitted with the housing.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">In some embodiments, the one or more mounting features comprises at least one of a mounting bracket, screw holes, or adhesive.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">In yet another example embodiment, a system for providing automatic product level tracking functionality for a sheet product roll dispenser is provided. The system comprises a product level sensor configured to move from a first position to a second position when a quantity of sheet product on a sheet product roll mounted within the sheet product dispenser is depleted below a threshold quantity. The system further includes a processor configured to determine an instance in which the product level sensor moves to the second position. The system further includes a communications module configured to transmit product level data to a remote computing device. The product level data is indicative of the quantity of sheet product on the sheet product roll. Transmissions initiated by the communications module are limited to pre-defined time intervals until the detection of a high priority event. The high priority event is selected from a group of events including an instance in which the product level sensor moves to the second position. The system further includes an electrically conductive contact configured to be in contact with a terminal of one or more batteries for providing electrical power to at least one of the product level sensor, the processor, and the communications module. The product level sensor, the processor, the communications module, and the at least one electrically conductive contact are configured to be coupled to the sheet product roll dispenser. The processor is further configured to determine one of occurrence of the high priority event or expiration of a pre-defined time interval and, in response thereto cause transmission of product level data to the remote computing device and cause resetting of a timer for determining expiration of the pre-defined time interval.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">In some embodiments, the system further includes the remote computing device, wherein the remote computing device comprises a processor configured to receive, via a remote computing device communications interface, the transmission from the communications module; and notify a user of the remote computing device that the sheet product dispenser is in need of a replacement sheet product roll upon the processor determining that the product level sensor moved to the second position.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">In some embodiments, the high priority event is one of an event requiring service at the dispenser and an event of service being provided at the dispenser. In some embodiments, the event requiring service at the dispenser is selected from the group consisting of the product level sensor moving to the second position, a charge remaining on one or more batteries coupled to the at least one electrically conductive contact being below a threshold level, and a detection of a fault. In some embodiments, the event of service being provided at the dispenser is selected from the group consisting of the product level sensor being reset to the first position and the replacement of one or more batteries.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In some embodiments, the pre-defined interval is at most about an hour. In some embodiments, the pre-defined interval is at most about 24 hours.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">In yet another example embodiment, a method of tracking product level of a sheet product roll dispenser is provided. The method comprises providing a product level tracking system comprising a product level sensor configured to move from a first position to a second position when a quantity of sheet product on a sheet product roll mounted within the sheet product dispenser is depleted below a threshold quantity. The system further includes a processor configured to determine an instance in which the product level sensor moves to the second position. The system further includes a communications module configured to transmit the product level data, wherein transmissions initiated by the communications module are limited to pre-defined time intervals until the detection of a high priority event. The high priority event is selected from a group of events including an instance in which the product level sensor moves to the second position. The system further includes an electrically conductive contact configured to be in contact with a terminal of one or more batteries for providing electrical power to at least one of the product level sensor, the processor, and the communications module. The product level sensor, the processor, the communications module, and the at least one electrically conductive contact are disposed within a housing coupled to the sheet product roll dispenser. The method further includes determining, via the processor, one of occurrence of a high priority event or expiration of a pre-defined time interval and, in response thereto causing transmission of product level data to a remote computing device, wherein the product level data is indicative of a quantity of sheet product on the sheet product roll coupled to the sheet product dispenser; and causing resetting of a timer for determining expiration of the pre-defined time interval.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE SEVERAL VIEWS OF THE DRAWING(S)</heading>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Having thus described the invention in general terms, reference will now be made to the accompanying drawings, which are not necessarily drawn to scale, and wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> shows an example conventional sheet product dispenser and sheet product roll known in the art;</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>A-B</figref> shows an example product level tracking system, such as for retrofitting the dispenser of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> in accordance with some embodiments discussed herein;</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> schematically depicts in additional detail the example product level sensor of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>A-B</figref>, in accordance with some embodiments discussed herein;</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>A-C</figref> schematically depict use of the example product level sensor of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>A-B</figref>, in accordance with some embodiments discussed herein;</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> shows another example product level tracking system in accordance with some embodiments discussed herein;</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b>A-B</figref> schematically depict an orientation sensor, such as for use in the example product level tracking system of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, in accordance with some embodiments discussed herein;</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>7</b>A-D</figref> show another example product level tracking system in accordance with some embodiments discussed herein;</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>8</b>A-C</figref> shows an example product level tracking system, such as for retrofitting the dispenser of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> in accordance with some embodiments discussed herein;</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>9</b>A-B</figref> schematically depicts in additional detail an example product level sensor, such as for use in the example product level tracking system of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>8</b>A-C</figref>, in accordance with some embodiments discussed herein;</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref> shows another example product level tracking system in accordance with some embodiments discussed herein;</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>11</b>A-B</figref> schematically depicts in additional detail another example product level sensor, such as for use in the example product level tracking system of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref>, in accordance with some embodiments discussed herein;</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>12</b>A-B</figref> shows another example product level tracking system in accordance with some embodiments discussed herein;</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>13</b>A-B</figref> schematically depicts in additional detail an example product level sensor, such as for use in the example product level tracking system of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>12</b>A-B</figref>, in accordance with some embodiments discussed herein;</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>14</b>A-B</figref> shows another example product level tracking system in accordance with some embodiments discussed herein;</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>15</b></figref> schematically depicts in additional detail an example product level sensor, such as for use in the example product level tracking system of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>8</b>A-C</figref>, in accordance with some embodiments discussed herein;</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>16</b></figref> shows another example product level tracking system in accordance with some embodiments discussed herein;</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>17</b></figref> shows another example product level tracking system in accordance with some embodiments discussed herein; and</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>18</b></figref> illustrates a flowchart detailing an example method of operating example product level tracking systems, in accordance with some embodiments discussed herein.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Some example embodiments now will be described more fully hereinafter with reference to the accompanying drawings, in which some, but not all example embodiments are shown. Indeed, the examples described and pictured herein should not be construed as being limiting as to the scope, applicability or configuration of the present disclosure. Rather, these example embodiments are provided so that this disclosure will satisfy applicable legal requirements. Like reference numerals refer to like elements throughout.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">As used herein, the term &#x201c;sheet product&#x201d; may include a product that is relatively thin in comparison to its length and width. Further, the sheet product may define a relatively flat, planar configuration. In some embodiments, the sheet product is flexible or bendable to permit, for example, folding, rolling, stacking, or the like. In this regard, sheet product may, in some cases, be formed into stacks or rolls for use with various embodiments described herein. Some example sheet products include towel, bath tissue, facial tissue, napkin, wipe, wrapping paper, aluminum foil, wax paper, plastic wrap, or other sheet-like products. Sheet products may be made from paper, cloth, non-woven, metallic, polymer or other materials, and in some cases may include multiple layers or plies. In some embodiments, the sheet product (such as in roll or stacked form) may be a continuous sheet that is severable or separable into individual sheets using, for example, a tear bar or cutting blade. Additionally or alternatively, the sheet product may include predefined areas of weakness, such as lines of perforations, that define individual sheets and facilitate separation and/or tearing. In some such embodiments, the lines of perforations may extend along the width of the sheet product to define individual sheets that can be torn off by a user.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">As used herein, a &#x201c;user&#x201d; of example product dispensers may be a maintainer (e.g., a maintenance person, a janitor, a facility manager, etc.) or a consumer (e.g., a person receiving a dispensed portion of the product).</p>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">Example Product Level Tracking Systems</heading>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">Various types of sheet product dispensers are known in the art. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> depicts an example of a conventional sheet product dispenser <b>10</b> that is configured to dispense sheet product <b>22</b> from a roll <b>20</b> that is rotatably supported by the dispenser <b>10</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, a typical sheet product roll <b>20</b> generally includes a sheet product <b>22</b> that is wrapped around a central longitudinal axis (A) such that numerous layers of the sheet product are wound around one another. The roll <b>20</b> may include a central bore <b>24</b> (in phantom) extending along the longitudinal axis (A) between a first side <b>24</b><i>a </i>and a second side <b>24</b><i>b. </i>Certain rolls of sheet product may be &#x201c;coreless&#x201d; (i.e., the central bore <b>24</b> of the roll is defined by an inner layer of sheet product <b>22</b>), while other rolls of sheet product may be &#x201c;cored&#x201d; (i.e., the bore <b>24</b> is defined by a core of paperboard or other material around which the layers of the sheet product <b>22</b> are wound). The sheet product <b>22</b> may be a continuous sheet that is severable or separable into individual sheets using, for example, a tear bar or cutting blade. Additionally or alternatively, the sheet product <b>22</b> may include predefined areas of weakness, such as lines of perforations <b>26</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, to facilitate separation and/or tearing. The line of perforations <b>26</b> may extend along the entire width or a portion of the width of sheet product <b>22</b> to define individual sheets <b>22</b><i>a </i>that can be torn off by a user.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">The example dispenser <b>10</b> includes a dispenser housing <b>12</b> defining a compartment <b>14</b> within which the roll <b>20</b> may be at least partially disposed so as to provide a user access to the sheet product <b>22</b>. Though only one roll <b>20</b> is accessible to the user in the depicted dispenser <b>10</b>, known dispensers may alternatively provide simultaneous access to a plurality of rolls and may utilize multiple spindles <b>18</b> each supporting a different roll of sheet product. For example, certain known dispensers may arrange the rolls on spindles in a side-by-side configuration, a stacked configuration, or a carousel configuration. Additionally, some known dispensers may cover one or more replacement rolls by a housing of the dispenser. The dispenser <b>10</b>, for example, comprises a storage location within the housing <b>12</b>, a cover of which may be secured via a lock <b>13</b> to prevent unauthorized access to a replacement roll stored therein. In some such dispensers, the dispensers may be configured to cause automatic repositioning of a stored sheet product roll into a dispensing position, such as by utilizing a track or other repositioning feature.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">The dispenser housing <b>12</b> may be securely installed at a location within the reach of an intended user. For example, a tissue paper dispenser <b>10</b> like that of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> may be affixed to a surface of a restroom wall or a stall partition (e.g., via adhesive, screws, brackets, etc.) or may be at least partially disposed within a cavity or recess in one of the wall or partition. Some known dispensers, for example, comprise a dispenser housing that is seated or secured within a cutout in a partition between adjacent restroom stalls, with the dispenser housing providing access to a different roll for each stall.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">Some sheet product dispensers may be configured to rotatably support the roll <b>20</b> so as to allow a user to unwind the sheet product <b>22</b> by rotating the roll about its longitudinal axis (A) and then separating the unwound portion from the roll for use. For example, certain sheet product dispensers may utilize a spindle <b>18</b> or other type of support that is positioned at least partially within the bore <b>24</b> and allows the roll <b>20</b> to rotate with respect to the sheet product dispenser. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, for example, an inner surface <b>14</b><i>a </i>on each side of the compartment <b>14</b> may include an installation feature, such as a hole <b>16</b> configured to receive an installation protrusion (not shown) extending outwardly from the ends of the spindle <b>18</b>. Though various spindles are known in the art for rotatably engaging the dispenser housing <b>12</b>, the example spindle <b>18</b> depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> includes two telescoping elongate body portions <b>18</b><i>a,b </i>that enable the spindle <b>18</b> to be compressed and extended along the spindle's longitudinal axis. After a user mounts a roll <b>20</b> on the spindle <b>18</b>, for example, the user may compress the spindle <b>18</b> to enable insertion of the installation protrusions into the corresponding installation holes <b>16</b> on the inner surface <b>14</b><i>a </i>of the compartment <b>14</b>. In such aspects, one or more springs disposed within the spindle <b>18</b> may be biased such that the telescoping portions <b>18</b><i>a,b </i>may extend across the width of the compartment <b>14</b> and secure the spindle's installation protrusions within the installation features <b>16</b> when the compressive force is released. In this regard, the depicted spindle <b>18</b> may be capable of engaging a wide variety of dispensers of varying dimensions (and may be used with product rolls of various lengths).</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">Some example sheet product dispensers such as that depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> may require a user (e.g., a maintainer) to regularly monitor the quantity of sheet product <b>22</b> remaining on a roll <b>20</b> mounted within the dispenser <b>10</b> in order to ensure that the roll does not become empty prior to the next scheduled inspection. If such a situation is likely, the maintainer may replace the roll <b>20</b> even if there is sufficient product on the roll for one or more future uses. Accordingly, such frequent inspections and/or premature roll replacements may result in substantially increased maintenance costs. Example embodiments of the present teachings, however, provide sheet product dispensers that provide an automatic notification when a sheet product has a reduced product level and/or is need of replacement, and in some aspects, may enable previously-installed sheet product dispensers to be retrofitted (e.g., without having to remove and/or replace a previously-installed dispenser) with such automatic product level tracking. As discussed in detail below, some example embodiments of the present invention provide a system that may be coupled to an existing sheet product dispenser so as to provide a notification when the dispenser is in need of maintenance and/or a replacement roll.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">In accordance with various aspects of the present teachings, the system generally includes a product level sensor, which may indicate when the quantity of sheet product on a roll falls below one or more threshold levels, and a wireless communications module that enables the transmission of such an indication to a remote computing device so as to alert a user regarding the need for a roll refill.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">Wherein some example systems in accordance with the present teachings may add such functionality to installed sheet product dispensers lacking a source of electrical power, various example embodiments for coupling to an existing sheet product dispenser may include one or more electrically-conductive contacts for electrically coupling to a battery for powering the automated tracking system. In some embodiments, various systems and methods described herein may provide automated tracking functionality while minimizing maintenance costs (e.g., reducing sheet product waste, decreasing frequency of battery replacement, etc.) by controlling sampling of the product level sensor(s), utilizing one or more mechanical product level sensors, and/or by restricting wireless transmissions to only certain high-priority events (e.g., upon determining that sheet product level and/or battery power is low) and/or only at certain, pre-defined intervals to confirm continued operation (e.g., once every few hours).</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>A-B</figref> illustrate an example product level tracking system <b>100</b> according to some embodiments of the present invention for enabling automated tracking of sheet product (e.g., tissue paper) remaining on a roll supported by a sheet product (e.g., tissue paper) dispenser <b>10</b>. As shown, the depicted system <b>100</b> may comprise a housing <b>102</b> that is configured to be coupled to the dispenser <b>10</b> and a remote computing device <b>130</b> configured to be in wireless communication with a communications module <b>180</b> within the housing <b>102</b>. It will be noted, however, that while the housing <b>102</b> of system <b>100</b> is depicted as being coupled to the housing <b>12</b> of the previously-installed dispenser <b>10</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> (e.g., without having to remove and/or replace the dispenser housing <b>12</b>), the present teachings also provide for standalone dispenser systems that fully replace a conventional dispenser like that of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, with one or more of the various features within housing <b>102</b> as being integrated within a dispenser housing itself</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">With reference first to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>A</figref>, the example housing <b>102</b> is configured to be disposed within the dispenser <b>10</b> in a location that allows for sensing the sheet product remaining on a roll (as discussed otherwise herein) without restricting rotation of a spindle <b>118</b> mounted within the dispenser <b>10</b>. It will be appreciated in light of the present teachings that the housing <b>102</b> may have a variety of shapes and sizes, but in some aspects may generally be shaped and sized to fit within the dispenser <b>10</b> to be retrofitted and may be configured to be coupled to the dispenser at a location that does not interfere with the dispensing of sheet product <b>22</b> therefrom. For example, in the example embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>A-B</figref>, the cross-sectional shape of the housing <b>102</b> is in the form of a truncated circle such that the flat portion of the cross-sectional shape can be disposed toward the front of the dispenser <b>10</b> and matches the profile of the front of the dispenser <b>10</b> when installed so as not to protrude therefrom, thereby reducing potential interference with operation and/or preventing a user from tampering with various components of the retrofitted system <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">With reference now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>B</figref>, the example housing <b>102</b> and spindle <b>118</b> are depicted in additional detail in partially exploded view. As shown, the housing <b>102</b> comprises an inner plate <b>102</b><i>c </i>and an outer cover <b>102</b><i>a </i>providing a space therebetween within which a product level sensor <b>140</b>, a processor <b>160</b>, and/or a communications module <b>180</b> may at least partially be disposed. The outer cover <b>102</b><i>a </i>may be fixedly coupled to the inner surface <b>14</b><i>a </i>of the compartment <b>14</b> (e.g., via screws, brackets, adhesive, etc. for mounting the housing <b>102</b> to the dispenser <b>10</b>) such that it does not rotate with the spindle <b>118</b> and/or sheet product roll. For example, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>B</figref>, the inner plate <b>102</b><i>c </i>and outer cover <b>102</b><i>a </i>comprise holes <b>105</b> through which mounting screws can be inserted to secure the housing <b>102</b> to the dispenser <b>10</b>. In some aspects, the outer cover <b>102</b><i>a </i>may comprise a protrusion on its outer surface that is configured to be secured within an installation hole <b>16</b> of a previously-installed dispenser <b>10</b>, while a spindle-receiving cavity similar in configuration to the installation feature <b>16</b> may be formed in the housing <b>102</b> (e.g., in the inner plate <b>102</b><i>c </i>and/or cover <b>102</b><i>a</i>) so as to receive the installation protrusions from a previously-installed dispenser's spindle <b>18</b>. However, in the example depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>A and <b>2</b>B</figref>, the outer cover <b>102</b><i>a </i>comprises a hole <b>106</b><i>a </i>through which at least a portion of the spindle <b>118</b> may extend for coupling thereto. Likewise, the inner plate <b>102</b><i>c </i>comprises a corresponding hole <b>106</b><i>c </i>through which at least a portion of the spindle <b>118</b> may extend. Thus, as shown, a spring <b>104</b> within spindle <b>118</b> allows the telescoping elongate body portions <b>118</b><i>a,b </i>to be compressed and extended against a surface of the dispenser housing <b>10</b> to allow for refill of an empty roll. As such, a person skilled in the art will appreciate that various aspects of the present teachings enable a wide variety of spindles, including conventional spindles such as spindle <b>18</b> from the previously-installed dispenser <b>10</b> as well as spindles provided with the housing <b>102</b> as otherwise described herein.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">Additionally, it will be appreciated that the housing <b>102</b> may be configured to exhibit a low-profile so as to be unobtrusively retrofitted into the previously-installed dispenser <b>10</b>. For example, the depicted housing <b>102</b> may comprise a relatively thin sidewall <b>102</b><i>b </i>extending from the inner plate <b>102</b><i>c </i>such that the compartment defined within the housing <b>102</b> is of minimal thickness to contain various components of the inventory tracking system <b>100</b> as otherwise discussed herein without obstructing the dispensing of sheet product from the dispenser <b>10</b>. In some aspects, retrofitting a dispenser <b>10</b> may encompass utilizing a replacement spindle (e.g., having a reduced length) and/or a roll <b>20</b> having a reduced width to accommodate the housing <b>102</b>, but preferably, no substantial modifications to the dispenser <b>10</b> would be required for coupling of the housing <b>102</b> thereto.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">In some embodiments, the housing <b>102</b> may comprise one or more mounting features that enable secure attachment to the sheet product dispenser <b>10</b>, such as to the inner surface <b>14</b><i>a </i>of the compartment <b>14</b> or a track or other repositioning feature. In some embodiments, the housing <b>102</b> may be configured with one or more lock features that are configured to lock the cover <b>102</b><i>a </i>to the inner plate <b>102</b><i>c </i>and/or to the sheet product dispenser (such as to the inner surface <b>14</b><i>a</i>). Accordingly, some embodiments may be enabled to prevent unauthorized access to the one or more components (e.g., the product level sensor <b>140</b>, the processor <b>160</b>, the communications module <b>180</b>, batteries, etc.). In some such embodiments, the maintainer may have a key that unlocks the lock features to enable access within the housing <b>102</b>, such as to replace the batteries.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">Finally, though the depicted housing <b>102</b> is configured to at least partially contain each of the product level sensor <b>140</b>, the processor <b>160</b>, the communications module <b>180</b>, and a plurality of batteries, these example components need not be contained within a single housing or within a housing at all. Rather, it will be appreciated that components of the product level tracking system <b>100</b> that are coupled to the dispenser <b>10</b> can be disposed at a variety of one or more distributed locations within the dispenser <b>10</b> so as not to interfere with operation thereof. By way of example, one or more components of the tracking system <b>100</b> (e.g., electrically conductive contacts for batteries) may be contained within the internal storage location within the housing <b>12</b> secured via the lock <b>13</b> of the sheet product dispenser <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">Depending on the configuration of the sheet product dispenser, various types of product level sensors can be used to determine the sheet product remaining on a sheet product roll being dispensed by a dispenser. For example, the product level sensor may comprise a mechanical product level sensor that interacts directly with the sheet product as it is dispensed from the roll. In various embodiments discussed below, example mechanical-based product level sensors may comprise a button, switch, toggle, lever, etc. having at least a portion that may be configured to be disposed in contact with the sheet product and to move as the quantity of sheet product on the roll changes, thereby indicating changes in the quantity of sheet product on the roll. Alternatively, product level sensors suitable for use in accordance with some embodiments of the present teachings may direct a signal, such as an electromagnetic signal (e.g., a beam of visible, IR, or UV light such a from a diode or laser, acoustic energy such as a sound wave), toward the product roll, with a detector being able to detect the reflected signal as the quantity of sheet product on the roll changes, e.g., being reduced below a threshold. Though any of such product level sensors described herein may be utilized in accordance with the present teachings to indicate the quantity of sheet product remaining on a roll, embodiments of systems in accordance with the present teachings may preferably utilize product level sensors that produce signals that enable the determination of the quantity of product remaining on the roll substantially continuously (if desired). For example, whereas some mechanical product level sensors discussed below may exhibit discrete on/off &#x201c;states&#x201d; indicating whether the remaining inventory is above or below a particular threshold, the present teachings also provide for automatic product level tracking with product level sensors that may be used to determine the quantity remaining at substantially any point during the lifetime of a sheet product roll. Non-limiting examples of such product level sensors include any mechanical-, optical-, time-of-flight-, ultrasonic-, infrared-, acceleration-, rotation- or weight-based product level sensors known in the art or hereafter developed and modified in accordance with the present teachings. By way of example, a product level sensor in accordance with present teachings may utilize optical, time-of-flight, ultrasonic, or infrared detection by directing an electromagnetic signal toward the product roll <b>20</b>, with one or more parameters of the reflected signal (e.g., characteristics such as time-of-flight, intensity, illuminance, phase shift, shape of the illuminated area on the sheet product, etc.) being detected to indicate the proximity of a portion of the product level sensor to the sheet product on an installed roll, thereby indicating the quantity of sheet product remaining on the roll.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">Alternatively, for example, a weight-based product level sensor may determine remaining inventory based on the weight of the roll, and thus, may indicate a &#x201c;low inventory&#x201d; when the weight of a product roll has decreased below a certain value. By way of another non-limiting example, the product level sensor may comprise one or more accelerometers configured to measure the rotation of a spindle such that inventory may be indicated when the number of revolutions has surpassed a certain value since the roll was last filled. In some aspects, the product level sensor may alternatively comprise a mechanical product level sensor that interacts directly with the sheet product as it is dispensed from the roll. For example, in various example embodiments, mechanical-based product level sensors may comprise a button, switch, toggle, lever, etc. having at least a portion that may be configured to be disposed in contact with the sheet product and to move as the quantity of sheet product on the roll changes, thereby indicating changes in the quantity of sheet product on the roll.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">Though any of such product level sensors described above and modified in accordance with the present teachings may be utilized, certain example embodiments of systems described herein utilize a proximity product sensor that enables the determination of the quantity of product based on a signal reflected from the circumference of the sheet product at substantially any point during the lifetime of a sheet product roll. With reference again to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>A-B</figref>, the example product level tracking system <b>100</b> includes a time-of-flight product level sensor <b>140</b> that is disposed within the housing <b>102</b> and utilizes non-contact time-of-flight techniques to determine the distance to the circumference of a roll disposed on the spindle <b>118</b>. In particular, the example time-of-flight sensor <b>140</b> includes a light source <b>140</b><i>a </i>and a light detector <b>140</b><i>b. </i>The light source <b>140</b><i>a </i>is configured to emit light directed at the sheet product <b>20</b>, from which light reflected off the circumference may be detected by the detector <b>140</b><i>b. </i>It will be appreciated by those skilled in the art that time-of-flight sensors suitable for use in accordance with the present teachings can utilize a variety of techniques to indicate the distance from the source <b>140</b><i>a </i>to the sheet product roll, for example, using both direct measurements (e.g., the actual time between emission and detection of a light pulse) and indirect measurements. Examples of indirect measurements of time-of-flight include detecting phase shifts in the reflected signal relative to an amplitude-modulated source signal (e.g., using differential voltage measurements of charged capacitors) or detecting the intensity of reflected light over an interval during on/off keying of the source signal (e.g., a square wave).</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">While a proximity product level sensor <b>140</b> in accordance with the present teachings can be disposed at a variety of locations within a dispenser <b>10</b> or housing <b>140</b>, the light source <b>140</b><i>a </i>may in some aspects be disposed relative to the roll <b>20</b> such that the light source <b>140</b><i>a </i>is configured to emit light toward the sheet product roll along a central axis that is neither parallel nor perpendicular to the longitudinal axis of the roll <b>20</b> or spindle <b>18</b> (e.g., axis (A) of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>). As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>B</figref>, the inner plate <b>102</b><i>c </i>of the housing <b>102</b> includes a recess <b>102</b><i>d </i>that allows the light source <b>140</b><i>a </i>to be angled such that its emission is directed toward the perimeter of the roll without interference from the housing <b>102</b> along the light source's &#x201c;line of sight.&#x201d; Likewise, the detector <b>140</b><i>b </i>may also be disposed within the recess <b>102</b><i>d </i>to allow reflected light to be reflected from the roll without interference. Though not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>A or <b>2</b>B</figref>, the light source <b>140</b><i>a </i>and detector <b>140</b><i>b </i>within housing <b>100</b> may be separated by an opaque barrier such that light from the light source <b>140</b><i>a </i>cannot be directly transmitted to the detector <b>140</b><i>b </i>(e.g., without reflection from the roll). Additionally or alternatively, one or more lenses can be provided to focus light transmitted from the light source <b>140</b><i>a </i>or to be received by the detector <b>140</b><i>b </i>so as to reduce direct transmission from the light source <b>140</b><i>a </i>to the detector <b>140</b><i>b </i>and/or to decrease the divergence of emitted light along its central axis (e.g., focus) and/or increase the intensity of reflected light provided to the detector <b>140</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">As noted above, emission of the light source <b>140</b><i>a </i>can be preferably angularly oriented relative to the longitudinal axis of the roll or spindle <b>118</b> such that the central axis of emission (whether diverging, converging, or a coherent EMR source) is neither parallel nor perpendicular to the longitudinal axis of the roll or spindle (e.g., axis (A) of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>). In accordance with the present teachings, a light source disposed in a housing along the side of a roll can be effective to continue to measure the distance to the perimeter of the roll despite its diminishing inventory, while providing an increased resolution of the time-of-flight sensor signal due to the increased distance between the light source and the perimeter of the roll.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">As best shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, three example central axes are schematically shown for light source <b>140</b><i>a </i>at 45 degrees, 60 degrees, and 70 degrees relative to the longitudinal axis of the spindle <b>118</b> in accordance with various aspects of the present teachings. The light source <b>140</b><i>a </i>is offset from the longitudinal axis of the spindle (e.g., axis (A) of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>) by a radial distance (r<sub>1</sub>) and an axial distance (a<sub>1</sub>) from the left end of a roll (not shown) if mounted on the spindle <b>118</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>. It will be appreciated in light of the depicted geometry (e.g., the radial distance of the light source <b>140</b><i>a </i>from the spindle <b>118</b> (34.7 mm) and distance from the center of the spindle <b>118</b> along the longitudinal axis) that a preferred emission angle may be selected in view of the present teachings.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">As shown, light transmitted and detected along the 70 degree and 60 degree angle traverse a greater distance than that transmitted and detected at 45 degrees. Notably, the distance traversed at 60 degrees (69.3 mm) is almost twice the distance that would be traveled by reflected light from a light source at the same radial distance from the roll but aimed perpendicular to the longitudinal axis of the spindle <b>118</b>. A person skilled in the art will therefore appreciate that an angled light source <b>140</b><i>a </i>in accordance with the present teachings can increase resolution relative to a light source that is aimed perpendicular to the longitudinal axis of the spindle <b>18</b> (e.g., the normal of the circumference of the roll).</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">Moreover, as depicted in the example configuration of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, light emitted at an angle of greater than about 75 degrees would not be able to be reflected off the sheet product itself, but would instead be reflected from another portion of the dispenser or spindle <b>118</b> and thereby fail to provide any information regarding the remaining inventory except perhaps that it is below a threshold. For example, it will be appreciated that a light source <b>140</b><i>a </i>that directs its emission substantially parallel to the longitudinal axis of the spindle <b>118</b> would act as a &#x201c;state&#x201d; threshold in that light would be reflected from the ends of the roll until its inventory was depleted below the central axis of emission. Thus, in accordance with certain aspects of the present teachings, the central axis of the light source <b>140</b><i>a </i>can exhibit an angle in a range of about 15 degrees to about 75 degrees relative to the longitudinal axis of the spindle <b>18</b> (e.g., in a range of about 40 degrees to about 50 degrees, about 45 degrees).</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">As noted above, various techniques can be used to measure the amount of time it takes for light to be transmitted and reflected, and ultimately, to correlate this duration with a distance to the object. By way of non-limiting example, in a direct measurement of time-of flight, a pulse of light or a sequence of pulses can be used to determine start and stop times for this transmission/detection pair. For example, after a pulse of light is emitted from the light source <b>140</b><i>a </i>at a first time (e.g., t<sub>1</sub>), it can be reflected from the surface of the sheet product and received by the light detector <b>140</b><i>b </i>at a second, subsequent time (e.g., t<sub>2</sub>). The processor <b>160</b>, which is contained within the housing <b>102</b> and operatively coupled to the product level sensor <b>140</b>, can determine the time-of-flight (i.e., t<sub>2</sub>&#x2212;t<sub>1</sub>) for the one or more light pulses to make such a roundtrip to the sheet product. This time-of-flight is inversely related to the inventory of the roll <b>20</b> at the time of measurement, where a roll having more inventory would exhibit a shorter time-of-flight relative to the same roll (or a roll of the same style (e.g., same diameter central bore)) having less sheet product remaining.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">It will be appreciated by those skilled in the art that the remaining inventory could thus be determined based on this measurement of time-of-flight, for example, by correlating the measured time-of-flight measured with the amount of sheet product remaining (e.g., via a look-up table determined empirically) and/or by calculating the actual distance from the light source <b>140</b><i>a </i>and light detector <b>140</b><i>b </i>to the sheet product (e.g., to determine the diameter of the roll), by way of non-limiting example. Distance (d) to the sheet product can be calculated as follows, for example:</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0000">
<maths id="MATH-US-00001" num="00001">
<math overflow="scroll">
 <mrow>
  <mi>d</mi>
  <mo>=</mo>
  <mfrac>
   <mrow>
    <mrow>
     <mo>(</mo>
     <mrow>
      <msub>
       <mi>t</mi>
       <mn>2</mn>
      </msub>
      <mo>-</mo>
      <msub>
       <mi>t</mi>
       <mn>1</mn>
      </msub>
     </mrow>
     <mo>)</mo>
    </mrow>
    <mo>*</mo>
    <mi>c</mi>
   </mrow>
   <mn>2</mn>
  </mfrac>
 </mrow>
</math>
</maths>
</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0000">where (t<sub>2</sub>-t<sub>1</sub>) is the time-of-flight and c is the speed of light. It will further be appreciated that the distance (d) is related to the diameter of the roll <b>20</b>, where a roll having more inventory (i.e., a larger diameter) would exhibit a smaller calculated distance (d) relative to the same roll having a smaller inventory (i.e., a smaller diameter). With knowledge of the relative geometry of the light source <b>140</b><i>a</i>/detector <b>140</b><i>b </i>and the central bore or spindle <b>118</b> (e.g., as exemplified in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>), the diameter of the roll can thus be calculated from the distance (d) indicated by the time-of-flight product level sensor.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0083">In addition to this direct measurement of time-of-flight (e.g., t<sub>2</sub>-t<sub>1</sub>), a person skilled in the art will appreciate that indirect techniques for determining the proximity of a product level sensor to the sheet product roll may also be utilized in accordance with the present teachings. By way of example, the source <b>140</b><i>a </i>could be configured to emit an amplitude-modulated source signal (e.g., a source of light), with the detected phase shift in the reflected signal being correlated with the time-of-flight, and thus, distance. For example, using indirect measurements, the distance (d) could be calculated from the detected phase shift as follows:</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0000">
<maths id="MATH-US-00002" num="00002">
<math overflow="scroll">
 <mrow>
  <mi>d</mi>
  <mo>=</mo>
  <mfrac>
   <mrow>
    <mi>c</mi>
    <mo>*</mo>
    <mi>&#x3c6;</mi>
   </mrow>
   <mrow>
    <mn>4</mn>
    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
    <mi>&#x3c0;</mi>
    <mo>*</mo>
    <mi>f</mi>
   </mrow>
  </mfrac>
 </mrow>
</math>
</maths>
</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0000">where c is the speed of light, &#x3c6; is the phase angle in radians, and f is the modulation frequency of the source signal. Any other known or hereafter developed technique for determining proximity of the EMR source to the sheet product roll are also within the scope of the present teachings, including the detection of the intensity of the reflected signal during an interval of emission of an amplitude modulated source signal (e.g., on/off keying), by way of non-limiting example. Moreover, proximity product level sensors in accordance with the present teachings may utilize other optical or acoustic techniques to determine the distance to the sheet product roll, which may then be used to determine the quantity of sheet product remaining. By way of example, it will be appreciated that similar calculations to those exemplified above can be used to determine the phase shift of a reflected acoustic signal if the EMR source generates acoustic energy (e.g., at ultrasonic frequencies) directed at the circumference of the sheet product roll.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0084">Additional examples of optical product sensors may comprise a light emitter (e.g., a source of visible, IR, or UV light such as a diode or laser) as the sensor signal source and a light receiver (e.g., a photodetector, photodiode, imaging array, etc.), which in some aspects may be configured to particularly detect the wavelength emitted by the source. In such examples, the emitter and receiver have a field of view that overlap at the distance range measured (e.g., on the perimeter of a roll at diminishing product levels). With the emitter on, reflected light from the circumference of the sheet product roll may return to the receiver to generate a signal (e.g., output voltage) that is proportional to the intensity or illuminance of the reflected light. Because illuminance is inversely proportional to the distance, the signal from the receiver may be utilized to determine distance (e.g., via a lookup table or direct calculation). In accordance with various aspects of the present teachings, an imaging array can alternatively be utilized as the receiver in a proximity product level sensor. In such aspects, the imaging array may be configured to image the shape of the area illuminated by the source on the circumference of the sheet product roll, with the size and/or shape of the illuminated area differing based on the distance of the sheet product roll from the source. As discussed otherwise herein, an angularly-oriented source may be preferable such to allow for increased resolution as the elliptical illuminated area lengthens.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0085">With reference now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>A-C</figref>, various rolls <b>20</b> of different remaining inventory are shown disposed on the spindle <b>118</b>, with the product level sensor <b>140</b> (including light source <b>140</b><i>a </i>and detector <b>140</b><i>b</i>) being disposed at a <b>45</b> degree angle relative to the longitudinal axis of the spindle <b>118</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>A</figref>, the time-of-flight (&#x394;t<sub>1</sub>) and/or distance between the light source and circumference of the product roll (d<sub>1</sub>) may be determined (e.g., by processor <b>160</b>) to correspond to a remaining product level of about 50% of a full roll. As schematically depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>B and <b>4</b>C</figref>, the time-of flight and/or distance increases as the roll is depleted (i.e., as the diameter of the roll <b>20</b> decreases) from 50% to about 20% (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>B</figref>) and to about 2% (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>C</figref>). In the depicted configuration of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>A</figref>, the time-of-flight and/or distance would remain substantially constant after a full replacement roll has been provided until the product level is less than about 50% (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>A</figref>). That is, depending on the size of the roll mounted on the spindle <b>118</b>, the recess <b>102</b><i>d </i>may be partially or fully covered by the roll such that the central axis of the emission from light source <b>102</b><i>a </i>would be directed at the end of the roll <b>20</b> instead of its perimeter. In such cases, it can be advantageous to limit, if not prevent sampling from the proximity product level sensor <b>140</b> until the inventory has been depleted to below the recess <b>1002</b>. By way of example, the sampling interval may be decreased until the product level has been initially indicated as being less than the recess <b>102</b><i>d </i>radial distance. However, a person skilled in the art will appreciate that the housing <b>102</b> and product level sensor <b>140</b> can be configured in accordance with the present teachings such that the signal source may be directed to the circumference of even a full roll (e.g., by increasing the radial distance of the EMR source <b>140</b><i>a</i>). In any event, an initial &#x201c;threshold&#x201d; for increased samplings may be utilized in that sampling from the product level sensor <b>140</b> may be less frequent until the amount of sheet product remaining is determined to be less than 50% in order to preserve battery life, by way of example. Moreover, it will be appreciated in light of the present teachings that one or more of the example values for remaining sheet product depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>A-C</figref> could cause a notification to be provided and/or one or more other thresholds may be utilized (e.g., less than 10% remaining sheet product, less than 2%), as discussed in detail below.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0086">With respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>A-C</figref>, it is noted that because of the angled orientation of the product level sensor <b>140</b> relative to the longitudinal axis of the spindle <b>118</b>, the difference between the distance between the light source and the circumference of the roll at various levels of sheet product (e.g., d<sub>2</sub>-d<sub>1</sub>) is greater than the corresponding reduction in the thickness of the sheet product remaining on the roll <b>20</b> (e.g., R<sub>1</sub>-R<sub>2</sub>) such that the angled product level sensor <b>140</b> may exhibit an increased resolution relative to a product level sensor that is aimed perpendicular to the longitudinal axis of the spindle <b>118</b> (i.e., normal to the circumference of the roll <b>20</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0087">With reference again to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>A-B</figref>, the processor <b>160</b> is operatively coupled to the product level sensor <b>140</b> and may be configured to control the transmission of light pulses from the light source <b>140</b><i>a </i>and/or to receive a signal from the detector <b>140</b><i>b </i>so as to determine the remaining sheet product based on the measurement of the time-of-flight. In various aspects, upon determining that the sheet product level is below a threshold quantity (e.g., below 2% as in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>C</figref>), the processor <b>160</b> may be configured to cause the communications module <b>180</b> to send information regarding the low remaining sheet product to a remote computing device <b>130</b> as otherwise discussed herein. The processor <b>160</b> is a suitable electronic device capable of executing inventory tracking functionality via hardware and/or software control. The processor <b>160</b> may be, but is not limited to, a microprocessor, microcomputer, a minicomputer, an optical computer, a board computer, a complex instruction set computer, an ASIC (application specific integrated circuit), a reduced instruction set computer, an analog computer, a digital computer, a molecular computer, a quantum computer, a cellular computer, a solid-state computer, a single-board computer, a buffered computer, a computer network, a desktop computer, a laptop computer, a personal digital assistant (PDA) or a hybrid of any of the foregoing.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0088">As discussed otherwise herein, the processor <b>160</b> may be operably coupled with one or more components of the product level tracking system <b>100</b>. Such operable coupling may include, but is not limited to, solid-core wiring, twisted pair wiring, coaxial cable, fiber optic cable, mechanical, wireless, radio, and infrared. Processor <b>160</b> may be configured to provide one or more operating signals to these components and to receive data from these components. Such communication can occur using a well-known communications protocol such as Bluetooth (e.g., Bluetooth Low Energy (BLE), WiFi, LoRa, Z-wave, Zigbee, cellular, Thread etc.), Inter-Integrated Circuit (I2C), Serial Peripheral Interface (SPI), System Management Bus (SMBus), Transmission Control Protocol/Internet Protocol (TCP/IP), RS-232, ModBus, or any other communications protocol suitable for the purposes disclosed herein.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0089">The processor <b>160</b> may include one or more processing units coupled to a memory device, and may optionally be connected to one or more input/output (I/O) controllers or data interface devices (not shown). The memory may be any form of memory such as an EPROM (Erasable Programmable Read Only Memory) chip, a flash memory chip, a disk drive, or the like. As such, the memory may store various data, protocols, instructions, computer program code, operational parameters, etc. In this regard, processor <b>160</b> may include operation control methods embodied in application code, typically in the form of software. The software can be encoded in any language, including, but not limited to, machine language, assembly language, VHDL (Verilog Hardware Description Language), VHSIC HDL (Very High Speed IC Hardware Description Language), Fortran (formula translation), C, C++, Visual C++, Java, ALGOL (algorithmic language), BASIC (beginners all-purpose symbolic instruction code), visual BASIC, ActiveX, HTML (HyperText Markup Language), and any combination or derivative of at least one of the foregoing. Additionally, an operator can use an existing software application such as a spreadsheet or database and correlate various cells with the variables enumerated in the algorithms. Furthermore, the software can be independent of other software or dependent upon other software, such as in the form of integrated software.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0090">As noted above, the communications module <b>180</b> may be configured to enable direct or indirect communication to an external system (e.g., a remote computing device <b>130</b>). In this manner, the processor <b>160</b> may retrieve data and/or instructions from or transmit data and/or instructions to the remote computing device <b>130</b> (e.g., indirectly via a remote, external server) in addition to or as an alternative to the memory within the housing <b>102</b>, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0091">The communications module <b>180</b> can have a variety of configurations, but may generally comprise a transmitter configured to transmit data including product level data to the remote computing device <b>130</b> (e.g., a smart hub, the user's mobile device (such as through the software application), a remote server, etc.)), for example, via one or more wireless communication protocols (e.g., WiFi, BLE, LoRa, Z-wave, Zigbee, Thread, cellular, etc.). In some embodiments, the system <b>100</b> is configured to receive sensor data from the product level sensor <b>140</b> and, through various logic, determine product level data indicative of the quantity of sheet product on the sheet product roll, for example, based on the measured time-of-flight and/or distance to the outer circumference of the sheet product roll. Such product level data can be sent to the remote device <b>130</b> (e.g., a smart hub, cloud server, etc.) that uses logic and algorithms to indicate to a maintainer, for example, that a new replacement roll is needed. In some embodiments, the product level data may include data corresponding to the time-of-flight and/or distance, and the remote computing device may utilize such data to determine the quantity of sheet product on the sheet product roll. In general, the term remote computing device comprises one or more computers, computing entities, desktop computers, mobile phones, tablets, phablets, notebooks, laptops, distributed systems, items/devices, servers or server networks, blades, gateways, switches, processing devices, processing entities, set-top boxes, relays, routers, network access points, base stations, the like, and/or any combination of devices or entities adapted to perform the functions, operations, and/or processes described herein.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0092">Electrical energy for one or more components of the product level tracking system <b>100</b> may be provided in a variety of manners such as by hard-wiring or plugging the components into an external power source, such as an alternating current (&#x201c;AC&#x201d;) power source (e.g., a 120V, 60 Hz wall outlet), a solar power source, or any other alternative external power source as may be appropriate for an application. However, in some embodiments, the electrical energy may preferably be provided by one or more batteries (e.g., arranged in series or parallel) that are electrically coupled to one or more of the various components of the product level tracking system <b>100</b>. For example, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>B</figref>, the housing <b>102</b> of the tracking system <b>100</b> may contain a battery compartment <b>107</b>, within which one or more batteries may be disposed for providing energy to one or more components of the product level tracking system <b>100</b> via a pair of electrically-conductive contacts <b>107</b><i>a,b </i>in the battery compartment(s) <b>107</b>. As depicted, the housing of the depicted tracking system <b>100</b> includes two battery compartments <b>107</b>, which together contain four sets of electrical contacts <b>107</b><i>a,b </i>for coupling to anodes and cathodes of four &#x201c;AAA&#x201d; cell batteries (not shown) in order to energize the product level sensor <b>140</b>, the processor <b>160</b>, and the communications module <b>180</b>, as otherwise discussed herein. It will be appreciated that more or fewer batteries (of different sizes and capacities) may be utilized in tracking systems in accordance with the present teachings based, for example, on the expected energy consumption and space constraints compelled by a previously-installed sheet product dispenser to which the tracking system <b>100</b> is to be coupled. Likewise, it will be appreciated that the batteries need not be contained between the inner plate <b>102</b><i>c </i>and outer cover <b>102</b><i>a </i>as depicted, but may instead be located at another location as long as in electrical contact with one or more components of the tracking system <b>100</b> requiring electrical power.</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0093">In light of the constraints on the size of batteries that may be disposed within embodiments of housings, such as those configured to retrofit sheet products dispensers in accordance with certain aspects of the present teachings, various embodiments may preferably be configured to conserve the limited electrical supply. By way of example, rather than continuously sample the sheet product level and send transmissions to a mobile computing device, some systems in accordance with the present teachings may limit energy consumption of the various electrical components such as the product level sensor <b>140</b>, the processor <b>160</b>, and/or the communications module <b>180</b> within the housing <b>102</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>A and <b>2</b>B</figref>. In some example embodiments of the present invention, the system <b>100</b> may be configured to extend battery life by generally operating in a &#x201c;low power&#x201d; mode, for example, in which the processor <b>160</b> causes the communications module <b>180</b> to be in a low or no power state (e.g., off, in standby, asleep) so as to reduce energy consumption by preventing the wireless communications module <b>180</b> from transmitting data, attempting to pair (e.g., enter a high power &#x201c;paired&#x201d; mode of communication), and/or advertising (e.g., operate in an &#x201c;advertising&#x201d; mode of communication) with a remote communication interface (e.g., a hub, router, server, or mobile computing device <b>130</b>). In some embodiments, unless and until the processor <b>160</b> determines that the sheet product remaining on the roll is below a certain threshold, the processor <b>160</b> may prevent the communications module <b>180</b> from being able to send or receive transmissions. Alternatively, in some example embodiments of a &#x201c;low power&#x201d; mode, the processor <b>160</b> may prevent the communications module <b>180</b> from transmitting data, attempting to pair, and/or advertising with a remote computing device unless and until the processor <b>160</b> determines the occurrence of the need for a replacement roll or another &#x201c;high priority&#x201d; event.</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0094">It will be appreciated in light of the present teachings that the definition of such high priority events can be selected for a particular system depending, for example, on the capacity of the one or more batteries that may be disposed within the housing <b>102</b>, the minimum desired frequency of battery replacement, and/or the expected frequency of roll changes, etc. In some example embodiments, &#x201c;high priority&#x201d; events may be defined to consist of events requiring maintenance such as the product level being depleted below a critically-low threshold (e.g., less than 2% indicating a near-immediate need for a replacement roll), the remaining charge on the batteries being below a threshold level (e.g., below a 10% battery capacity), and/or the occurrence of any other event indicating a need for service of the portion of the system <b>100</b> coupled to the dispenser <b>10</b> (e.g., detection of a fault). Additionally, in some embodiments, the high priority events may be defined to include an indication that a previously-determined service need has been addressed, for example, when the processor <b>160</b> determines that a replacement roll has been provided or upon the system <b>100</b> being powered up and that the remaining charge on the batteries is above a threshold level (e.g., above 50% battery capacity, indicating that batteries have been replaced). In such aspects, the example system <b>100</b> may thus consume minimal energy unless service is required and/or to provide notification that service has been provided.</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0095">In some aspects, the system <b>100</b> may also be configured to temporarily exit the &#x201c;low power&#x201d; mode in which the communications module <b>180</b> is in a low or no power state as discussed above in order to provide an indication to the remote computing device <b>130</b> (e.g., to initiate a &#x201c;heartbeat&#x201d;). Such an indication, for example, may be that the portion of the system <b>100</b> coupled to the dispenser <b>10</b> remains operational. By way of example, when the processor <b>160</b> has determined that the roll has sufficient sheet product for one or more future uses, the processor <b>160</b> may be configured to allow transmissions by the communications module <b>180</b> only at pre-defined intervals until a threshold product level is reached. In such aspects, the processor <b>160</b> may provide &#x201c;wake-up&#x201d; functionality at relatively infrequent intervals to enable the communications module <b>180</b> to &#x201c;advertise&#x201d; to the remote computing device <b>130</b> (or another remote computing device such as a hub, router, server, etc.) that the product level tracking system <b>100</b> remains operational. When no immediate service is needed (e.g., in the absence of a high priority event), as detected by the processor <b>160</b> during the interval, a relatively short &#x201c;advertising&#x201d; transmission (e.g., a beacon) may be utilized in order to conserve battery power. By way of example, the advertising transmission could merely identify the system <b>100</b> (e.g., a unique ID associated with the housing <b>102</b> in a particular stall), thereby indicating that the local portion of the system <b>100</b> remains present and operational. In certain aspects, messages from the communications module <b>180</b> in &#x201c;advertising&#x201d; mode may additionally comprise product level data (e.g., whether sheet product quantity is above or below one or more thresholds, such as a 50% threshold) and non-product level data such as the occurrence of any faults and/or the remaining charge for batteries contained within the housing <b>102</b>. In some embodiments, for example, such pre-defined intervals for advertising operability may occur no more than an hour apart, though longer or shorter intervals are also contemplated herein (e.g., no more than 24 hours). Indeed, it will be appreciated in light of the present teachings that in some embodiments, the system <b>100</b> need not include an &#x201c;advertising&#x201d; mode, depending on the capacity of the one or more batteries that may be disposed within the housing <b>102</b> and the desired frequency of battery replacement, for example. Further, although some described embodiments are indicated as being in a &#x201c;low&#x201d;, &#x201c;lower&#x201d;, or &#x201c;no&#x201d; power mode, such modes may be the normal operating power mode.</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0096">For example, with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>A-C</figref>, when the roll has sufficient sheet product for one or more future uses (e.g., greater than 2% as in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>A and <b>4</b>B</figref>), the processor <b>160</b> may generally cause the local portion of the system <b>100</b> to operate in lower power mode, thereby limiting transmissions initiated by the communications module <b>180</b> to only pre-defined &#x201c;advertising mode&#x201d; intervals. However, upon the product level sensor <b>140</b> indicating that the 2% remaining threshold has been met as in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>C</figref> (or upon the occurrence of another high priority event), the processor <b>160</b> may cause the communications module <b>180</b> to initiate a pairing (e.g., with a remote wireless communication interface) so as to enable a notification to be provided to the remote computing device <b>130</b>, indicating the remaining inventory (or other desirable data, such as a low battery capacity in response to a high priority event indicating a low battery). Likewise, in various embodiments, the processor <b>160</b> may cause the communications module <b>180</b> to send a message comprising product level data upon any occurrence of the sensor <b>140</b> indicating that the time-of-flight has decreased to a duration equal to or less than a certain threshold (e.g., &#x394;t<sub>1 </sub>of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>A</figref>), thereby indicating that a new roll has been mounted on the spindle <b>118</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0097">In addition to or as an alternative to maintaining the communications module <b>180</b> in a low or no power state during the low power mode of operation of system <b>100</b> as discussed above, the processor <b>160</b> itself may be maintained in a relatively low power state, for example, between intermittent determinations of whether there is a need for service. By way of example, rather than determining substantially continuously whether a proximity product level sensor <b>140</b> indicates a need for a replacement roll, the processor <b>160</b> may be configured to activate the product level sensor <b>140</b> at only pre-defined sampling intervals in order to preserve battery life. In order to avoid the roll becoming totally empty, however, it may be preferred that the intervals between samplings is shorter than the intervals between &#x201c;advertising&#x201d; messages indicating continued functionality as discussed above. By way of example, the processor <b>160</b> may be configured to generally remain in a low power state between samplings of the state of the product level sensor at least once every 15 minutes (e.g., every 10 minutes, every 5 minutes, etc.).</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0098">It will also be appreciated in light of the present teachings that the intervals between samplings can also be adjusted based on the determined product level. With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>A-C</figref>, for example, the processor <b>160</b> may cause a first interval between time-of-flight samplings to occur until it is determined that that the roll has been depleted below a first threshold (e.g., &#x2dc;50% as in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>A</figref>) as it is unlikely that the roll could be depleted within that first interval. However, upon the processor <b>160</b> determining that the roll has been depleted below this first threshold, the frequency of sampling by the product level sensor <b>140</b> could increase such that the interval is decreased to a second interval that is shorter than the first interval. Likewise, upon the processor <b>160</b> determining that the roll has been further depleted below this second threshold (e.g., &#x2dc;20% as in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>B</figref>), the frequency of sampling by the product level sensor <b>140</b> could increase further (or operate substantially continuously) as the roll becomes almost fully depleted.</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0099">Additionally or alternatively, the processor <b>160</b> may, in some embodiments, be configured to intermittently check the status of charge remaining on the one or more batteries within the housing <b>102</b>. Though a battery status check may be performed according to the same pre-defined interval, if any, as sampling the product level sensor, pre-defined intervals between checking battery life may also be different (e.g., longer) than intervals between checking whether sheet product inventory has fallen below a threshold. By way of example, because it may be less likely that the one or more batteries within the housing <b>102</b> could reach a critically-low level while operating the system <b>100</b> in &#x201c;low power&#x201d; mode, the processor <b>160</b> may be configured to sample the battery charge remaining at less frequent intervals (e.g., once every several hours).</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0100">As noted above, the product level sensor can be disposed at a variety of locations within a dispenser or a housing for coupling thereto. For example, in certain aspects the housing <b>102</b> may be fixed (e.g., to an inner surface of the dispenser <b>10</b>) such that the product level sensor <b>140</b> is disposed behind the spindle <b>118</b> relative to a user (e.g., toward the rear of the dispenser <b>10</b>) so as to restrict access to the sensor <b>140</b> to prevent tampering with the light source <b>140</b><i>a </i>or detector <b>140</b><i>b </i>as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>A</figref>, for example. While it may additionally be preferable to fix the example housing <b>102</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>A-B</figref> to prevent unauthorized removal of the electronics therewithin, the housing and/or product level sensor may alternatively be configured to rotate along with the sheet product roll and/or spindle according to various aspects of the present teachings.</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0101">With reference now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, another example product level tracking system <b>500</b> according to some embodiments of the present invention is depicted. The system <b>500</b> is similar to the system <b>100</b> discussed above with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>A-B</figref>, for example, in that the system <b>500</b> also includes a housing <b>502</b> containing a proximity product level sensor <b>540</b>, as well as a processor and a communications module (not shown), the communications module configured to be in wireless communication with a remote computing device as otherwise discussed herein. As noted above, a housing for containing various components of systems in accordance with the present teachings may have a variety of shapes and sizes configured so as to enable coupling to a sheet product dispenser, such as a previously-installed dispenser, without interfering with the operation therewith. For example, whereas in the example embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>A-B</figref>, the housing <b>102</b> has a flat portion that substantially matches the profile of the front of the dispenser <b>10</b>, the example housing <b>502</b> comprises a substantially circular inner plate <b>502</b><i>c </i>and outer cover <b>502</b><i>a </i>and inner plate <b>502</b><i>c </i>according to differences in the shape and/or size of the dispenser to which the housing <b>502</b> is to be coupled. The housing <b>502</b> also differs from housing <b>102</b> discussed above in that the housing <b>502</b> is configured to be coupled to the dispenser <b>10</b> such that it may rotate along with a sheet product roll mounted on the spindle <b>518</b>. By way of example, the outer plate <b>502</b><i>a </i>may comprise a protrusion on its outer surface (not shown) that is configured to engage and rotate within the installation features <b>16</b> of the dispenser <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0107" num="0102">In addition to providing security features to the housing <b>502</b> (e.g., tethers or additional security sensors), it may also be preferable to include one or more additional features to help ensure the accuracy of the proximity measurement during rotation of the product level sensor <b>540</b>. By way of example, such features in accordance with the present teachings may take into account changes in ambient light as the product level sensor <b>540</b> rotates in and out of the dispenser housing by tracking the position of the product level sensor <b>540</b> relative to the dispenser <b>10</b>. Such an ambient light sensor could be located near the detector of the product level sensor <b>540</b> such that any detected ambient light could be taken into account by processor when analyzing the signal from the detector. Similarly, a gyroscope or tilt sensor could be provided to determine the orientation of the detector as the housing <b>502</b> rotates, with the known orientation being used to adjust the signal from the detector. Alternatively, because many dispensers are metal (or include metal parts), changes in capacitance can be detected by a capacitor sensor mounted near the detector as the capacitor sensor moves into or out of the dispenser.</p>
<p id="p-0108" num="0103">With reference now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b>A-B</figref>, an exemplary orientation sensor suitable for use with the system <b>500</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is depicted. As shown, a magnet <b>542</b><i>b </i>is disposed within the dispenser <b>12</b>, while an additional sensor <b>542</b><i>a </i>capable of sensing the magnetic field generated by the magnet <b>542</b><i>b </i>is disposed within the housing <b>502</b> of the system <b>500</b>. Because the relative orientation of the sensor <b>542</b><i>b </i>and the product level sensor <b>540</b> are known, the position of the product level sensor <b>540</b> can be determined and the effect of the ambient light can be taken into account. By way of example, the sensor <b>542</b><i>a </i>could indicate that the product level sensor <b>540</b> is within the dispenser <b>12</b> as in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref> (low ambient light conditions) or outside of the dispenser <b>12</b> as in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>B</figref> (high ambient light conditions). It will be appreciated that though <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b>A-B</figref> depict the sensor <b>542</b><i>a </i>positioned near the product level sensor <b>540</b> as being capable of detecting the position relative to the magnet <b>542</b><i>b </i>(e.g., Hall effect sensor), the orientation sensor <b>542</b><i>a </i>associated with the rotating housing <b>502</b> could instead detect capacitance changes, orientation (e.g., an accelerometer), or even ambient light itself to account for such changes in orientation of the housing <b>502</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0109" num="0104">With reference now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>7</b>A-D</figref>, an example product level tracking system <b>700</b> according to some embodiments of the present invention is depicted. As discussed otherwise herein, the system <b>700</b> can be incorporated into a newly-installed sheet product dispenser <b>710</b> and/or can be retrofitted into a previously installed dispenser to enable automatic tracking functionality to be added thereto. The example product level tracking system <b>700</b> is similar to the system of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>A-B</figref> in that it comprises a housing <b>702</b> that can be secured to the inner surface of the dispenser <b>710</b> and contains a communications module configured to be in wireless communication with a remote computing device (not shown). As discussed otherwise herein, the housing <b>702</b> may include various coupling features (e.g., via screws, brackets, adhesive, etc.) to enable it to be coupled to a newly-installed dispenser <b>710</b> and/or retrofitted within the compartment of a previously-installed dispenser, for example. Additionally, the housing <b>702</b> may comprise a spindle-receiving cavity so as to secure a spindle thereto.</p>
<p id="p-0110" num="0105">The system <b>700</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>7</b>A-D</figref> also includes a proximity product level sensor <b>740</b> and processor (not shown) that may be configured to determine the quantity of product remaining on the roll via non-contact optical or acoustic techniques for determining proximity, for example, based on the distance between the sensor's light source and the circumference of a roll mounted on the spindle <b>18</b> as discussed above. As best shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>B</figref> (the cover plate and spindle <b>718</b> are removed for clarity), the sensor <b>740</b> is disposed behind the spindle <b>718</b> so as to prevent tampering therewith.</p>
<p id="p-0111" num="0106"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>7</b>C-D</figref> depict a rear view of the dispenser <b>710</b>. Retrofitting a previously existing dispenser could be accomplished, for example, by coupling housing <b>702</b> thereto, or one could install the entire depicted dispenser <b>710</b> within a hole in a wall or a partition, for example. In various aspects, a user of the system <b>700</b> could replace a roll or otherwise access the housing <b>712</b> or its components by opening the rear cover <b>717</b> (e.g., connected via a hinge). Should service of the dispenser <b>710</b> be required, a user could remove the dispenser <b>710</b> from its installed location and/or open the rear cover <b>717</b> to access the components of the housing <b>702</b>, which can be secured by a lock <b>713</b> to prevent unauthorized access.</p>
<p id="p-0112" num="0107">While the above-described example systems generally utilize proximity product level sensors, product level tracking systems in accordance with various aspects of the present teachings can additionally or alternatively utilize optical-, ultrasonic-, infrared-, acceleration-, rotation-, weight-, and/or mechanical-based product level sensors, etc. to determine product level. For example, in certain embodiments, the product level sensor may comprise a mechanical product level sensor that interacts directly with the sheet product as it is dispensed from the roll in order to reduce the consumption of electrical energy (e.g., to preserve battery life). In various example embodiments, mechanical-based product level sensors may comprise a button, switch, toggle, lever, etc. having at least a portion that may be configured to be disposed in contact with the sheet product and to move as the quantity of sheet product on the roll changes.</p>
<p id="p-0113" num="0108"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>8</b>A-C</figref> illustrate an example product level tracking system <b>800</b> according to some embodiments of the present invention utilizing a mechanical product level sensor <b>840</b> for enabling automated tracking of sheet product (e.g., tissue paper) remaining on a roll supported by a sheet product dispenser like that of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>. As above, the system <b>800</b> may comprise a housing <b>802</b> configured to be coupled to the dispenser <b>10</b> and a remote computing device <b>830</b> configured to be in wireless communication with a communications module <b>880</b> within the housing <b>802</b>. With specific reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>8</b>A</figref> (shown as an exploded view) and <b>8</b>B, the housing <b>802</b> comprises an outer plate <b>802</b><i>a </i>and a cover <b>802</b><i>c </i>providing a space therebetween within which a product level sensor <b>840</b>, a processor <b>860</b>, and/or a communications module <b>880</b> may at least partially be disposed, the housing <b>802</b> configured to be disposed within the dispenser <b>10</b> in a location that allows for sensing the sheet product remaining on a roll (as discussed in detail below) without restricting rotation of a product roll mounted on the spindle <b>18</b>. For example, the outer plate <b>802</b><i>a </i>may be fixedly coupled to the inner surface <b>14</b><i>a </i>of the compartment <b>14</b> (e.g., via screws, brackets, adhesive, etc. for mounting the housing <b>802</b> to the dispenser <b>10</b>) such that it does not rotate with the spindle <b>18</b> and/or sheet product roll, for example. In some aspects, the outer plate <b>802</b><i>a </i>may comprise a protrusion on its outer surface that is configured to be secured within an installation hole <b>16</b> of the dispenser <b>10</b>, while a spindle-receiving cavity similar in configuration to the installation feature <b>16</b> may be formed in the housing <b>802</b> (e.g., in the outer plate <b>802</b><i>a </i>and/or the cover <b>802</b><i>c</i>) so as to receive the spindle's installation protrusions. However, in the example depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>8</b>A-C</figref>, the outer plate <b>802</b><i>a </i>may comprise a hole <b>806</b><i>a </i>that surrounds the dispenser's installation holes <b>16</b> and through which at least a portion of the spindle <b>18</b> may extend for coupling thereto. Likewise, the inner plate <b>802</b><i>c </i>comprises a corresponding hole <b>806</b><i>c </i>through which at least a portion of the spindle <b>18</b> may extend.</p>
<p id="p-0114" num="0109">As discussed above with reference to housing <b>102</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>A-C</figref>, the housing <b>802</b> may likewise have a variety of shapes and sizes, but may generally be shaped and sized to fit within the dispenser <b>10</b> to be retrofitted and may be configured to be coupled to the dispenser at a location that does not interfere with the dispensing of sheet product <b>22</b> therefrom. For example, in the example embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>8</b>A-C</figref>, the cross-sectional shape of the housing <b>802</b> is in the form of a truncated circle such that the flat portion of the cross-sectional shape can be disposed downward toward the bottom of the dispenser <b>10</b> such that the spindle <b>18</b>, its installation feature, and/or housing <b>802</b> may move within the sheet product dispenser <b>10</b> along a track or another auto-repositioning feature to allow a spare roll secured within the dispenser to be accessed. For example, the flat portion may face downward so as to rest on a bottom portion of the track such that the spindle <b>18</b> is positioned close to the bottom of the track, thereby allowing the replacement roll to drop down in the track to be accessible by a user (e.g., the track may be designed such that positioning of the spindle <b>18</b> at the bottom of the track is necessary to release the replacement roll (e.g., on a second spindle (not shown)) such that it falls into a dispensing position). In addition, in some example embodiments, the cross-sectional shape of the housing <b>802</b> can be configured to match the profile of the front of the dispenser <b>10</b> when installed (e.g., so as not to protrude therefrom), thereby reducing potential interference with operation and/or preventing a user from tampering with various components of the retrofitted system <b>800</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0115" num="0110">Additionally, housing <b>802</b> exhibits a low-profile so as to be unobtrusively retrofitted into the previously-installed dispenser <b>10</b>. For example, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>8</b>A-C</figref>, the depicted housing <b>802</b> comprises a relatively thin sidewall <b>802</b><i>b </i>extending from the outer plate <b>802</b><i>a </i>such that the compartment defined within the housing <b>802</b> is of minimal thickness for containing the various components of the product level tracking system <b>800</b> as otherwise discussed herein without obstructing the dispensing of sheet product from the dispenser <b>10</b>. In some aspects, retrofitting a dispenser <b>10</b> may encompass utilizing a replacement spindle <b>18</b> (e.g., having a reduced length) and/or a roll <b>20</b> having a reduced width to accommodate the housing <b>802</b>, but preferably, no substantial modifications to the dispenser <b>10</b> would be required for coupling of the housing <b>802</b> thereto.</p>
<p id="p-0116" num="0111">In some embodiments, the housing <b>802</b> may comprise one or more mounting features that enable secure attachment to the sheet product dispenser <b>10</b>, such as to the inner surface <b>14</b><i>a </i>of the compartment <b>14</b> or a track or other repositioning feature. In some embodiments, the housing <b>802</b> may be configured with one or more lock features that are configured to lock the outer plate <b>802</b><i>a </i>to the inner plate <b>802</b><i>c </i>and/or the sheet product dispenser (such as to the inner surface <b>14</b><i>a</i>). In such a regard, some embodiments may be enabled to prevent unauthorized access to the one or more components (e.g., the product level sensor <b>840</b>, the processor <b>860</b>, the communications module <b>880</b>, the batteries, etc.). In some such embodiments, the maintainer may have a key that unlocks the lock features to enable access within the housing <b>802</b>, such as to replace the batteries.</p>
<p id="p-0117" num="0112">Though the depicted housing <b>802</b> is configured to at least partially contain each of the product level sensor <b>840</b>, the processor <b>860</b>, the communications module <b>880</b>, and a plurality of batteries, these example components need not be contained within a single housing or within a housing at all. Rather, components of the product level tracking system <b>800</b> that are coupled to the dispenser <b>10</b> can be disposed at a variety of one or more distributed locations within the dispenser <b>10</b> so as not to interfere with operation thereof. By way of example, electrically conductive contacts for batteries may be contained within the internal storage location within the housing <b>12</b> secured via the lock <b>13</b> of the sheet product dispenser <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0118" num="0113">As noted above, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>8</b>A-C</figref> illustrate an example product level tracking system <b>800</b> utilizing a mechanical product level sensor <b>840</b>, which comprises a switch configured to extend from the cover <b>802</b><i>c </i>into contact with a side of a tissue paper roll mounted on the spindle <b>18</b> when the housing <b>802</b> of the tracking system <b>800</b> is coupled to an inner surface of the dispenser <b>10</b>. Depending on the quantity of tissue paper on the roll, the switch <b>840</b> may be moved between a first position and one or more other positions that is different from the first position. By way of example, the switch <b>840</b> may have two states, a first position (state) when a quantity of sheet product is above a threshold for refill and a second position (state) when the quantity of sheet product is depleted below the threshold. In such aspects, the processor <b>860</b> may be able to determine the state of the switch <b>840</b>, for example, based on a change to a product level signal generated by the product level sensor when the switch <b>840</b> moves between the first position and second position. Though switch <b>840</b> is depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b>C</figref> extending from the cover <b>802</b><i>c </i>from a location above the spindle <b>18</b>, it will be appreciated that switch <b>840</b> could extend from the housing <b>802</b> at various locations around the spindle <b>18</b> and be in contact with the sheet product so as to move as the quantity of sheet product on the roll changes as discussed otherwise herein. For example, in certain embodiments, the switch <b>840</b> may preferably extend from behind the spindle <b>18</b> relative to prevent inadvertent actuation and/or tampering with switch <b>840</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0119" num="0114">An example switch <b>840</b> that may be used with the tracking system of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>8</b>A-C</figref> is shown in additional schematic detail in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>9</b>A-B</figref>. Switch <b>840</b> comprises a contact surface <b>842</b> configured to be disposed in contact with the side of a roll <b>20</b> mounted on a spindle <b>18</b> extending through holes <b>806</b><i>a,c </i>of the outer and inner plates <b>802</b><i>a,c, </i>respectively. Contact surface <b>842</b> represents the innermost surface of a body <b>846</b> that is biased, such as due to one or more springs <b>844</b>, to extend from the interior of the housing <b>802</b> through the inner plate <b>802</b><i>c. </i>As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b>A</figref>, when the roll <b>20</b> has sufficient sheet product thereon, the contact surface <b>842</b> may be in contact with the sides of a plurality of sheets of the sheet product, which is effective to compress the spring(s) <b>844</b> from their biased state. However, when the quantity of sheet product remaining on the roll <b>20</b> is depleted beyond the threshold (R<sub>threshold</sub>) represented by the inner radial surface of the contact surface <b>842</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b>B</figref>, the spring(s) <b>844</b> extend such that the body <b>846</b> moves toward its biased configuration. Electrically-conductive contacts <b>848</b> coupled to the body <b>846</b> likewise move from the retracted position, until contacting one or more electrodes <b>803</b> of the inner plate <b>802</b><i>c. </i>By electrically coupling the electrically-conductive contacts <b>848</b> to a power source (e.g., a battery within the housing <b>802</b>) and the electrodes <b>803</b> to the processor <b>860</b>, for example, movement of the contacts <b>848</b> into contact with the electrodes <b>803</b> may close an electrical circuit therebetween, thereby providing an electrical signal to the processor <b>860</b> indicating that the switch <b>840</b> has moved from its first position (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b>A</figref>) to its second position (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b>B</figref>) and signifying that the roll <b>20</b> has a remaining inventory of sheet product that is less than the threshold quantity. Notably, while described with respect to the tracking system of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>8</b>A-C</figref>, the example product level sensor <b>840</b> may be used with other example product level tracking systems described herein.</p>
<p id="p-0120" num="0115">With reference again to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>8</b>A-C</figref>, the processor <b>860</b>, upon receiving the electrical signal from the switch <b>840</b> indicating the product level is below the threshold quantity (R<sub>threshold</sub>), may be configured to cause the communications module <b>880</b> to send information regarding the low remaining inventory of product to a remote computing device <b>830</b> as otherwise discussed herein. Additionally, as discussed in detail above, the communications module <b>880</b> may be configured to enable direct or indirect communication to an external system (e.g., a remote computing device <b>830</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0121" num="0116">In some embodiments, the system <b>800</b> is configured to receive sensor data from the product level sensor <b>840</b> and, through various logic, determine product level data indicative of the quantity of sheet product on the sheet product roll, for example, whether the product level sensor <b>840</b> in a first position (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b>A</figref>) or a second position (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b>B</figref>) signifying whether the roll <b>20</b> has a remaining inventory of sheet product that is above or below a threshold quantity.</p>
<p id="p-0122" num="0117">Electrical energy for one or more components of the product level tracking system <b>800</b> may be provided in a variety of manners such as by hard-wiring or plugging the components into an external power source, such as an alternating current (&#x201c;AC&#x201d;) power source (e.g., a 120V, <b>60</b> Hz wall outlet), a solar power source, or any other alternative external power source as may be appropriate for an application. However, in some embodiments as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b>A and <b>8</b>B</figref>, the housing <b>802</b> may contain one or more battery compartments <b>807</b> having a pair of electrically-conductive contacts <b>807</b><i>a,b </i>for electrically coupling to a battery. As depicted, the housing <b>802</b> includes two battery compartments <b>107</b>, which together contain four sets of electrical contacts <b>807</b><i>a,b </i>for coupling to anodes and cathodes of four &#x201c;AAA&#x201d; cell batteries (not shown) in order to energize one or more of the product level sensor <b>840</b>, the processor <b>860</b>, and the communications module <b>880</b>, as otherwise discussed herein. It will be appreciated that more or fewer batteries (of different sizes and capacities) may be utilized in inventory tracking systems in accordance with the present teachings based, for example, on the expected energy consumption and space constraints compelled by a previously-installed sheet product dispenser to which the inventory tracking system <b>800</b> is to be coupled. Further, it will be appreciated that the batteries need not be contained within the housing <b>802</b> as depicted, but may instead be located at another location as long as in electrical contact with one or more components of the product level tracking system <b>800</b> requiring electrical power.</p>
<p id="p-0123" num="0118">With reference now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref>, another example product level tracking system <b>1000</b> according to some embodiments of the present invention is depicted. The system <b>1000</b> is similar to the system <b>800</b> discussed above with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b>A</figref>, for example, in that the system <b>1000</b> also includes a housing <b>1002</b> containing a product level sensor <b>1040</b>, a processor <b>1060</b>, and a communications module <b>1080</b>, the communications module <b>1020</b> configured to be in wireless communication with a remote computing device <b>1030</b>. As noted above, a housing for containing various components of systems in accordance with the present teachings may have a variety of shapes and sizes configured so as to enable coupling to a sheet product dispenser, such as a previously-installed dispenser, without interfering with the operation therewith. For example, whereas in the example embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>8</b>A-C</figref>, the housing <b>802</b> has a flat portion that substantially matches the profile of the bottom of the dispenser <b>10</b>, the example housing <b>1002</b> comprises a substantially circular outer plate <b>1002</b><i>a </i>and inner plate <b>1002</b><i>c </i>according to differences in the shape and/or size of the dispenser to which the housing <b>1002</b> is to be coupled. The housing <b>1002</b> also differs from housing <b>802</b> discussed above in that the outer surface of the outer plate <b>1002</b><i>a </i>may be configured to fixedly engage the installation holes <b>16</b> of the dispenser <b>10</b>. By way of example, the outer plate <b>1002</b><i>a </i>may comprise a protrusion on its outer surface (not shown) that is configured to be at least partially secured within the installation features <b>16</b>, while the inner surface of the outer plate <b>1002</b><i>a </i>may comprise a spindle-receiving cavity <b>1006</b><i>a </i>for rotatably coupling to installation protrusions of a spindle <b>18</b> extending through the hole <b>1006</b><i>c </i>in the inner plate <b>1002</b><i>c. </i></p>
<p id="p-0124" num="0119">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref>, the wireless communications module <b>1080</b> is also configured to be indirectly coupled to a remote computing device <b>1030</b> (e.g., a remote server, a base station, the maintainer's mobile phone, etc.), which receives a notification of when the product level becomes depleted such that a replacement role is (or is soon to be) required, for example. By way of example, in the exemplary system of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref>, the communications module <b>480</b> may transmit product level data to a router or smart hub <b>1025</b> via utilizing a WiFi (or other short range wireless protocol), which can transmit the data to a cloud server <b>1028</b> (e.g., via the Internet), which can provide a notification to the user of the mobile phone <b>1030</b> (e.g., via the Internet or a cellular network).</p>
<p id="p-0125" num="0120">An example product level sensor <b>1040</b>, such as for use with the product level tracking system of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref> is depicted in additional schematic detail in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>11</b>A-B</figref>. As shown, product level sensor <b>1040</b> comprises a lever <b>1046</b> that is configured to rotate about pivot <b>1045</b>. The lever <b>1046</b> comprises a contact surface <b>1042</b> configured to be disposed in contact with the side of a roll <b>20</b> mounted on a spindle <b>18</b> extending through holes <b>1006</b><i>c </i>of the inner plates <b>1002</b><i>c, </i>with the spindle installation protrusions <b>19</b><i>a </i>being retained within the spindle receiving-cavity <b>1006</b><i>a </i>of the outer plate <b>1002</b><i>a. </i>In its biased state and when the quantity of sheet product is below a threshold quantity (R<sub>threshold</sub>) as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b>B</figref>, the contact surface <b>1042</b> of the lever <b>1046</b> is configured to extend outwardly away from the inner plate <b>1002</b><i>c. </i>When a new roll has been mounted on a spindle or when sufficient sheet product remains thereon, however, the sheet product exerts a force on the contact surface <b>1042</b> such that the lever <b>1046</b> maintains the position shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b>A</figref> in which an electrically-conductive contact <b>1048</b> is not in contact with an electrode <b>1003</b> of the inner plate <b>1002</b><i>a</i>. By electrically coupling the electrode <b>1003</b> to a power source (e.g., a battery within the housing <b>1002</b>) and the electrically-conductive contact <b>1048</b> to the processor <b>1060</b>, for example, a circuit may be opened or closed depending on whether the quantity of product on the roll is above or below the threshold at which a need for replacement is indicated. Notably, while described with respect to the product level tracking system of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref>, the example product level sensor <b>1040</b> may be used with other example tracking systems described herein.</p>
<p id="p-0126" num="0121">With reference now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>12</b>A-B</figref>, another example product level tracking system <b>1200</b> according to some embodiments of the present invention is depicted. The system <b>1200</b> is similar to the systems discussed above, for example, in that the system <b>1200</b> comprises a housing <b>1202</b> configured to at least partially contain a product level sensor <b>1240</b>, a processor <b>1260</b>, a communications module <b>1280</b>, and one or more batteries <b>1208</b> (which can provide power to components within the housing via an electrical contact) and can be coupled to a sheet product dispenser, such as a previously-installed sheet product dispenser <b>10</b>. However, whereas the housing <b>802</b> of the system <b>100</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> and the housing <b>1002</b> of the system <b>1000</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref> are configured to be fixedly coupled to the dispenser such that they do not rotate upon rotation of the spindle and/or roll, the housing <b>1202</b> is configured to be disposed within a bore of the roll of sheet product as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>12</b>B</figref> such that the housing <b>1202</b> rotates therewith. In particular, the elongate housing <b>1202</b> may comprise one or more compartments such that one or more of the product level sensor <b>1240</b>, the processor <b>1260</b>, the communications module <b>1280</b>, and the one or more batteries <b>1208</b> may at least partially be disposed within the bore upon mounting a product roll <b>20</b> on the housing. Moreover, each end of the housing <b>1202</b> may comprise installation protrusions <b>1219</b><i>a </i>that are configured to extend into installation features <b>16</b> of the dispenser <b>10</b>, for example. In various embodiments, the housing <b>1202</b> may be extendable from a first retracted configuration having a reduced length to a second extended configuration to allow the housing to be secured within an installation feature <b>16</b> of the dispenser <b>10</b>. By way of example, a spring (not shown) within one or both of the protrusions <b>1219</b><i>a </i>may bias a telescoping portion of the protrusions <b>1219</b><i>a </i>outward to allow the housing <b>1202</b> to be extended and compressed along its longitudinal axis.</p>
<p id="p-0127" num="0122">An example product level sensor <b>1240</b>, such as for use with the product level tracking system of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>12</b>A-B</figref>, is depicted in additional schematic detail in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>13</b>A-B</figref>. Product level sensor <b>1240</b> is similar to product level sensor <b>1040</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref>, but differs in that the lever <b>1246</b> extends through a circumferential wall of the housing <b>1202</b> and is configured to rotate with the roll <b>20</b>. Nonetheless, the lever <b>1246</b> likewise comprises a contact surface <b>1242</b> configured to be disposed in contact with the side of a roll <b>20</b> mounted on the housing <b>1202</b>. The lever <b>1246</b> is configured to be biased in the position of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>13</b>B</figref> (e.g., due to the force of one of more springs <b>1244</b>). However, when a new roll has been mounted on the housing <b>1202</b> or when sheet product above a threshold quantity remains thereon, the roll is configured to rotate the lever <b>1246</b> about the pivot <b>1245</b> to the position of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>13</b>A</figref> in which an electrically-conductive contact <b>1248</b> is not in contact with an electrode (not shown). When the quantity of sheet product is below a threshold quantity (R<sub>threshold</sub>) as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>13</b>B</figref>, the lever <b>1246</b> may rotate about pivot <b>1245</b> such that the electrically-conductive contact <b>1248</b> may close a circuit, for example, thereby indicating to the processor <b>1260</b> that a replacement roll is needed. Notably, while described with respect to the product level tracking system of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>12</b>A-B</figref>, the example product level sensor <b>1240</b> may be used with other example tracking systems described herein.</p>
<p id="p-0128" num="0123">With reference now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>14</b>A-B</figref>, another example product level tracking system <b>1400</b> according to some embodiments of the present invention is depicted. The system <b>1400</b> is similar to the system <b>1000</b> discussed above with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>10</b>A-B</figref>, for example, in that the system <b>1000</b> comprises a housing <b>1402</b> that is configured to rotate with a sheet product roll <b>20</b> mounted thereon, but differs in that the compartment of the housing <b>802</b> within which a product level sensor <b>1440</b>, a processor (not shown), a communications module (not shown), and a battery <b>1408</b> may at least partially be contained is not configured to be disposed in the bore of the sheet product roll. Rather, as best shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>14</b>A</figref>, the compartment of the housing <b>1402</b> is configured to be disposed between a side of the roll <b>20</b> and an inner surface of the dispenser <b>10</b> when mounted within the dispenser. Whereas the above-described example embodiment of the housing <b>1202</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>12</b>A-B</figref> is depicted as being configured to receive one or more &#x201c;AAA&#x201d; cell batteries in order to energize one or more of the product level sensor, processor, and communications module, the size of the compartment of the housing <b>1402</b> may be constrained such that the compartment may comprise one or more electrical contacts for coupling to a battery having a lower profile (e.g., a button cell such as a CR2032 battery as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>14</b>B</figref> by way of non-limiting example). In particular, the compartment of housing <b>1402</b> is defined by an outer plate <b>1402</b><i>a, </i>an inner plate <b>1402</b><i>c, </i>and a sidewall <b>1402</b><i>b </i>extending therebetween. The outer plate <b>1402</b> comprises an installation protrusion <b>1419</b><i>a </i>extending therefrom, while the inner plate <b>1402</b><i>c </i>may be coupled to one of two telescoping elongate body portions <b>818</b><i>a,b </i>that enable the housing <b>802</b> to be compressed and extended along the bore's longitudinal axis. For example, one or more springs disposed within the elongate body portions <b>1418</b><i>a,b </i>may bias the housing <b>1402</b> into an extended state. As such, a user may compress the housing <b>1402</b> to enable insertion of installation protrusions <b>1419</b><i>a,b </i>into the corresponding installation holes <b>16</b> on the inner surface <b>14</b><i>a of the compartment <b>14</b>. </i></p>
<p id="p-0129" num="0124">Because the spindle-shaped housings <b>1202</b> and <b>1402</b> are configured for removable mounting to a dispenser and may contain the more expensive electronic components relative to various other systems in accordance with the present teachings, it may be preferable in some embodiments to include one or more additional security features such as a tether or additional sensor to indicate when authorized removal has occurred to prevent loss and/or swapping from one stall to another.</p>
<p id="p-0130" num="0125">Due to the constraints on the size of batteries that may be disposed within embodiments of housings as disclosed herein, various embodiments may preferably be configured to conserve the limited electrical supply as discussed above. Moreover, rather than rely on relatively high-power product level sensors, some systems in accordance with the present teachings may utilize a mechanical product level sensor that interacts directly with the sheet product as it is dispensed from the roll in order to reduce the consumption of electrical energy. Various example mechanical product level sensors discussed above, for example, may generally move from a first position to a second position only when the roll is in need of replacement or about to need replacement. In some such example embodiments, because movement of the product level sensor may be effective to close a circuit only upon the sheet product being depleted below a threshold level, for example, energy may generally be conserved when the product level sensor is in the first (open circuit) position. Additionally, in some embodiments, the mechanical product sensors may be configured to reset upon a replacement sheet product roll being provided to the dispenser. By way of example, the mechanical product sensor may move from the first position to the second position, thereby opening the circuit and indicating to the processor that a replacement sheet product roll has been provided.</p>
<p id="p-0131" num="0126">As above, in some example embodiments of a &#x201c;low power&#x201d; mode, the processor <b>860</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>8</b>A-C</figref>, for example, may prevent the communications module <b>180</b> from transmitting data, attempting to pair, and/or advertising with a remote computing device unless and until the processor <b>860</b> determines the occurrence of the need for a replacement roll or another &#x201c;high priority&#x201d; event such as the switch <b>840</b> being moved to the second position (e.g., indicating the need for a replacement roll), the remaining charge on the batteries being below a threshold level (e.g., below a 10% battery capacity), and/or the occurrence of any other event indicating a need for service of the portion of the system <b>800</b> coupled to the dispenser <b>10</b> (e.g., detection of a fault). Additionally, in some embodiments, the high priority events may be defined to include an indication that a previously-determined service need has been addressed, for example, when the processor <b>860</b> determines that the switch has been reset to the first position (e.g., indicating that a replacement roll has been provided) or upon the system <b>800</b> being powered up and that the remaining charge on the batteries is above a threshold level (e.g., above 50% battery capacity, indicating that batteries have been replaced). In such aspects, the example system <b>800</b> may thus consume minimal energy unless service is required and/or to provide notification that service has been provided.</p>
<p id="p-0132" num="0127">Additionally, by way of example, when the switch <b>840</b> is in the first position (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b>A</figref>) such that the roll has sufficient sheet product for one or more future uses, the processor <b>860</b> may generally cause the local portion of the system <b>800</b> to operate in lower power mode, thereby limiting transmissions initiated by the communications module <b>880</b> to only pre-defined &#x201c;advertising mode&#x201d; intervals. Upon the switch being moved to the second position (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b>B</figref>) (or upon the occurrence of another high priority event), however, the processor <b>860</b> may cause the communications module <b>880</b> to initiate a pairing (e.g., with a remote wireless communication interface) so as to enable a notification to be provided to the remote computing device <b>830</b>, indicating a state change of the switch <b>840</b> (or other desirable data, such as a low battery capacity in response to a high priority event indicating a low battery). Likewise, in various embodiments, the processor <b>860</b> may cause the communications module <b>880</b> to send a message comprising product level data upon any occurrence of the switch <b>840</b> being moved between the first and second positions. In such embodiments, for example, the mobile computing device <b>830</b> and/or a different mobile computing device may be notified upon the processor <b>860</b> determining the switch <b>840</b> has been reset from the second position (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b>B</figref>) to the first position (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b>A</figref>), thereby indicating that the roll has been refilled, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0133" num="0128">In addition to or as an alternative to maintaining the communications module <b>180</b> in a low or no power state during the low power mode of operation of system <b>800</b> as discussed above, the processor <b>860</b> itself may be maintained in a relatively low power state, for example, between intermittent determinations of whether there is a need for service as otherwise discussed herein.</p>
<p id="p-0134" num="0129">In some embodiments, multiple product level sensors may be used to determine when multiple different thresholds are met throughout the life of the product roll. For example, with reference to the system <b>1500</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>15</b></figref>, another example embodiment in accordance with the present teachings is depicted in which a plurality of mechanical product level sensors are disposed at a variety of locations in order to provide product level data relative to multiple thresholds. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>15</b></figref>, each of the example switches (e.g., first switch <b>1540</b><i>a </i>and second switch <b>940</b><i>b</i>) are similar to switch <b>840</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>9</b>A-B</figref> but differ in that they extend from the housing at different positions so as to indicate when the quantity of sheet product remaining on product roll <b>20</b> is below different thresholds. In particular, when the quantity of sheet product remaining on the product roll <b>20</b> is depleted beyond the threshold (R<sub>50</sub>%) represented by the inner radial surface of the second switch <b>1540</b><i>b, </i>the spring(s) extend such that the second switch <b>1540</b><i>b </i>moves toward its biased configuration, thereby providing an electrical signal indicating that the second switch <b>1540</b><i>b </i>has moved from its first position to its second position and signifying that the product roll <b>20</b> has approximately 50% (or less) remaining inventory of sheet product. In this regard, the second switch <b>1540</b><i>b </i>may be mounted a second radial distance D<b>2</b> away from the central bore <b>24</b>, which may correspond to the product roll <b>20</b> having 50% (or less) remaining inventory of sheet product. On the other hand, the first switch <b>1540</b><i>a </i>(like switch <b>840</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>9</b>A-B</figref>), may be mounted a second radial distance Di away from the central bore <b>24</b>, which may correspond to the product roll <b>20</b> having 10% (or less) remaining inventory of sheet product. In this regard, for example, the first switch <b>1540</b><i>a </i>may be located so as to indicate that the threshold R<sub>refill </sub>has been passed (e.g., thereby indicating that replacement product roll is needed).</p>
<p id="p-0135" num="0130">In some embodiments, depending on the desired configuration of the system, two or more product level sensors (each associated with a different threshold) may be used in accordance with the present teachings to enable a user to track the product remaining at a plurality of different levels. For example, a particular facility may want to know when the roll is &#x201c;low&#x201d; in addition to when it is &#x201c;out&#x201d; so as to be forewarned of an impending &#x201c;out&#x201d; before it happens to enable the dispenser to be restocked (e.g., before an expected high-consumption time such as halftime of a sporting event). Additionally, it will be appreciated that providing multiple product level sensors may enable the local processor or a processor associated with a remote computing device to calculate a &#x201c;rate of consumption&#x201d; related to the time between each switch threshold being passed, which may help predict when replacement of a product roll is likely to be needed. Notably, the example product level sensors <b>1540</b><i>a, </i><b>1540</b><i>b </i>may be used with any example product level tracking system described herein.</p>
<p id="p-0136" num="0131">Indeed, in some aspects, systems in accordance with the present teachings can include a product level sensor of one type (e.g., a mechanical sensor) and a product level sensor of a different type (e.g., a proximity product level sensor). With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>16</b></figref>, for example, a mechanical switch can additionally be provided as discussed above, for example, to limit the use (and thus energy consumption) of a higher-energy product level sensor until an initial threshold has been detected by the mechanical product level sensor. For example, as discussed above with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>15</b></figref>, a switch (e.g., switch <b>1540</b><i>b</i>) can be provided at or below the level capable of being measured by a time-of-flight product level sensor <b>140</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>A-<b>4</b></figref> such that power would not be provided to the time-of-flight sensor <b>140</b> until a relevant threshold is met, thereby conserving energy.</p>
<p id="p-0137" num="0132">With reference now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>16</b> and <b>17</b></figref>, some example aspects of the present teachings alternatively provide for limiting consumption of energy until the proximity product level sensor is mechanically moved from a retracted position to an extended position. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>16</b></figref>, for example, system <b>1600</b> is similar to that of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>B</figref> in that it includes a proximity product level sensor <b>1640</b> within the housing <b>1602</b>. However, rather than have a recess <b>102</b><i>d </i>through which the sensor <b>140</b> emits and detects light as in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>B</figref>, the light source and detector of sensor <b>1640</b> are instead contained within the housing <b>1602</b> until the sheet product level of the roll is below the level of the slide <b>1603</b>. While the slide <b>1603</b> containing the sensor <b>1640</b> is biased to extend away from the inner plate <b>1602</b><i>c </i>of housing <b>1602</b>, a roll having a sufficient diameter may be effective to compress the slide <b>1603</b> to its retracted position, indicating that the proximity sensor does not need power supplied thereto. Upon sufficient depletion of the sheet product inventory, however, the slide <b>1603</b> may extend to its biased configuration shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>16</b></figref> and the proximity product level sensor <b>1640</b> may be activated as otherwise discussed herein.</p>
<p id="p-0138" num="0133">The system <b>1700</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>17</b></figref> is similar to that of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>16</b></figref>, but rather than translating outwardly from the inner surface of the housing as with slide <b>1603</b>, the sensor <b>1740</b> may instead rotate out (e.g., pivot) of the housing <b>1702</b> when the inventory of the roll is below the threshold level via the action of a spring, for example.</p>
<heading id="h-0008" level="1">Example Flowchart(s)</heading>
<p id="p-0139" num="0134">Embodiments of the present invention provide methods, apparatuses and computer program products for operating example inventory tracking systems according to various embodiments described herein. Various examples of the operations performed in accordance with embodiments of the present invention will now be provided with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>18</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0140" num="0135"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>18</b></figref> illustrates a flowchart according to an example method for operating an example product level tracking system according to an example embodiment. The operations illustrated in and described with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>18</b></figref> may, for example, be performed by, with the assistance of, and/or under the control of one or more of the components of example product level tracking systems described herein, such as systems <b>100</b>, <b>500</b>, <b>700</b>, <b>800</b>, <b>1000</b>, <b>1200</b>, <b>1400</b>, <b>1500</b>, <b>1600</b>, and <b>1700</b>. Such an example method <b>1800</b> provides for efficient use of electrical energy (e.g., to preserve battery life), while still providing appropriate data to the remote computing device.</p>
<p id="p-0141" num="0136">The method <b>1800</b> may include setting/resetting a timer for determining expiration of a predefined interval at operation <b>1802</b>. Operation <b>1804</b> illustrates an example of a continuous check as to whether a High Priority Event has occurred.</p>
<p id="p-0142" num="0137">If a High Priority Event occurs, such as described herein, the method <b>1800</b> proceeds to operation <b>1806</b> where a data signal is sent to a remote computing device (e.g., a paired communication mode may be utilized and data, such as product level data, may be transmitted to the remote computing device). After such communication is sent, the method <b>1800</b> may return to operation <b>1802</b> to reset the timer.</p>
<p id="p-0143" num="0138">If there is not a detection of a High Priority Event, the method <b>1800</b> proceeds to operation <b>1808</b> to check whether the timer has expired. If the timer has not expired, the method <b>1800</b> returns to operation <b>1804</b> to continue the checking loop. However, if the timer expires or has expired, the method <b>1000</b> initiates a &#x201c;heartbeat&#x201d; communication at operation <b>1810</b>. In this regard, the &#x201c;heartbeat&#x201d; communication may include transmitting data to a remote computing device to indicate that the product level tracking system is, for example, still operating. Such a communication may utilize any communication mode, such as advertising mode or paired mode as described herein, and may transmit any type of data (e.g., a device identifier, etc.). After such communication is sent, the method <b>1800</b> may return to operation <b>1802</b> to reset the timer.</p>
<p id="p-0144" num="0139"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>18</b></figref> illustrates an example flowchart of a system, method, and computer program product according to various example embodiments described herein. It will be understood that each block of the flowcharts, and combinations of blocks in the flowcharts, may be implemented by various means, such as hardware and/or a computer program product comprising one or more computer-readable mediums having computer readable program instructions stored thereon. For example, one or more of the procedures described herein may be embodied by computer program instructions of a computer program product. In this regard, the computer program product(s) which embody the procedures described herein may be stored by, for example, the memory and executed by, for example, a processor such as described herein. As will be appreciated, any such computer program product may be loaded onto a computer or other programmable apparatus to produce a machine, such that the computer program product including the instructions which execute on the computer or other programmable apparatus creates means for implementing the functions specified in the flowchart block(s). Further, the computer program product may comprise one or more non-transitory computer-readable mediums on which the computer program instructions may be stored such that the one or more computer-readable memories can direct a computer or other programmable device to cause a series of operations to be performed on the computer or other programmable apparatus to produce a computer-implemented process such that the instructions which execute on the computer or other programmable apparatus implement the functions specified in the flowchart block(s).</p>
<heading id="h-0009" level="1">Conclusion</heading>
<p id="p-0145" num="0140">Many modifications and other embodiments of the inventions set forth herein may come to mind to one skilled in the art to which these inventions pertain having the benefit of the teachings presented in the foregoing descriptions and the associated drawings. Therefore, it is to be understood that the embodiments of the invention are not to be limited to the specific embodiments disclosed and that modifications and other embodiments are intended to be included within the scope of the invention. Moreover, although the foregoing descriptions and the associated drawings describe example embodiments in the context of certain example combinations of elements and/or functions, it should be appreciated that different combinations of elements and/or functions may be provided by alternative embodiments without departing from the scope of the invention. In this regard, for example, different combinations of elements and/or functions than those explicitly described above are also contemplated within the scope of the invention. Although specific terms are employed herein, they are used in a generic and descriptive sense only and not for purposes of limitation.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00001" nb-file="US20230225570A1-20230720-M00001.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00001" he="5.25mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US20230225570A1-20230720-M00001.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00002" nb-file="US20230225570A1-20230720-M00002.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00002" he="5.25mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US20230225570A1-20230720-M00002.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A system for providing automatic product level tracking functionality to a sheet product roll dispenser, the system comprising:
<claim-text>a product level sensor configured to move from a first position to a second position when a quantity of sheet product on a sheet product roll mounted within the sheet product dispenser is depleted below a threshold quantity;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a communications module configured to transmit product level data to a remote computing device based on a determination that the product level sensor moved to the second position, wherein the product level data is indicative of the quantity of sheet product on the sheet product roll; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an electrically conductive contact configured to be in contact with a terminal of one or more batteries for providing electrical power to at least one of the product level sensor and the communications module.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the system is configured to be coupled to the sheet product roll dispenser while the sheet product roll dispenser is installed on one of a wall or a partition such that the sheet product roll dispenser is retrofitted with the system.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the product level sensor is biased to be in the second position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein movement of the product level sensor from the first position to the second position is configured to close a circuit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the sheet product roll comprises a central bore extending along a longitudinal axis from a first side to a second side, and wherein at least a portion of the product level sensor is configured to be disposed in contact with the first side of the sheet product roll when in the first position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, further comprising a housing at least partially containing the product level sensor, the communications module, and the electrically conductive contact, wherein the housing is configured to be coupled to the sheet product dispenser between an inner surface of the sheet product dispenser and the first side of the sheet product roll mounted on a spindle within the sheet product dispenser.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the housing comprises an outer plate, an inner plate, and sidewall extending therebetween, the inner plate defining an opening through which at least a portion of the product level sensor extends to be disposed in contact with the first side of the sheet product roll.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein each of the inner and outer plate comprises a bore through which the spindle engages a spindle-receiving cavity on the inner surface of the sheet product dispenser.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the product level sensor is a first product level sensor and is mounted so as to contact the first side of the sheet product roll when in the first position at a first radial distance from the central bore, wherein the threshold quantity is a first threshold quantity, wherein the system includes a second product level sensor that is configured to move from a first position to a second position when a quantity of sheet product on the sheet product roll mounted within the sheet product dispenser is depleted below a second threshold quantity, wherein the second product level sensor is mounted so as to contact the first side of the sheet product roll when in the first position at a second radial distance from the central bore, wherein the second radial distance is smaller than the first radial distance, and wherein the second threshold quantity is smaller than the first threshold quantity.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein, when the product level sensor is in the first position, transmissions initiated by the communications module are limited until the product level sensor is moved to the second position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein movement of the product level sensor from the first position to the second position is a first high priority event from among a plurality of high priority events, and wherein transmission of product level data to the remote computing device by the communications module is only allowed upon detection of at least one of the plurality of high priority events.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein a second high priority event from among the plurality of high priority events is an event from the group consisting of a charge remaining on the one or more batteries coupled to the electrically conductive contact being below a threshold level, the product level sensor being reset to the first position, the replacement of the one or more batteries, and a detection of a fault.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein, other than upon determination that the product level sensor moved to the second position, transmissions initiated by the communications module are limited to pre-defined intervals.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the pre-defined intervals are at most about an hour.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. An apparatus for providing automatic product level tracking functionality to a sheet product roll dispenser, the apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a housing configured to be coupled to the sheet product roll dispenser, the housing at least partially containing:
<claim-text>a product level sensor configured to move from a first position to a second position when a quantity of sheet product on a sheet product roll mounted within the sheet product dispenser is depleted below a threshold quantity;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a communications module configured to transmit product level data to a remote computing device based on a determination that the product level sensor moved to the second position, wherein the product level data is indicative of the quantity of sheet product on the sheet product roll when the product level sensor moved to the second position; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an electrically conductive contact configured to be in contact with a terminal of one or more batteries for providing electrical power to the product level sensor and the communications module; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>one or more mounting features configured to enable coupling of the housing to the sheet product dispenser.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. A method of tracking product level of a sheet product roll dispenser, the method comprising:
<claim-text>providing a product level tracking system comprising:
<claim-text>a product level sensor configured to move from a first position to a second position when a quantity of sheet product on a sheet product roll mounted within the sheet product dispenser is depleted below a threshold quantity;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining, via the processor, one of occurrence of a high priority event or expiration of a pre-defined time interval; and, in response thereto:
<claim-text>determining product level data indicative of a quantity of sheet product on the sheet product roll mounted in the sheet product dispenser;</claim-text>
<claim-text>causing transmission of the product level data to a remote computing device; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>causing resetting of a timer for determining expiration of the pre-defined time interval,</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the high priority event includes an event from a group of events including an instance in which the product level sensor moves to the second position.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the group of events further includes requiring service at the dispenser, and an event of service being provided at the dispenser.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the group of events further includes a charge remaining on one or more batteries coupled to the product level tracking system being below a threshold level, and a detection of a fault.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the group of events further includes the product level sensor being reset to the first position, and the replacement of one or more batteries for the product level tracking system.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the pre-defined interval is at most about an hour.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
