<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225468A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225468</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17648198</doc-number>
<date>20220118</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>17</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>45</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>11</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>45</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>17</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>45</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>11</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>45</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>17</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">UMBRELLA MOUNT SYSTEM</invention-title>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Green</last-name>
<first-name>Michael John</first-name>
<address>
<city>Murrieta</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Green</last-name>
<first-name>Michael John</first-name>
<address>
<city>Murrieta</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An adjustable mount and handle to support an umbrella onto a tube is disclosed. The present invention permits a user attach the umbrella to a tube or post and quickly and easily adjust the angle at any time. Thus, an individual can be shaded by the umbrella without having to manually hold the umbrella themselves.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="158.24mm" wi="101.26mm" file="US20230225468A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="225.21mm" wi="162.14mm" file="US20230225468A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="232.49mm" wi="170.43mm" file="US20230225468A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="231.82mm" wi="172.38mm" file="US20230225468A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="180.26mm" wi="121.16mm" file="US20230225468A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention relates to umbrellas and, more particularly, to an adjustable mount and handle for securing an umbrella onto a tube.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Exposure to sunlight for prolonged periods of time can lead to various health conditions such as, but not limited to, sunburn, heat sickness, and skin cancer. Consequently, shade is important to help protect from constant sun exposure that may otherwise occur at, for example, the beach or while in a desert region. You can attach the mount to an exposed tube on the vehicle and the attach the umbrella to it. An umbrella is a popular method for shading from the sun, but that conventionally requires a user manually grasping the umbrella. This can be particularly burdensome when the user has other things they would prefer to be doing, such as sitting with friends.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">As can be seen, there is a need for an umbrella mount that can mount an umbrella to a tube of a vehicle or post for support and is angularly adjustable.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In one aspect of the present invention, an umbrella mount comprises: a first clamp arm; a second clamp arm pivotally coupled to the first clamp arm about a first axis, the second clamp arm defining at least one clamp arm hole, and the first clamp arm and the second clamp arm being configured to compressibly couple to a post or vehicle; a swivel plate pivotally coupled to the second clamp arm about a second axis, the swivel plate defining a plurality of swivel plate holes along a perimeter thereof; and a handle post integral with the swivel plate, the handle post defining an opening configured to receive an umbrella handle that supports an umbrella.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In another aspect of the present invention, an umbrella mount system comprises an umbrella; an umbrella handle coupled to and supporting the umbrella; and an umbrella mount comprising: a first clamp arm; a second clamp arm pivotally coupled to the first clamp arm about a first axis, the second clamp arm defining at least one clamp arm hole, and the first clamp arm and the second clamp arm being configured to compressibly couple to a post; a swivel plate pivotally coupled to the second clamp arm about a second axis, the swivel plate defining a plurality of swivel plate holes along a perimeter thereof; and a handle post integral with the swivel plate, the handle post defining an opening that receives an umbrella handle that supports the umbrella.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">These and other features, aspects and advantages of the present invention will become better understood with reference to the following drawings, description, and claims.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The following figures are included to illustrate certain aspects of the present disclosure and should not be viewed as exclusive embodiments. The subject matter disclosed is capable of considerable modifications, alterations, combinations, and equivalents in form and function, without departing from the scope of this disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a perspective view of an embodiment of the present invention, shown in use;</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a perspective view of the embodiment of the present invention, shown removed from a post;</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is an exploded view of the embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is a detailed exploded view illustrating a swivel plate and a handle of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is a section view of the embodiment of the present invention, taken along line <b>4</b>-<b>4</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is a section view of the embodiment of the present invention, taken along line <b>5</b>-<b>5</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> is a section view of the embodiment of the present invention, illustrating the handle holding clamp arms and to the post;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> is a front view of the embodiment of the present invention, illustrating the adjustment of the angle of the swivel plate and post.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The subject disclosure is described with reference to the drawings, wherein like reference numerals are used to refer to like elements throughout. In the following description, for purposes of explanation, numerous specific details are set forth in order to provide a thorough understanding of the present disclosure such that one skilled in the art will be enabled to make and use the present invention. It may be evident, however, that the present disclosure may be practiced without some of these specific details.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Broadly, one embodiment of the present invention is an adjustable umbrella mount and umbrella mount system that may be quickly and easy connected and adjusted. As stated above, while sitting out in the direct sunlight, individuals are often in need of protection from that sunlight. The invention claimed here solves this problem. This adjustable mount with umbrella handle will hold the umbrella at any angle to a post for the best protection from the sun. Previously, individuals were forced to manually hold an umbrella. The present invention allows a user to be hands free while still benefiting from the shade of an umbrella. It is also fully adjustable to any angle needed. Thus, a high level of customization can be achieved with a simple adjustment process, improving the user experience and improving the sun protection provided by the umbrella.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>-<b>8</b></figref>, the adjustable umbrella amount is generally provided with a first clamp arm <b>10</b>, a second clamp arm <b>16</b>, a swivel plate <b>28</b>, a handle post <b>32</b>, and a handle <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The first clamp arm <b>10</b> and the second clamp arm <b>16</b> are substantially C-shaped and are hingedly connected to one another via a hinge tab <b>12</b> integral with the first clamp arm <b>10</b> and a corresponding hinge tab slot <b>18</b> defined in the second clamp arm <b>16</b>. There are different size C-shaped opening to choose from in the first and second clamp to fit different diameter tubes. Once the hinge tab <b>12</b> is inserted into the hinge tab slot <b>18</b>, they may be coupled together via a connector, such as a hinge screw <b>20</b> and a hinge screw nut <b>22</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b> and <b>7</b></figref>, an adjustable handle <b>14</b> with a grip <b>15</b> is provided at an opposite side of the clamp arms <b>10</b>, <b>16</b> to adjustably connect the arms <b>10</b>, <b>16</b> to one another (via coupling in the handle slot <b>34</b>) such that they can accommodate slightly different size posts <b>58</b> and to squeezably engage the post <b>58</b>, in use.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The second clamp arm <b>16</b> further includes a pair of swivel adjustment shoulders <b>24</b> that define respective swivel adjustment post holes <b>26</b>. In use, and as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b> and <b>8</b></figref>, at least one of these holes <b>26</b> align with one of a plurality of swivel plate holes <b>30</b> that are defined along a perimeter of the swivel plate <b>28</b>. The holes <b>16</b>, <b>30</b> operably engage one another via a short quick release pin <b>48</b>. A center screw couples with a nut <b>54</b> to function as a pivot rod <b>52</b> for the swivel plate <b>28</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b> and <b>5</b></figref>, the nut <b>54</b> is received in a relief <b>47</b> formed on a bottom side of the handle post <b>36</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref>, the swivel plate <b>28</b> can be rotated above the pivot rod <b>52</b> to adjust the angle of a retained umbrella pole <b>56</b> (as described in greater detail below). The short quick release pin <b>48</b> makes it easy to adjust, as a user can simply pull it out of the holes <b>26</b>, <b>30</b> rotate the swivel plate <b>28</b> to a desired position, and insert the quick release pin <b>48</b> back through the respectively aligned holes <b>26</b>, <b>30</b> to lock the swivel plate <b>28</b> in angular position.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, an umbrella handle opening <b>46</b> is formed in the handle post <b>32</b> for receiving the handle <b>40</b>. To secure the handle <b>40</b> to the rest of the assembly, a long quick release pin <b>50</b> is provided to extend through pin holes <b>50</b> laterally defined in the handle post <b>32</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>3</b>, <b>6</b> and <b>7</b></figref>, The handle <b>40</b> defines pin holes <b>42</b> therethrough to align with the pin holes <b>38</b> of the handle post <b>32</b>. The long quick release pin <b>50</b> is configured to extend through both sets of pin holes <b>38</b>, <b>42</b> to secure the handle <b>40</b> and the umbrella pole <b>56</b> (which may also have a hole defined therethrough) to the handle post <b>32</b>. To ensure alignment of the handle <b>40</b> relative to the handle post <b>32</b>, a raised nub <b>44</b> is provided on an upper rim of the handle <b>40</b>, which sits on top of the handle post <b>32</b> when assembled. The handle post <b>32</b> has a handle detent <b>36</b> formed on an upper surface thereof to matingly engage the nub <b>44</b>. This ensures proper alignment so that the long quick release pin <b>50</b> can easily lock the umbrella into place.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The handle <b>40</b>, in use, secures with the umbrella pole <b>56</b>. In certain embodiments, it may be permanently attached, such as via an adhesive. As described above, the design of the assembly facilitates easy and quick adjustment of the umbrella mount to adapt it for varying scenarios and needs of the end user. The components may be formed from various appropriate materials, such as plastics and metals, such that the functionality described herein is achieved.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">To use the umbrella mount, the above-described steps may be followed. A post/tube <b>58</b> is identified for attaching an umbrella thereto. The first clamp arm <b>10</b> and the second clamp arm <b>16</b> are opened and fit around the post <b>58</b>. The clamp arms <b>10</b>, <b>16</b> are rotated closed, with the adjustable handle <b>14</b> pulling the arms <b>10</b>, <b>16</b> together to compress against the post <b>58</b> and be retained in place. The swivel plate <b>28</b> can be rotated to a desired position and locked into place by inserting the short release pin <b>48</b> into the swivel plate hole <b>30</b> that is aligned with a swivel adjustment post hole <b>26</b>. The handle <b>40</b> is inserted into the opening <b>46</b> in the handle post <b>32</b>, with the nub <b>44</b> being aligned with the detent <b>36</b>. The long quick release pin <b>50</b> is inserted through the handle post <b>32</b>, thus securing the umbrella fixedly to the umbrella mount, with the post <b>58</b> supporting the assembly such that shade is provided to the user(s) in need of protection from the sun.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">While one or more preferred embodiments are disclosed, many other implementations will occur to one of ordinary skill in the art and are all within the scope of the invention. Each of the various embodiments described above may be combined with other described embodiments in order to provide multiple features. Furthermore, while the foregoing describes a number of separate embodiments of the apparatus and method of the present invention, what has been described herein is merely illustrative of the application of the principles of the present invention. Other arrangements, methods, modifications, and substitutions by one of ordinary skill in the art are therefore also considered to be within the scope of the present invention, which is not to be limited except by the claims that follow.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">While apparatuses and methods are described in terms of &#x201c;comprising,&#x201d; &#x201c;containing,&#x201d; or &#x201c;including&#x201d; various components or steps, the apparatuses and methods can also &#x201c;consist essentially of&#x201d; or &#x201c;consist of&#x201d; the various components and steps. Also, the terms in the claims have their plain, ordinary meaning unless otherwise explicitly and clearly defined by the patentee. Moreover, the indefinite articles &#x201c;a&#x201d; or &#x201c;an,&#x201d; as used in the claims, are defined herein to mean one or more than one of the elements that it introduces. If there is any conflict in the usages of a word or term in this specification and one or more patent or other documents that may be incorporated herein by reference, the definitions that are consistent with this specification should be adopted. Moreover, the use of directional terms such as above, below, upper, lower, upward, downward, left, right, and the like are used in relation to the illustrative embodiments as they are depicted in the figures, the upward or upper direction being toward the top of the corresponding figure and the downward or lower direction being toward the bottom of the corresponding figure.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. An umbrella mount comprising:
<claim-text>a first clamp arm;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second clamp arm pivotally coupled to the first clamp arm about a first axis, the second clamp arm defining at least one clamp arm hole, and the first clamp arm and the second clamp arm being configured to compressibly couple to a post;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a swivel plate pivotally coupled to the second clamp arm about a second axis, the swivel plate defining a plurality of swivel plate holes along a perimeter thereof; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a handle post integral with the swivel plate, the handle post defining an opening configured to receive an umbrella handle that supports an umbrella.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The umbrella mount of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first axis and the second axis are perpendicular to one another.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The umbrella mount of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein one swivel plate hole of the plurality of swivel plate holes to angularly position the swivel plate relative to the second clamp arm.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The umbrella mount of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, further comprising a first quick release pin extending through the one swivel plate hole and the at least one clamp arm hole.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The umbrella mount of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising an adjustable handle that releasably couples a distal end of the first clamp arm and a distal end of the second clamp arm.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. An umbrella mount system comprising:
<claim-text>an umbrella;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an umbrella handle coupled to and supporting the umbrella; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an umbrella mount comprising:
<claim-text>a first clamp arm;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second clamp arm pivotally coupled to the first clamp arm about a first axis, the second clamp arm defining at least one clamp arm hole, and the first clamp arm and the second clamp arm being configured to compressibly couple to a post;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a swivel plate pivotally coupled to the second clamp arm about a second axis, the swivel plate defining a plurality of swivel plate holes along a perimeter thereof; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a handle post integral with the swivel plate, the handle post defining an opening that receives an umbrella handle that supports the umbrella.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The umbrella mount system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the first axis and the second axis are perpendicular to one another.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The umbrella mount system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the handle post defines a detent, and the umbrella handle comprises a nub that engages the detent to position the handle post.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The umbrella mount system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, further comprising a first quick release pin extending through the one swivel plate hole and the at least one clamp arm hole.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The umbrella mount system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, further comprising a second quick release pin, and wherein the umbrella handle defines a transverse hole extending therethrough, the transverse hole being receiving the second quick release pin therethrough.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
