<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225438A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225438</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18125481</doc-number>
<date>20230323</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>2021102188424</doc-number>
<date>20210226</date>
</priority-claim>
<priority-claim sequence="02" kind="national">
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>2021106540978</doc-number>
<date>20210611</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>31</main-group>
<subgroup>102</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>19</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20190201</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>31</main-group>
<subgroup>102</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>19</main-group>
<subgroup>0006</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e79">COMPOSITE ITEMS OF FOOTWEAR AND HANDWEAR</invention-title>
<us-related-documents>
<division>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17397095</doc-number>
<date>20210809</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11638452</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18125481</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</division>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Shanghai Uniwise International Co Limited</orgname>
<address>
<city>Shanghai</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>XU</last-name>
<first-name>Qian</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shanghai</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A composite item of footwear and handwear having a main body to accommodate the hand/foot of a wearer of the item, the main body comprising an outer layer, an inner layer and a waterproof and breathable intermediate layer between the outer and inner layers, and an opening through which a foot/hand can be inserted, the opening defined by a cuff arrangement comprising a cuff region that comprises an end region of each of the inner and intermediate layers and a cuff inner portion of the outer layer that extends beyond the said end regions, the cuff arrangement further comprising a waterproof cuff band fixed to one or both of the cuff inner portion and end region of the inner layer to lie over and be fixed to the outside of the outer layer, the location at which the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the outer layer is at a distance from the opening that is greater than the distance between the opening and the location at which the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the cuff inner portion or end region of the inner layer.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="138.68mm" wi="130.89mm" file="US20230225438A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="117.77mm" wi="83.90mm" file="US20230225438A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="151.55mm" wi="132.93mm" file="US20230225438A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="142.75mm" wi="116.25mm" file="US20230225438A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="84.07mm" wi="41.15mm" file="US20230225438A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="159.68mm" wi="118.70mm" file="US20230225438A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="120.40mm" wi="80.60mm" file="US20230225438A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="168.74mm" wi="128.44mm" file="US20230225438A1-20230720-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a divisional of U.S. patent application Ser. No. 17/397,095, filed Aug. 9, 2021, which claims the benefit of Chinese Application Nos. 2021106540978, filed Jun. 11, 2021, and 2021102188424, filed Feb. 26, 2021, which are incorporated in their entirety by reference.</p>
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="tail"?>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">FIELD OF INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to composite items of footwear and handwear, and specifically but not exclusively to composite waterproof socks and gloves.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">There are many circumstances and environments in which waterproof socks and gloves find utility, including use in certain outdoor interests and activities like walking, running, trekking, hiking, cycling, fishing, camping and gardening, as well as use in commercial and industrial environments where it is important or desirable to keep the wearer's feet and/or hands dry.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The opening or cuff area of known socks and gloves offers the potential for water to seep between the sock/glove and the leg/arm of the wearer and through the cuff area itself, thus compromising the ability of known socks and gloves to keep the hands and feet of a wearer dry.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">It is an object of the present invention to provide items of footwear and handwear, in particular socks and gloves, that have a cuff arrangement that helps to seal the item against the wearer to help prevent the ingress of water between the item and the wearer, whilst providing a close-fitting and comfortable item of wear, and that has a construction that helps prevent the ingress of water through the cuff arrangement itself.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In the present specification the term &#x2018;sock&#x2019; is used to refer to flexible and stretchable items of footwear, including such items to be worn between the foot and a boot or shoe, as well as other sock-like items of footwear such as over-shoes, flexible booties and the like.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In the present specification the term &#x2018;glove&#x2019; is used to refer to flexible and stretchable items of handwear, in particular fingered gloves and mittens.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY OF INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">According to the present invention there is provided a composite item of footwear/handwear having a main body defining a volume to accommodate the hand/foot of a wearer of the item, the main body comprising an outer layer, an inner layer and a waterproof and breathable intermediate layer between the outer and inner layers, the main body having an opening through which a foot/hand can be inserted to be accommodated in the volume, the opening defined by a cuff arrangement comprising a cuff region of the main body that comprises an end region of each of the inner and intermediate layers and a cuff inner portion of the outer layer that extends beyond the said end regions, the cuff arrangement further comprising a waterproof cuff band that is fixed to one or both of the cuff inner portion of the outer layer and end region of the inner layer to extend over the inside and around the open end of the cuff inner portion and back over the outside of the cuff inner portion to lie over and fixed to the outside of the outer layer, the location at which the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the outer layer is at a distance from the opening that is greater than the distance between the opening and the location at which the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the cuff inner portion or end region of the inner layer.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The part of the waterproof cuff band that extends over the inside of the cuff inner portion is provided to fit comfortably against the leg, typically the ankle or calf of the leg of the wearer of the item when the item is one of footwear, or the wrist or forearm of the wearer of the item when the item is one of handwear, to provide a comfortable seal to help prevent the ingress of water between the cuff arrangement and the wearer's body.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The extension of the waterproof cuff over the inside and around the open end of the cuff inner portion and back over the outer surface with the location at which the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the outer layer being at a distance from the opening that is greater than the distance between the opening and the location at which the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the cuff inner portion or end region of the inner layer provides a cuff arrangement that is resistant to the ingress of water through the cuff arrangement itself, to the inside of the item as will be explained in more detail hereinafter.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The location at which the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the outer layer is between 10 and 40 millimetres further from the opening than the distance between the opening and the location at which the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the cuff inner portion or end region of the inner layer, to provide an area of overlap.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">This degree of overlap has been shown to provide the cuff arrangement with favourable resistance to water ingressing through the cuff arrangement into the volume.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Preferably, the location at which the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the outer layer is between 20 and 40 millimetres further from the opening than is the location at which the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the cuff inner portion or end region of the inner layer.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">This has been shown to provide favourable water resistance characteristics balanced with favourable design and comfort characteristics.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Preferably, the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the inner surface of the cuff inner portion and/or the end region of the inner layer.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">This helps ensure the waterproof cuff band remains securely positioned around the inside of the cuff region.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Preferably, the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the inner surface of the cuff inner portion and/or the end region of the inner layer in a continuous band around the waterproof cuff band.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">This helps ensure the waterproof cuff band remains securely in place all the way around the cuff region.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Preferably, the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the inner surface of the cuff inner portion and/or the end region of the inner layer by a continuous band of stitching.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">This helps ensure the waterproof cuff band remains securely in place all the way around the cuff region and opening of the item and provides for relative ease of manufacture and comfort for the wearer.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Preferably, the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the inner surface of the cuff inner portion and/or the end region of the inner layer by a continuous band of adhesive.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Preferably the adhesive penetrates through the inner layer to seal against the intermediate layer when the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the end region of the inner layer.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">This inhibits any water that finds its way inside the waterproof cuff band from wicking along the inner layer, past the location at which the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the end region of the inner layer and into the inside of the item.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The continuous band of adhesive may be provided as adhesive tape.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">This helps ensure the waterproof cuff band remains securely in place all the way around the cuff region and opening of the item and also does not run the risk of compromising the waterproof character of the waterproof cuff band.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Preferably, the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the inner surface of the cuff inner portion and/or the end region of the inner layer by a continuous band of waterproof adhesive.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">This helps maintain the integrity of the fixing, even in the event the adhesive is exposed to water.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Preferably, the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the inner surface of the cuff inner portion and/or the end region of the inner layer by continuous bands of both stitching and adhesive.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">This can provide a more secure fixing of the waterproof cuff band to the inner surface of the cuff inner portion.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The waterproof cuff band may be fixed to the end region of the inner layer by stitching that extends through the inner layer only, the inner layer and the intermediate layer only, or the inner layer, the intermediate layer and the outer layer.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Preferably, the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the outer layer, which ensures the waterproof cuff band is held in place around the cuff region.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Preferably, the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the outer layer to lie generally flat over the outer layer.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">This can help with the functioning and aesthetics of the item.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Preferably, the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the outer layer in a continuous band around the outer layer.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">This helps ensure the waterproof cuff band remains securely in place all the way around the opening of the item and over the cuff region and helps to seal the waterproof cuff band to the outer layer.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Preferably, the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the outer layer by a continuous band of adhesive around the outer layer.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">This helps ensure the waterproof cuff band remains securely in place all the way around the opening and cuff region of the item.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Preferably the adhesive penetrates through the outer layer to seal against the intermediate layer.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">This seals the outer layer to the waterproof intermediate layer, thereby inhibiting water from wicking along the outer layer, past the intermediate layer and into the inside of the waterproof cuff band to the inner layer.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The continuous band of adhesive may be provided as adhesive tape.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Preferably, the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the outer layer by a continuous band of waterproof adhesive around and through the outer layer.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">This helps maintain the integrity of the fixing, and inhibits ingress of water to the inside volume as a result of wicking through the outer layer, when the adhesive is exposed to water.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Stitching may be used to fix the waterproof cuff band to the outer layer.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The stitching may be provided in a continuous band around the outer layer.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The waterproof cuff band may be fixed to the outer layer in continuous bands of both adhesive and stitching around the outer layer.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">This can provide a particularly secure and water-tight fixing of the waterproof cuff band to the outer layer.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Preferably, the waterproof cuff band comprises a resiliently stretchable waterproof material, stretchable to enable the waterproof cuff band to expand and contract as the open end expands and contracts to accommodate a foot/hand as it is inserted and removed from the volume.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">Preferably, the waterproof cuff band comprises a stretchable waterproof polyurethane material.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Preferably, the outer layer comprises main body yarns and twisted elastic yarns woven throughout the main body yarns.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Preferably, the main body yarns comprise one or more of polyamide, cotton, modal, polyester.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">Preferably, the inner layer comprises inner layer main body yarns of one or more of cotton, wool, acrylic, rayon, polyamide, polyester.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Preferably, one or more adhesives are used to fix the outer layer and the inner layer to the waterproof and breathable intermediate layer.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">Preferably, the waterproof and breathable intermediate layer extends between the inner and outer layers with a corrugated structure in both weft X and warp Y directions.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">Preferably, the waterproof and breathable intermediate layer is configured to be stretchable circumferentially and longitudinally.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Preferably, the adhesive(s) is/are provided on both inner and outer layers as discrete spots or islands of adhesive to fix the waterproof and breathable intermediate layer to each of and in between the inner and outer layers at discrete locations.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">Preferably, in at least one region of the main body the discrete spots or islands of adhesive are spaced further apart from each other in one or both of the weft X and warp Y directions than elsewhere in the main body, thus giving that at least one region differential stretch characteristics in one or both of the weft X and warp Y directions than elsewhere in the main body.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Specific embodiments of the present invention will now be described by way of example only, with reference to the accompanying drawings in which:</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a diagrammatic perspective view of a composite item of footwear according to the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a diagrammatic cross-section of the composite item of footwear of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> in the plane II-II;</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is an enlarged view of the region III of the composite item of footwear of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is an enlarged cross-sectional view of the region IV of the composite item of footwear of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is a view equivalent to the view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, but of a composite item of footwear of an alternative embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is a diagrammatic perspective view of a composite item of handwear according to a further embodiment of the present invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> is a diagrammatic view equivalent to that of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, but of a composite item of handwear according to a still further embodiment of the present invention</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DESCRIPTION FO THE SPECIFIC EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> to <b>4</b></figref>, the present invention provides a composite item of footwear in the form of a sock <b>10</b> having a main body <b>12</b> defining a volume <b>14</b> to accommodate the foot of a wearer of the item <b>10</b>, the main body <b>12</b> comprising an outer layer <b>16</b>, an inner layer <b>18</b> and a waterproof and breathable intermediate layer <b>20</b> between the outer and inner layers <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>, the main body <b>12</b> having an opening <b>22</b> through which a foot/hand can be inserted to be accommodated in the volume <b>14</b>. The opening <b>22</b> is defined by a cuff arrangement <b>24</b> comprising a cuff region <b>25</b> of the main body <b>12</b> that comprises an end region <b>28</b>, <b>30</b> of each of the inner <b>18</b> and intermediate <b>20</b> layers and a cuff inner portion <b>32</b> of the outer layer <b>16</b> that extends beyond the said end regions <b>28</b>, <b>30</b>. The cuff arrangement <b>24</b> further comprises a waterproof cuff band <b>34</b> that is fixed to the cuff inner portion <b>32</b> of the outer layer <b>16</b> to extend over the inside <b>36</b> and around the open end <b>38</b> of the cuff inner portion <b>32</b> and back over the outside <b>40</b> of the outer layer <b>16</b>, with the location L<b>1</b> at which the waterproof cuff band <b>34</b> is fixed to the outer layer <b>16</b> being at a distance d<b>1</b> from the opening <b>22</b> that is greater than the distance d<b>2</b> between the opening <b>22</b> and the location L<b>2</b> at which the waterproof cuff band <b>34</b> is fixed to the cuff inner portion <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">In more detail, the present invention provides composite waterproof socks <b>10</b> that have a laminate structure in which the inner layer <b>18</b> comprises inner layer main body yarns of one or more of cotton, wool, acrylic, rayon, polyamide, polyester and/or any other suitable materials or blends of materials, particularly selected for comfort of the wearer and according to the intended use or purpose of the sock.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">The outer layer <b>16</b> comprises main body yarns and twisted elastic yarns woven throughout or substantially throughout the main body yarns.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">The main body yarns comprise one or more of polyamide, cotton, modal, polyester and/or any other suitable materials or blends of materials, particularly selected according to the intended purpose or use of the sock.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">The twisted elastic yarns comprise spandex yarns or other suitable elastic yarns, and are typically incorporated at approximately 350 twists per metre.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">The inner and outer layers <b>18</b>, <b>16</b> are typically knitted, such as on a 13 gauges toe sock knitting machine. The outer layer <b>16</b> is typically knitted with a heel portion. The inner layer <b>18</b> can be knitted with or without a heel portion, depending upon the desired design and/or application of the sock <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">The waterproof and breathable intermediate layer <b>20</b> comprises a polyurethane or other suitable waterproof breathable material and one or more adhesives <b>44</b> are used to fix the outer layer <b>16</b> to the outer surface of the waterproof intermediate layer <b>20</b> and to fix the inner layer <b>18</b> to the inner surface of the waterproof intermediate layer <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">Suitable adhesives are heat-activated thermoplastic polyurethane (TPU) materials.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">As illustrated particularly in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>, the waterproof and breathable intermediate layer <b>20</b> is fixed between the inner and outer layers <b>18</b>, <b>16</b> so that when the sock <b>10</b> is in a relaxed state, the waterproof and breathable intermediate layer <b>20</b> has a corrugated structure in both weft X and warp Y directions. This enables the waterproof and breathable intermediate layer <b>20</b> to extend both circumferentially and longitudinally as the inner and outer layers <b>18</b>, <b>16</b> are stretched, enabling the sock <b>10</b> to stretch and contract as the sock <b>10</b> is fitted, worn and removed by a wearer.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">The adhesive(s) <b>44</b> is/are provided on both the inner and outer layers <b>18</b>, <b>16</b> as discrete spots or islands <b>44</b> of adhesive to fix the waterproof and breathable intermediate layer <b>20</b> to each of and in between the inner and outer layers <b>18</b>, <b>16</b> such that when the inner and outer layers <b>18</b>, <b>16</b> are in relaxed condition the waterproof and breathable intermediate layer <b>20</b> adopts the three-dimensional corrugated structure.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">In certain embodiments, in at least one region of the main body <b>12</b> the discrete spots or islands <b>44</b> of adhesive are spaced further apart from each other in one or both of the weft X and warp Y directions than elsewhere in the main body <b>12</b>, thus giving that at least one region a differential corrugated profile and thus differing stretch characteristics in one or both of the weft X and the warp Y directions than elsewhere in the main body <b>12</b>. This enables the main body <b>12</b> to stretch circumferentially and longitudinally and to stretch to different extents in different regions, being more resistant to further stretch in the region where the spacings between the discrete dots or islands <b>44</b> of adhesive are smaller than elsewhere.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">Such differential stretch characteristics can be designed or engineered into the overall composition of the socks <b>10</b> to provide improved comfort for wearers of the socks <b>10</b> of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">The cuff arrangement <b>24</b> provides for sealing of the opening or cuff of the sock <b>10</b> against the leg of the wearer. The precise part of the leg against which the sock <b>10</b> is designed to seal will in large part be determined by the intended utility or style of the sock <b>10</b>, but socks <b>10</b> of the present invention would typically extend from the ankle to partway up the calf and shin of the wearer of the sock <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">The cuff arrangement <b>24</b> also provides for resistance to water permeating through the structure of the cuff arrangement <b>24</b> and thus ingressing into the inside of the sock <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">In the embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b> and <b>3</b></figref>, the waterproof cuff band <b>34</b> extends from the open ends <b>28</b><i>a, </i><b>30</b><i>a </i>of the end regions <b>28</b>, <b>30</b> of the inner and intermediate layers <b>18</b>, <b>20</b>, where it generally abuts or is in close proximity to these open ends <b>28</b><i>a, </i><b>30</b><i>a </i>and from there extends closely over the inside <b>36</b> of the cuff inner portion <b>32</b>, around the open end <b>38</b> and back over the outside <b>40</b> of the cuff inner portion <b>32</b> to lie closely over, adjacent to the outside <b>40</b> of the outer layer <b>16</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">The part of the waterproof cuff band <b>34</b> that extends over the inside of the cuff inner portion <b>32</b> is provided to fit comfortably against the leg, typically the ankle or calf of the leg of the wearer of the item when the item is one of footwear, or the wrist or forearm of the wearer of the item when the item is one of handwear, to provide a comfortable seal to help prevent the ingress of water between the cuff arrangement and the wearer's body.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">In this embodiment the waterproof cuff band <b>34</b> is fixed to the cuff inner portion <b>32</b> only, and the location L<b>2</b> at which it is fixed is at a shorter distance d<b>2</b> from the opening <b>22</b> than the distance d<b>1</b> of the location L<b>1</b> at which the waterproof cuff band <b>34</b> is fixed to the outer layer <b>16</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">This arrangement of fixing locations provides the cuff arrangement <b>24</b> with resistance to the ingress of water through the cuff arrangement <b>24</b> itself, to the inside of the sock <b>10</b> as will be explained in more detail hereinafter.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">The location L<b>1</b> at which the waterproof cuff band <b>34</b> is fixed to the outer layer <b>16</b> is also at a greater distance from the opening <b>22</b> than the ends <b>28</b><i>a</i>,<b>30</b><i>a </i>of the inner and intermediate layers <b>18</b>, <b>20</b> are distanced from the opening <b>22</b>. This results in the ends <b>28</b><i>a</i>,<b>30</b><i>a </i>being located between the location L<b>1</b> at which the waterproof cuff band <b>34</b> is fixed to the outer layer <b>16</b> and location L<b>2</b> whereat the waterproof cuff band <b>34</b> is fixed to the cuff inner portion <b>32</b>, which configuration further enhances the resistance of the cuff arrangement <b>24</b> from the ingress of water therethrough.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">In certain embodiments, the location L<b>1</b> at which the waterproof cuff band <b>34</b> is fixed to the outer layer <b>16</b> is between 10 and 40 millimetres further from the opening <b>22</b> than the location L<b>2</b> at which the waterproof cuff band <b>34</b> is fixed to the cuff inner portion <b>32</b>. That is, d<b>1</b> is between 10 and 40 millimetres greater than d<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">This differential has been shown to provide the cuff arrangement <b>24</b> with favourable resistance to water ingressing through the cuff arrangement <b>24</b> into the volume.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">In further embodiments the location L<b>1</b> at which the waterproof cuff band <b>34</b> is fixed to the outer layer <b>16</b> is between 20 and 40 millimetres further from the opening <b>22</b> than the location L<b>2</b> at which the waterproof cuff band <b>34</b> is fixed to the cuff inner portion <b>32</b>. That is, d<b>1</b> is between 20 and 40 millimetres greater than d<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">This has been shown to provide favourable water resistance characteristics balanced with favourable design and comfort characteristics.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">The waterproof cuff band <b>34</b> comprises resiliently stretchable waterproof material, stretchable to enable the waterproof cuff band <b>34</b> to expand and contract as the opening <b>22</b> expands and contracts to receive and release the foot of a person when it is inserted into and removed from the volume.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">Typically, the waterproof cuff band <b>34</b> comprises a stretchable waterproof polyurethane material, although other suitable waterproof materials can be used.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">The waterproof cuff band <b>34</b> is fixed to the inner surface <b>36</b> of the cuff inner portion <b>32</b> in a continuous, circumferential band around the waterproof cuff band <b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">In certain embodiments, like the one shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, the waterproof cuff band <b>34</b> is fixed to the inner surface <b>36</b> of the cuff inner portion <b>32</b> by a continuous band of stitching <b>46</b> of thread.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">In alternative embodiments, the waterproof cuff band <b>34</b> is fixed to the inner surface <b>36</b> of the cuff inner portion <b>32</b> by a continuous band of adhesive, and typically waterproof adhesive.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">The adhesive can be provided as an adhesive tape.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">In still further embodiments, the waterproof cuff band <b>34</b> is fixed to the inner surface <b>36</b> of the cuff inner portion <b>32</b> by a continuous band of both stitching <b>46</b> and adhesive.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">The waterproof cuff band <b>34</b> is also fixed to the outer layer <b>16</b> and is fixed to lie generally flat on the outer surface <b>40</b> of the outer layer <b>16</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">The location L<b>1</b> at which the waterproof cuff band <b>34</b> is fixed to the outer layer <b>16</b> is at a greater distance from the opening <b>22</b> than are the ends <b>28</b><i>a</i>,<b>30</b><i>a </i>of the inner and intermediate layers <b>18</b>, <b>20</b>. The ends <b>28</b><i>a</i>,<b>30</b><i>a </i>are located between the location L<b>1</b> at which the waterproof cuff band <b>34</b> is fixed to the outer layer <b>16</b> and location L<b>2</b> at which the waterproof cuff band <b>34</b> is fixed to the cuff inner portion <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">In preferred embodiments the waterproof cuff band <b>34</b> is fixed to the outer layer <b>16</b> by a continuous band of adhesive, most preferably waterproof adhesive <b>48</b> that penetrates the outer layer <b>16</b> to seal against the intermediate layer <b>20</b> This provides fixing and sealing of the waterproof cuff band <b>34</b> to, through and around the outer layer <b>16</b> in a continuous water-sealed manner that acts to prevent water from seeping in between the waterproof cuff band <b>34</b> and the waterproof intermediate layer <b>20</b> and from wicking from outside of the item along the outer layer <b>16</b>, past location L<b>1</b> to the end <b>30</b><i>a </i>of the intermediate layer <b>20</b> and beyond. This acts to prevent water from outside of the sock <b>10</b> wicking along the outer layer <b>16</b> to positions at which it could seep past the end <b>30</b><i>a </i>of the intermediate layer <b>20</b> and into the inside of the sock, such as the position at which the waterproof intermediate layer <b>20</b> ends <b>30</b><i>a </i>and the position at L<b>2</b> where the stitching <b>46</b> might compromise the waterproof barrier of the waterproof cuff band <b>34</b> as it passes therethrough.</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0098">This ensures the waterproof cuff band <b>34</b> is secured and sealed against the intermediate layer over the outside of the area at which the waterproof cuff band <b>34</b> extends from the open ends <b>28</b>, <b>30</b> of the inner layer and the intermediate layer <b>18</b>, <b>20</b>. In this area the intermediate layer <b>20</b> ends and so no longer provides a waterproof barrier through the main body in the cuff region <b>25</b>, so there would be risk of water ingress through that area of the cuff region <b>25</b>. This risk is addressed by fixing and sealing the waterproof cuff band <b>34</b> to the outer layer <b>16</b> at location L<b>1</b> as described, so that the waterproof cuff band <b>34</b> lies over this area to provide a sealed, waterproof covering which acts to prevent water from wicking from the outside of the sock <b>10</b>, along the outer layer <b>16</b>, past the end <b>30</b><i>a </i>of the intermediate layer <b>20</b> and thus through the cuff region <b>25</b> to the inside of the sock <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0099">In alternative embodiments, the waterproof cuff layer <b>34</b> may be fixed to the outer layer <b>16</b> with a continuous band of stitching of thread. In such embodiments, it is important that the stitching does not puncture the intermediate layer <b>20</b>, otherwise this could compromise the waterproof structure of the cuff arrangement <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0100">The stitching is such that it inhibits wicking of water from the outside of the sock <b>10</b>, along the outer layer <b>16</b>, past the end <b>30</b><i>a </i>of the intermediate layer <b>20</b> and thus through the cuff region <b>25</b> to the inside of the sock <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0101">In certain embodiments the stitching is of waterproof thread and the stitching pattern such that it presents a barrier that inhibits wicking as aforesaid.</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0102">In certain embodiments, the waterproof cuff band <b>34</b> may be fixed to the outer layer <b>16</b> by both stitching and adhesive, as described above.</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0103"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> shows an equivalent view to the view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, but of an item of footwear according to an alternative embodiment of the present invention. This embodiment shares features of the embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> and those features that are visible in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> have been identified with the same reference numerals used in relation to the illustration in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, but prefixed with the numeral 1.</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0104">In this embodiment the waterproof cuff <b>134</b> is fixed to and through the end region <b>128</b> of the inner layer <b>118</b> to extend in similar manner as described above, over the inside and around the open end <b>138</b> of the cuff inner portion <b>132</b> and back over the outside <b>140</b> of the cuff inner portion <b>132</b> to lie over and fixed to the outside <b>140</b> of the outer layer <b>116</b>, with the location L<b>1</b> at which the waterproof cuff band <b>134</b> is fixed to the outer layer <b>116</b> at a distance d<b>1</b> from the opening that is greater than the distance d<b>2</b> between the opening <b>122</b> and the location L<b>2</b> at which the waterproof cuff band <b>134</b> is fixed to the end region <b>128</b> of the inner layer <b>118</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0105">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, the waterproof cuff band <b>34</b> is fixed by stitching <b>146</b> that extends through the waterproof cuff band <b>134</b>, through the end region <b>128</b> of the inner layer <b>118</b>, through the end region <b>130</b> of the waterproof intermediate layer <b>120</b>, and through the outer layer <b>116</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0107" num="0106">Although in this embodiment the stitching <b>146</b> may to some degree compromise the waterproof barrier provided by the waterproof intermediate layer <b>120</b>, the location L<b>2</b> of the stitching <b>146</b> being closer to the opening <b>122</b> than the location L<b>1</b> at which the waterproof cuff band <b>134</b> is fixed to the outer layer <b>116</b> by the continuous band of adhesive penetrating through the outer layer <b>116</b> to seal against the intermediate layer <b>120</b> and/or the stitching <b>148</b> as described above means that this does not compromise the water impermeable nature of the cuff arrangement <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0108" num="0107">In other embodiments the stitching of the waterproof cuff band <b>134</b> at location L<b>2</b> could extend through the inner layer <b>118</b> only, or through the inner layer <b>118</b> and the waterproof intermediate layer <b>120</b> only.</p>
<p id="p-0109" num="0108"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> shows an equivalent view to the view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, but of an item of footwear according to a further alternative embodiment of the present invention. This embodiment shares features of the embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> and those features that are visible in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> have been identified with the same reference numerals used in relation to the illustration in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, but prefixed with the numeral 3.</p>
<p id="p-0110" num="0109">In this embodiment adhesive <b>349</b> is used to fix the waterproof cuff band <b>334</b> to the inner layer <b>318</b> instead of or in addition to stitching.</p>
<p id="p-0111" num="0110">The adhesive <b>349</b> is a continuous band, most preferably of waterproof adhesive, that extends continuously circumferentially around the end region penetrating the inner layer <b>318</b> to seal against the intermediate layer <b>320</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0112" num="0111">This provides fixing and sealing of the waterproof cuff band <b>334</b> to and around the inner layer <b>318</b> in a continuous water-sealed manner that acts to prevent any water that's found its way inside the waterproof cuff band <b>334</b> (such as in the event the outer seal <b>348</b> has been compromised or damaged) from wicking from the inside of the waterproof cuff band <b>334</b>, through the end <b>328</b><i>a </i>and along the inner layer <b>318</b>, past location L<b>2</b>, and thus to the inside of the sock <b>310</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0113" num="0112"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is a diagrammatic perspective view of an item of handwear <b>210</b>, in the form of a glove, which has the same structural features of the item of footwear (sock) <b>10</b> described above. Visible features have therefore been identified with the same reference numerals used in relation to the illustrations of the sock <b>10</b>, but prefixed with the numeral &#x2018;2&#x2019;.</p>
<p id="p-0114" num="0113">It will be appreciated that the structure and configuration of the cuff arrangement <b>24</b> of the items of the present invention as described above in the context of footwear find the same utility in items of handwear, providing for a cuff arrangement <b>24</b> that resists the ingress of water between the open end of the glove and the wrist/arm of the wearer of the glove and the ingress of water through the cuff arrangement <b>24</b> itself.</p>
<p id="p-0115" num="0114">Various modifications may be made without departing from the spirit or scope of the present invention. The present document discloses specific embodiments of the present invention, but is not limiting on the scope of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0116" num="0115">A plurality of bands of one or both of adhesive and/or stitching can be provided to fix the waterproof cuff band to one or both of the cuff inner portion of the outer layer and end region of the inner layer and the outside of the outer layer.</p>
<p id="p-0117" num="0116">Whilst endeavouring in the foregoing specification to draw attention to those features of the invention believed to be of particular importance, it should be understood that the applicant claims protection in respect of any patentable feature or combination of features hereinbefore referred to and/or shown in the drawings, whether or not particular emphasis has been placed thereon.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A composite item of handwear comprising a main body defining a volume to accommodate a hand of a wearer of the item, the main body comprising an outer layer, an inner layer and a waterproof and breathable intermediate layer between the outer and inner layers, the main body having an opening through which the hand can be inserted to be accommodated in the volume, the opening defined by a cuff arrangement comprising a cuff region of the main body that comprises an end region of each of the inner and intermediate layers and a cuff inner portion of the outer layer that extends beyond the end regions, the cuff arrangement further comprising a waterproof cuff band that is fixed to one or both of the cuff inner portion of the outer layer and the end region of the inner layer to extend over an inside and around the open end of the cuff inner portion and back over an outside of the cuff inner portion to lie over and fixed to an outside of the outer layer, a location at which the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the outer layer is at a distance from the opening that is greater than the distance between the opening and a location at which the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the cuff inner portion or the end region of the inner layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The composite item of handwear as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, in which the location at which the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the outer layer is between 10 and 40 millimetres further from the opening than the distance between the opening and the location at which the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the cuff inner portion or the end region of the inner layer, to provide an area of overlap.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The composite item of handwear as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, in which the location at which the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the outer layer is between 20 and 40 millimetres further from the opening than the distance between the opening and the location at which the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the cuff inner portion or the end region of the inner layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The composite item of handwear as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, in which the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the inner surface of the cuff inner portion and/or the end region of the inner layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The composite item of handwear as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, in which the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the inner surface of the cuff inner portion and/or the end region of the inner layer in a continuous band around the waterproof cuff band.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The composite item of handwear as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, in which the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the inner surface of the cuff inner portion and/or the end region of the inner layer by a continuous band of stitching.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The composite item of handwear as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, in which the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the inner surface of the cuff inner portion and/or the end region of the inner layer by a continuous band of adhesive.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The composite item of handwear as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, in which the continuous band of adhesive penetrates through the inner layer to seal against the intermediate layer when the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the end region of the inner layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The composite item of handwear as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, in which the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the inner surface of the cuff inner portion and/or the end region of the inner layer by a continuous band of adhesive tape.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The composite item of handwear as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, in which the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the inner surface of the cuff inner portion and/or the end region of the inner layer by a continuous band of waterproof adhesive.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The composite item of handwear as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, in which the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the inner surface of the cuff inner portion and/or the end region of the inner layer by continuous bands of both stitching and adhesive.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The composite item of handwear as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, in which the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the end region of the inner layer by stitching that extends through the inner layer only, the inner layer and the intermediate layer only, or the inner layer, the intermediate layer and the outer layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. The composite item of handwear as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, in which the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the outer layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The composite item of handwear as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, in which the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the outer layer to lie generally flat over the outer layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. The composite item of handwear as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, in which the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the outer layer in a continuous band around the outer layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. The composite item of handwear as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, in which the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the outer layer in a continuous band of stitching around the outer layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. The composite item of handwear as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, in which the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the outer layer in a continuous band of adhesive around the outer layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. The composite item of handwear as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, in which the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the outer layer in a continuous band of adhesive tape around the outer layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. The composite item of handwear as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, in which the adhesive penetrates through the outer layer to seal against the intermediate layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. The composite item of handwear as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, in which the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the outer layer in a continuous band of waterproof adhesive around the outer layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text><b>21</b>. The composite item of handwear as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, in which the waterproof cuff band is fixed to the outer layer in continuous bands of both adhesive and stitching around the outer layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text><b>22</b>. The composite item of handwear as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, in which the waterproof cuff band comprises a stretchable waterproof material, stretchable to enable the waterproof cuff band to expand and contract as the open end expands and contracts as the hand is inserted and removed from the volume.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text><b>23</b>. The composite item of handwear as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00022">claim 22</claim-ref>, in which the waterproof cuff band comprises a stretchable waterproof polyurethane material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024" num="00024">
<claim-text><b>24</b>. The composite item of handwear as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, in which the outer layer comprises main body yarns and twisted elastic yarns woven throughout the main body yarns.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025" num="00025">
<claim-text><b>25</b>. The composite item of handwear as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00024">claim 24</claim-ref>, in which the main body yarns comprise one or more of polyamide, cotton, modal, or polyester.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026" num="00026">
<claim-text><b>26</b>. The composite item of handwear as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, in which the inner layer comprises inner layer main body yarns of one or more of cotton, wool, acrylic, rayon, polyamide, or polyester.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027" num="00027">
<claim-text><b>27</b>. The composite item of handwear as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, in which one or more adhesives are used to join the outer layer, the inner layer, and the waterproof and breathable intermediate layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028" num="00028">
<claim-text><b>28</b>. The composite item of handwear as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, in which the waterproof and breathable intermediate layer extends between the inner and outer layers with a corrugated structure in both weft X and warp Y directions.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029" num="00029">
<claim-text><b>29</b>. The composite item of handwear as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00028">claim 28</claim-ref>, in which the waterproof and breathable intermediate layer is configured to be stretchable circumferentially and longitudinally.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030" num="00030">
<claim-text><b>30</b>. The composite item of handwear as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00027">claim 27</claim-ref>, in which the adhesive(s) is/are provided on both inner and outer layers as discrete spots or islands of adhesive to fix the waterproof and breathable intermediate layer to each of and in between the inner and outer layers.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031" num="00031">
<claim-text><b>31</b>. The composite item of handwear as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00030">claim 30</claim-ref>, in which in at least one region of the main body the discrete spots or islands of adhesive are spaced further apart from each other in one or both of the weft X and warp Y directions than elsewhere in the main body, thus giving that at least one region differential stretch characteristics in one or both of the weft X and warp Y directions than elsewhere in the main body.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
