<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225467A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230710" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225467</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18188871</doc-number>
<date>20230323</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>44</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>17</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>44</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>17</main-group>
<subgroup>001</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="yqwngn6fot4yw">GEMSTONE AND METHODS OF CUTTING THE SAME</invention-title>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17150580</doc-number>
<date>20210115</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11633023</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18188871</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>62961607</doc-number>
<date>20200115</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Albert Gad Ltd.</orgname>
<address>
<city>New York</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>PAIKIN</last-name>
<first-name>Reuven</first-name>
<address>
<city>Windhoek</city>
<country>NA</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A gemstone includes a crown, a pavilion, and a girdle disposed between the crown and the pavilion. The girdle has an elliptical cross-section with a major axis and a minor axis. The surface of the gemstone is generally divided into a number of groups of interlocking facets disposed at a variety of angles. The groups of facets comprising the surface of the crown generally include star facets, upper intermediate crown facets, lower intermediate crown facets, main crown facets, and upper girdle facets. The upper girdle facets generally abut an upper edge of the girdle. The groups of facets comprising the surface of the pavilion include culet-adjacent facets, candle facets, main pavilion facets, and lower girdle facets. The lower girdle facets generally abut a lower edge of the girdle.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="157.90mm" wi="476.76mm" file="US20230225467A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="227.67mm" wi="153.92mm" file="US20230225467A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="241.13mm" wi="153.92mm" file="US20230225467A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="219.54mm" wi="158.92mm" file="US20230225467A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="219.71mm" wi="158.92mm" file="US20230225467A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="204.89mm" wi="150.88mm" file="US20230225467A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="221.32mm" wi="156.46mm" file="US20230225467A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="238.34mm" wi="114.13mm" file="US20230225467A1-20230720-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="238.34mm" wi="114.13mm" file="US20230225467A1-20230720-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="111.17mm" wi="114.13mm" file="US20230225467A1-20230720-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="238.34mm" wi="114.30mm" file="US20230225467A1-20230720-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="242.23mm" wi="140.04mm" file="US20230225467A1-20230720-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="lead"?>
<heading level="1" id="h-0001">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present application claims the benefit of and priority to U.S. Provisional Patent Application No. 62/961,607, filed Jan. 15, 2020, which is hereby incorporated by reference herein in its entirety.</p>
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="tail"?>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading level="1" id="h-0002">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates to gemstones, more specifically, the present disclosure relates to a pattern of facets of gemstones.</p>
<heading level="1" id="h-0003">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Some gemstones are designed/cut to produce a desirable amount of brilliance, or &#x201c;sparkle&#x201d; by forming or cutting a number of individual facets on the exterior surface of the gemstone. Other gemstones are designed/cut to enhance a natural color (e.g., yellow, pink, etc.) of the gemstone. However, it can be difficult to produce a gemstone having a layout of facets at specific angles that produce both a desirable amount of brilliance and also enhance the natural color of the gemstone.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The present disclosure is directed to solving these problems and addressing other needs.</p>
<heading level="1" id="h-0004">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">According to some implementations of the present disclosure, a gemstone comprises a girdle, a crown, and a pavilion. The girdle defines a perimeter of the gemstone and has a cushion-shaped cross-section with a major axis and a minor axis, the major axis being larger than the minor axis. The crown forms an upper portion of the gemstone. A surface of the crown includes: a table forming a generally horizontal upper surface of the crown; a plurality of star facets, each of the plurality of star facets being disposed adjacent to and abutting an edge of the table; a plurality of upper intermediate crown facets, each of the plurality of upper intermediate crown facets being disposed generally between two of the plurality of star facets, an upper vertex of each of the plurality of upper intermediate crown facets abutting a vertex of the table; a plurality of lower intermediate crown facets, each of the plurality of lower intermediate crown facets being disposed between two of the plurality of upper intermediate crown facets, an upper vertex of each of the plurality of lower intermediate crown facets abutting a lower vertex of one of the plurality of star facets; a plurality of main crown facets, each of the plurality of main crown facets being disposed between two of the plurality of lower intermediate crown facets, an upper vertex of each of the plurality of main crown facets abutting a lower vertex of one of the plurality of lower intermediate crown facets, the plurality of main crown facets including a plurality of major main crown facets and a plurality of minor main crown facets, the plurality of major main crown facets being aligned along the maj or axis, the plurality of minor main crown facets being aligned along the minor axis; and a plurality of upper girdle facets formed in pairs of adjacent upper girdle facets, each pair of adjacent upper girdle facets being disposed generally between two of the plurality of main crown facets, upper vertices of both upper girdle facets in each pair of upper girdle facets abutting a lower vertex of one of the plurality of lower intermediate crown facets. The pavilion forms a lower portion of the gemstone. A surface of the pavilion includes a plurality of culet-adjacent facets forming a lower point of the pavilion, the plurality of culet-adjacent facets including a plurality of major culet-adjacent facets and a plurality of minor culet-adjacent facets, the plurality of major culet-adjacent facets being aligned along the maj or axis, the plurality of minor culet-adj acent facets being aligned along the minor axis; a plurality of candle facets, a lower portion of each of the plurality of candle facets being disposed generally between two of the plurality of culet-adjacent facets; a plurality of main pavilion facets, each of the main pavilion facets being disposed between two of the plurality of candle facets, a lower edge of each of the plurality of main pavilion facets abutting an upper edge of one of the plurality of culet-adjacent facets, the plurality of main pavilion facets including a plurality of major main pavilion facets and a plurality of minor main pavilion facets, the plurality of major main pavilion facets being aligned along the major axis, the plurality of minor main pavilion facets being aligned along the minor axis; and a plurality of lower girdle facets formed in pairs of adjacent lower girdle facets, each pair of adjacent lower girdle facets being disposed generally between two of the plurality of main pavilion facets, each pair of adjacent lower girdle facets having an upper portion of a respective one of the plurality of candle facets disposed generally therebetween. Each of the plurality of upper girdle facets is disposed adjacent to and abuts an upper edge of the girdle. Each of the plurality of lower girdle facets is disposed adjacent to and abuts a lower edge of the girdle.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">According to some implementations of the present disclosure, a gemstone comprises a girdle and crown. The girdle forms a perimeter of the gemstone and has a cushion-shaped cross-section. The crown forms an upper portion of the gemstone. The surface of the crown includes a table forming a generally horizontal upper surface of the crown; a plurality of star facets, each of the plurality of star facets being disposed adjacent to and abutting an edge of the table; a plurality of upper intermediate crown facets, each of the plurality of upper intermediate crown facets being disposed generally between two of the plurality of star facets, an upper vertex of each of the plurality of upper intermediate crown facets abutting a vertex of the table; a plurality of lower intermediate crown facets, each of the plurality of lower intermediate crown facets being disposed between two of the plurality of upper intermediate crown facets, an upper vertex of each of the plurality of lower intermediate crown facets abutting a lower vertex of one of the plurality of star facets; a plurality of main crown facets, each of the plurality of main crown facets being disposed between two of the plurality of lower intermediate crown facets, an upper vertex of each of the plurality of main crown facets abutting a lower vertex of one of the plurality of lower intermediate crown facets; and a plurality of upper girdle facets formed in pairs of adjacent upper girdle facets, each pair of adjacent upper girdle facets being disposed generally between two of the plurality of main crown facets, upper vertices of both upper girdle facets in each pair of upper girdle facets abutting a lower vertex of one of the plurality of lower intermediate crown facets.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">According to some implementations of the present disclosure, a gemstone comprises a girdle and a pavilion. The girdle forms a perimeter of the gemstone and has a cushion-shaped cross-section. The pavilion forms a lower portion of the gemstone. A surface of the pavilion includes a plurality of culet-adjacent facets forming a lower point of the pavilion; a plurality of candle facets, a lower portion of each of the plurality of candle facets being disposed generally between two of the plurality of culet-adjacent facets; a plurality of main pavilion facets, each of the plurality of main pavilion facets being disposed between two of the plurality of candle facets, a lower edge of each of the plurality of main pavilion facets abutting an upper edge of one of the plurality of culet-adjacent facets; and a plurality of lower girdle facets formed in pairs of adjacent lower girdle facets, each pair of adjacent lower girdle facets being disposed generally between two of the plurality of main pavilion facets, each pair of adjacent lower girdle facets having an upper portion of a respective one of the plurality of candle facets disposed generally therebetween.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">According to some implementations of the present disclosure, a gemstone comprises a girdle, a crown, and a pavilion. The girdle forms a perimeter of the gemstone and has a cushion-shaped cross-section. The crown forms an upper portion of the gemstone. A surface of the crown includes a table forming a generally horizontal upper surface of the crown, the table having a generally octagonal shape; a plurality of star facets disposed adjacent to the table, each of the plurality of star facets being triangle-shaped; a plurality of upper intermediate crown facets disposed adjacent to the plurality of star facets, each of the plurality of upper intermediate crown facets being kite-shaped; a plurality of lower intermediate crown facets disposed adjacent to the plurality of upper intermediate crown facets, each of the plurality of lower intermediate crown facets being kite-shaped; a plurality of main crown facets disposed adjacent to the plurality of lower intermediate crown facets, each of the plurality of main crown facets being kite-shaped; and a plurality of upper girdle facets disposed adjacent to the plurality of main crown facets, each of the plurality of upper girdle facets being triangle-shaped. The pavilion forms a lower portion of the gemstone. A surface of the pavilion includes a plurality of culet-adjacent facets forming a lower point of the pavilion, each of the plurality of culet-adjacent facets having a generally pentagonal shape; a plurality of candle facets disposed adjacent to the plurality of culet-adjacent facets, each of the plurality of candle facets having six edges; a plurality of main pavilion facets, each of the main pavilion facets being disposed between two of the plurality of candle facets and being pentagon-shaped; and a plurality of lower girdle facets formed in pairs of adjacent lower girdle facets, each pair of adjacent lower girdle facets being disposed generally between two of the plurality of main pavilion facets, each lower girdle facet having four edges. The girdle is positioned between the crown and the pavilion. Each of the plurality of upper girdle facets is disposed adjacent to and abuts an upper edge of the girdle. Each of the plurality of lower girdle facets is disposed adjacent to and abuts a lower edge of the girdle.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">According to some implementations of the present disclosure, a gemstone comprises a crown, a pavilion, and a girdle. The crown forms an upper portion of the gemstone. The pavilion forms a lower portion of the gemstone. The girdle is positioned between the crown and the pavilion, and encircles the gemstone. The girdle has a cushion-shaped cross-section with a major axis and a minor axis, the major axis being larger than the minor axis. The gemstone has a top depth percentage between about 15% and about 35%, and a bottom depth percentage between about 45% and about 60%.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">According to some implementations of the present disclosure, a gemstone comprises a crown, a pavilion, and a girdle. The crown forms an upper portion of the gemstone. The pavilion forms a lower portion of the gemstone. The girdle is positioned between the crown and the pavilion, and encircles the gemstone. The girdle has a cushion-shaped cross-section with a major axis and a minor axis, the major axis being larger than the minor axis. The gemstone has a total depth percentage between about 75% and about 95%.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">According to some implementations of the present disclosure, a gemstone comprises a crown forming an upper portion of the gemstone and a pavilion forming a lower portion of the gemstone. The surface of the crown is defined by a first plurality of facets, each of the first plurality of facets being disposed at an angle between about 5&#xb0; and about 60&#xb0; relative to an upper surface of the gemstone. The surface of the pavilion is defined by a second plurality of facets, each of the second plurality of facets being disposed at an angle between about 25&#xb0; and about 60&#xb0; relative to the upper surface of the gemstone.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">According to some implementations of the present disclosure, a method of forming a crown of a gemstone comprises forming a generally horizontal upper surface on an upper portion of the gemstone; forming a first temporary set of crown facets and a second temporary set of crown facets on the upper portion of the gemstone, the first temporary set of crown facets being formed at an angle of between about 37&#xb0; and about 45&#xb0; relative to the first preliminary table, the second temporary set of crown facets being formed at an angle of between about 42&#xb0; and about 49&#xb0; relative to the first preliminary table; forming a third temporary set of crown facets on the upper portion of the gemstone from portions of the generally horizontal upper surface, the first temporary set of crown facets, and the second temporary set of crown facets, the third temporary set of crown facets being formed at an angle of between about 25&#xb0; and about 35&#xb0; relative to the generally horizontal upper surface, a remainder of the first temporary set of crown facets forming a fourth temporary set of crown facets, a remainder of the second temporary set of crown facets forming a fifth temporary set of crown facets; forming a sixth temporary set of crown facets on the upper portion of the gemstone from portions of the generally horizontal upper surface and the third temporary set of crown facets, the sixth temporary set of crown facets being formed at an angle of between about 15&#xb0; and about 24&#xb0; relative to the generally horizontal upper surface, a remainder of the third temporary set of crown facets forming a first final set of crown facets; forming a second final set of crown facets on the upper portion of the gemstone from portions of the fourth temporary set of crown facets and the fifth temporary set of crown facets, the second final set of crown facets being formed at an angle of between about 42.5&#xb0; and about 57&#xb0; relative to the generally horizontal upper surface, a remainder of the fourth temporary set of crown facets forming a third final set of crown facets, a remainder of the fifth temporary set of crown facets forming a fourth final set of crown facets; and forming a fifth final set of crown facets on the upper portion of the gemstone from portions of the generally horizontal surface and the sixth temporary set of crown facets, the fifth final set of crown facets being formed at an angle of between about 10&#xb0; and about 17&#xb0; relative to the generally horizontal upper surface, a remainder of the sixth temporary set of crown facets forming a sixth final set of crown facets, such that the upper portion of the gemstone is formed from the first, second, third, fourth, fifth, and sixth final sets of crown facets.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">According to some implementations of the present disclosure, a method of forming a pavilion of a gemstone having a horizontal upper surface comprises forming a first temporary set of pavilion facets, a second temporary set of pavilion facets, and a flat lower facet on a lower portion of the gemstone, the first temporary set of pavilion facets being formed at an angle of between about 41&#xb0; and about 45&#xb0; relative to the horizontal upper surface, the second temporary set of pavilion facets being formed at an angle of between about 45&#xb0; and about 49&#xb0; relative to the horizontal upper surface; forming a third temporary set of pavilion facets and a fourth temporary set of pavilion facets on the lower portion of the gemstone, the third temporary set of pavilion facets being formed from the first temporary set of pavilion facets and the flat lower facet, and being formed at an angle of between about 32&#xb0; and about 38&#xb0; relative to the horizontal upper surface, the fourth temporary set of pavilion facets being formed from the second temporary set of pavilion facets and the flat lower facet, and being formed at an angle of between about 36&#xb0; and about 42&#xb0; relative to the horizontal upper surface, a remainder of the first temporary set of pavilion facets forming a fifth temporary set of pavilion facets; a remainder of the second temporary set of pavilion facets forming a sixth temporary set of pavilion facets; forming a seventh temporary set of pavilion facets on the lower portion of the gemstone from portions of third temporary set of pavilion facets, the fourth temporary set of pavilion facets, the fifth temporary set of pavilion facets, and the sixth temporary set of pavilion facets, the seventh set of temporary pavilion facets being formed at an angle of between about 40&#xb0; and about 42&#xb0; relative to the horizontal upper surface, a remainder of the third temporary set of pavilion facets forming a first final set of pavilion facets, a remainder of the fourth temporary set of pavilion facets forming an second final set of pavilion facets, a remainder of the fifth temporary set of pavilion facets forming an eighth temporary set of pavilion facets, a remainder of the sixth temporary set of pavilion facets forming a ninth temporary set of pavilion facets; and forming a third final set of pavilion facets on the lower portion of the gemstone from the seventh temporary set of pavilion facets, the eighth temporary set of pavilion facets, and the ninth temporary set of pavilion facets, the third final set of pavilion facets being formed at an angle of between about 43&#xb0; and about 57&#xb0; relative to the horizontal upper surface, a remainder of the seventh temporary set of pavilion facets forming a fourth final set of pavilion facets, a remainder of the eighth temporary set of pavilion facets forming a fifth final set of pavilion facets, a remainder of the ninth temporary set of pavilion facets forming a sixth final set of pavilion facets, such that the lower portion of the gemstone is formed from the first, second, third, fourth, fifth, and sixth final sets of pavilion facets.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The foregoing and additional aspects and implementations of the present disclosure will be apparent to those of ordinary skill in the art in view of the detailed description of various embodiments and/or implementations, which is made with reference to the drawings, a brief description of which is provided next.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading level="1" id="h-0005">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The foregoing and other advantages of the present disclosure will become apparent upon reading the following detailed description and upon reference to the drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref> is a first elevation view of a gemstone along a minor axis, according to some implementations of the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>B</figref> is a second elevation view of the gemstone of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref> along a major axis, according to some implementation of the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a top plan view of the gemstone of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A and <b>1</b>B</figref>, according to some implementations of the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a bottom plan view of the gemstone of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A and <b>1</b>B</figref>, according to some implementations of the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>A</figref> is a perspective view of the gemstone of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A and <b>1</b>B</figref> viewed at a downward angle, according to some implementations of the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>B</figref> is a perspective view of the gemstone of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A and <b>1</b>B</figref> viewed at an upward angle, according to some implementations of the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b>A</figref> illustrates a first step of a method of forming a crown of the gemstone of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A and <b>1</b>B</figref>, according to some implementations of the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b>B</figref> illustrates a second step of the method of forming the crown of the gemstone of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A and <b>1</b>B</figref>, according to some implementations of the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b>C</figref> illustrates a third step of the method of forming the crown of the gemstone of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A and <b>1</b>B</figref>, according to some implementations of the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b>D</figref> illustrates a fourth step of the method of forming the crown of the gemstone of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A and <b>1</b>B</figref>, according to some implementations of the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b>E</figref> illustrates a fifth step of the method of forming the crown of the gemstone of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A and <b>1</b>B</figref>, according to some implementations of the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref> illustrates a first step of a method of forming a pavilion of the gemstone of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A and <b>1</b>B</figref>, according to some implementations of the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>B</figref> illustrates a second step of the method of forming the pavilion of the gemstone of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A and <b>1</b>B</figref>, according to some implementations of the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>C</figref> illustrates a third step of the method of forming the pavilion of the gemstone of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A and <b>1</b>B</figref>, according to some implementations of the present disclosure; and</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>D</figref> illustrates a fourth step of the method of forming the pavilion of the gemstone of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A and <b>1</b>B</figref>, according to some implementations of the present disclosure.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">While the present disclosure is susceptible to various modifications and alternative forms, specific implementations and embodiments have been shown by way of example in the drawings and will be described in detail herein. It should be understood, however, that the present disclosure is not intended to be limited to the particular forms disclosed. Rather, the present disclosure is to cover all modifications, equivalents, and alternatives falling within the spirit and scope of the present disclosure as defined by the appended claims.</p>
<heading level="1" id="h-0006">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A and <b>1</b>B</figref> illustrate elevation views of an implementation of the gemstone <b>1</b>. The gemstone <b>1</b> is generally divided into a crown <b>10</b> formed as the upper portion of the gemstone <b>1</b>, a pavilion <b>30</b> formed as the lower portion of the gemstone <b>1</b>, and a girdle <b>50</b>, which is generally disposed between the crown <b>10</b> and the pavilion <b>30</b>. The girdle <b>50</b> generally encircles the entire circumference of the gemstone <b>1</b>. The crown <b>10</b> generally has a flat top surface (as seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>), referred to as a table <b>12</b>. The lower portion of the gemstone <b>1</b> at the pavilion <b>30</b> can terminate in a lower point <b>33</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A and <b>1</b>B</figref>, or can terminate in a flat facet called a culet. The gemstone <b>1</b> is generally a precious stone, such as but not limited to a diamond, ruby, emerald, sapphire, or pearl. The gemstone <b>1</b> can also be a synthetic material, such as cubic zirconium. More broadly, the gemstone <b>1</b> can include any material capable of being cut, such as, for example, precious or non-precious stones, cubic zirconia, ceramic, metal, plastic, wood, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The girdle <b>50</b> is generally the widest portion of the gemstone <b>1</b>. When the gemstone <b>1</b> is viewed from above or below (e.g., the view in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b> and <b>3</b></figref>, respectively), the girdle <b>50</b> defines the outer perimeter of the gemstone <b>1</b>. The gemstone <b>1</b> has a cushion shape, which is generally a rectangle, but with rounded corners instead of right-angled corners. Thus, the girdle <b>50</b> and the perimeter of the gemstone <b>1</b> have a cushion-shaped a cross-section, which is generally rectangular with rounded corners. The cross section of the girdle <b>50</b> and the gemstone <b>1</b> has a major axis A<sub>1</sub> and a minor axis A<sub>2</sub> that are generally perpendicular to each other. The dimension of the gemstone <b>1</b> along the major axis A<sub>1</sub> is larger than the dimension of the gemstone <b>1</b> along the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. Viewing <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref>, the minor axis A<sub>2</sub> extends horizontally relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref>, while the major axis A<sub>1</sub> (not shown) extends into and out of the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref>. Viewing <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>B</figref>, the major axis A<sub>1</sub> extends horizontally relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>B</figref>, while the minor axis A<sub>2</sub> (not shown) extends into and out of the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>B</figref>. In some implementations however, the girdle <b>50</b> and the perimeter of the gemstone <b>1</b> have a generally square cross-section with rounded corners, such that the dimensions of the gemstone <b>1</b> along the axes are generally equal. It is understood that as used herein, the term cushion-shaped generally refers to either a rectangular or square shape with rounded corners.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The dimensional characteristics of the gemstone <b>1</b> are based off of the width of the gemstone <b>1</b>. The width of the gemstone <b>1</b> can also be expressed as the diameter of the girdle <b>50</b>. The gemstone <b>1</b> has a table percentage that is a measure of a width or diameter of the table of the gemstone <b>1</b>. The table can be formed in a variety of shapes, as thus the measure of the width of the table can vary. In an implementation, the table is a circle, and thus the diameter of the circle is used to express the table percentage of the gemstone <b>1</b>. In another implementation, the table is an octagon, and either the distance between opposing edges of the octagon or between opposing vertices of the octagon is used to express the table percentage. The table percentage is generally expressed as the width of the table <b>12</b> divided by the width of the gemstone <b>1</b>. In an implementation, the table percentage is between about 31.5% and about 35.5%. In a further implementation, the table percentage is between about 30% and about 40%. In an additional implementation, the table percentage is between about 25% and about 45%. In yet a further implementation the table percentage is about 33.5%.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The gemstone <b>1</b> has a top depth percentage that is a measure of the height of the crown <b>10</b> of the gemstone <b>1</b>. The top depth percentage is generally expressed as the height of the crown <b>10</b> divided by the width of the gemstone <b>1</b>. In an implementation, the top depth percentage is between about 24.5% and about 28.5%. In another implementation, the top depth percentage is between about 20% and about 30%. In a further implementation, the top depth percentage is between about 15% and about 35%. In yet a further implementation the top depth percentage is about 26.2%.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The gemstone <b>1</b> has a bottom depth percentage that is a measure of the total height of the pavilion <b>30</b> of the gemstone <b>1</b>. The bottom depth percentage is generally expressed as the height of the pavilion <b>30</b> divided by the width of the gemstone <b>1</b>. In an implementation, the bottom depth percentage is between about 48.5% and about 52.5%. In another implementation, the bottom depth percentage is between about 45% and about 55%. In a further implementation the bottom depth percentage is between about 40% and about 60 %. In still another implementation, the bottom depth percentage is about 47.6%.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The gemstone <b>1</b> has a girdle thickness percentage that is a measure of the total height of the girdle <b>50</b> of the gemstone <b>1</b>. The girdle thickness percentage is generally expressed as the height of the girdle <b>50</b> divided by the width of the gemstone <b>1</b>. In an implementation, the girdle thickness percentage is between about 4% and about 10%. In another implementation, the girdle thickness percentage is between about 6% and about 8%. In a further implementation, the girdle thickness percentage is between about 2% and about 12%. In yet a further implementation the girdle thickness percentage is about 7.6%.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The gemstone <b>1</b> has a total depth percentage that is a measure of the total height of the gemstone <b>1</b>. The total depth percentage is generally expressed as the height of the gemstone <b>1</b> divided by the width of the gemstone <b>1</b>. The total depth percentage may also be expressed as the sum of the top depth percentage, the bottom depth percentage, and the girdle thickness percentage. In an implementation, the total depth percentage is between about 82.5% and about 86.5%. In another implementation, the total depth percentage is between about 80% and about 90%. In further implementation, the total depth percentage is between about 75% and about 95%. In yet a further implementation the total depth percentage is about 84.5%.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The surface of the gemstone <b>1</b> is generally divided into a number of groups of interlocking facets disposed at a variety of angles. The facets comprising the surface of the crown <b>10</b> generally include a table <b>12</b>, star facets, upper intermediate crown facets, lower intermediate crown facets, main crown facets, and upper girdle facets. The star facets include major star facets <b>14</b>A and minor star facets <b>14</b>B. The upper intermediate crown facets include major upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>A, minor upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>B, and median upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>C. The lower intermediate crown facets include major lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A and minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>B. The main crown facets include central major main crown facets <b>20</b>A, outer major main crown facets <b>20</b>B, and minor main crown facets <b>22</b>. The upper girdle facets include major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A, minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B, and median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C. The major, minor, and median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A, <b>24</b>B, <b>24</b>C generally abut an upper edge of the girdle <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The groups of facets comprising the surface of the pavilion <b>30</b> include culet-adjacent facets, candle facets, main pavilion facets, and lower girdle facets. The culet-adjacent facets include central major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>A, outer major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>B, and minor culet-adjacent facets <b>34</b>. The candle facets include candle facets <b>36</b>. The main pavilion facets include central major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A, outer major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>B, and minor main pavilion facets <b>40</b>. The lower girdle facets include major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A, minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B, and median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C. The major, minor, and median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A, <b>42</b>B, <b>42</b>C generally abut a lower edge of the girdle <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">In an implementation, the girdle <b>50</b> is a continuous cushion-shaped facet that encircles the entirety of the gemstone <b>1</b>. In another implementation, the girdle <b>50</b> is divided into a plurality of sub-facets. In yet another implementation, each sub-facet of the girdle <b>50</b> comprises a plurality of individual facets. The upper edge of the girdle <b>50</b> that abuts the crown <b>10</b> may be generally straight or may be curved. The lower edge of the girdle <b>50</b> that abuts the pavilion <b>30</b> may be generally straight or may be curved.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The angles that each of the facets of the crown <b>10</b> are disposed at may be measured relative to a horizontal plane defined by the table of the gemstone <b>1</b> (e.g. the top surface of the gemstone <b>1</b>). As shown in the upper set of axes in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A and <b>1</b>B</figref>, each of the facets of the crown <b>10</b> is formed at an angle &#x3b8;<sub>C</sub> relative to the horizontal plane defined by the table of the gemstone <b>1</b>. As is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A and <b>1</b>B</figref>, the angle &#x3b8;<sub>C</sub> that each of the facets of the crown <b>10</b> are disposed at is formed by rotating in a clockwise direction downward from the horizontal plane defined by the table.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Generally, every facet within a group of facets is disposed at the same angle or at an angle within the same range. For example, all of the major star facets <b>14</b>A are disposed at the same angle or at an angle within the same range as the minor star facets <b>14</b>B. Similarly, all of the major, minor, and median upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>A, <b>16</b>B, <b>16</b>C are disposed at the same angle or at an angle with the same range, etc. In some implementations, the range of angles for different groups of facets can overlap, such that two facets within two different groups of facets may have identical or substantially identical angles. Generally, each facets within a group of facets (e.g., all of the star facets, all of the main crown facets, etc.) has the same shape. However, as is discussed in more detail below, due to the oval or elliptical shape of the gemstone, some facets within a group of facets have different shapes.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">In an implementation, the angle of the major and minor star facets <b>14</b>A, <b>14</b>B is between about 10&#xb0; and about 17&#xb0;. In another implementation, the angle of the major and minor star facets <b>14</b>A, <b>14</b>B is between about 5&#xb0; and about 20&#xb0;. In a further implementation, the angle of the major and minor star facets <b>14</b>A, <b>14</b>B is about 12.5&#xb0;.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">In an implementation, the angle of the major, minor, and median upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>A, <b>16</b>B, <b>16</b>C is between about 15&#xb0; and about 24&#xb0;. In another implementation, the angle of the major, minor, and median upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>A, <b>16</b>B, <b>16</b>C is between about 10&#xb0; and about 30&#xb0;. In a further implementation, the angle of the major, minor, and median upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>A, <b>16</b>B, <b>16</b>C is between about 17&#xb0; and about 21&#xb0;. In yet another implementation, the angle of the major, minor, and median upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>A, <b>16</b>B, <b>16</b>C is about 18.5&#xb0;.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">In an implementation, the angle of the major and minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A, <b>18</b>B is about between about 25&#xb0; and about 35&#xb0;. In another implementation, the angle of the major and minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A, <b>18</b>B is between about 25&#xb0; and about 35&#xb0;. In still another implementation, the angle of the major and minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A, <b>18</b>B is between about 20&#xb0; and about 40&#xb0;. In a further implementation, the angle of the major and minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A, <b>18</b>B is between about 29&#xb0; and about 32&#xb0;. In yet another further implementation, the angle of the major and minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A, <b>18</b>B is about 30.5&#xb0;.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">In an implementation, the angle of the central and outer major main crown facets <b>20</b>A, <b>20</b>B is between about 37&#xb0; and about 45&#xb0;. In another implementation, the angle of the central and outer major main crown facets <b>20</b>A, <b>20</b>B is between about 35&#xb0; and about 50&#xb0;. In still another implementation, the angle of the central and outer major main crown facets <b>20</b>A, <b>20</b>B is between about 30&#xb0; and about 55&#xb0;. In a further implementation, the angle of the central and outer major main crown facets <b>20</b>A, <b>20</b>B is between about 39&#xb0; and about 40&#xb0;. In yet another implementation, the angle of the central and outer major main crown facets <b>20</b>A, <b>20</b>B is about 39.5&#xb0;.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">In an implementation, the angle of the minor main crown facets <b>22</b> is between about 42&#xb0; and about 49&#xb0;. In another implementation, the angle of the minor main crown facets <b>22</b> is between about 40&#xb0; and about 50&#xb0;. In yet another implementation, the angle of the minor main crown facets <b>22</b> is between about 35&#xb0; and about 55&#xb0;. In still another implementation, the angle of the minor main crown facets <b>22</b> is between about 44&#xb0; and about 51&#xb0;. In a further implementation, the angle of the minor main crown facets <b>22</b> is between about 45&#xb0; and about 46&#xb0;. In yet another implementation, the angle of the minor main crown facets <b>22</b> is about 45.5&#xb0;.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">In an implementation, the angle of the major, minor, and median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A, <b>24</b>B, <b>24</b>C is between about 42.5&#xb0; and about 57&#xb0;. In a further implementation, the angle of the major, minor, and median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A, <b>24</b>B, <b>24</b>C is between about 40&#xb0; and about 60&#xb0;. In a further implementation, the angle of the major, minor, and median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A, <b>24</b>B, <b>24</b>C is between about 44&#xb0; and about 51&#xb0;. In a further implementation, the angle of the major, minor, and median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A, <b>24</b>B, <b>24</b>C is about 47.5&#xb0;.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The angles that each of the facets of the pavilion <b>30</b> are disposed at may also be measured relative to the horizontal plane defined by the table of the gemstone <b>1</b> (e.g. the top surface of the gemstone <b>1</b>). As shown in the lower set of axes in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A and <b>1</b>B</figref>, each of the facets of the pavilion <b>30</b> is formed at an angle &#x3b8;<sub>P</sub> relative to this horizontal plane defined by the table of the gemstone <b>1</b>. As is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A and <b>1</b>B</figref>, the angle &#x3b8;<sub>P</sub> that each of the facets of the pavilion <b>30</b> are disposed at is formed by rotating in a counterclockwise direction upward from the horizontal plane defined by the table.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">In an implementation, the angle of the major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b> is between about 32&#xb0; and about 38&#xb0;. In another implementation, the angle of the major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b> is between about 30&#xb0; and about 40&#xb0;. In still another implementation, the angle of the major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b> is between about 25&#xb0; and about 45&#xb0;. In a further implementation, the angle of the major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b> is between about 34&#xb0; and about 35&#xb0;. In yet another implementation, the angle of the major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b> is about 35&#xb0;.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">In an implementation, the angle of the minor culet-adjacent facets <b>34</b> is between about 36&#xb0; and about 42&#xb0;. In another implementation, the angle of the minor culet-adjacent facets <b>34</b> is between about 35&#xb0; and about 45&#xb0;. In still another implementation, the angle of the minor culet-adjacent facets <b>34</b> is between about 30&#xb0; and about 50&#xb0;. In a further implementation, the angle of the minor culet-adjacent facets <b>34</b> is between about 38&#xb0; and about 39&#xb0;. In yet another implementation, the angle of the minor culet-adjacent facets <b>34</b> is about 38.5&#xb0;.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">In an implementation, the angle of the candle facets <b>36</b> is between about 40&#xb0; and about 42&#xb0;. In another implementation, the angle of the candle facets <b>36</b> is between about 35&#xb0; and about 45&#xb0;. In another implementation, the angle of the candle facets <b>36</b> is between about 30&#xb0; and about 50&#xb0;. In a further implementation, the angle of the candle facets <b>36</b> is between about 41&#xb0; and about 44&#xb0;. In yet another implementation, the angle of the candle facets <b>36</b> is about 42&#xb0;.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">In an implementation, the angle of the central and outer major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A, <b>38</b>B is between about 41&#xb0; and about 45&#xb0;. In another implementation, the angle of the central and outer major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A, <b>38</b>B is between about 40&#xb0; and about 50&#xb0;. In still another implementation, the angle of the central and outer major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A, <b>38</b>B is between about 35&#xb0; and about 55&#xb0;. In a further implementation, the angle of the central and outer major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A, <b>38</b>B is between about 43&#xb0; and about 44&#xb0;. In yet another implementation, the angle of the central and outer major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A, <b>38</b>B is about 43.5&#xb0;.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">In an implementation, the angle of the minor main pavilion facets <b>40</b> is between about 45&#xb0; and about 49&#xb0;. In another implementation, the angle of the minor main pavilion facets <b>40</b> is between about 40&#xb0; and about 50&#xb0;. In a further implementation, the angle of the minor main pavilion facets <b>40</b> is between about 35&#xb0; and about 55&#xb0;. In yet another implementation, the angle of the minor main pavilion facets <b>40</b> is between about 47&#xb0; and about 48&#xb0;. In yet a further implementation, the angle of the minor main pavilion facets <b>40</b> is about 47.5&#xb0;.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">In an implementation, the angle of the major, minor, and median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A, <b>42</b>B, <b>42</b>C is between about 43&#xb0; and about 57&#xb0;. In another implementation, the angle of the major, minor, and median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A, <b>42</b>B, <b>42</b>C is between about 40&#xb0; and about 60&#xb0;. In yet another implementation, the angle of the major, minor, and median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A, <b>42</b>B, <b>42</b>C is between about 45&#xb0; and about 52&#xb0;. In yet a further implementation, the angle of the major, minor, and median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A, <b>42</b>B, <b>42</b>C is about 48&#xb0;.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, a top plan view of the gemstone <b>1</b> showing the crown <b>10</b> is illustrated. The major axis A<sub>1</sub> of the perimeter of the gemstone (which is formed by the girdle <b>50</b>) extends horizontally relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, while the minor axis A<sub>2</sub> extends vertically relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>. The major and minor axes A<sub>1</sub> and A<sub>2</sub> generally divide the facets of the crown <b>10</b> into a first quadrant <b>11</b>A, a second quadrant <b>11</b>B, a third quadrant <b>11</b>C, and fourth quadrant <b>11</b>D. The first quadrant <b>11</b>A generally corresponds to the top-right corner region of the crown <b>10</b> relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>. The second quadrant <b>11</b>B generally corresponds to the top-left corner region of the crown <b>10</b> relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>. The third quadrant <b>11</b>C generally corresponds to the bottom-left corner region of the crown <b>10</b> relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>. The fourth quadrant <b>11</b>D generally corresponds to the bottom-right corner region of the crown <b>10</b> relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">The terms &#x201c;top,&#x201d; &#x201c;bottom,&#x201d; &#x201c;left,&#x201d; &#x201c;right,&#x201d; &#x201c;above,&#x201d; below,&#x201d; etc. are used herein to refer to the locations of the various facets on the crown <b>10</b>. However, those of skill in the art will understand that these are relative terms that are generally used in reference to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>. Thus, any of these terms used to describe an individual facet may not apply when viewing the crown <b>10</b> from a different perspective. The facets on the surface of the crown <b>10</b> share edges and vertices where the facets meet. When describing the facets on the surface of the crown <b>10</b>, the term &#x201c;upper&#x201d; is used to refer to edges or vertices nearer to the table <b>12</b>, while the term &#x201c;lower&#x201d; is used to refer to edges or vertices nearer to the girdle <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">The crown <b>10</b> includes a number of main crown facets, which include six major main crown facets <b>20</b>A, <b>20</b>B, and two minor main crown facets <b>22</b>. Relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the six major main crown facets <b>20</b>A, <b>20</b>B are generally disposed either to the left or to the right along the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. The major main crown facets <b>20</b>A, <b>20</b>B are divided into two groups of three major main crown facets <b>20</b>A, <b>20</b>B. A left group of three major main crown facets <b>20</b>A, <b>20</b>B is generally disposed along the left side of the major axis A<sub>1</sub>, which is to the left of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. A right group of three major main crown facets <b>20</b>A, <b>20</b>B is generally disposed along the right side of the major axis A<sub>1</sub>, which is to the right of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">The major main crown facets <b>20</b>A, <b>20</b>B within the left group of major main crown facets <b>20</b>A, <b>20</b>B extend generally vertically relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>. In this manner, the three major main crown facets <b>20</b>A, <b>20</b>B within the left group of major main crown facets <b>20</b>A, <b>20</b>B are aligned along an axis that is parallel to and to the left of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. Similarly, the major main crown facets <b>20</b>A, <b>20</b>B within the right group of major main crown facets <b>20</b>A, <b>20</b>B also extend generally vertically relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>. In this manner, the three major main crown facets <b>20</b>A, <b>20</b>B within the right group of major main crown facets <b>20</b>A, <b>20</b>B are aligned along an axis that is parallel to and to the right of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">Each group of three major main crown facets includes a central major main crown facet <b>20</b>A surrounded by two outer major main crown facets <b>20</b>B. The two central major main crown facets <b>20</b>A (e.g. the left and right central major main crown facets <b>20</b>A relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>) are generally aligned along the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. The left central major main crown facet <b>20</b>A extends into both the second quadrant <b>11</b>B and the third quadrant <b>11</b>C. The right central major main crown facet <b>20</b>A extends into both the first quadrant <b>11</b>A and the fourth quadrant <b>11</b>D.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">Relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the two outer major main crown facets <b>20</b>B above the central major main crown facets <b>20</b>A (e.g., the top-right and top-left major main crown facets <b>20</b>B) are aligned along a line parallel to and above the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. Similarly, relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the two outer major main crown facets <b>20</b>B below the central major main crown facets <b>20</b>A (e.g., the bottom-left and bottom-right major main crown facets <b>20</b>B) are aligned along a line parallel to and below the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. The top-right major main crown facet <b>20</b>B is disposed in the first quadrant <b>11</b>A. The top-left major main crown facet <b>20</b>B is disposed in the second quadrant <b>11</b>B. The bottom-left major main crown facet <b>20</b>B is disposed in the third quadrant <b>11</b>C. The bottom-right major main crown facet <b>20</b>B is disposed in the fourth quadrant <b>11</b>D. Generally, at least a portion of each of the major main crown facets <b>20</b>A, <b>20</b>B is disposed between two of the lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A, <b>18</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">The two minor main crown facets <b>22</b> are generally aligned along the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. Relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, one of the minor main crown facets <b>22</b> (e.g., the top minor main crown facet <b>22</b>) is generally disposed along the top side of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>, which is above the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. The other minor main crown facet <b>22</b> (e.g., the bottom minor main crown facet <b>22</b>) is disposed along the bottom side of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>, which is below the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. The top minor main crown facet <b>22</b> generally extends into both the first quadrant <b>11</b>A and the second quadrant <b>11</b>B. The bottom minor main crown facet <b>22</b> generally extends into both the third quadrant <b>11</b>C and the fourth quadrant <b>11</b>D. Generally, at least a portion of each of the minor main crown facets <b>22</b> is disposed between two of the lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A, <b>18</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">Each major main crown facet <b>20</b>A, <b>20</b>B is generally diamond or kite-shaped (e.g., four sides) with an upper vertex, a lower vertex, and two lateral vertices. The lower vertex of each major main crown facet <b>20</b>A, <b>20</b>B abuts the upper edge of the girdle. Similarly, each minor main crown facet <b>22</b> is generally diamond or kite-shaped (e.g., four sides) with an upper vertex, a lower vertex, and two lateral vertices. The lower vertex of each minor main crown facet <b>22</b> abuts the upper edge of the girdle. Each central major main crown facet <b>20</b>A shares first and second edges with two adjacent major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A, and third and fourth edges with two adjacent major lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A. Each outer major main crown facet <b>20</b>B shares first and second edges with two adjacent median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C, a third edge with an adjacent major lower intermediate crown facet <b>18</b>A, and a fourth edge with an adjacent minor lower intermediate crown facet <b>18</b>B. Each minor main crown facet <b>22</b> shares first and second edges with two adjacent minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B, and third and fourth edges with two adjacent minor lower intermediate crown faces <b>18</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">The two lateral vertices of each minor main crown facet <b>22</b> abut the lateral vertex of one of the outer major main crown facets <b>20</b>B. The two lateral vertices of the central major main crown facet <b>20</b>A abut the lateral vertex of one of the outer major main crown facets <b>20</b>B, opposite the lateral vertex of that same outer major main crown facet <b>20</b>B that abuts the lateral vertex of one of the central major main crown facets <b>20</b>A. The lateral vertices of the outer major main crown facets <b>20</b>B of each group of three major main crown facets <b>20</b>A, <b>20</b>B abut one lateral vertex of one of the central major main crown facets <b>20</b>A and one lateral vertex of one of the minor main crown facets <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">The upper vertex of the central major main crown facets <b>20</b>A abuts a lower vertex of an adjacent major upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>A, and a lateral vertex of each of two adjacent major lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A. The upper vertex of each outer major main crown facet <b>20</b>B abuts a lower vertex of an adjacent median upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>C, a lateral vertex of an adjacent major lower intermediate crown facet <b>18</b>A, and a lateral vertex of an adjacent minor lower intermediate crown facet <b>18</b>B. The upper vertex of the minor main crown facets <b>22</b> abuts a lower vertex of an adjacent minor upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>B, and a lateral vertex of each of two adjacent minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">The upper vertex of each of the outer major main crown facets <b>20</b>B is generally shifted away from the nearest central major main crown facet <b>20</b>A, and toward the nearest minor main crown facet <b>22</b>. In this manner, the angle bisector of the upper vertex of the outer major main crown facets <b>20</b>B does not also bisect the angle formed at the lower vertex of the outer major main crown facets <b>20</b>B. In contrast, the angle bisectors of upper and lower vertices of the central major main crown facets <b>20</b>A are generally parallel. In addition, the distance between the lateral vertices of the central major main crown facets <b>20</b>A and the minor main crown facets <b>22</b> is generally greater than the distance between the lateral vertices of the outer major main crown facets <b>20</b>B. Thus, the central major main crown facets <b>20</b>A and the minor main crown facets <b>20</b>B are generally wider than the outer major main crown facets <b>20</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">Thus, while all of the central and outer major main crown facets <b>20</b>A, <b>20</b>B generally have the same angle or an angle within the same range, the central and outer major main crown facets <b>20</b>A, <b>20</b>B can have slightly differ different shapes depending on their location along the crown <b>10</b> of the gemstone <b>1</b>. However, in some implementations, any one of the groups of main crown facets <b>20</b>A, <b>20</b>B, <b>22</b> can have the same size and shape as any of the other groups of main crown facets <b>20</b>A, <b>20</b>B, <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">The crown <b>10</b> includes four major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A, four minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B, and eight median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C. Relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the four major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A are disposed either to the left or to the right on the crown <b>10</b> along the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. The major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A are divided into two groups of two major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A. A left group of two major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A is generally disposed along the left side of the major axis A<sub>1</sub>, which is to the left of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. A right group of two major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A is generally disposed along the right side of the major axis A<sub>1</sub>, which is to the right of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. The major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A within the left group of major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A extend generally vertically relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>. In this manner, the two major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A within the left group of major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A are aligned along an axis that is parallel to and to the left of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. Similarly, the major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A within the right group of major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A also extend generally vertically relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>. In this manner, the two major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A within the right group of major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A are aligned along an axis that is parallel to and to the right of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">One major upper girdle facet <b>24</b>A of the right group of major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A is disposed generally in the first quadrant <b>11</b>A of the crown <b>10</b>. The other major upper girdle facet <b>24</b>A of the right group of major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A is disposed generally in the fourth quadrant <b>11</b>D of the crown <b>10</b>. One major upper girdle facet <b>24</b>A of the left group of major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A is disposed generally in the second quadrant <b>11</b>B of the crown <b>10</b>. The other major upper girdle facet <b>24</b>A of the left group of major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A is disposed generally in the third quadrant <b>11</b>C of the crown <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">Relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the four minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B are disposed either toward the top of the crown <b>10</b>, or toward the bottom of the crown <b>10</b>, along the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. The minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B are divided into two groups of two minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B. A top group of two minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B is generally disposed along the top side of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>, which is above the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. A bottom group of two minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B is generally disposed along the bottom side of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>, which is below the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. The minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B within the top group of minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B extend generally horizontally relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>. In this manner, the two minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B within the top group of minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B are aligned along an axis that is parallel to and above the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. Similarly, the minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B within the bottom group of minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B also extend generally horizontally relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>. In this manner, the two minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B within the bottom group of minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B are aligned along an axis that is parallel to and below the major axis A<sub>1</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">One minor upper girdle facet <b>24</b>B of the top group of minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B is disposed generally in the first quadrant <b>11</b>A of the crown <b>10</b>. The other minor upper girdle facet <b>24</b>B of the top group of minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B is disposed generally in the second quadrant <b>11</b>B of the crown <b>10</b>. One minor upper girdle facet <b>24</b>B of the bottom group of minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B is disposed generally in the third quadrant <b>11</b>C of the crown <b>10</b>. The other minor upper girdle facet <b>24</b>B of the bottom group of minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B is disposed generally in the fourth quadrant <b>11</b>D of the crown <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">Relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the eight median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C are generally positioned diagonally relative to the major axis A<sub>1</sub> and the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. The median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C are divided into four groups of two median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C. A top-right group of median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C is positioned in the first quadrant <b>11</b>A, above the major axis A<sub>1</sub> and to the right of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. A top-left group of median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C is positioned in the second quadrant <b>11</b>B, above the major axis A<sub>1</sub> and to the left of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. A bottom-left group of median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C is positioned in the third quadrant <b>11</b>C, below the major axis A<sub>1</sub> and to the left of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. A bottom-right group of median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C is positioned in the fourth quadrant <b>11</b>D, below the major axis A<sub>1</sub> and to the right of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">Each of the major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A is disposed between one of the central major main crown facets <b>20</b>A, an adjacent one of the outer main crown facets <b>20</b>B, and the upper edge of the girdle <b>50</b>. Each of the major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A has a generally triangular shape. A first edge of each of the major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A is shared with the girdle <b>50</b>, and can be flat or curved depending on the shape of the girdle <b>50</b>. A second edge of each of the major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A is shared with one of the central major main crown facets <b>20</b>A.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">As shown, each of the major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A shares a third edge with an adjacent one of the median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C. One of the left group of major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A shares its third edge with one of the top-left median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C. The other of the left group of major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A shares its third edge with one of the bottom-left median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C. One of the right group of major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A shares its third edge with one of the top-right median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C. The other of the right group of major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A shares its third edge with one of the bottom-right median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C. Thus, each major girdle facet <b>24</b>A is part of a pair of upper girdle facets along with its corresponding median upper girdle facet <b>24</b>C.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">The minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B are disposed in a similar fashion as the major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A. Each of the minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B is disposed between one of the outer major main crown facets <b>20</b>B, an adjacent one of the minor main crown facets <b>22</b>, and the upper edge of the girdle <b>50</b>. Each of the minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B has a generally triangular shape. A first edge of each of the minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B is shared with the girdle <b>50</b>, and can be flat or curved depending on the shape of the girdle <b>50</b>. A second edge of each of the minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B is shared with one of the minor main crown facets <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">As shown, each of the minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B shares a third edge with an adjacent one of the median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C. One of the top group of minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B shares its third edge with one of the top-left median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C. The other of the top group of minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B shares its third edge with one of the top-right median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C. One of the bottom group of minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B shares its third edge with one of the bottom-left median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C. The other of the bottom group of minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B shares its third edge with one of the bottom-right median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C. Thus, each minor girdle facet <b>24</b>B is part of a pair of upper girdle facets along with its corresponding median upper girdle facet <b>24</b>C.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">Each of the median crown facets <b>16</b>C is disposed between the upper edge of the girdle, one of the outer major main crown facets <b>20</b>B, and either (i) an adjacent one of the central major main crown facets <b>20</b>A, or (ii) an adjacent one of the minor main crown facets <b>22</b>. Each of the median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C has a generally triangular shape. A first edge of each of the median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C is shared with the girdle <b>50</b>, and can be flat or curved depending on the shape of the girdle <b>50</b>. A second edge of each of the median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C is shared with one of the outer major main crown facets <b>20</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">As shown, each of the minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B shares a third edge with either (i) an adjacent one of the major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A, or (ii) an adjacent one of the minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B. One of the top-right group of median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C shares its third edge with one of the right group of major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A. The other of the top-right group of median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C shares its third edge with one of the top group of minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B. One of the top-left group of median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C shares its third edge with one of the top group of minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B. The other of the top-left group of median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C shares its third edge with one of the left group of major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A. One of the bottom-left group of median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C shares its third edge with one of the left group of major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A. The other of the bottom-left group of median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C shares its third edge with one of the bottom group of minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B. One of the bottom-right group of median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C shares its third edge with one of the bottom group of minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B. The other of the bottom-right group of median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C shares its third edge with one of the right group of major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A. Thus, each median upper girdle facet <b>24</b>C is part of a pair of upper girdle facets along with either its corresponding major upper girdle facet <b>24</b>A or its corresponding minor upper girdle facet <b>24</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">Each of the major, minor, and median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A, <b>24</b>B, <b>24</b>C has two lower vertices and an upper vertex. Each of the two lower vertices of each respective upper girdle facet abuts both (i) the upper edge of the girdle and (ii) a lower vertex of an adjacent one of the upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A, <b>24</b>B, <b>24</b>C. For the major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A, one of the lower vertices abuts a lower vertex of the other major upper girdle facet <b>24</b>A in the same group (e.g., left or right). The other lower vertex abuts a lower vertex of an adjacent one of the median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C. For the minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B, one of the lower vertices abuts a lower vertex of the other minor upper girdle facet <b>24</b>B in the same group (e.g. top or bottom). The other lower vertex abuts a lower vertex of an adjacent one of the median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C. For the median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C, one of the lower vertices abuts a lower vertex of the other minor upper girdle facet <b>24</b>B in the same group (e.g., top-right, top-left, bottom-left, or bottom-right). The other lower vertex abuts a lower vertex of either (i) one of the major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A or (ii) one of the minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">The upper vertex of each major upper girdle facet <b>24</b>A abuts a vertex of (i) an adjacent one of the median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C, (ii) one of the central major main crown facets <b>20</b>A, (iii) one of the outer major main crown facets <b>20</b>B, and (iv) one of the major lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A. The upper vertex of each minor upper girdle facet <b>24</b>B abuts a vertex of (i), an adjacent one of the median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C (ii) one of the outer major main crown facets <b>20</b>B, (iii) one of the minor main crown facets <b>22</b>, and (iv) one of the minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>B. The upper vertex of each median upper girdle facet <b>24</b>C abuts a vertex of (i), either an adjacent one of the major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A or an adjacent one of the minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B, (ii) one of the outer major main crown facets <b>20</b>B, (iii) either one of the central major main crown facets <b>20</b>A or one of the minor main crown facets <b>22</b>, and (iv) either one of the major lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A or one of the minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">In the illustrated implementation, the lower edge of each major and minor upper girdle facet <b>24</b>A, <b>24</b>B that abuts the upper edge of the girdle is larger than the lower edge of each median upper girdle facet <b>24</b>C that abuts the upper edge of the girdle. Thus, the major and minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A, <b>24</b>B are generally larger than the median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C. However, in other implementations, the lower edge of each major and minor upper girdle facet <b>24</b>A, <b>24</b>B is generally the same length as the lower edge of each median upper girdle facet <b>24</b>C, such that all of the major, minor, and median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A, <b>24</b>B, <b>24</b>C are the same size.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">The crown <b>10</b> includes sixteen lower intermediate crown facets. Major lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A are disposed between the major main crown facets <b>20</b>A, <b>20</b>B, and the table <b>12</b>. Minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>B are disposed between major crown facets <b>20</b>B and minor crown facets <b>22</b>, and the table <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">Relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the major lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A are disposed either to the left or to the right on the crown <b>10</b> along the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. The major lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A are divided into two groups of two major lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A. A left group of two major lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A is generally disposed along the left side of the major axis A<sub>1</sub>, which is to the left of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. A right group of two major lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A is generally disposed along the right side of the major axis A<sub>1</sub>, which is to the right of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">The major lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A within the left group of major lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A extend generally vertically relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>. In this manner, the two major lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A within the left group of major lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A are aligned along an axis that is parallel to and to the left of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. Similarly, the major lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A within the right group of major lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A also extend generally vertically relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>. In this manner, the two major lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A within the right group of major lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A are aligned along an axis that is parallel to and to the right of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. The left group of two major lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A thus includes a top-left major lower intermediate crown facet <b>18</b>A and a bottom-left major lower intermediate crown facet <b>18</b>A. The right group of two major lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A thus includes a top-right major lower intermediate crown facet <b>18</b>A and a bottom-right major lower intermediate crown facet <b>18</b>A.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">Relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>B are disposed either toward the top of the crown <b>10</b> or toward the bottom of the crown <b>10</b>, along the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. The minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>B are divided into two groups of two minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>B. A top group of two minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>B is generally disposed along the top side of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>, which is above the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. A bottom group of two minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>B is generally disposed along the bottom side of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>, which is below the major axis A<sub>1</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">The minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>B within the top group of minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>B extend generally horizontally relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>. In this manner, the two minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>B within the top group of minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>B are aligned along an axis that is parallel to and above the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. Similarly, the minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>B within the bottom group of minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>B also extend generally horizontally relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>. In this manner, the two minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>B within the bottom group of minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>B are aligned along an axis that is parallel to and below the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. The top group of two minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>B thus includes a top-left minor lower intermediate crown facet <b>18</b>B and a top-right minor lower intermediate crown facet <b>18</b>B. The bottom group of two minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>B thus includes a bottom-left minor lower intermediate crown facet <b>18</b>B and a bottom-right major lower intermediate crown facet <b>18</b>A.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">The top-right major and minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A, <b>18</b>B are disposed generally in the first quadrant <b>11</b>A of the crown <b>10</b>. The top-left major and minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A, <b>18</b>B are disposed generally in the second quadrant <b>11</b>B of the crown <b>10</b>. The bottom-left major and minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A, <b>18</b>B are disposed generally in the third quadrant <b>11</b>C of the crown <b>10</b>. The bottom-right major and minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A, <b>18</b>B are disposed generally in the fourth quadrant <b>11</b>D of the crown <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">Each of the major and minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A, <b>18</b>B, are generally diamond or kite-shaped (e.g., four sides) with an upper vertex, a lower vertex, and two lateral vertices. Generally, each of the lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A, <b>18</b>B is disposed between two of the upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>A, <b>16</b>B, <b>16</b>C. An upper portion of each major lower intermediate crown facet <b>18</b>A is positioned between one of the major upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>A and an adjacent one of the median upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>C. A lower portion of each major lower intermediate crown facet <b>18</b>A is positioned between one of the center major main crown facets <b>20</b>A and an adjacent one of the outer major main crown facets <b>20</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">An upper portion of each minor lower intermediate crown facet <b>18</b>B is positioned between one of the minor upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>B and an adjacent one of the median upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>C. A lower portion of each minor lower intermediate crown facet <b>18</b>B is positioned between one of the minor main crown facets <b>22</b> and an adjacent one of the outer maj or main crown facets <b>20</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">A lower vertex of each major lower intermediate crown facet <b>18</b>A abuts a lateral vertex of one of the central major main crown facets <b>20</b>A, a lateral vertex of an adjacent one of the outer major main crown facets <b>20</b>B, the top vertex of one of the major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A, and the top vertex of an adjacent one of the median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C. One lateral vertex of each major lower intermediate crown facet <b>18</b>A abuts the top vertex of one of the central major main crown facets <b>20</b>A, and the lateral vertex of an adjacent major lower intermediate crown facet <b>18</b>A. The other lateral vertex of each major lower intermediate crown facet <b>18</b>A abuts the top vertex of one of the outer major main crown facets <b>20</b>B, and the lateral vertex of an adjacent minor lower intermediate crown facet <b>18</b>B. Each major lower intermediate crown facet <b>18</b>A shares a first edge with one of the central major main crown facets <b>20</b>A, a second edge with one of the outer major main crown facets <b>20</b>B, a third edge with a major upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>A, and a fourth edge with an adjacent median upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>C.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">A lower vertex of each minor lower intermediate crown facet <b>18</b>B abuts a lateral vertex of one of the outer major main crown facets <b>20</b>B, a lateral vertex of an adjacent one of the minor main crown facets <b>22</b>, the top vertex of one of the minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B, and the top vertex of an adjacent one of the median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C. One lateral vertex of each minor lower intermediate crown facet <b>18</b>B abuts the top vertex of one of the outer major main crown facets <b>20</b>B, and the lateral vertex of an adjacent major lower intermediate crown facet <b>18</b>A. The other lateral vertex of each minor lower intermediate crown facet <b>18</b>B abuts the top vertex of one of the minor main crown facets <b>22</b>, and the lateral vertex of an adjacent minor lower intermediate crown facet <b>18</b>B. Each minor lower intermediate crown facet <b>18</b>B shares a first edge with one of the outer major main crown facets <b>20</b>B, a second edge with one of the minor main crown facets <b>22</b>, a third edge with a minor upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>B, and a fourth edge with an adjacent median upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>C.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">The upper vertex of each of the major lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A abuts an upper vertex of a corresponding one of the major star facets <b>14</b>A. Similarly, the upper vertex of each of the minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>B abuts an upper vertex of a corresponding one of the minor star facets <b>14</b>B. The upper vertex of each of the major lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A is generally shifted away from the central major main crown facet <b>20</b>A toward the nearest outer major main crown facet <b>20</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">The upper vertex of each of the minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>B is generally shifted away from the nearest outer major main crown facet <b>20</b>B toward the nearest minor main crown facet <b>22</b>. In this manner, the angle bisector of the upper vertex of each major lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A does not also bisect the angle formed at the lower vertex of each lower intermediate crown facet <b>18</b>A. Similarly, the angle bisector of the upper vertex of the minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>B does not also bisect the angled formed at the lower vertex of each minor lower intermediate crown facet <b>18</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">Thus, while all of the major and minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A, <b>18</b>B generally have the same angle or an angle within the same range, the major and minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A, <b>18</b>B can have different shapes depending on their location along the crown <b>10</b> of the gemstone <b>1</b>. However, in some implementations, the major lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A can have the same size and shape as the minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">The crown <b>10</b> includes eight upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>A, <b>16</b>B, <b>16</b>C, disposed between the major and minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A, <b>18</b>B, and the table <b>12</b>. The upper intermediate crown facets include two major upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>A, two minor upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>B, and two median upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>C.</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">Relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the major upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>A are disposed either to the left or to the right on the crown <b>10</b> along the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. A left major upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>A is generally disposed along the left side of the major axis A<sub>1</sub>, which is to the left of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. A right major upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>A is generally disposed along the right side of the major axis A<sub>1</sub>, which is to the right of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. The left major upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>A generally extends into both the second quadrant <b>11</b>B and the third quadrant <b>11</b>C. The right major upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>A generally extends into both the first quadrant <b>11</b>A and the fourth quadrant <b>11</b>D.</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0098">Relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the minor upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>B are disposed either toward the top of the crown <b>10</b> or toward the bottom of the crown <b>10</b>, along the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. A top minor upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>B is generally disposed along the top side of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>, which is above the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. A bottom minor upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>B is generally disposed along the bottom side of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>, which is below the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. The top minor upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>B generally extends into both the first quadrant <b>11</b>A and the second quadrant <b>11</b>B. The bottom minor upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>B generally extends into both the third quadrant <b>11</b>C and the fourth quadrant <b>11</b>D.</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0099">The four median upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>C are generally positioned diagonally relative to the major axis A<sub>1</sub> and the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. A top-right median upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>C is positioned in the first quadrant <b>11</b>A, above the major axis A<sub>1</sub> and to the right of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. A top-left median upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>C is positioned in the second quadrant <b>11</b>B, above the major axis A<sub>1</sub> and to the left of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. A bottom-left median upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>C is positioned in the third quadrant <b>11</b>C, below the major axis A<sub>1</sub> and to the left of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. A bottom-right median upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>C is positioned in the fourth quadrant <b>11</b>D, below the major axis A<sub>1</sub> and to the right of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0100">An upper portion of each major upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>A is positioned between two of the major star facets <b>14</b>A. A lower portion of each major upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>A is positioned between two of the major lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A. An upper portion of each minor upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>B is positioned between two of the minor star facets <b>14</b>A. A lower portion of each minor upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>B is positioned between two of the minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>B. An upper portion of each median upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>C is positioned between one of the major star facets <b>14</b>A and an adjacent one of the minor star facets <b>14</b>B. A lower portion of each median upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>C is positioned between one of the major lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A and an adjacent one of the minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0101">All of the upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>A, <b>16</b>B, <b>16</b>C, are generally diamond or kite-shaped (e.g., four sides) with an upper vertex, a lower vertex, and two lateral vertices. The lower vertex of each major upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>A abuts the upper vertex of one of the central major main crown facets <b>20</b>A, as well as lateral vertices of a pair of adjacent major lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A. The lateral vertices of each major upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>A abut the upper vertex of one of the major lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A, as well as one of the lateral vertices of an adjacent median upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>C. Each major upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>A shares first and second edges with two adjacent major lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A, and third and fourth edges with two adjacent major star facets <b>14</b>A. The upper vertex of each of the upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>A, <b>16</b>B, <b>16</b>C abuts a vertex of the table <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0102">The lower vertex of each minor upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>B abuts the upper vertex of one of the minor main crown facets <b>22</b>, as well as lateral vertices of a pair of adjacent minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>B. The lateral vertices of each minor upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>B abut the upper vertex of one of the minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>B, as well as one of the lateral vertices of an adjacent median upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>C. Each minor upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>B shares first and second edges with two adjacent minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>B, and third and fourth edges with two adjacent minor star facets <b>14</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0103">The lower vertex of each median upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>C abuts the upper vertex of one of the outer maj or main crown facets <b>20</b>B, one of the lateral vertices of one of the major lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A, and one of the lateral vertices of one of the minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>B. One of the lateral vertices of each median upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>C abuts the upper vertex of one of the major lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A and one of the lateral vertices of an adjacent major upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>A. The other lateral vertex of each median upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>C abuts the upper vertex of one of the minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>B and one of the lateral vertices of an adjacent minor upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>B. Each median upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>C shares a first edge with an adjacent major lower intermediate crown facet <b>18</b>A, a second edge with an adjacent minor lower intermediate crown facet <b>18</b>B, a third edge with an adjacent major star facet <b>14</b>A, and a fourth edge with an adjacent minor star facet <b>14</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0104">Each of the major, minor, and median upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>A, <b>16</b>B, <b>16</b>C are generally shaped differently due to the oval or elliptical shape of the gemstone <b>1</b>. The distance between the upper and lower vertices of the major upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>A is generally larger than the distance between the upper and lower vertices of the minor and median upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>B, <b>16</b>C. The major upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>A are thus generally vertically elongated (e.g., between the girdle <b>50</b> and the table <b>12</b>). The distance between the lateral vertices of the minor upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>B is generally larger than the distance between the lateral vertices of the major and median upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>A, <b>16</b>C. The minor upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>B are thus laterally elongated (e.g., along the circumference of the crown <b>10</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0105">Both the major upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>A and the minor upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>B are generally symmetrical. However, the median upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>C are generally asymmetrical. The upper vertex of each of the median upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>C is shifted slightly toward the adjacent one of the minor upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>B. In this manner, the angle bisector of the upper vertex of the median upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>C is generally not parallel to the angle bisector of the lower vertex of the median upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>C.</p>
<p id="p-0107" num="0106">Thus, while all of the major, minor, and median upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>A, <b>16</b>B, <b>16</b>C generally have the same angle or an angle within the same range, the major, minor, and median upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>A, <b>16</b>B, <b>16</b>C can have different shapes depending on their location along the crown <b>10</b> of the gemstone <b>1</b>. However, in some implementations, any one of the groups of upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>A, <b>16</b>B, <b>16</b>C can have the same size and shape as any of the other groups of upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>A, <b>16</b>B, <b>16</b>C.</p>
<p id="p-0108" num="0107">Eight star facets <b>14</b>A, <b>14</b>B are disposed between the major, minor, and median upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>A, <b>16</b>B, <b>16</b>C, and the table <b>12</b>. Each star facet <b>14</b>A, <b>14</b>B is disposed adjacent to and abutting an edge of the table <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0109" num="0108">Relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the major star facets <b>14</b>A are disposed either to the left or to the right on the crown <b>10</b> along the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. The major star facets <b>14</b>A are divided into two groups of two major star facets <b>14</b>A. A left group of two major star facets <b>14</b>A is generally disposed along the left side of the major axis A<sub>1</sub>, which is to the left of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. A right group of two major star facets <b>14</b>A is generally disposed along the right side of the major axis A<sub>1</sub>, which is to the right of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0110" num="0109">The major star facets <b>14</b>A within the left group of major star facets <b>14</b>A extend generally vertically relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>. In this manner, the two major star facets <b>14</b>A within the left group of major star facets <b>14</b>A are aligned along an axis that is parallel to and to the left of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. Similarly, the major star facets <b>14</b>A within the right group of major star facets <b>14</b>A also extend generally vertically relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>. In this manner, the two major star facets <b>14</b>A within the right group of major star facets <b>14</b>A  are aligned along an axis that is parallel to and to the right of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. The left group of two major star facets <b>14</b>A thus includes a top-left major star facet <b>14</b>A and a bottom-left major star facet <b>14</b>A. The right group of two major star facets <b>14</b>A thus includes a top-right major star facet <b>14</b>A and a bottom-right major star facet <b>14</b>A.</p>
<p id="p-0111" num="0110">Relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the minor star facets <b>14</b>B are disposed either toward the top of the crown <b>10</b> or toward the bottom of the crown <b>10</b>, along the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. The minor star facets <b>14</b>B are divided into two groups of two minor star facets <b>14</b>B. A top group of two minor star facets <b>14</b>B is generally disposed along the top side of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>, which is above the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. A bottom group of two minor star facets <b>14</b>B is generally disposed along the bottom side of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>, which is below the major axis A<sub>1</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0112" num="0111">The minor star facets <b>14</b>B within the top group of minor star facets <b>14</b>B extend generally horizontally relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>. In this manner, the two minor star facets <b>14</b>B within the top group of minor star facets <b>14</b>B are aligned along an axis that is parallel to and above the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. Similarly, the minor star facets <b>14</b>B within the bottom group of minor star facets <b>14</b>B also extend generally horizontally relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>. In this manner, the two minor star facets <b>14</b>B within the bottom group of minor star facets <b>14</b>B are aligned along an axis that is parallel to and below the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. The top group of two minor star facets <b>14</b>B thus includes a top-left minor star facet <b>14</b>B and a top-right minor star facet <b>14</b>B. The bottom group of two minor star facets <b>14</b>B thus includes a bottom-left minor star facet <b>14</b>B and a bottom-right minor star facet <b>14</b>A.</p>
<p id="p-0113" num="0112">The top-right major and minor star facets <b>14</b>A, <b>14</b>B are disposed generally in the first quadrant <b>11</b>A of the crown <b>10</b>. The top-left major and minor star facets <b>14</b>A, <b>14</b>B are disposed generally in the second quadrant <b>11</b>B of the crown <b>10</b>. The bottom-left major and minor star facets <b>14</b>A, <b>14</b>B are disposed generally in the third quadrant <b>11</b>C of the crown <b>10</b>. The bottom-right major and minor star <b>14</b>A, <b>14</b>B are disposed generally in the fourth quadrant <b>11</b>D of the crown <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0114" num="0113">Each major star facet <b>14</b>A is positioned between a major upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>A, a median upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>C, and the table <b>12</b>. Each minor star facet <b>14</b>B is positioned between a minor upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>B, a median upper intermediate crown facet <b>16</b>C, and the table <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0115" num="0114">All of the major and minor star facets <b>14</b>A, <b>14</b>B are generally triangle-shaped with three vertices and three edges. A first vertex of each of the major star facets <b>14</b>A abuts the upper vertex of one of the major lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A, a lateral vertex of one of the major upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>A, and a lateral vertex of one of the median upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>C. A second vertex of each of the major star facets <b>14</b>A abuts a vertex of an adjacent major star facet <b>14</b>A, the upper vertex of one of the major upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>A, and a vertex of the table <b>12</b>. A third vertex of each of the major star facets <b>14</b>A abuts a vertex of an adjacent minor star facet <b>14</b>B, the upper vertex of one of the median upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>C, and a vertex of the table <b>12</b>. A first edge of each major star facet <b>14</b>A is shared with one edge of one of the major upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>A. A second edge of each major star facet <b>14</b>A is shared with one edge of one of the median upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>C. A third edge of each major star facet <b>14</b>A is shared with the table <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0116" num="0115">A first vertex of each of the minor star facets <b>14</b>B abuts the upper vertex of one of the minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>B, a lateral vertex of one of the minor upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>B, and a lateral vertex of one of the median upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>C. A second vertex of each of the minor star facets <b>14</b>B abuts a vertex of an adjacent major star facet <b>14</b>A, the upper vertex of one of the median upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>C, and a vertex of the table <b>12</b>. A third vertex of each of the minor star facets <b>14</b>B abuts a vertex of an adjacent minor star facet <b>14</b>B, the upper vertex of one of the minor upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>B, and a vertex of the table <b>12</b>. A first edge of each minor star facet <b>14</b>B is shared with one edge of one of the minor upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>B. A second edge of each minor star facet <b>14</b>B is shared with one edge of one of the median upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>C. A third edge of each minor star facet <b>14</b>B is shared with the table <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0117" num="0116">The major star facets <b>14</b>A generally have a different shape as compared to the minor star facets <b>14</b>B. The distance between the edge shared with the table <b>12</b> and the first vertex (e.g., the vertex opposite the edge shared with the table <b>12</b>) for the major star facets <b>14</b>A is generally greater than the distance between the edge shared with the table <b>12</b> and the first vertex for the minor star facets <b>14</b>B. Thus, the minor star facets <b>14</b>B can be said to be generally flattened toward the table <b>12</b> as compared to the major star facets <b>14</b>A. However, in some implementations, the major star facets <b>14</b>A have the same general size and shape as the minor star facets <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0118" num="0117">The table <b>12</b> is a generally horizontal surface having a number of edges and is located at the top of the crown <b>10</b>. In the implementation illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, table <b>12</b> has a generally octagonal shape. In this implementation, four edges of the table <b>12</b> are shared with the major star facets <b>14</b>A, and the other four edges of the table <b>12</b> are shared with the minor star facets <b>14</b>B. Other shapes for table <b>12</b> are contemplated in other implementations. As is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the table <b>12</b> has a generally longer dimension along the major axis A<sub>1</sub>, and a generally shorter dimension along the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0119" num="0118">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, a bottom plan view of the gemstone <b>1</b> showing the pavilion <b>30</b> is illustrated. The major axis A<sub>1</sub> of the perimeter of the gemstone (which is formed by the girdle <b>50</b>) extends horizontally relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, while the minor axis A<sub>2</sub> extends vertically relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>. The major and minor axes A<sub>1</sub> and A<sub>2</sub> generally divide the facets of the pavilion <b>30</b> into a first quadrant <b>31</b>A, a second quadrant <b>31</b>B, a third quadrant <b>31</b>C, and fourth quadrant <b>31</b>D. The first quadrant <b>31</b>A generally corresponds to the top-right corner region of the pavilion <b>30</b> relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>. The second quadrant <b>31</b>B generally corresponds to the top-left corner region of the pavilion <b>30</b> relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>. The third quadrant <b>31</b>C generally corresponds to the bottom-left corner region of the pavilion <b>30</b> relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>. The fourth quadrant <b>31</b>D generally corresponds to the bottom-right corner region of the pavilion <b>30</b> relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0120" num="0119">The terms &#x201c;top,&#x201d; &#x201c;bottom,&#x201d; &#x201c;left,&#x201d; &#x201c;right,&#x201d; &#x201c;above,&#x201d; below,&#x201d; etc. are used herein to refer to the locations of the various facets on the pavilion <b>30</b>. However, those of skill in the art will understand that these are relative terms that are generally used in reference to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>. Thus, any of these terms used to describe an individual facet may not apply when viewing the pavilion <b>30</b> from a different perspective. The facets on the surface of the pavilion <b>30</b> share edges and vertices where the facets meet. The facets on the surface of the pavilion <b>30</b> share edges and vertices where the facets meet. When describing the facets on the surface of the pavilion <b>30</b>, the term &#x201c;lower&#x201d; is used to refer to edges or vertices nearer to the lower point <b>33</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A and <b>1</b>B</figref>), while the term &#x201c;upper&#x201d; is used to refer to edges or vertices nearer to the girdle <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0121" num="0120">The pavilion <b>30</b> includes a number of main pavilion facets, which include six major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A, <b>38</b>B, and two minor main pavilion facets <b>40</b>. Relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, the six major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A, <b>38</b>B are generally disposed either to the left or to the right along the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. The major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A, <b>38</b>B are divided into two groups of three major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A, <b>38</b>B. A left group of three major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A, <b>38</b>B is generally disposed along the left side of the major axis A<sub>1</sub>, which is to the left of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. A right group of three major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A, <b>38</b>B is generally disposed along the right side of the major axis A<sub>1</sub>, which is to the right of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0122" num="0121">The major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A, <b>38</b>B within the left group of major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A, <b>38</b>B extend generally vertically relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>. In this manner, the three major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A, <b>38</b>B within the left group of major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A, <b>38</b>B are aligned along an axis that is parallel to and to the left of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. Similarly, the major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A, <b>38</b>B within the right group of major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A, <b>38</b>B also extend generally vertically relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>. In this manner, the three major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A, <b>38</b>B within the right group of major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A, <b>38</b>B are aligned along an axis that is parallel to and to the right of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0123" num="0122">Each group of three major main pavilion facets includes a central major main pavilion facet <b>38</b>A surrounded by two outer major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>B. The two central major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A (e.g. the left and right central major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>) are generally aligned along the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. The left central major main pavilion facet <b>38</b>A extends into both the second quadrant <b>31</b>B and the third quadrant <b>31</b>C. The right central major main pavilion facet <b>38</b>A extends into both the first quadrant <b>31</b>A and the fourth quadrant <b>31</b>D.</p>
<p id="p-0124" num="0123">Relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, the two outer major main pavilion facets <b>20</b>B above the central major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A (e.g., the top-right and top-left major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>B) are aligned along a line parallel to and above the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. Similarly, relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, the two outer major main crown facets <b>38</b>B below the central major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A (e.g., the bottom-left and bottom-right major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>B) are aligned along a line parallel to and below the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. The top-right major main pavilion facet <b>38</b>B is disposed in the first quadrant <b>31</b>A. The top-left major main pavilion facet <b>38</b>B is disposed in the second quadrant <b>31</b>B. The bottom-left major main pavilion facet <b>38</b>B is disposed in the third quadrant <b>31</b>C. The bottom-right major main pavilion facet <b>38</b>B is disposed in the fourth quadrant <b>31</b>D. Generally, at least a first portion of each of the major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A, <b>38</b>B is disposed between two of the candle facets <b>36</b>. At least a second portion of each of the central major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A is disposed between two of the major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A. At least a second portion of each of the outer major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>B is disposed between two of the median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C.</p>
<p id="p-0125" num="0124">The two minor main pavilion facets <b>40</b> are generally aligned along the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. Relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, one of the minor main pavilion facets <b>40</b> (e.g., the top minor main pavilion facet <b>40</b>) is generally disposed along the top side of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>, which is above the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. The other minor main pavilion facet <b>40</b> (e.g., the bottom minor pavilion facet <b>40</b>) is disposed along the bottom side of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>, which is below the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. The top minor main pavilion facet <b>40</b> generally extends into both the first quadrant <b>31</b>A and the second quadrant <b>31</b>B. The bottom minor main pavilion crown facet <b>40</b> generally extends into both the third quadrant <b>31</b>C and the fourth quadrant <b>31</b>D. Generally, at least a first portion of each of the minor main pavilion facets <b>40</b> is disposed between two of the candle facets <b>36</b>, while at least a second portion of each of the minor main pavilion facets <b>40</b> is disposed between two of the minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0126" num="0125">Each major main pavilion facet <b>38</b>A, <b>38</b>B is generally diamond or kite-shaped with a flattened lower edge. Thus, each major main pavilion facet <b>38</b>A, <b>38</b>B has a pentagon shape with five edges. The major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A, <b>38</b>B thus have one upper vertex, two lower vertices, and two lateral vertices. The upper vertex of each major main pavilion facet <b>38</b>A, <b>38</b>B abuts the lower edge of the girdle. Similarly, each minor main pavilion facet <b>40</b> is generally diamond or kite-shaped with a flattened lower edge. Thus, each minor main pavilion facet <b>40</b> has a pentagon shape with five edges. The minor main pavilion facets <b>40</b> thus have an upper vertex, two lower vertices, and two lateral vertices. The upper vertex of each minor main pavilion facet <b>40</b> abuts the lower edge of the girdle.</p>
<p id="p-0127" num="0126">Each central major main pavilion facet <b>38</b>A thus shares first and second edges with two adjacent major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A, third and fourth edges with two adjacent candle facets <b>36</b>, and a fifth edge (the lower edge) with the upper edge of a single corresponding central major culet-adjacent facet <b>32</b>A. Each outer major main pavilion facet <b>38</b>B shares first and second edges with two adjacent median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C, third and fourth edges with two adjacent candle facets <b>36</b>, and a fifth edge (the lower edge) with the upper edge of a single corresponding outer major culet-adjacent facet <b>34</b>B. Each minor main pavilion facet <b>40</b> shares first and second edges with two adjacent minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B, third and fourth edges with two adjacent candle facets <b>36</b>, and a fifth edge (the lower edge) with the upper edge of a single corresponding minor culet-adjacent facet <b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0128" num="0127">The two lateral vertices of each central major main pavilion facet <b>38</b>A, each outer major main pavilion facet <b>38</b>B, and each minor main pavilion facet <b>40</b> abut vertices of adjacent candle facets <b>36</b>. The two lower vertices of each of the central major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A and all of the outer major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>B each abut a vertex of an adjacent candle facet <b>36</b> and a vertex of the single corresponding major culet-adjacent facet <b>32</b>. The two lower vertices of the minor main pavilion facets <b>40</b> each abut a vertex of an adjacent candle facet <b>36</b> and a vertex of the single corresponding minor culet-adjacent facet <b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0129" num="0128">The upper vertex of each of the outer major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>B is generally shifted toward the nearest central major main pavilion facet <b>38</b>A, and away from the nearest minor main pavilion facet <b>40</b>. In this manner, the angle bisector of the upper vertex of the outer major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>B is generally not perpendicular to the corresponding flattened lower edge of the same outer major main pavilion facet <b>38</b>B. In contrast, the upper vertex of the central major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A is not shifted, and thus the angle bisectors of the upper vertex of the central major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A are generally parallel to the corresponding flattened lower edge of the same central major main pavilion facet <b>38</b>A.</p>
<p id="p-0130" num="0129">Thus, while all of the central and outer major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A, <b>38</b>B generally have the same angle or an angle within the same range, the central and outer major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A, <b>38</b>BB can have slightly differ different shapes depending on their location along the pavilion <b>30</b> of the gemstone <b>1</b>. However, in some implementations, any one of the groups of main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A, <b>38</b>B, <b>40</b> can have the same size and shape as any of the other groups of main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A, <b>38</b>B, <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0131" num="0130">The pavilion <b>30</b> includes four major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A, four minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B, and eight median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C. Relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, the four major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A are disposed either to the left or to the right on the pavilion <b>30</b> along the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. The major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A are divided into two groups of two major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A. A left group of two major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A is generally disposed along the left side of the major axis A<sub>1</sub>, which is to the left of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. A right group of two major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A is generally disposed along the right side of the major axis A<sub>1</sub>, which is to the right of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. The major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A within the left group of major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A extend generally vertically relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>. In this manner, the two major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A within the left group of major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A are aligned along an axis that is parallel to and to the left of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. Similarly, the major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A within the right group of major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A also extend generally vertically relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>. In this manner, the two major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A within the right group of major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A are aligned along an axis that is parallel to and to the right of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0132" num="0131">One major lower girdle facet <b>42</b>A of the right group of major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A is disposed generally in the first quadrant <b>31</b>A of the pavilion <b>30</b>. The other major lower girdle facet <b>42</b>A of the right group of major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A is disposed generally in the fourth quadrant <b>31</b>D of the pavilion <b>30</b>. One major lower girdle facet <b>42</b>A of the left group of major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A is disposed generally in the second quadrant <b>31</b>B of the pavilion <b>30</b>. The other major lower girdle facet <b>42</b>A of the left group of major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A is disposed generally in the third quadrant <b>31</b>C of the pavilion <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0133" num="0132">Relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, the four minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B are disposed either toward the top of the pavilion <b>30</b>, or toward the bottom of the pavilion <b>30</b>, along the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. The minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B are divided into two groups of two minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B. A top group of two minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B is generally disposed along the top side of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>, which is above the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. A bottom group of two minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B is generally disposed along the bottom side of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>, which is below the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. The minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B within the top group of minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B extend generally horizontally relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>. In this manner, the two minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B within the top group of minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B are aligned along an axis that is parallel to and above the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. Similarly, the minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B within the bottom group of minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B also extend generally horizontally relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>. In this manner, the two minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B within the bottom group of minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B are aligned along an axis that is parallel to and below the major axis A<sub>1</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0134" num="0133">One minor lower girdle facet <b>42</b>B of the top group of minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B is disposed generally in the first quadrant <b>31</b>A of the pavilion <b>30</b>. The other minor lower girdle facet <b>42</b>B of the top group of minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B is disposed generally in the second quadrant <b>31</b>B of the pavilion <b>30</b>. One minor lower girdle facet <b>42</b>B of the bottom group of minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B is disposed generally in the third quadrant <b>31</b>C of the pavilion <b>30</b>. The other minor lower girdle facet <b>42</b>B of the bottom group of minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B is disposed generally in the fourth quadrant <b>31</b>D of the pavilion <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0135" num="0134">Relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, the eight median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C are generally positioned diagonally relative to the major axis A<sub>1</sub> and the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. The median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C are divided into four groups of two median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C. A top-right group of median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C is positioned in the first quadrant <b>31</b>A, above the major axis A<sub>1</sub> and to the right of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. A top-left group of median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C is positioned in the second quadrant <b>31</b>B, above the major axis A<sub>1</sub> and to the left of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. A bottom-left group of median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C is positioned in the third quadrant <b>31</b>C, below the major axis A<sub>1</sub> and to the left of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. A bottom-right group of median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C is positioned in the fourth quadrant <b>31</b>D, below the major axis A<sub>1</sub> and to the right of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0136" num="0135">Each of the major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A is disposed between one of the central major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A, an adjacent one of the candle facets <b>36</b>, and the lower edge of the girdle <b>50</b>. Each of the major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A has a generally triangular shape. A first edge of each of the major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A is shared with the girdle <b>50</b>, and can be flat or curved depending on the shape of the girdle <b>50</b>. A second edge of each of the major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A is shared with one of the central major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A.</p>
<p id="p-0137" num="0136">As shown, each of the major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A shares a third edge with an adjacent one of the median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C. One of the left group of major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A shares its third edge with one of the top-left median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C. The other of the left group of major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A shares its third edge with one of the bottom-left median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C. One of the right group of major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A shares its third edge with one of the top-right median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C. The other of the right group of major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A shares its third edge with one of the bottom-right median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C. Thus, each major lower girdle facet <b>42</b>A is part of a pair of lower girdle facets along with its corresponding median lower girdle facet <b>42</b>C. The upper portions of each pair of major and median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A, <b>42</b>C form a gap into which an upper portion of one of the candle facets <b>36</b> extends.</p>
<p id="p-0138" num="0137">The minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B are disposed in a similar fashion as the major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A. Each of the minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B is disposed between one of the minor main pavilion facets <b>40</b>, an adjacent one of the candle facets <b>36</b>, and the lower edge of the girdle <b>50</b>. Each of the minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B has a generally triangular shape. A first edge of each of the minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B is shared with the girdle <b>50</b>, and can be flat or curved depending on the shape of the girdle <b>50</b>. A second edge of each of the minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B is shared with one of the minor main pavilion facets <b>40</b></p>
<p id="p-0139" num="0138">As shown, each of the minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B shares a third edge with an adjacent one of the median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C. One of the top group of minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B shares its third edge with one of the top-left median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C. The other of the top group of minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B shares its third edge with one of the top-right median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C. One of the bottom group of minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B shares its third edge with one of the bottom-left median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C. The other of the bottom group of minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B shares its third edge with one of the bottom-right median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C. Thus, each minor girdle facet <b>42</b>B is part of a pair of lower girdle facets along with its corresponding median lower girdle facet <b>42</b>C. The upper portions of each pair of minor and median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B, <b>42</b>C form a gap into which an upper portion of one of the candle facets <b>36</b> extends.</p>
<p id="p-0140" num="0139">Each of the median crown facets <b>16</b>C is disposed between the lower edge of the girdle, one of the outer major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>B, and an adjacent one of the candle facets <b>36</b>. Each of the median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C has a generally triangular shape. A first edge of each of the median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C is shared with the girdle <b>50</b>, and can be flat or curved depending on the shape of the girdle <b>50</b>. A second edge of each of the median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C is shared with one of the outer major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0141" num="0140">As shown, each of the minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B shares a third edge with either (i) an adjacent one of the major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A, or (ii) an adjacent one of the minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B. One of the top-right group of median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C shares its third edge with one of the right group of major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A. The other of the top-right group of median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C shares its third edge with one of the top group of minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B. One of the top-left group of median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C shares its third edge with one of the top group of minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B. The other of the top-left group of median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C shares its third edge with one of the left group of major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A. One of the bottom-left group of median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C shares its third edge with one of the left group of major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A. The other of the bottom-left group of median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C shares its third edge with one of the bottom group of minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B. One of the bottom-right group of median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C shares its third edge with one of the bottom group of minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B. The other of the bottom-right group of median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C shares its third edge with one of the right group of major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A. Thus, each median lower girdle facet <b>42</b>C is part of a pair of lower girdle facets along with either its corresponding major lower girdle facet <b>42</b>A or its corresponding minor lower girdle facet <b>42</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0142" num="0141">Each of the major, minor, and median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A, <b>42</b>B, <b>42</b>C has two upper vertices, a lower vertex, and a lateral vertex. Each of the two upper vertices of each respective lower girdle facet abuts both (i) the lower edge of the girdle and (ii) an upper vertex of an adjacent one of the lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A, <b>42</b>B, <b>42</b>C. For the major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A, one of the upper vertices abuts an upper vertex of the other major lower girdle facet <b>42</b>A in the same group (e.g., left or right). The other upper vertex abuts an upper vertex of an adjacent one of the median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C. For the minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B, one of the upper vertices abuts an upper vertex of the other minor lower girdle facet <b>42</b>B in the same group (e.g. top or bottom). The other upper vertex abuts an upper vertex of an adjacent one of the median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C. For the median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C, one of the upper vertices abuts an upper vertex of the other minor lower girdle facet <b>42</b>B in the same group (e.g., top-right, top-left, bottom-left, or bottom-right). The other upper vertex abuts an upper vertex of either (i) one of the major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A or (ii) one of the minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0143" num="0142">The lower vertex of each major lower girdle facet <b>42</b>A abuts a vertex of one of the central main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A, and one of the candle facets <b>36</b>. The lower vertex of each minor lower girdle facet <b>42</b>B abuts a vertex of one of the minor pavilion facets <b>40</b>, and one of the candle facets <b>36</b>. The lower vertex of each median lower girdle facet <b>42</b>C abuts a vertex of one of the outer main pavilion facets <b>38</b>B, and one of the candle facets <b>36</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0144" num="0143">The lateral vertex of each major lower girdle facet <b>42</b>A abuts a vertex of one of the candle facets <b>36</b> and an adjacent one of the median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C. The lateral vertex of each minor lower girdle facet <b>42</b>B abuts a vertex of one of the candle facets <b>36</b> and an adjacent one of the median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C. The lateral vertex of each median lower girdle facet <b>42</b>C abuts a vertex of one of the candle facets <b>36</b> and either (i) an adjacent one of the major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A, or (ii) an adjacent one of the minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0145" num="0144">In the illustrated implementation, the upper edge of each major and minor lower girdle facet <b>42</b>A, <b>42</b>B that abuts the lower edge of the girdle is larger than the upper edge of each median lower girdle facet <b>42</b>C that abuts the lower edge of the girdle. Thus, the major and minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A, <b>42</b>B are generally larger than the median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C. However, in other implementations, the upper edge of each major and minor lower girdle facet <b>42</b>A, <b>42</b>B is generally the same length as the upper edge of each median lower girdle facet <b>42</b>C, such that all of the major, minor, and median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A, <b>42</b>B, <b>42</b>C are the same size.</p>
<p id="p-0146" num="0145">Eight culet-adjacent facets are formed at the lowermost portion of the pavilion <b>30</b>, which includes six major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>A, <b>32</b>B, and two minor culet-adjacent facets <b>34</b>. Each culet-adjacent facet <b>32</b>A, <b>32</b>B, <b>34</b> has a generally pentagonal shape with a lower vertex, two lateral vertices, and two upper vertices. An upper flat edge is opposite the lower vertex of each culet-adjacent facet <b>32</b>A, <b>32</b>B, <b>34</b>. In some implementations, the major and minor culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>A, <b>32</b>B, <b>34</b> terminate in a culet, which is a horizontal surface forming the bottom of the pavilion <b>30</b>. In the implementation illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, each of the major and minor culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>A, <b>32</b>B, <b>34</b> has a bottom vertex. Together, the bottom vertices of each of the major and minor culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>A, <b>32</b>B, <b>34</b> form the lower point <b>33</b> of the gemstone <b>1</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A and <b>1</b>B</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0147" num="0146">Relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, the six major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>A, <b>32</b>B are generally disposed either to the left or to the right along the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. The major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>A, <b>32</b>B are divided into two groups of three major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>A, <b>32</b>B. A left group of three major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>A, <b>32</b>B is generally disposed along the left side of the major axis A<sub>1</sub>, which is to the left of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. A right group of three major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>A, <b>32</b>B is generally disposed along the right side of the major axis A<sub>1</sub>, which is to the right of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0148" num="0147">The major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>A, <b>32</b>B within the left group of major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>A, <b>32</b>B extend generally vertically relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>. In this manner, the three major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>A, <b>32</b>B within the left group of major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>A, <b>32</b>B are aligned along an axis that is parallel to and to the left of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. Similarly, the major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>A, <b>32</b>B within the right group of major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>A, <b>32</b>B also extend generally vertically relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>. In this manner, the three major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>A, <b>32</b>B within the right group of major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>A, <b>32</b>B are aligned along an axis that is parallel to and to the right of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0149" num="0148">Each group of three major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>A, <b>32</b>B includes a central major culet-adjacent facet <b>32</b>A surrounded by two outer major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>B. The two central major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>A (e.g. the left and right central major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>A relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>) are generally aligned along the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. The left central major culet-adjacent facet <b>32</b>A extends into both the second quadrant <b>31</b>B and the third quadrant <b>31</b>C. The right central major culet-adjacent facet <b>32</b>A extends into both the first quadrant <b>31</b>A and the fourth quadrant 3 1D</p>
<p id="p-0150" num="0149">Relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, the two outer major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>B above the central major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>A (e.g., the top-right and top-left major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>B) are aligned along a line parallel to and above the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. Similarly, relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, the two outer major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>B below the central major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>A (e.g., the bottom-left and bottom-right major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>B) are aligned along a line parallel to and below the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. The top-right major culet-adjacent facet <b>32</b>B is disposed in the first quadrant <b>31</b>A. The top-left major culet-adjacent facet <b>32</b>B is disposed in the second quadrant <b>31</b>B. The bottom-left major culet-adjacent facet <b>32</b>B is disposed in the third quadrant <b>31</b>C. The bottom-right major culet-adjacent facet <b>32</b>B is disposed in the fourth quadrant <b>31</b>D. Generally, at least an upper portion of each of the major main culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>A, <b>32</b>B is disposed between two of the candle facets <b>36</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0151" num="0150">The two minor culet-adjacent facets <b>34</b> are generally aligned along the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. Relative to the plane of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, one of the minor culet-adjacent facets <b>34</b> (e.g., the top minor culet-adjacent facet <b>34</b>) is generally disposed along the top side of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>, which is above the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. The other minor culet-adjacent facet <b>34</b> (e.g., the bottom minor culet-adjacent facet <b>34</b>) is disposed along the bottom side of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>, which is below the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. The top minor culet-adjacent facet <b>34</b> generally extends into both the first quadrant <b>31</b>A and the second quadrant <b>31</b>B. The bottom minor culet-adjacent facet <b>34</b> generally extends into both the third quadrant <b>31</b>C and the fourth quadrant <b>31</b>D. Generally, at least an upper portion of each of the minor main pavilion facets <b>40</b> is disposed between two of the candle facets <b>36</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0152" num="0151">The two lateral vertices of the central major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>A each abut a lower vertex of an adjacent candle facet <b>36</b> and a lateral vertex of an adjacent outer major culet-adjacent facet <b>32</b>B. The two upper vertices of the central major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>A each abut a vertex of an adjacent candle facet <b>36</b> and a lower vertex of the adjacent major central main pavilion facet <b>38</b>A. Each central major culet-adjacent facet <b>32</b>A shares two edges with two adjacent outer major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>B, two edges with two adjacent candle facets <b>36</b>, and one edge with an adjacent central major main pavilion facet <b>38</b>A.</p>
<p id="p-0153" num="0152">The two lateral vertices of the outer major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>B abut a vertex of an adjacent candle facet <b>36</b>, and either (i) a lateral vertex of the adjacent central major culet-adjacent facet <b>32</b>A or (ii) a lateral vertex of the adjacent minor culet-adjacent facet <b>34</b>. The two upper vertices of the outer major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>B each abut a vertex of an adjacent candle facet <b>36</b> and a lower vertex of the adjacent major outer main pavilion facet <b>38</b>B. Each outer major culet-adjacent facet <b>32</b>B shares one edge with an adjacent central major culet-adjacent facet <b>32</b>A, one edge with an adjacent minor culet-adjacent facet <b>34</b>, two edges with two adjacent candle facets <b>36</b>, and one edge with an adjacent outer major main pavilion facet <b>38</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0154" num="0153">The two lateral vertices of the minor culet-adjacent facets <b>34</b> abut a vertex of an adjacent candle facet <b>36</b> and a lateral vertex of an adjacent outer major culet-adjacent facet <b>32</b>B. The two upper vertices of the minor culet-adjacent facets <b>34</b> each abut a vertex of an adjacent candle facet <b>36</b> and a lower vertex of the adjacent minor central main pavilion facet <b>40</b>. Each minor culet-adjacent facet <b>34</b> shares two edges with two adjacent outer major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>B, two edges with two adjacent candle facets <b>36</b>, and one edge with an adjacent minor main pavilion facet <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0155" num="0154">Due to the oval or elliptical shape of the gemstone <b>1</b>, the major and minor culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>A, <b>32</b>B, <b>34</b> have slightly different shapes. Generally, the distance between lateral vertices of the minor culet-adjacent facets <b>34</b> is larger than the distance between lateral vertices of both the central major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>A and the outer major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>B. The distance between lateral vertices of the central major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>A is larger than the distance between lateral vertices of the outer major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>B. However, in some implementations, any one of the groups of culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>A, <b>32</b>B, <b>34</b> can have the same size and shape as any of the other groups of culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>A, <b>32</b>B, <b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0156" num="0155">Eight candle facets <b>36</b> are formed on the surface of the pavilion <b>30</b>. Each candle facet <b>36</b> is positioned between (i) two of the major and minor main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A, <b>38</b>B, <b>40</b>, (ii) two of the major and minor culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>A, <b>32</b>B, <b>34</b>, and (iii) either a pair of major and median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A, <b>42</b>C, or a pair of minor and median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B, <b>42</b>C. Each candle facet <b>36</b> has six edges and six vertices. Each candle facet shares two edges with two adjacent main pavilion facets (e.g., two of a central major main pavilion facet <b>38</b>A, an outer major main pavilion facet <b>38</b>B, and a minor main pavilion facet <b>40</b>), two edges with two adjacent culet-adjacent facets (e.g., two of a central major culet-adjacent facet <b>32</b>A, an outer major culet-adjacent facet <b>32</b>B, and a minor main culet-adjacent facet <b>34</b>), and two edges with either (i) a pair of the major and median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A, <b>42</b>C, or (ii) a pair of the minor and median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B, <b>42</b>C. A lower portion of each of the candle facets <b>36</b>, including a bottom point, is disposed between two adjacent culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>A, <b>32</b>B, <b>34</b>. An upper portion of each of the candle facets <b>36</b> is slotted between either (i) a pair of major and median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A, <b>42</b>B, or (ii) a pair of minor and median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B, <b>42</b>C. In the illustrated implementation, two candle facets <b>36</b> are positioned in the first quadrant <b>31</b>A, two candle facets <b>36</b> are positioned in the second quadrant <b>31</b>B, two candle facets <b>36</b> are positioned in the third quadrant <b>31</b>C, and two candle facets <b>36</b> are positioned in the fourth quadrant <b>31</b>D.</p>
<p id="p-0157" num="0156"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>A</figref> illustrates a perspective view of gemstone <b>1</b> at a downward angle, while <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>B</figref> illustrates a perspective view of gemstone <b>1</b> at an upward angle. These figures show the table <b>12</b>, the major star facets <b>14</b>A, the minor star facets <b>14</b>B, the major upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>A, the minor upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>B, the median upper intermediate crown facets <b>16</b>C, the major lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>A, the minor lower intermediate crown facets <b>18</b>B, the central major main crown facets <b>20</b>A, the outer major main crown facets <b>20</b>B, the minor main crown facets <b>22</b>, the major upper girdle facets <b>24</b>A, the minor upper girdle facets <b>24</b>B, the median upper girdle facets <b>24</b>C, the central major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>A, the outer major culet-adjacent facets <b>32</b>B, the minor culet-adjacent facets <b>34</b>, the candle facets <b>36</b>, the central major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>A, the outer major main pavilion facets <b>38</b>B, the minor main pavilion facets <b>40</b>, the major lower girdle facets <b>42</b>A, the minor lower girdle facets <b>42</b>B, the median lower girdle facets <b>42</b>C, and the girdle <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0158" num="0157">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>5</b>A-<b>5</b>E</figref>, the steps for forming the crown of the gemstone are illustrated. As used in relation to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>5</b>A-<b>5</b>E</figref>, the major axis A<sub>1</sub> and the minor axis A<sub>2</sub> have the same orientations relative to the gemstone as gemstone <b>1</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b> and <b>3</b></figref>, but are not shown. Thus, in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>5</b>A-<b>5</b>E</figref>, the major axis A<sub>1</sub> extends horizontally relative to the plane of the figures, while the minor axis A<sub>2</sub> extends vertically relative to the plane of the figures. Generally, the gemstone may be formed from an uncut sample, which can have any shape. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b>A</figref>, the first step includes forming a first preliminary table <b>101</b>A, a first set of crown facets <b>104</b> (e.g., a first temporary set of crown facets), and a second set of crown facets <b>106</b> (e.g., a second temporary set of crown facets). In an implementation, the width of the first preliminary table <b>101</b>A is formed to be the same as the table <b>102</b> of the final gemstone, and thus is between about 31.5% and about 35.5% of the width of the gemstone, about 30% to about 40% of the width of the gemstone, about 25% to about 45% of the width of the gemstone, or about 33.5% of the width of the gemstone.</p>
<p id="p-0159" num="0158">The facets of the first set of crown facets <b>104</b> are formed at an angle of between about 37&#xb0; and about 45&#xb0;. The facets of the first set of crown facets <b>104</b> are disposed along the left and right sides of the major axis A<sub>1</sub>, to the left and right of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. The second set of crown facets <b>106</b> are formed at an angle of between about 42&#xb0; and about 49&#xb0;. One of the second set of crown facets <b>106</b> is disposed along the top side of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>, above the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. The other of the second set of crown facets <b>106</b> is disposed along the bottom side of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>, below the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. The angle of the first and second sets of crown facets <b>104</b>, <b>106</b> and the angles of subsequent crown facets formed in subsequent steps are measured relative to the horizontal plane that is defined by the first preliminary table 101 A, similar to how the angles of the facets of the completed crown were measured in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A and <b>1</b>B</figref>. After this step, the crown of the gemstone includes the first preliminary table <b>101</b>A, the first set of crown facets <b>104</b>, and the second set of crown facets <b>106</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0160" num="0159">The next step is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b>B</figref>. Here, a third set of crown facets <b>108</b> (e.g., a third temporary set of crown facets) is formed on the crown of the gemstone. The third set of crown facets <b>108</b> is formed by carving a pentagonal surface out of portions of the first preliminary table, the first set of crown facets <b>104</b>, and the second set of crown facets <b>106</b>. The third set of crown facets <b>108</b> can be formed at an angle of between about 25&#xb0; and about 35&#xb0;. The gemstone after this step is thus left with a second preliminary table <b>101</b>B, the third set of crown facets <b>108</b>, a fourth set of crown facets <b>110</b>, and a fifth set of crown facets <b>112</b>. The second preliminary table <b>101</b>B is formed from the remainder of the first preliminary table <b>101</b>A, and is generally horizontal. The fourth set of crown facets <b>110</b> (e.g., a fourth temporary set of crown facets) is formed from the remainder of the first set of crown facets <b>104</b>, and is formed at the same angle as the first set of crown facets <b>104</b>. The facets of the fourth set of crown facets <b>110</b> are disposed along the left and right sides of the major axis A<sub>1</sub>, to the left and right of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. The fifth set of crown facets <b>112</b> (e.g., a fifth temporary set of crown facets) is formed from the remainder of the second set of crown facets <b>106</b>, and is formed at the same angle as the second set of crown facets <b>106</b>. One of the fifth set of crown facets <b>112</b> is disposed along the top side of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>, above the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. The other of the fifth set of crown facets <b>112</b> is disposed along the bottom side of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>, below the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. After this step, the crown of the gemstone includes the second preliminary table <b>101</b>B, the third set of crown facets <b>108</b>, the fourth set of crown facets <b>110</b>, and the fifth set of crown facets <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0161" num="0160">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b>C</figref>, the next step is to carve out a pentagonal-shaped portions from the second preliminary table <b>101</b>B and the third set of crown facets <b>108</b>, to form a sixth set of crown facets <b>114</b> (e.g., a sixth temporary set of crown facets). The sixth set of crown facets <b>114</b> are formed at an angle of between about 15&#xb0; and about 24&#xb0;, and are generally disposed in a circular pattern on the crown <b>10</b> of the gemstone. The remaining portion of the second preliminary table <b>101</b>B forms a third preliminary table <b>101</b>C, which is generally horizontal. The remaining portions of the third set of crown facets <b>108</b> form a seventh set of crown facets <b>116</b> (e.g., a first final set of crown facets), which are thus disposed at the same angle as the third set of crown facets <b>108</b>. After this step, the crown of the gemstone includes the third preliminary table <b>101</b>C, the fourth set of crown facets <b>110</b>, the fifth set of crown facets <b>112</b>, the sixth set of crown facets <b>114</b>, and the seventh set of crown facets <b>116</b>. The seventh set of crown facets <b>116</b> corresponds to the major and minor lower intermediate crown facets of the final gemstone.</p>
<p id="p-0162" num="0161">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b>D</figref>, the following step is to carve out an eighth set of crown facets <b>118</b> (e.g., a second final set of crown facets) from portions of the fourth set of crown facets <b>110</b> and portions of the fifth set of crown facets <b>112</b>. Some of the facets of the eighth set of crown facets <b>118</b> are disposed along the left and right sides of the major axis A<sub>1</sub>, to the left and right of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. The remaining facets of the eighth set of crown facets <b>118</b> are disposed along the top and bottom sides of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>, above and below the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. The facets of the eighth set of crown facets <b>118</b> are triangular-shaped and abut the upper edge of the girdle. The eighth set of crown facets <b>118</b> are formed at an angle of between about 42.5&#xb0; and about 57&#xb0;.</p>
<p id="p-0163" num="0162">After the eighth set of crown facets <b>118</b>, two additional sets of crown facets are left behind from the remainder of the fourth set of crown facets <b>110</b> and the fifth set of crown facets <b>112</b>. A ninth set of crown facets <b>120</b> (e.g., a third final set of crown facets) is formed from the remainder of the fourth set of crown facets <b>110</b>, and is thus formed at the same angle as the fourth set of crown facets <b>110</b> and the first set of crown facets <b>104</b>. A tenth set of crown facets <b>122</b> (e.g., a fourth final set of crown facets) is formed from the remainder of the fifth set of crown facets <b>112</b>, and is thus formed at the same angle as the fifth set of crown facets <b>112</b> and the second set of crown facets <b>106</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0164" num="0163">After this step, the crown of the gemstone includes the third preliminary table <b>101</b>C, the sixth set of crown facets <b>114</b>, the seventh set of crown facets <b>116</b>, the eighth set of crown facets <b>118</b>, the ninth set of crown facets <b>120</b>, and the tenth set of crown facets <b>122</b>. The eighth set of crown facets <b>118</b> corresponds to the major, minor, and median upper girdle facets of the final gemstone. The ninth set of crown facets <b>120</b> corresponds to the central and outer major main crown of the final gemstone. The tenth set of crown facets <b>122</b> corresponds to the minor main crown facets of the final gemstone.</p>
<p id="p-0165" num="0164">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b>E</figref>, the final step in forming the crown of the gemstone is to carve out an eleventh set of crown facets <b>124</b> (e.g., a fifth final set of crown facets) from the sixth set of crown facets <b>114</b> and the third preliminary table <b>101</b>C. The eleventh set of crown facets <b>124</b> are generally triangular-shaped, and are formed at an angle of between about 10&#xb0; and about 17&#xb0;. The remaining portions of the sixth set of crown facets <b>114</b> form a twelfth set of crown facets <b>126</b> (e.g., a sixth final set of crown facets), which are thus formed at the same angle as the sixth set of crown facets <b>114</b>. The remaining portion of the third preliminary table <b>10</b>C forms a table <b>102</b>, this is generally horizontal (e.g., disposed at an angle of about 0&#xb0;).</p>
<p id="p-0166" num="0165">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b>E</figref>, the remaining set of facets on the crown (e.g., the first, second, third, fourth, fifth, and sixth final sets of crown facets) correspond to the facets on the finished crown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A, <b>1</b>B, and <b>2</b></figref>. The seventh set of crown facets <b>116</b> corresponds to the major and minor lower intermediate crown facets. The eighth set of crown facets <b>118</b> corresponds to the major, minor, and median upper girdle facets. The ninth set of crown facets <b>120</b> corresponds to the central and outer major main crown facets. The tenth set of crown facets <b>122</b> corresponds to the minor main crown facets. The eleventh set of crown facets <b>124</b> corresponds to the major and minor star facets.</p>
<p id="p-0167" num="0166">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b>A-<b>6</b>D</figref>, the steps for forming the pavilion of the gemstone are illustrated. As used in relation to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b>A-<b>6</b>E</figref>, the major axis A<sub>1</sub> and the minor axis A<sub>2</sub> have the same orientations relative to the gemstone as gemstone <b>1</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b> and <b>3</b></figref>, but are not shown. Thus, in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b>A-<b>6</b>D</figref>, the major axis A<sub>1</sub> extends horizontally relative to the plane of the figures, while the minor axis A<sub>2</sub> extends vertically relative to the plane of the figures. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref>, the first step includes carving a first set of pavilion facets <b>202</b> (e.g., a first temporary set of pavilion facets) and a second set of pavilion facets <b>204</b> (e.g., a second temporary set of pavilion facets). In the illustrated implementation, a flat lower facet <b>201</b> is formed. However, in other implementations, a lower point can be formed. The first set of pavilion facets <b>202</b> are formed at an angle of between about 41&#xb0; and about 45&#xb0;. The facets of the first set of pavilion facets <b>202</b> are disposed along the left and right sides of the major axis A<sub>1</sub>, to the left and right of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. The second set of pavilion facets <b>204</b> are formed at an angle of between about 45&#xb0; and about 49&#xb0;. One of the second set of pavilion facets <b>204</b> is disposed along the top side of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>, above the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. The other of the second set of pavilion facets <b>204</b> is disposed along the bottom side of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>, below the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. The angle of the first and second sets of pavilion facets <b>202</b>, <b>204</b> and the angles of subsequent pavilion facets formed in subsequent steps are measured relative to the horizontal plane that is defined by the preliminary tables <b>101</b>A, <b>101</b>B, <b>101</b>C and the table <b>102</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>5</b>A-<b>5</b>E</figref>), similar to how the angles of the facets of the completed pavilion were measured in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A and <b>1</b>B</figref>. After this step, the pavilion of the gemstone includes the first set of pavilion facets <b>202</b> and the second set of pavilion facets <b>204</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0168" num="0167">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>B</figref>, the next step in forming the pavilion is to carve a third set of pavilion facets <b>206</b> (e.g., a third temporary set of pavilion facets) from the first set of pavilion facets <b>202</b> and the flat lower facet <b>201</b>, and a fourth set of pavilion facets <b>208</b> (e.g., a fourth temporary set of pavilion facets) from the second set of pavilion facets <b>204</b> and the flat lower facet <b>201</b>. The third set of pavilion facets <b>206</b> is formed at angle of between about 32&#xb0; and about 38&#xb0;. The fourth set of pavilion facets <b>208</b> is formed at an angle of between about 36&#xb0; and about 42&#xb0;. The third set of pavilion facets <b>206</b> and the fourth set of pavilion facets <b>208</b> meet in the middle of the pavilion to form a lower point. The remaining portions of the first set of pavilion facets <b>202</b> form a fifth set of pavilion facets <b>210</b> (e.g., a fifth temporary set of pavilion facets), and are thus generally formed at the same angle as the first set of pavilion facets <b>202</b>. The facets of the fifth set of pavilion facets <b>210</b> are disposed along the left and right sides of the major axis A<sub>1</sub>, to the left and right of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. The remaining portions of the second set of pavilion facets <b>204</b> form a sixth set of pavilion facets <b>212</b> (e.g., a sixth temporary set of pavilion facets), and are thus generally formed at the same angle as the second set of pavilion facets <b>204</b>. One of the sixth set of pavilion facets <b>212</b> is disposed along the top side of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>, above the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. The other of the sixth set of pavilion facets <b>212</b> is disposed along the bottom side of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>, below the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. After this step, the pavilion of the gemstone includes the third set of pavilion facets <b>206</b>, the fourth set of pavilion facets <b>208</b>, the fifth set of pavilion facets <b>210</b>, and the sixth set of pavilion facets <b>212</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0169" num="0168">The next step is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>C</figref>. Here, a seventh set of pavilion facets <b>214</b> (e.g., a seventh temporary set of pavilion facets) are carved into the pavilion. The seventh set of pavilion facets <b>214</b> are generally formed along (i) the shared edge between two of the third set of pavilion facets <b>206</b> and the fourth set of pavilion facets <b>208</b> (e.g., two of the third set <b>206</b>; two of the fourth set <b>208</b>; or one of the third set <b>206</b> and one of the fourth set <b>208</b>), and (ii) the shared edge between two of the fifth set of pavilion facets <b>210</b> and the sixth set of pavilion facets <b>212</b> (e.g., two of the fifth set <b>210</b>; two of the sixth set <b>212</b>; or one of the fifth set <b>210</b> and one of the sixth set <b>212</b>). The seventh set of pavilion facets <b>214</b> are formed at an angle of between about 40&#xb0; and about 42&#xb0;.</p>
<p id="p-0170" num="0169">The seventh set of pavilion facets <b>214</b> are formed from portions of each of the third set of pavilion facets <b>206</b>, the fourth set of pavilion facets <b>208</b>, the fifth set of pavilion facets <b>210</b>, and the sixth set of pavilion facets <b>212</b>. The remainder of the third set of pavilion facets <b>206</b> form the eighth set of pavilion facets <b>216</b> (e.g., a first final set of pavilion facets). The facets of the eighth set of pavilion facets <b>216</b> are disposed along the left and right sides of the major axis A<sub>1</sub>, to the left and right of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. The eighth set of pavilion facets <b>216</b> are formed at the same angle as the third set of pavilion facets <b>206</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0171" num="0170">The remainder of the fourth set of pavilion facets <b>208</b> form the ninth set of pavilion facets <b>218</b> (e.g., a second final set of pavilion facets). One of the ninth set of pavilion facets <b>218</b> is disposed along the top side of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>, above the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. The other of the ninth set of pavilion facets <b>218</b> is disposed along the bottom side of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>, below the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. The ninth set of pavilion facets <b>218</b> are formed at the same angle as the fourth set of pavilion facets <b>208</b>. The remainder of the fifth set of pavilion facets <b>210</b> form the tenth set of pavilion facets <b>220</b> (e.g., an eighth temporary set of pavilion facets). The facets of the tenth set of pavilion facets <b>220</b> are disposed along the left and right sides of the major axis A<sub>1</sub>, to the left and right of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. The tenth set of pavilion facets <b>220</b> are formed at the same angle as the fifth set of pavilion facets <b>210</b> and the first set of pavilion facets <b>202</b>. The remainder of the sixth set of pavilion facets <b>212</b> form the eleventh set of pavilion facets <b>222</b> (e.g., a ninth temporary set of pavilion facets). One of the eleventh set of pavilion facets <b>222</b> is disposed along the top side of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>, above the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. The other of the eleventh set of pavilion facets <b>222</b> is disposed along the bottom side of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>, below the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. The eleventh set of pavilion facets <b>222</b> are formed at the same angle as the sixth set of pavilion facets <b>212</b> and the second set of pavilion facets <b>204</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0172" num="0171">After this step, the pavilion of the gemstone includes the seventh set of pavilion facets <b>214</b>, the eighth set of pavilion facets <b>216</b>, the ninth set of pavilion facets <b>218</b>, the tenth set of pavilion facets <b>220</b>, and the eleventh set of pavilion facets <b>222</b>. The seventh set of pavilion facets <b>214</b> corresponds to the candle facets of the final gemstone. The eighth set of pavilion facets <b>216</b> corresponds to the major culet-adjacent facets of the final gemstone. The ninth set of pavilion facets <b>218</b> corresponds to the minor culet-adjacent facets of the final gemstone.</p>
<p id="p-0173" num="0172">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>D</figref>, the final step in forming the pavilion of the gemstone is to carve a twelfth set of pavilion facets <b>224</b> (e.g., a third final set of pavilion facets) from portions of the seventh set of pavilion facets <b>214</b>, the tenth set of pavilion facets <b>220</b>, and the eleventh set of pavilion facets <b>222</b>. Some of the facets of the twelfth set of pavilion facets <b>224</b> are disposed along the left and right sides of the major axis A<sub>1</sub>, to the left and right of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. The remainder of the facets of the twelfth set of pavilion facets <b>224</b> are disposed along the left and right sides of the major axis A<sub>1</sub>, to the left and right of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. The twelfth set of pavilion facets <b>224</b> are generally triangular-shaped with a flattened top (e.g., have four edges), and abut the lower edge of the girdle. The twelfth set of pavilion facets <b>224</b> are formed at an angle of between about 43&#xb0; and about 57&#xb0;.</p>
<p id="p-0174" num="0173">The remainder of the seventh set of pavilion facets <b>214</b> form a thirteenth set of pavilion facets <b>225</b> (e.g., a fourth final set of pavilion facets), which are formed at the same angle as the seventh set of pavilion facets <b>214</b>. The remainder of the tenth set of pavilion facets <b>220</b> form a fourteenth set of pavilion facets <b>228</b> (e.g., a fifth final set of pavilion facets), which are formed at the same angle as the tenth set of pavilion facets <b>220</b> and the fifth set of pavilion facets <b>210</b>. The facets of the fourteenth set of pavilion facets <b>228</b> are disposed along the left and right sides of the major axis A<sub>1</sub>, to the left and right of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>. The remainder of the eleventh set of pavilion facets <b>222</b> form a fifteenth set of pavilion facets <b>230</b> (e.g., a sixth final set of pavilion facets), which are formed at the same angle as the eleventh set of pavilion facets <b>222</b> and the sixth set of pavilion facets <b>212</b>. One of the fifteenth set of pavilion facets <b>230</b> is disposed along the top side of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>, above the major axis A<sub>1</sub>. The other of the fifteenth set of pavilion facets <b>230</b> is disposed along the bottom side of the minor axis A<sub>2</sub>, below the major axis A<sub>1</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0175" num="0174">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>D</figref>, the remaining set of facets on the pavilion (e.g., the first, second, third, fourth, fifth, and sixth final sets of pavilion facets) correspond to the facets on the finished pavilion in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A, <b>1</b>B, and <b>3</b></figref>. The eighth set of pavilion facets <b>216</b> corresponds to the major culet-adjacent facets. The ninth set of pavilion facets <b>218</b> corresponds to the minor culet-adjacent facets. The twelfth set of pavilion facets <b>224</b> corresponds to the major, minor, and median lower girdle facets. The thirteenth set of pavilion facets <b>226</b> corresponds to the candle facets. The fourteenth set of pavilion facets <b>228</b> corresponds to the central and outer major main pavilion facets. The fifteenth set of pavilion facets <b>230</b> corresponds to the minor main pavilion facets.</p>
<p id="p-0176" num="0175">Thus, a gemstone having a crown, a girdle, and a pavilion are thus formed. The crown and the pavilion comprise a number of sets of interlocking facets that share edges and vertices on the surface of the gemstone. Each of the sets of interlocking facets is disposed at a specific angle. The shape of the facets, the organization of the facets, and the angles that the facets are formed at on the surface of the gemstone result in a gemstone having an improved brilliance. The brilliance refers to the amount of light that enters the gemstone, and is internally reflected such that it exits out of the crown of the gemstone. The facets according to aspects of the present disclosure increase the amount of light reflecting off of the internal surfaces of the facets, thus increasing the brilliance of the gemstone.</p>
<p id="p-0177" num="0176">While the present disclosure has been described with reference to one or more particular implementations, those skilled in the art will recognize that many changes may be made thereto without departing from the spirit and scope of the present disclosure. Each of these implementations and obvious variations thereof is contemplated as falling within the spirit and scope of the present disclosure. It is also contemplated that additional implementations according to aspects of the present disclosure may combine any number of features from any of the implementations described herein, such as, for example, in the alternative implementations described below.</p>
<heading level="1" id="h-0007">ALTERNATIVE IMPLEMENTATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0178" num="0177">Alternative Implementation 1. A gemstone comprising: a girdle defining a perimeter of the gemstone, the girdle having a cushion-shaped cross-section with a major axis and a minor axis, the major axis being larger than the minor axis; a crown forming an upper portion of the gemstone, a surface of the crown including: a table forming a generally horizontal upper surface of the crown; a plurality of star facets, each of the plurality of star facets being disposed adjacent to and abutting an edge of the table; a plurality of upper intermediate crown facets, each of the plurality of upper intermediate crown facets being disposed generally between two of the plurality of star facets, an upper vertex of each of the plurality of upper intermediate crown facets abutting a vertex of the table; a plurality of lower intermediate crown facets, each of the plurality of lower intermediate crown facets being disposed between two of the plurality of upper intermediate crown facets, an upper vertex of each of the plurality of lower intermediate crown facets abutting a lower vertex of one of the plurality of star facets; a plurality of main crown facets, each of the plurality of main crown facets being disposed between two of the plurality of lower intermediate crown facets, an upper vertex of each of the plurality of main crown facets abutting a lower vertex of one of the plurality of lower intermediate crown facets, the plurality of main crown facets including a plurality of major main crown facets and a plurality of minor main crown facets, the plurality of major main crown facets being aligned along the major axis, the plurality of minor main crown facets being aligned along the minor axis; and a plurality of upper girdle facets formed in pairs of adjacent upper girdle facets, each pair of adjacent upper girdle facets being disposed generally between two of the plurality of main crown facets, upper vertices of both upper girdle facets in each pair of upper girdle facets abutting a lower vertex of one of the plurality of lower intermediate crown facets; and a pavilion forming a lower portion of the gemstone, a surface of the pavilion including: a plurality of culet-adjacent facets forming a lower point of the pavilion, the plurality of culet-adjacent facets including a plurality of major culet-adjacent facets and a plurality of minor culet-adjacent facets, the plurality of major culet-adjacent facets being aligned along the major axis, the plurality of minor culet-adjacent facets being aligned along the minor axis; a plurality of candle facets, a lower portion of each of the plurality of candle facets being disposed generally between two of the plurality of culet-adjacent facets; a plurality of main pavilion facets, each of the main pavilion facets being disposed between two of the plurality of candle facets, a lower edge of each of the plurality of main pavilion facets abutting an upper edge of one of the plurality of culet-adjacent facets, the plurality of main pavilion facets including a plurality of major main pavilion facets and a plurality of minor main pavilion facets, the plurality of major main pavilion facets being aligned along the major axis, the plurality of minor main pavilion facets being aligned along the minor axis; and a plurality of lower girdle facets formed in pairs of adjacent lower girdle facets, each pair of adjacent lower girdle facets being disposed generally between two of the plurality of main pavilion facets, each pair of adjacent lower girdle facets having an upper portion of a respective one of the plurality of candle facets disposed generally therebetween; and wherein the girdle is positioned between the crown and the pavilion, each of the plurality of upper girdle facets being disposed adjacent to and abutting an upper edge of the girdle, and each of the plurality of lower girdle facets being disposed adjacent to and abutting a lower edge of the girdle.</p>
<p id="p-0179" num="0178">Alternative Implementation 2. The gemstone of Alternative Implementation 1, wherein the gemstone has a table percentage between about 31.5% and about 35.5%.</p>
<p id="p-0180" num="0179">Alternative Implementation 3. The gemstone of Alternative Implementation 1, wherein the gemstone has a top depth percentage between about 24.5% and about 28.5%.</p>
<p id="p-0181" num="0180">Alternative Implementation 4. The gemstone of Alternative Implementation 1, wherein the gemstone has a bottom depth percentage between about 48.5% to about 52.5%.</p>
<p id="p-0182" num="0181">Alternative Implementation 5. The gemstone of Alternative Implementation 1, wherein the gemstone has a total depth percentage between about 82.5% and about 86.5%.</p>
<p id="p-0183" num="0182">Alternative Implementation 6. The gemstone of Alternative Implementation 1, wherein the gemstone has a girdle thickness percentage between about 4% and about 10%.</p>
<p id="p-0184" num="0183">Alternative Implementation 7. The gemstone of Alternative Implementation 1, wherein a horizontal plane is defined by the table of the gemstone, and wherein each of the plurality of star facets is disposed at a first angle relative to the horizontal plane, each of the plurality of upper intermediate crown facets is disposed at a second angle relative to the horizontal plane, each of the plurality of lower intermediate crown facets is disposed at a third angle relative to the horizontal plane, each of the plurality of major main crown facets is disposed at a fourth angle relative to the horizontal plane, each of the plurality of minor main crown facets is disposed at a fifth angle relative to the horizontal plane, and each of the plurality of upper girdle facets is disposed at a sixth angle relative to the horizontal plane.</p>
<p id="p-0185" num="0184">Alternative Implementation 8. The gemstone of Alternative Implementation 7, wherein first angle is between about 10&#xb0; and about 17&#xb0;.</p>
<p id="p-0186" num="0185">Alternative Implementation 9. The gemstone of Alternative Implementation 7, wherein the second angle is between about 15&#xb0; and about 24&#xb0;.</p>
<p id="p-0187" num="0186">Alternative Implementation 10. The gemstone of Alternative Implementation 7, wherein the third angle is between about 25&#xb0; and about 35&#xb0;.</p>
<p id="p-0188" num="0187">Alternative Implementation 11. The gemstone of Alternative Implementation 7, wherein the fourth angle is between about 37&#xb0; and about 45&#xb0;.</p>
<p id="p-0189" num="0188">Alternative Implementation 12. The gemstone of Alternative Implementation 7, wherein the fifth angle is between about 42&#xb0; and about 49&#xb0;.</p>
<p id="p-0190" num="0189">Alternative Implementation 13. The gemstone of Alternative Implementation 7, wherein the sixth angle is between about 42.5&#xb0; and about 57&#xb0;.</p>
<p id="p-0191" num="0190">Alternative Implementation 14. The gemstone of Alternative Implementation 1, wherein a horizontal plane is defined by the table of the gemstone, and wherein each of plurality of major culet-adjacent facets is disposed at a first angle relative to the horizontal plane, each of plurality of minor culet-adjacent facets is disposed at a second angle relative to the horizontal plane, each of plurality of candle facets is disposed at a third angle relative to the horizontal plane, each of plurality of major main pavilion facets is disposed at a fourth angle relative to the horizontal plane, each of the plurality of minor main pavilion facets is disposed at a fifth angle relative to the horizontal plane, and each of the plurality of lower girdle facets is disposed at a sixth angle relative to the horizontal plane.</p>
<p id="p-0192" num="0191">Alternative Implementation 15. The gemstone of Alternative Implementation 14, wherein the first angle is between about 32&#xb0; and about 38&#xb0;.</p>
<p id="p-0193" num="0192">Alternative Implementation 16. The gemstone of Alternative Implementation 14, wherein second angle is between about 36&#xb0; and about 42&#xb0;.</p>
<p id="p-0194" num="0193">Alternative Implementation 17. The gemstone of Alternative Implementation 14, wherein the third angle is between about 40&#xb0; and about 42&#xb0;.</p>
<p id="p-0195" num="0194">Alternative Implementation 18. The gemstone of Alternative Implementation 14, wherein the fourth angle is between about 41&#xb0; and about 45&#xb0;.</p>
<p id="p-0196" num="0195">Alternative Implementation 19. The gemstone of Alternative Implementation 14, wherein the fifth angle is between about 45&#xb0; and about 49&#xb0;.</p>
<p id="p-0197" num="0196">Alternative Implementation 20. The gemstone of Alternative Implementation 14, wherein the sixth angle is between about 43&#xb0; and about 57&#xb0;.</p>
<p id="p-0198" num="0197">Alternative Implementation 21. The gemstone of Alternative Implementation 1, wherein the cross-section of the gemstone is a rectangular shape with rounded corners.</p>
<p id="p-0199" num="0198">Alternative Implementation 22. The gemstone of Alternative Implementation 1, wherein the cross-section of the gemstone is a square shape with rounded corners.</p>
<p id="p-0200" num="0199">Alternative Implementation 23. A gemstone comprising: a girdle defining a perimeter of the gemstone, the girdle having a cushion-shaped cross-section; and a crown forming an upper portion of the gemstone, a surface of the crown including: a table forming a generally horizontal upper surface of the crown; a plurality of star facets, each of the plurality of star facets being disposed adjacent to and abutting an edge of the table; a plurality of upper intermediate crown facets, each of the plurality of upper intermediate crown facets being disposed generally between two of the plurality of star facets, an upper vertex of each of the plurality of upper intermediate crown facets abutting a vertex of the table; a plurality of lower intermediate crown facets, each of the plurality of lower intermediate crown facets being disposed between two of the plurality of upper intermediate crown facets, an upper vertex of each of the plurality of lower intermediate crown facets abutting a lower vertex of one of the plurality of star facets; a plurality of main crown facets, each of the plurality of main crown facets being disposed between two of the plurality of lower intermediate crown facets, an upper vertex of each of the plurality of main crown facets abutting a lower vertex of one of the plurality of lower intermediate crown facets; and a plurality of upper girdle facets formed in pairs of adjacent upper girdle facets, each pair of adjacent upper girdle facets being disposed generally between two of the plurality of main crown facets, upper vertices of both upper girdle facets in each pair of upper girdle facets abutting a lower vertex of one of the plurality of lower intermediate crown facets.</p>
<p id="p-0201" num="0200">Alternative Implementation 24. A gemstone comprising: a girdle defining a perimeter of the gemstone, the girdle having a cushion-shaped cross-section; and a pavilion forming a lower portion of the gemstone, a surface of the pavilion including: a plurality of culet-adjacent facets forming a lower point of the pavilion; a plurality of candle facets, a lower portion of each of the plurality of candle facets being disposed generally between two of the plurality of culet-adjacent facets; a plurality of main pavilion facets, each of the plurality of main pavilion facets being disposed between two of the plurality of candle facets, a lower edge of each of the plurality of main pavilion facets abutting an upper edge of one of the plurality of culet-adjacent facets; and a plurality of lower girdle facets formed in pairs of adjacent lower girdle facets, each pair of adjacent lower girdle facets being disposed generally between two of the plurality of main pavilion facets, each pair of adjacent lower girdle facets having an upper portion of a respective one of the plurality of candle facets disposed generally therebetween.</p>
<p id="p-0202" num="0201">Alternative Implementation 25. A gemstone comprising: a girdle defining a perimeter of the gemstone, the girdle having a cushion-shaped cross-section; a crown forming an upper portion of the gemstone, a surface of the crown including: a table forming a generally horizontal upper surface of the crown, the table having a generally octagonal shape; a plurality of star facets disposed adjacent to the table, each of the plurality of star facets being triangle-shaped; a plurality of upper intermediate crown facets disposed adjacent to the plurality of star facets, each of the plurality of upper intermediate crown facets being kite-shaped; a plurality of lower intermediate crown facets disposed adjacent to the plurality of upper intermediate crown facets, each of the plurality of lower intermediate crown facets being kite-shaped; a plurality of main crown facets disposed adjacent to the plurality of lower intermediate crown facets, each of the plurality of main crown facets being kite-shaped; and a plurality of upper girdle facets disposed adjacent to the plurality of main crown facets, each of the plurality of upper girdle facets being triangle-shaped; and a pavilion forming a lower portion of the gemstone, a surface of the pavilion including: a plurality of culet-adjacent facets forming a lower point of the pavilion, each of the plurality of culet-adjacent facets having a generally pentagonal shape; a plurality of candle facets disposed adjacent to the plurality of culet-adjacent facets, each of the plurality of candle facets having six edges; a plurality of main pavilion facets, each of the main pavilion facets being disposed between two of the plurality of candle facets and being pentagon-shaped; and a plurality of lower girdle facets formed in pairs of adjacent lower girdle facets, each pair of adjacent lower girdle facets being disposed generally between two of the plurality of main pavilion facets, each lower girdle facet having four edges; and wherein the girdle is positioned between the crown and the pavilion, each of the plurality of upper girdle facets being disposed adjacent to and abutting an upper edge of the girdle, and each of the plurality of lower girdle facets being disposed adjacent to and abutting a lower edge of the girdle.</p>
<p id="p-0203" num="0202">Alternative Implementation 26. A gemstone comprising: a crown forming an upper portion of the gemstone; a pavilion forming a lower portion of the gemstone; and a girdle positioned between the crown and the pavilion and encircling the gemstone, the girdle having a cushion-shaped cross-section with a major axis and a minor axis, the major axis being larger than the minor axis, wherein the gemstone has a top depth percentage between about 15% and about 35%, and a bottom depth percentage between about 40% and about 60%.</p>
<p id="p-0204" num="0203">Alternative Implementation 27. The gemstone of Alternative Implementation 26, wherein the gemstone has a total depth percentage between about 75% and about 95%.</p>
<p id="p-0205" num="0204">Alternative Implementation 28. The gemstone of Alternative Implementation 26, wherein the gemstone has a table percentage between about 25% and about 45%.</p>
<p id="p-0206" num="0205">Alternative Implementation 29. The gemstone of Alternative Implementation 26, wherein the gemstone has a girdle thickness percentage between about 2% and about 12%.</p>
<p id="p-0207" num="0206">Alternative Implementation 30. A gemstone comprising: a crown forming an upper portion of the gemstone; a pavilion forming a lower portion of the gemstone; and a girdle positioned between the crown and the pavilion and encircling the gemstone, the girdle having a cushion-shaped cross-section with a major axis and a minor axis, the major axis being larger than the minor axis, wherein the gemstone has a total depth percentage between about 75% and about 95%.</p>
<p id="p-0208" num="0207">Alternative Implementation 31. A gemstone comprising: a crown forming an upper portion of the gemstone, a surface of the crown including a first plurality of facets, each of the first plurality of facets being disposed at an angle between about 5&#xb0; and about 60&#xb0; relative to an upper surface of the gemstone; and a pavilion forming a lower portion of the gemstone, a surface of the pavilion including a second plurality of facets, each of the second plurality of facets being disposed at an angle between about 25&#xb0; and about 60&#xb0; relative to the upper surface of the gemstone.</p>
<p id="p-0209" num="0208">Alternative Implementation 32. A method of forming a crown of a gemstone, comprising: forming a generally horizontal upper surface on an upper portion of the gemstone; forming a first temporary set of crown facets and a second temporary set of crown facets on the upper portion of the gemstone, the first temporary set of crown facets being formed at an angle of between about 37&#xb0; and about 45&#xb0; relative to the first preliminary table, the second temporary set of crown facets being formed at an angle of between about 42&#xb0; and about 49&#xb0; relative to the first preliminary table; forming a third temporary set of crown facets on the upper portion of the gemstone from portions of the generally horizontal upper surface, the first temporary set of crown facets, and the second temporary set of crown facets, the third temporary set of crown facets being formed at an angle of between about 27&#xb0; and about 35.5&#xb0; relative to the generally horizontal upper surface, a remainder of the first temporary set of crown facets forming a fourth temporary set of crown facets, a remainder of the second temporary set of crown facets forming a fifth temporary set of crown facets; forming a sixth temporary set of crown facets on the upper portion of the gemstone from portions of the generally horizontal upper surface and the third temporary set of crown facets, the sixth temporary set of crown facets being formed at an angle of between about 15&#xb0; and about 24&#xb0; relative to the generally horizontal upper surface, a remainder of the third temporary set of crown facets forming a first final set of crown facets; forming a second final set of crown facets on the upper portion of the gemstone from portions of the fourth temporary set of crown facets and the fifth temporary set of crown facets, the second final set of crown facets being formed at an angle of between about 42.5&#xb0; and about 57&#xb0; relative to the generally horizontal upper surface, a remainder of the fourth temporary set of crown facets forming a third final set of crown facets, a remainder of the fifth temporary set of crown facets forming a fourth final set of crown facets; and forming a fifth final set of crown facets on the upper portion of the gemstone from portions of the generally horizontal surface and the sixth temporary set of crown facets, the fifth final set of crown facets being formed at an angle of between about 10&#xb0; and about 17&#xb0; relative to the generally horizontal upper surface, a remainder of the sixth temporary set of crown facets forming a sixth final set of crown facets, such that the upper portion of the gemstone is formed from the first, second, third, fourth, fifth, and sixth final sets of crown facets.</p>
<p id="p-0210" num="0209">Alternative Implementation 33. A method of forming a pavilion of a gemstone having a horizontal upper surface, comprising: forming a first temporary set of pavilion facets, a second temporary set of pavilion facets, and a flat lower facet on a lower portion of the gemstone, the first temporary set of pavilion facets being formed at an angle of between about 41&#xb0; and about 45&#xb0; relative to the horizontal upper surface, the second temporary set of pavilion facets being formed at an angle of between about 45&#xb0; and about 49&#xb0; relative to the horizontal upper surface; forming a third temporary set of pavilion facets and a fourth temporary set of pavilion facets on the lower portion of the gemstone, the third temporary set of pavilion facets being formed from the first temporary set of pavilion facets and the flat lower facet, and being formed at an angle of between about 32&#xb0; and about 38&#xb0; relative to the horizontal upper surface, the fourth temporary set of pavilion facets being formed from the second temporary set of pavilion facets and the flat lower facet, and being formed at an angle of between about 36&#xb0; and about 42&#xb0; relative to the horizontal upper surface, a remainder of the first temporary set of pavilion facets forming a fifth temporary set of pavilion facets; a remainder of the second temporary set of pavilion facets forming a sixth temporary set of pavilion facets; forming a seventh temporary set of pavilion facets on the lower portion of the gemstone from portions of third temporary set of pavilion facets, the fourth temporary set of pavilion facets, the fifth temporary set of pavilion facets, and the sixth temporary set of pavilion facets, the seventh set of temporary pavilion facets being formed at an angle of between about 40&#xb0; and about 42&#xb0; relative to the horizontal upper surface, a remainder of the third temporary set of pavilion facets forming a first final set of pavilion facets, a remainder of the fourth temporary set of pavilion facets forming an second final set of pavilion facets, a remainder of the fifth temporary set of pavilion facets forming an eighth temporary set of pavilion facets, a remainder of the sixth temporary set of pavilion facets forming a ninth temporary set of pavilion facets; and forming a third final set of pavilion facets on the lower portion of the gemstone from the seventh temporary set of pavilion facets, the eighth temporary set of pavilion facets, and the ninth temporary set of pavilion facets, the third final set of pavilion facets being formed at an angle of between about 43&#xb0; and about 57&#xb0; relative to the horizontal upper surface, a remainder of the seventh temporary set of pavilion facets forming a fourth final set of pavilion facets, a remainder of the eighth temporary set of pavilion facets forming a fifth final set of pavilion facets, a remainder of the ninth temporary set of pavilion facets forming a sixth final set of pavilion facets, such that the lower portion of the gemstone is formed from the first, second, third, fourth, fifth, and sixth final sets of pavilion facets.</p>
<p id="p-0211" num="0210">Alternative Implementation 34. The method of Alternative Implementation 32 or Alternative Implementation 33, further comprising forming a girdle defining a perimeter of the gemstone, the girdle having a cushion-shaped cross-section with a major axis and a minor axis, the major axis being larger than the minor axis.</p>
<p id="p-0212" num="0211">Alternative Implementation 35. A gemstone comprising: a girdle defining a perimeter of the gemstone; a crown forming an upper portion of the gemstone, a surface of the crown including: a table forming a generally horizontal upper surface of the crown; a plurality of star facets, each of the plurality of star facets being disposed adjacent to and abutting an edge of the table; a plurality of upper intermediate crown facets, each of the plurality of upper intermediate crown facets being disposed generally between two of the plurality of star facets, an upper vertex of each of the plurality of upper intermediate crown facets abutting a vertex of the table; a plurality of lower intermediate crown facets, each of the plurality of lower intermediate crown facets being disposed between two of the plurality of upper intermediate crown facets, an upper vertex of each of the plurality of lower intermediate crown facets abutting a lower vertex of one of the plurality of star facets; a plurality of main crown facets, each of the plurality of main crown facets being disposed between two of the plurality of lower intermediate crown facets, an upper vertex of each of the plurality of main crown facets abutting a lower vertex of one of the plurality of lower intermediate crown facets, the plurality of main crown facets including a plurality of major main crown facets and a plurality of minor main crown facets, the plurality of major main crown facets being aligned along the major axis, the plurality of minor main crown facets being aligned along the minor axis; and a plurality of upper girdle facets formed in pairs of adjacent upper girdle facets, each pair of adjacent upper girdle facets being disposed generally between two of the plurality of main crown facets, upper vertices of both upper girdle facets in each pair of upper girdle facets abutting a lower vertex of one of the plurality of lower intermediate crown facets; and a pavilion forming a lower portion of the gemstone, a surface of the pavilion including: a plurality of culet-adjacent facets forming a lower point of the pavilion, the plurality of culet-adjacent facets including a plurality of major culet-adjacent facets and a plurality of minor culet-adjacent facets, the plurality of major culet-adjacent facets being aligned along the major axis, the plurality of minor culet-adjacent facets being aligned along the minor axis; a plurality of candle facets, a lower portion of each of the plurality of candle facets being disposed generally between two of the plurality of culet-adjacent facets; a plurality of main pavilion facets, each of the main pavilion facets being disposed between two of the plurality of candle facets, a lower edge of each of the plurality of main pavilion facets abutting an upper edge of one of the plurality of culet-adjacent facets, the plurality of main pavilion facets including a plurality of major main pavilion facets and a plurality of minor main pavilion facets, the plurality of major main pavilion facets being aligned along the major axis, the plurality of minor main pavilion facets being aligned along the minor axis; and a plurality of lower girdle facets formed in pairs of adjacent lower girdle facets, each pair of adjacent lower girdle facets being disposed generally between two of the plurality of main pavilion facets, each pair of adjacent lower girdle facets having an upper portion of a respective one of the plurality of candle facets disposed generally therebetween; wherein the girdle is positioned between the crown and the pavilion, each of the plurality of upper girdle facets being disposed adjacent to and abutting an upper edge of the girdle, and each of the plurality of lower girdle facets being disposed adjacent to and abutting a lower edge of the girdle.</p>
<p id="p-0213" num="0212">It is expressly contemplated that one or more elements or any portion(s) thereof from any of the Alternative Implementations 1-35 above can be combined with one or more elements or any portion(s) thereof from any of the other ones of the Alternative Implementations 1-35 to form one or more additional alternative implementations of the present disclosure.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A gemstone comprising:
<claim-text>a girdle defining a perimeter of the gemstone, the girdle having a cushion-shaped cross-section with a major axis and a minor axis, the major axis being larger than the minor axis; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a crown forming an upper portion of the gemstone, a surface of the crown including:
<claim-text>a table forming a generally horizontal upper surface of the crown;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of star facets, each of the plurality of star facets being disposed adjacent to and abutting an edge of the table;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of upper intermediate crown facets, each of the plurality of upper intermediate crown facets being disposed generally between two of the plurality of star facets, an upper vertex of each of the plurality of upper intermediate crown facets abutting a vertex of the table;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of lower intermediate crown facets, each of the plurality of lower intermediate crown facets being disposed between two of the plurality of upper intermediate crown facets, an upper vertex of each of the plurality of lower intermediate crown facets abutting a lower vertex of one of the plurality of star facets;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of main crown facets, each of the plurality of main crown facets being disposed between two of the plurality of lower intermediate crown facets, an upper vertex of each of the plurality of main crown facets abutting a lower vertex of one of the plurality of lower intermediate crown facets; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of upper girdle facets formed in pairs of adjacent upper girdle facets, each pair of adjacent upper girdle facets being disposed generally between two of the plurality of main crown facets, each of the plurality of upper girdle facets being disposed adjacent to and abutting an upper edge of the girdle, upper vertices of both upper girdle facets in each pair of upper girdle facets abutting a lower vertex of one of the plurality of lower intermediate crown facets.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-02-20" num="02-20">
<claim-text><b>2</b>-<b>20</b>. (canceled)</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
