<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225509A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225509</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18156556</doc-number>
<date>20230119</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>96</main-group>
<subgroup>20</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>96</main-group>
<subgroup>20</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>2096</main-group>
<subgroup>209</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">DAMAGE-FREE REMOVABLE AND INTERCHANGEABLE CABINET ACCESSORY</invention-title>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>63266958</doc-number>
<date>20220120</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Bebout</last-name>
<first-name>Theresa</first-name>
<address>
<city>Bellevue</city>
<state>WA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Bebout</last-name>
<first-name>Theresa</first-name>
<address>
<city>Bellevue</city>
<state>WA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Disclosed herein is a damage-free, removably mountable, interchangeable cabinet covering system that allows a user to quickly and easily change the outward appearance of their cabinets. The system disclosed herein can be retrofitted onto existing cabinets without damaging the external appearance thereof. In some embodiments, the system can be mounted and dismounted without the use of tools in a quick and convenient manner. Since the system can be mounted without damaging the external appearance, the cabinets can be returned to their original look with minimal time and effort.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="124.21mm" wi="138.68mm" file="US20230225509A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="247.23mm" wi="144.86mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225509A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="185.42mm" wi="134.70mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225509A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="184.74mm" wi="135.04mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225509A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="192.02mm" wi="132.93mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225509A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="190.16mm" wi="133.27mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225509A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="113.11mm" wi="52.24mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225509A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims the benefit of U.S. Provisional Patent Application No. 63/266,958, filed Jan. 20, 2022, which is incorporated by reference herein in its entirety.</p>
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="tail"?>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">Field</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure generally relates to cabinet accessory systems configured to overlay at least a portion of the outward facing surface of a piece of furniture such as a cabinet door.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">Description of Certain Related Art</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Past attempts have been made to facilitate the process of renovating or otherwise reconfiguring the outward appearance of a cabinet. However, these implementations involve complicated mounting mechanisms that are inconvenient to use, expensive to manufacture, difficult to install, are specific to different types of cabinets, and are permanent once installed. As such, these implementations are incompatible with traditional cabinet designs and therefore cannot be retrofitted onto an existing cabinet without making substantial modifications or implementing an entirely new cabinet system. Furthermore, the systems require making permanent modifications to the existing cabinet, meaning that the user cannot revert the cabinet back to its original outward appearance.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">For example, Kane U.S. Pat. No. 9,433,286B2 purports to disclose a cabinetry system having removable cabinet faces. However, the apparatus disclosed by Kane requires adding an additional intervening magnetic cabinet door frame that is mounted to the cabinet to which a removable cabinet door is affixed. From the disclosure it is clear that this implementation cannot be retrofitted onto an existing cabinet without making substantial, permanent modifications to the existing cabinet frame.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Similarly, Osen U.S. Pat. No. 6,053,585A purports to disclose an interchangeable cabinet front system. The system includes a hollow cabinet door frame including a channel configured to receive a removable cabinet front. However, it is clear from this disclosure that this system cannot be retrofitted onto an existing cabinet without performing substantial modifications to implement the disclosed channel and hollow frame into the cabinet door.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Finally, documents such as Martinez U.S. Pat. No. 3,697,363A purport to disclose a magnetic covering system. However, the implementations disclosed by Martinez require hollow channels to be permanently carved into a panel assembly configured to slidably receive the removable panel to be displayed through a hollow opening in a similar manner to Osen, or require the outward facing surface to be prepared with a frontward facing attachment mechanism configured to directly interface with the removable panel. As such, the system cannot be implemented without damaging or otherwise altering the outward surface of the cabinet to implement the attachment mechanism and therefore the user cannot revert the cabinet back to its original outward appearance.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The present disclosure generally relates to cabinet accessory systems. In some configurations the cabinet accessory systems disclosed herein can be quickly and removably mounted to a cabinet to change the outward appearance thereof. In some embodiments, the cabinet accessory system can be mounted without the use of tools. In the same or different embodiment, the cabinet accessory system can be mounted without damaging the external appearance of the cabinet system. In this manner, the cabinet accessory system can be quickly and easily removed to revert the cabinet to their original appearance without leaving any scuffs or damaging marks caused from application of the present system.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In some embodiments, the system may be a damage-free removable cabinet accessory system. In various configurations, the system may comprise at least one retaining element affixed to the interior of the cabinet door; and a cabinet accessory configured to interface with the at least one retaining element disposed on the interior of the cabinet door to removably couple the cabinet accessory to the cabinet door.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In the same or different embodiment, the system may further include a layer, such as a protective covering over at least a portion of the cabinet-door facing surface of the cabinet accessory configured to prevent damage to the cabinet door when the accessory is mounted thereto.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In still further configurations, the cabinet accessory may be prepared from a variety of lightweight materials, including a lightweight polymer such as polyethylene, polyurethane, or polystyrene. In other configurations the cabinet accessory may be prepared from balsa wood, formica, composite plastic, dry erase board, or paneling. In the same or different embodiment, the lightweight cabinet accessory may be configured to include an anti-stain and/or heat resistant coating.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In some embodiments, the present disclosure relates to a damage-free cabinet accessory system comprising: an accessory attachment mechanism configured to be coupled to an interior surface of a cabinet door; and a removable cabinet accessory configured for application to an exterior surface of a cabinet door; wherein the removable cabinet accessory includes a first coupling system configured to interface with the accessory attachment mechanism to removably affix the cabinet accessory to the cabinet door.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In the same or different embodiment, the system may further comprise: a protective coating layer configured to prevent damage to the exterior surface of the cabinet. The protective coating layer may have a thickness ranging between about 1 mm to about 10 mm. The protective coating layer may be prepared from a polymer. In the same or different configuration, the protective coating layer may be prepared from a fabric, such as felt or velvet. In some embodiments, the protective coating layer covers substantially the entire cabinet-facing surface of the accessory. In the same or different embodiment, the protective coating layer may comprise at least two separated sections of protective coating.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In some implementations, the removable cabinet accessory configured for application to an external surface of a cabinet door has a weight ranging from about 5 oz to about 10.5 oz. Likewise, in some configurations, the removable cabinet accessory configured for application to an external surface of a cabinet door is prepared from wood, such as balsa wood and can be configured to receive acrylic paint. In other embodiments, the removable cabinet accessory configured for application to an external surface of a cabinet door is prepared from a polymer such as polyethylene, polyurethane, or polystyrene. In some configurations, the removable cabinet accessory configured for application to an external surface of a cabinet door includes at least one of: a stain resistant coating; and a heat resistant coating. Likewise, the removable cabinet accessory configured for application to an external surface of a cabinet door can also include a decorative or useful surface ornamentation.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In some embodiments of the present disclosure, the accessory attachment mechanism configured to be coupled to the interior surface of the cabinet door includes a magnetic mounting mechanism configured to be affixed to the interior surface of the cabinet door and further configured to interface with the first coupling system implemented on the removable cabinet accessory. In some configurations the magnetic mounting mechanism configured to be affixed to the interior surface of the cabinet door includes a first magnet positioned near one edge of the removable cabinet accessory, and a second magnet positioned near the opposing edge of the removable cabinet accessory.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In some instances, the present disclosure relates to a kit for reconfiguring the outward appearance of a cabinet, the kit comprising: a removable cabinet accessory, having an outward and inward face, the accessory configured for application to an external surface of a cabinet door, having at least one magnetic attachment mechanism affixed to the inward face of the accessory; wherein the removable cabinet accessory includes at least one useful embellishment implemented along the outward face of the accessory; and a magnetic accessory attachment mechanism configured to be coupled to the interior surface of a cabinet door and configured to interface with the at least one magnetic attachment mechanism affixed to the inward face of the accessory. In various embodiments, the at least one useful embellishment is selected from the group consisting of: a chalkboard; white board; dart board; calendar; potty chart; toothbrush chart; and a peg or hook board.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In some instances, the present disclosure relates to a consumer product set for reconfiguring the outward appearance of one or more kitchen cabinets, the product set comprising: a removable cabinet accessory, having an outward and inward face, the accessory configured for application to an external surface of a cabinet door; wherein the removable cabinet accessory includes a protective surface covering affixed to the inward face of the accessory; wherein the removable cabinet accessory includes four magnetic attachment mechanisms affixed to the inward face of the accessory; wherein the removable cabinet accessory includes at least one useful embellishment implemented along the outward face of the accessory; and a magnetic accessory attachment mechanism configured to be coupled to the interior surface of a cabinet door and configured to interface with the at least one magnetic attachment mechanism affixed to the inward face of the accessory.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Various embodiments are depicted in the accompanying drawings for illustrative purposes and should in no way be interpreted as limiting the scope of the disclosure. Various features of different disclosed embodiments can be combined to form additional embodiments, which are part of this disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref> depicts a front view of a cabinet accessory system including a cabinet and a removable accessory covering.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>B</figref> depicts a front view of an accessory removably mounted to a cabinet system.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>A</figref> presents a rear view of a cabinet accessory covering and the interior of the cabinet to which it may be mounted.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>B</figref> presents a rear view of a cabinet and accessory covering including a protective layer alongside a view of the interior of a cabinet to which it may be mounted.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>C</figref> presents a rear view of a cabinet including an accessory covering that includes a two-piece attachment mechanism and an associated mechanism implemented on the interior of a cabinet.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>D</figref> presents a rear view of a cabinet and accessory covering including a single-piece attachment mechanism and an associated mechanism implemented on the interior of a cabinet.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> presents a view of an isolated attachment mechanism.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION INCLUDING PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Various systems and methods relating to damage-free removably mountable cabinet accessories are described below to illustrate various examples that may achieve one or more desired improvements. These examples are only illustrative and not intended in any way to restrict the general disclosure presented or the various aspects and features described herein. Furthermore, the general principles described herein may be applied to embodiments and applications other than those specifically discussed herein without departing from the spirit and scope of this disclosure. For example, although the present disclosure refers to damage-free removably mountable cabinet accessories, it will be apricated by those of skill in the art that the systems and methods disclosed herein can be applied to other surfaces as well, such as drawers, wardrobes, dressers, toolkits, and the like. As such, this disclosure is not limited to any particular embodiment shown but is instead to be accorded the widest scope consistent with the principles and features that are disclosed or suggested.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Although certain aspects, advantages, and features are described herein, it is not necessary that any particular embodiment include or achieve any or all of those aspects, advantages, or features. Some embodiments may not achieve the advantages described herein but may achieve other advantages instead. Any structure, material, feature, or step in any embodiment can be used in place of, or in addition to, any structure, feature, or step in any other embodiment, or omitted. This disclosure contemplates all combinations of features from the various disclosed embodiments. No feature, structure, or step is essential or indispensable.</p>
<heading id="h-0008" level="2">Overview</heading>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Cabinets take up a substantial amount of a kitchen's visible area, and therefore, the outward appearance of a kitchen or other room's cabinets contribute greatly to the overall appearance and style of the room. As such, reconfiguring the outward appearance of cabinets can drastically alter the appearance of the room and is a common practice in home renovations, seasonal decorations, party planning, and similar activities. Unfortunately, replacing cabinet doors can be a time intensive and costly endeavor requiring that the original cabinet door be removed from its hinges as a new cabinet door is fabricated and installed. Furthermore, cabinets are typically implemented in a series, which only multiplies the time and expense required to complete the renovation by the number of cabinets in need of refinishing.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Some cabinet systems are built to be modular and interchangeable to facilitate modifying the appearance of the cabinet quickly. However, these approaches require that the cabinet be specially built for this purpose since they require intervening magnetic frames to mount different coverings upon, or they require hollow openings in the cabinet door and channels into which different coverings can be slid into place. Unfortunately, these designs are complicated and expensive to manufacture which can dissuade homeowners from implementing these systems in their homes. Furthermore, these systems are incompatible with existing cabinet designs and cannot be retrofitted onto existing cabinets without significant modifications. As such, these systems fail to achieve their purpose for the vast majority of homeowners who do not already utilize a modular cabinet system and instead maintain traditional cabinets.</p>
<heading id="h-0009" level="2">Removably Mountable Cabinet Accessory Systems</heading>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Disclosed herein are various systems and methods for implementing a removably mountable cabinet accessory system. In various configurations, the cabinet accessory systems disclosed herein are quick and easy to mount, convenient to remove, and do not damage the outward appearance of the cabinet such that the cabinet can be returned to its original outward appearance when the accessory is removed.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">In various configurations, the removably mountable cabinet accessory systems include a cabinet accessory configured to be removably mounted to the outward facing surface of the door of a cabinet. In some configurations, the facade may be lightweight and can further include various coatings suitable for the application area and suitable to achieve certain desired functionalities.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">In some embodiments, the facade may have a weight ranging from about 0.05 lbs to about 5 lbs. For example, in some configurations the facade may have a weight of about 0.05 lbs, 0.1 lbs, 0.15 lbs, 0.2 lbs, 0.25 lbs, 0.5 lbs, 1 lbs, 2 lbs, 4 lbs, about 5 lbs, or any weight therein. It will be appreciated that the precise weight of a given device may depend on a number of factors including the size, shape, and material selection. For example, in one embodiment a plastic backsplash material may be employed in a cabinet covering having a height of about 16 inches, a width of about 12.5 inches, and a weight of about 5.7 ounces. A similar facade having a height of about 31 inches and a width of about 11.5 inches may have a weight of about 10.3 ounces. In other configurations, light weight materials may be employed, including polymers such as polystyrene. In one such configuration, a panel having a thickness of about 0.040 inches, a height of about 31 inches, and a width of about 11.5 inches may have a weight of about 6.4 ounces. Similarly, a styrene panel having a thickness of about 0.040 inches, a height of about 31 inches, and a width of about 11.5 inches may have a weight of about 5.7 ounces. However, it will be appreciated that the precise measurement and weight of the device may depend on a particular application, material choice, size, design selection, and the like, and is not bound by the foregoing examples.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The accessory may include a mounting mechanism to facilitate mounting the accessory to the cabinet door. Likewise, the accessory system may further include an attachment mechanism configured to be disposed on the interior of the cabinet door. As such, the attachment mechanism mounted to the interior of the cabinet door can be configured to interact with the accessory to affix the accessory to the cabinet. In this manner, the accessory can be quickly and easily mounted to the front of the cabinet door and removed or replaced when desired without permanently altering the outward appearance of the cabinet to which it was mounted.</p>
<heading id="h-0010" level="2">Accessory Systems</heading>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">In some embodiments, the cabinet covering system makes use of a front accessory covering configured to be temporarily affixed to the front of a cabinet, such as to a cabinet door. The accessory may also be referred to as a veneer or other covering. The accessory can be configured to rest over an entire surface such as the entire front surface, or only a portion of the front surface of the cabinet to which it is mounted to alter the appearance thereof, and in some embodiments, provide advantageous functionality.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref> depicts a front view of a cabinet accessory system <b>100</b> prepared in accordance with the present disclosure. As can be seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref>, the cabinet accessory system <b>100</b> includes a cabinet <b>101</b> having a cabinet door <b>102</b>. The cabinet door <b>102</b> includes the cabinet door attachment system <b>103</b><i>a</i>-<i>d </i>configured to interface with an attachment system <b>111</b><i>a</i>-<i>d </i>implemented on the removable cabinet accessory <b>110</b>, the front surface <b>112</b> of which is depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>B</figref> depicts a front view of the cabinet accessory <b>110</b> removably mounted to the cabinet door <b>102</b> to alter the appearance thereof. Accordingly, in the depicted configuration, the removably mountable cabinet accessory <b>110</b> can be mounted and dismounted from the cabinet door <b>102</b> in a simple and convenient manner that, in various configurations, does not require any additional tooling or permanent modifications be made to the surface to which it is mounted.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>A-B</figref> further depict a rear view of a cabinet accessory system <b>100</b> prepared in accordance with the present disclosure. As can be seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>A-B</figref>, the cabinet accessory system <b>100</b> includes a cabinet <b>101</b> having a cabinet door <b>102</b>. Implemented along the cabinet door <b>102</b> is at least one attachment mechanism <b>103</b><i>a</i>-<i>d. </i>Similarly, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>A-B</figref> depict a removably mountable cabinet accessory <b>110</b>, the rear surface <b>113</b> of which is clearly visible. Implemented along the rear surface <b>113</b> of the cabinet accessory <b>110</b> is at least one attachment mechanism <b>111</b><i>a</i>-<i>d </i>configured to interface with the at least one attachment mechanism <b>103</b><i>a</i>-<i>d </i>disposed on the internal surface of the cabinet door <b>102</b>. In this manner, the cabinet accessory <b>110</b> can be removably affixed to the cabinet door <b>102</b> to alter the outward appearance thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The cabinet accessory system <b>100</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref> includes a removably mountable cabinet accessory <b>110</b>. The removably mountable cabinet accessory <b>110</b> can serve to alter the outward facing appearance of the cabinet to which it is mounted in a temporary and reversible manner. As such, in various embodiments the removably mountable cabinet accessory <b>110</b> includes a decorative or otherwise useful surface <b>112</b>. The decorative surface <b>112</b> may be adorned with a variety of ornamental features, pictures, depictions, or other useful designs.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">For instance, in some configurations the decorative surface <b>112</b> of the cabinet accessory <b>110</b> may include pictures, 3D designs, faux-material finishes, and other similar designs which can alter the outward appearance of the cabinet. In some embodiments, the decorative surface <b>112</b> of the cabinet accessory may include functional designs. By way of example, in some configurations, the decorative surface <b>112</b> may include a chalkboard or whiteboard style surface for marking, such as for children to draw on or for grocery lists to be recorded. Likewise, the decorative surface <b>112</b> may include other useful designs, such as a dart board design or calendar. From the foregoing description, it will be appreciated that a wide variety of different forms and finishes may be employed to alter the existing cabinet design or to introduce new functionality by providing a surface that can be drawn or written on, decorated, adorned, or used for other purposes&#x2014;such as providing a dartboard style surface, potty charts, reusable sticker charts, tooth brush charts, and the like&#x2014;that can later be removed or interchanged without damaging or permanently altering the original cabinet finish below.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The accessory <b>110</b> may be prepared from a variety of different materials suitable for the intended purpose of the accessory or system. For example, in various embodiments, the accessory <b>110</b> may be made from a lightweight material to facilitate a magnetic attachment process. For example, in some embodiments the accessory <b>110</b> may be prepared from a lightweight material including polymers such as vinyl, polyvinyl chloride, polystyrene, or polyurethane. Polymer materials are a suitable choice for preparing the accessory <b>110</b> because the materials are economical to source and are stain resistant. In this manner, the accessory <b>110</b> can be painted or otherwise marked, and then washed and re-used. Likewise, accessories <b>110</b> prepared from polymer materials are resistant to stains from everyday kitchen use, such as splattering of food residue and oils, which can be a common occurrence in many kitchens. The lightweight design of such system allows for a variety of attachment mechanisms to be implemented, including magnetic attachment mechanisms that can provide significant advantageous functionality.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">In other embodiments, the accessory <b>110</b> may be prepared from a different lightweight material such as balsa wood. Balsa wood is a particularly advantageous material to prepare the accessory <b>110</b> from, due in part to its light weight and further due to its ability to receive acrylic paints. As such, balsa wood accessories are especially suitable for applications where the accessory <b>110</b> will be coated in an acrylic paint or configured to receive an acrylic paint. For example, in some configurations, the accessory <b>110</b> may be mounted to a cabinet to provide a surface upon which children may draw or color without damaging or otherwise tarnishing the cabinet finish. In other configurations, the accessory <b>110</b> may be prepared from plywood or particleboard to produce the lightweight panels in an economical manner. Nevertheless, it will be appreciated that a wide variety of other materials are suitable and may be utilized without deviating from the scope of the present disclosure. For instance, in some embodiments the accessory <b>110</b> may be prepared from a lightweight composite material such as carbon fiber. In other embodiments, the accessory <b>110</b> may be prepared from a thin or otherwise lightweight metallic sheet, such as aluminum. In still other embodiments, the accessory can include a mirrored surface, corkboard, peg board, a surface with multiple hooks, or one or more surfaces having other utilitarian functions as discussed herein.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">In various embodiments, the accessory is configured to prevent damaging the cabinet or other surface to which it may be mounted. To facilitate removing the accessory <b>110</b> from the cabinet door <b>102</b> without leaving any scuffs or damaging marks thereon, the accessory <b>110</b> may include a non-damaging coating to prevent the system from damaging the outward appearance of the cabinet. Suitable non-damaging coatings include a fabric liner, such as a felt or velvet liner. In other embodiments, a polymer may be employed such as a soft polymer including soft rubbers and the like. Polymer based coatings can be advantageous to increase the friction between the accessory <b>110</b> and the cabinet door <b>101</b> to reduce the chance of the accessory <b>110</b> slipping or becoming displaced from its original orientation. In various configurations, it can be advantageous to employ a thin non-damaging layer to reduce the amount of material through which the magnetic forces must be transferred to affix the removable accessory <b>110</b> to the cabinet door <b>102</b>. In some configurations, the thickness of the protective coating may range from about 0.1 mm to about 10 mm. For example, in some embodiments the protective coating may have a thickness of about 0.1 mm, 0.2 mm, 0.3 mm, 0.6 mm, 1 mm, 2 mm, 4 mm, 8 mm, 10 mm, or any thickness therein.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">For instance, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>B</figref> presents a rear view of an embodiment of a damage-free removably mountable accessory <b>110</b> having a non-damaging coating <b>114</b> applied to the rear surface <b>113</b> of the removably mountable accessory <b>110</b>. The non-damaging coating <b>114</b> can be applied over the top of the attachment mechanism <b>111</b> or beneath the attachment mechanism <b>113</b>. In various configurations, it can be advantageous to apply the non-damaging coating <b>114</b> over the top of the attachment mechanism <b>113</b> so that the front surface of the cabinet door <b>102</b> is not damaged through the application of the removable accessory <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">While the embodiment depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>B</figref> includes a non-damaging coating <b>114</b> overlaid across substantially the entire portion of the rear surface <b>113</b> of the accessory <b>110</b>, it will be appreciated that in some configurations the non-damaging coating <b>114</b> may be overlaid across only a portion of the rear surface <b>113</b>. In other configurations, multiple portions of a non-damaging coating may be overlaid across disparate portions of the rear surface <b>113</b> of the accessory <b>110</b> to prevent damaging the underlying structure. For example, two or more strips of the non-damaging coating may be applied along the top and bottom edges of the rear surface <b>113</b>. In other configurations, the non-damaging coating may be applied along the perimeter of the rear surface <b>113</b>, or only along the midportion of the rear surface <b>113</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">In various embodiments, the accessory <b>110</b> further includes at least one attachment mechanism <b>111</b> disposed along its rear surface <b>113</b>. In various embodiments, the at least one attachment mechanism <b>111</b> can be configured to interface with the at least one attachment mechanism <b>103</b> disposed on the interior surface <b>105</b> of the cabinet door <b>102</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">For instance, in the embodiment depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref>, the removable cabinet accessory <b>110</b> includes as an attachment mechanism a series of four magnetic plates <b>111</b><i>a</i>-<i>d </i>configured to interface with the series of four magnets <b>103</b><i>a</i>-<i>d </i>serving as the attachment mechanism disposed on the interior of the cabinet door <b>102</b>. In this manner, the magnetic forces are transmitted through the cabinet door <b>102</b> to affix the removable accessory <b>110</b> thereto. As used herein, terms such as a magnetic plate or magnet may be used to refer to a segment of material exhibiting magnetic character such as paramagnetism, diamagnetism, and ferromagnetism. For instance, the magnetic plate may be a permanent magnet or a band of iron, among other suitable materials.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">In this manner, utilizing a series of magnets&#x2014;such as a series of four magnetic plates as shown in the embodiment depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref>&#x2014;provides several advantages. For instance, in some embodiments the poles of the magnets on opposite sides of the device may be altered to automatically align the removable accessory <b>110</b> into the correct orientation with regard to the cabinet door <b>102</b>. For instance, the upper magnets <b>103</b><i>a, </i><b>103</b><i>b </i>may have a reversed polarity with respect to the lower magnets <b>103</b><i>c, </i><b>103</b><i>d. </i>Likewise, the magnets implemented along the removable accessory <b>110</b> may also have reversed polarities with respect to the upper set <b>111</b><i>a, </i><b>111</b><i>b </i>and the lower set <b>111</b><i>c, </i><b>111</b><i>d. </i>In this manner, the removable accessory <b>110</b> can only affix to the cabinet door <b>102</b> in a single orientation and can be configured to automatically align itself into the correct orientation due to the polarity of the magnets.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Although the present implementation is discussed with regard to a series of four magnets and the associated advantages the configuration provides, it will be appreciated that other implementations may be utilized, such as using fewer than four magnets or more than four magnets.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">For instance, in some embodiments, fewer than four magnets are utilized. By way of example, in the embodiment depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>C</figref>, two magnetic plates <b>111</b><i>a</i>-<b>111</b><i>b </i>are implemented along opposite ends of the rear surface <b>113</b> of the accessory <b>110</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>C</figref>, the two magnetic plates <b>111</b><i>a</i>-<b>111</b><i>b </i>are configured to interface with the magnets <b>103</b><i>a</i>-<b>103</b><i>b </i>disposed along the interior surface <b>105</b> of the cabinet door <b>102</b>. As in the depicted configuration, when fewer than four magnetic plates are utilized, it can be advantageous to position the magnetic plates along opposite ends of the accessory <b>110</b>, such as along the top and bottom ends, or along the left and right sides to ensure a secure attachment.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">In still further configurations, such as the configuration depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>D</figref>, only one magnetic plate <b>111</b> may be implemented along the rear surface <b>113</b> of the accessory <b>110</b>. In this manner, the magnetic plate <b>111</b> may be configured to interface with a single magnet <b>103</b> disposed along the interior surface <b>105</b> of the cabinet door <b>102</b>. By leveraging the magnetic interaction between the magnet <b>103</b> and the magnetic plate <b>111</b>, the accessory <b>110</b> can be removably affixed to the cabinet door <b>102</b>. In the depicted embodiment, the magnetic plate <b>111</b> is disposed substantially along the center axis of the accessory <b>110</b>. It has been found that by positioning the attachment point towards the centerline of the accessory <b>110</b> that the attachment between the accessory <b>110</b> and the cabinet door <b>102</b> is secure and suitable for the intended purpose such that the accessory <b>110</b> does not become dislodged when the door <b>102</b> is actuated or otherwise used.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">In other configurations, a combination of the foregoing embodiments may be employed. For example, in some embodiments, one magnetic attachment point may be implemented along the center of the rear surface of the accessory. The one magnetic attachment point may have its north pole aligned towards the upper edge of the accessory while the south pole is aligned towards the bottom edge of the accessory. A corresponding magnetic attachment mechanism may be affixed to the interior of the cabinet door. In this manner, the accessory can still be configured to self-align into the correct orientation due to the opposing forces of the opposite poles of the magnetic plates when the accessory is brought close to the cabinet door to be removably affixed thereto.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">With regard to the foregoing discussion, it will be appreciated by those of skill in the art that less than four magnets may be utilized such as about one magnet, two magnets, or about three magnets. Similarly, in other configurations, more than four magnets may be used such as about five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten, or more magnets. In other embodiments, the accessory itself may be prepared from a magnetic material configured to interface with the attachment mechanism disposed on the interior of the cabinet door <b>102</b> to reduce or eliminate the need for additional magnets or magnetic plates to be implemented along the rear surface <b>113</b> of the accessory <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">It has been found that there are a variety of mechanisms suitable for adhering various plates to the accessory <b>110</b>. In some embodiments, the one or more magnets or magnetic plates <b>111</b> can be adhered to the accessory <b>110</b> through the use of an adhesive, be mechanically affixed, or otherwise adhered through methods known to those skilled in the art.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">For example, in some embodiments, the magnets or magnetic plates <b>111</b> can be adhered to the accessory <b>110</b> through the use of an adhesive, such as an adhesive coating provided on one surface of the magnet <b>111</b> so it may be adhered to the rear surface <b>113</b> of the accessory <b>110</b>. In other configurations, a magnet or magnetic plate <b>111</b> can be mechanically affixed to the accessory <b>110</b>. For example, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> depicts a magnetic plate <b>311</b> having teeth <b>311</b><i>a</i>-<i>b </i>configured to grab the accessory when the flat rear surface of the accessory is pressed against the magnetic plate <b>311</b>. Specifically, it can be seen that the resilient teeth <b>311</b><i>a</i>-<i>b </i>are configured to bow outwards and apply tension along the accessory as the teeth attempt to return to their original configuration. In this manner, the accessory may be pressed against the magnetic plate <b>311</b> to affix the accessory between the teeth <b>311</b><i>a</i>-<i>b </i>of the magnetic plate <b>311</b>. It will be appreciated that two, three, four, or more teeth may be implemented as discussed herein without deviating from the scope of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">In other embodiments, the magnetic plates <b>111</b> may be adhered to the accessory <b>110</b> using a heat treatment system. For example, the magnetic plate <b>111</b> may have teeth or other outcroppings implemented along one or more surfaces of the magnetic plate <b>111</b>. The teeth or other outcroppings may be pressed into the accessory <b>110</b> and heat may be applied to mechanically affix the two pieces together.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Likewise, in various configurations, the at least one magnet <b>103</b> disposed along the interior surface <b>105</b> of the cabinet door <b>102</b> may be adhered thereto in a variety of manners. By way of example, in some embodiments, such as the embodiment depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>A</figref>, each of the four magnets <b>103</b><i>a</i>-<i>d </i>may be affixed to the interior of the cabinet door <b>102</b> through the use of an adhesive.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">For instance, in some embodiments each of the four magnets <b>103</b><i>a</i>-<i>d </i>may include an adhesive coating on one surface of the magnet so it may be adhered to the interior of the cabinet door <b>102</b>. The adhesive employed may be a pressure-sensitive adhesive, structural adhesive, or other adhesive known to those of skill in the art. In the present context, a pressure-sensitive adhesive provides the advantage of being simple to install without requiring additional drying or curing agents to complete the bond.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">In other embodiments, one or more of the magnets <b>103</b><i>a</i>-<i>d </i>may be mechanically fixed to the cabinet door <b>102</b> through the use of screws, nails, hooks, tension fittings, or other fasteners.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">In these embodiments the magnets <b>103</b><i>a</i>-<i>d </i>may be permanently affixed to the interior of the cabinet door using a mechanical attachment mechanism. For instance, one or more of the magnets <b>103</b><i>a</i>-<i>d </i>may include a screw, nail, or other penetrating member to be driven into the cabinet door to affix the magnet thereto. Nevertheless, in these embodiments the outward appearance of the cabinet is left unaffected. As such, the system can still be removed while reverting the cabinet to its original outward appearance.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">In some embodiments, the cabinet door <b>102</b> may be prepared to receive one or more of the magnets <b>103</b><i>a</i>-<i>d. </i>For instance, in some embodiments small holes or divots may be drilled into the interior of the cabinet door without penetrating all the way through. In this manner, one or more of the magnets <b>103</b><i>a</i>-<i>d </i>may be inserted into the hole or divot to reduce the amount of material that the magnetic forces must be transmitted through to affix the accessory <b>110</b> to the cabinet door <b>102</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">By reducing the amount of material required for the magnetic forces to be transmitted through, the bond between the accessory <b>110</b> and the cabinet door <b>102</b> can be strengthened to reduce the chance that the accessory <b>110</b> will become displaced during everyday use.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">However, it will be appreciated that a variety of other attachment mechanisms can be implemented without deviating from the scope of the present disclosure. For instance, in some configurations a removable adhesive may be used to adhere the accessory to the cabinet. By way of example, <b>3</b>M removable adhesive can be used to adhere the accessory to the cabinet. In other configurations, clips, snaps, buckles, or clasps can be used to affix the accessory to the cabinet. In still further configurations, a combination of the foregoing elements may be employed to affix the accessory to the cabinet. For example, in some configurations clips can be adhered to the cabinet door using a removable adhesive or magnetic device, and the accessory can be configured to interface with the clips in a removable manner.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">In this manner, the present system can be quickly, simply, and removably mounted to a piece of furniture, such as the door of a cabinet, to alter the outward appearance thereof while still providing the owner with the option to revert the piece of furniture to its original appearance.</p>
<heading id="h-0011" level="2">Certain Terminology</heading>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">Conditional language, such as &#x201c;can,&#x201d; &#x201c;could,&#x201d; &#x201c;might,&#x201d; or &#x201c;may,&#x201d; unless specifically stated otherwise, or otherwise understood within the context as used, is generally intended to convey that certain embodiments include, while other embodiments do not include, certain features, elements, and/or steps. Thus, such conditional language is not generally intended to imply that features, elements, and/or steps are in any way required for one or more embodiments or that one or more embodiments necessarily include logic for deciding, with or without user input or prompting, whether these features, elements, and/or steps are included or are to be performed in any particular embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">Conjunctive language such as the phrase &#x201c;at least one of X, Y, and Z,&#x201d; unless specifically stated otherwise, is otherwise understood with the context as used in general to convey that an item, term, etc. may be either X, Y, or Z. Thus, such conjunctive language is not generally intended to imply that certain embodiments require the presence of at least one of X, at least one of Y, and at least one of Z.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">Unless otherwise explicitly stated, articles such as &#x201c;a&#x201d; or &#x201c;an&#x201d; should generally be interpreted to include one or more described items. Accordingly, phrases such as &#x201c;a device configured to&#x201d; are intended to include one or more recited devices. Such one or more recited devices can also be collectively configured to carry out the stated recitations. For example, &#x201c;a processor configured to carry out recitations A, B, and C&#x201d; can include a first processor configured to carry out recitation A working in conjunction with a second processor configured to carry out recitations B and C.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">The terms &#x201c;comprising,&#x201d; &#x201c;including,&#x201d; &#x201c;having,&#x201d; and the like are synonymous and are used inclusively, in an open-ended fashion, and do not exclude additional elements, features, acts, operations, and so forth. Likewise, the terms &#x201c;some,&#x201d; &#x201c;certain,&#x201d; and the like are synonymous and are used in an open-ended fashion. Also, the term &#x201c;or&#x201d; is used in its inclusive sense (and not in its exclusive sense) so that when used, for example, to connect a list of elements, the term &#x201c;or&#x201d; means one, some, or all of the elements in the list. One skilled in the art will appreciate that the terms affix or secure are used herein to describe coupling various elements of the apparatus to one another. In various configurations those elements may be connected directly, coupled via intervening structure, or the various elements can be formed from a contiguous piece of material.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">The terms &#x201c;approximately,&#x201d; &#x201c;about,&#x201d; and &#x201c;substantially&#x201d; as used herein represent an amount close to the stated amount that still performs a desired function or achieves a desired result. For example, in some embodiments, as the context may dictate, the terms &#x201c;approximately&#x201d;, &#x201c;about&#x201d;, and &#x201c;substantially&#x201d; may refer to an amount that is within, less than, or equal to 10% of the stated amount. The term &#x201c;generally&#x201d; as used herein represents a value, amount, or characteristic that predominantly includes, or tends toward, a particular value, amount, or characteristic. As an example, in certain embodiments, as the context may dictate, the term &#x201c;generally parallel&#x201d; can refer to something that departs from exactly parallel by less than or equal to 20 degrees and/or the term &#x201c;generally perpendicular&#x201d; can refer to something that departs from exactly perpendicular by less than or equal to 20 degrees. Anatomical terms of location as used herein may be understood to reference the device refer to the orientation of the device when mounted on a user. Elastic and elasticity may be understood to refer to a material's ability to resist a deforming influence and return to its original shape and size upon removal of the deforming influence. Unless indicated otherwise, measurements are typically provided in inches. For instance, 7.5&#x2033; as used herein may be understood to refer to seven and a half inches. As used herein, exemplary may be understood to refer to serving as an example of a particular embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">Overall, the language of the claims is to be interpreted broadly based on the language employed in the claims. The claims are not to be limited to the non-exclusive embodiments and examples that are illustrated and described in this disclosure, or that are discussed during the prosecution of the application.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The following is claimed:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A damage-free cabinet accessory system comprising:
<claim-text>an accessory attachment mechanism configured to be coupled to an interior surface of a cabinet door;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a removable cabinet accessory configured for application to an exterior surface of a cabinet door;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the removable cabinet accessory includes a first coupling system configured to interface with the accessory attachment mechanism to removably affix the cabinet accessory to the cabinet door.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The damage-free removable cabinet accessory system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, the system further comprising: a protective coating layer configured to prevent damage to the exterior surface of the cabinet.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The damage-free removable cabinet accessory system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the protective coating layer has a thickness ranging between about 1 mm to about 10 mm.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The damage-free removable cabinet accessory system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the protective coating layer is prepared from a polymer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The damage-free removable cabinet accessory system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the protective coating layer is prepared from a fabric.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The damage-free removable cabinet accessory system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the protective coating layer is felt or velvet.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The damage-free removable cabinet accessory system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the protective coating layer covers substantially the entire cabinet-facing surface of the accessory.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The damage-free removable cabinet accessory system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the protective coating layer comprises at least two separated sections of protective coating.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The damage-free removable cabinet accessory system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the removable cabinet accessory configured for application to an external surface of a cabinet door has a weight ranging from about 5 oz to about 10.5 oz.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The damage-free removable cabinet accessory system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the removable cabinet accessory configured for application to an external surface of a cabinet door is prepared from wood.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The damage-free removable cabinet accessory system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the removable cabinet accessory configured for application to an external surface of a cabinet door is prepared from balsa wood and is configured to receive acrylic paint.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The damage-free removable cabinet accessory system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the removable cabinet accessory configured for application to an external surface of a cabinet door is prepared from a polymer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. The damage-free removable cabinet accessory system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the removable cabinet accessory configured for application to an external surface of a cabinet door is prepared from a polyethylene, polyurethane, or polystyrene.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The damage-free removable cabinet accessory system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the removable cabinet accessory configured for application to an external surface of a cabinet door includes at least one of: a stain resistant coating; and a heat resistant coating.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. The damage-free removable cabinet accessory system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the removable cabinet accessory configured for application to an external surface of a cabinet door includes a decorative or useful surface ornamentation.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. The damage-free cabinet accessory system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the accessory attachment mechanism configured to be coupled to the interior surface of the cabinet door includes a magnetic mounting mechanism configured to be affixed to the interior surface of the cabinet door and further configured to interface with the first coupling system implemented on the removable cabinet accessory.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. The damage-free cabinet accessory system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the magnetic mounting mechanism configured to be affixed to the interior surface of the cabinet door includes a first magnet positioned near one edge of the removable cabinet accessory, and a second magnet positioned near the opposing edge of the removable cabinet accessory.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. A kit for reconfiguring the outward appearance of a cabinet, the kit comprising:
<claim-text>a removable cabinet accessory, having an outward and inward face, the accessory configured for application to an external surface of a cabinet door, having at least one magnetic attachment mechanism affixed to the inward face of the accessory;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the removable cabinet accessory includes at least one useful embellishment implemented along the outward face of the accessory; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a magnetic accessory attachment mechanism configured to be coupled to the interior surface of a cabinet door and configured to interface with the at least one magnetic attachment mechanism affixed to the inward face of the accessory.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. The kit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one useful embellishment is selected from the group consisting of: a chalkboard; white board; dart board; calendar; potty chart; toothbrush chart; and a peg or hook board.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. A consumer product set for reconfiguring the outward appearance of one or more kitchen cabinets, the product set comprising:
<claim-text>a removable cabinet accessory, having an outward and inward face, the accessory configured for application to an external surface of a cabinet door;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the removable cabinet accessory includes a protective surface covering affixed to the inward face of the accessory;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the removable cabinet accessory includes four magnetic attachment mechanisms affixed to the inward face of the accessory;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the removable cabinet accessory includes at least one useful embellishment implemented along the outward face of the accessory; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a magnetic accessory attachment mechanism configured to be coupled to the interior surface of a cabinet door and configured to interface with the at least one magnetic attachment mechanism affixed to the inward face of the accessory.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
