<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225569A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225569</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17575935</doc-number>
<date>20220114</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>17</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>04</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>08</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>043</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>B</section>
<class>08</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>001</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">PERSONAL CLEANSING DEVICE</invention-title>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Peeq Industries, Inc.</orgname>
<address>
<city>Omaha</city>
<state>NE</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chapman</last-name>
<first-name>Thomas A.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Omaha</city>
<state>NE</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="01" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chapman</last-name>
<first-name>Cheryl</first-name>
<address>
<city>Omaha</city>
<state>NE</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="02" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wolfe</last-name>
<first-name>Chris</first-name>
<address>
<city>Omaha</city>
<state>NE</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="03" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wolfe</last-name>
<first-name>Jamie</first-name>
<address>
<city>Omaha</city>
<state>NE</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="04" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Bragg</last-name>
<first-name>Scott</first-name>
<address>
<city>Omaha</city>
<state>NE</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="05" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Aziz-Seible</last-name>
<first-name>Razia</first-name>
<address>
<city>Omaha</city>
<state>NE</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="06" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Morris</last-name>
<first-name>Richard</first-name>
<address>
<city>Omaha</city>
<state>NE</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="07" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Tipp</last-name>
<first-name>Alan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Elkhorn</city>
<state>NE</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="08" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Tipp</last-name>
<first-name>David</first-name>
<address>
<city>Chandler</city>
<state>AZ</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="09" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Gridley</last-name>
<first-name>Curtis D.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Wichita</city>
<state>KS</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="10" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hoover</last-name>
<first-name>Tracy A.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Wichita</city>
<state>KS</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A personal cleansing device may include, but is not limited to: a body portion; an electric motor disposed within the body portion; control circuitry configured for control of operation of the electric motor; and a recess defined in the body portion and configured to receive at least one sponge insert.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="196.09mm" wi="158.75mm" file="US20230225569A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="231.06mm" wi="187.37mm" file="US20230225569A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="135.55mm" wi="138.77mm" file="US20230225569A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="236.64mm" wi="194.31mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225569A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="219.29mm" wi="153.59mm" file="US20230225569A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="176.02mm" wi="154.94mm" file="US20230225569A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The invention relates generally to the field of personal cleansing, namely, a device for skin cleansing. Specifically, the present invention may be employed for the cleansing of facial surfaces around the eyes to remove makeup or other applied skin care products, naturally produced oils, and the like, so as to prevent buildup in meibomian glands which may result in various undesired conditions including blepharitis.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The numerous advantages of the disclosure may be better understood by those skilled in the art by reference to the accompanying figures in which:</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> shows an exploded view of components of a personal cleaning device;</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> shows electrical components of a personal cleaning device;</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> shows a personal cleaning device including a sponge insert;</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> shows a personal cleaning device including a sponge insert;</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> shows a personal cleaning device including a sponge insert;</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> shows a personal cleaning device including a sponge insert; and</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> shows a personal cleaning device including a sponge insert.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Reference will now be made in detail to various embodiments of the invention, examples of which are illustrated in the accompanying drawings. While the invention will be described in conjunction with the following embodiments, it will be understood that the descriptions are not intended to limit the invention to these embodiments. On the contrary, the invention is intended to cover alternatives, modifications and equivalents that may be included within the spirit and scope of the invention. Furthermore, in the following detailed description, numerous specific details are set forth in order to provide a thorough understanding of the present invention. However, it will be readily apparent to one skilled in the art that the present invention may be practiced without these specific details. In other instances, well-known methods, procedures, components, and materials have not been described in detail so as not to unnecessarily obscure aspects of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The technical proposal(s) of embodiments of the present invention will be fully and clearly described in conjunction with the drawings in the following embodiments. It will be understood that the descriptions are not intended to limit the invention to these embodiments. Based on the described embodiments of the present invention, other embodiments can be obtained by one skilled in the art without creative contribution and are in the scope of legal protection given to the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Furthermore, all characteristics, measures or processes disclosed in this document, except characteristics and/or processes that are mutually exclusive, can be combined in any manner and in any combination possible. Any characteristic disclosed in the present specification, claims, Abstract and Figures can be replaced by other equivalent characteristics or characteristics with similar objectives, purposes and/or functions, unless specified otherwise.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The advantages of the present invention will become readily apparent from the detailed description of various embodiments below.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, a personal cleaning device <b>100</b> is shown. The device <b>100</b> may include an internal housing <b>101</b> having a top portion <b>102</b> and a bottom portion <b>103</b>. The top portion <b>102</b> and/or the bottom portion <b>103</b> may be constructed of a rigid or semi-rigid plastic material (e.g., injection-molded or 3D printed thermoplastics such as Acrylonitrile Butadiene Styrene (ABS), Polyethylene terephthalate (PET), Polypropylene (PP), and the like). The top portion <b>102</b> and/or the bottom portion <b>103</b> may define a recess <b>104</b> and may be coupled to form the housing <b>101</b>. In one embodiment, the top portion <b>102</b> may define a flanged portion <b>105</b> which may be configured to be received within and frictionally engage a perimeter wall <b>106</b> of the bottom portion <b>103</b> so as to couple the top portion <b>102</b> and the bottom portion <b>103</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The device <b>100</b> may further include an electric motor <b>107</b> operably coupled to a control circuitry board <b>108</b> and at least one battery (not shown). The electric motor <b>107</b> may include a vibrational component (not shown), the movement of which is configured to induce vibration in the device <b>100</b> as a whole. For example, the vibrational component may include a mass coupled to a rotating drive shaft defining an axis <b>109</b> of the electric motor <b>107</b>. The mass may be asymmetrically distributed around the axis <b>109</b> such that rotation of the vibrational component about the axis <b>109</b> may cause vibration of the device <b>100</b>. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, the axis <b>109</b> may be oriented such that it points generally in a direction of a front corner <b>110</b> of the device <b>100</b> configured to receive a sponge insert <b>111</b>, as will be described further below. In other embodiments, the vibrational component may be any other electrically powered rotational or oscillating structure configured to induce vibration in the device <b>100</b>. The vibrational component may cause vibration of the device <b>100</b> at sonic frequencies (e.g., above 200 Hz) up to ultrasonic frequencies (e.g., at or above 1.6 MHz). Rotational vibration induced via the vibrational component around the axis <b>109</b> may serve to optimize cleansing using the front corner <b>110</b> as high-frequency, circular motion of the front corner <b>110</b> may be focused on a particular surface (e.g. a facial surface) to be cleaned.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The device <b>100</b> may include an external body <b>112</b>. The external body <b>112</b> may be constructed of a semi-rigid or elastomeric material (e.g., silicone). The external body <b>112</b> may include an aperture <b>113</b> configured to receive and frictionally retain the bottom portion <b>103</b> of the housing <b>101</b>. Further, the top portion <b>102</b> of the housing <b>101</b> may include a projecting portion <b>114</b> which may be received into and be frictionally retained within a recess defined by a cover <b>115</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the control circuitry board <b>108</b> may include one or more user interface components (e.g., one or more switches or buttons) configured to allow user control of the activation and/or speed of vibration of the device <b>100</b> induced by the electric motor <b>107</b>. For example, the control circuitry board <b>108</b> may be coupled to a power switch <b>116</b>. Referring again to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, the top portion <b>102</b> of the housing <b>101</b> may include a corresponding actuatable button <b>117</b> formed in a top surface of the top portion <b>102</b> of the housing <b>101</b>. Additionally, a pressure pad <b>118</b> may be formed in a top surface of the cover <b>115</b>. Upon an application of pressure to the pressure pad <b>118</b> by a user, a corresponding pressure may be applied to the button <b>117</b> which may then contact the power switch <b>116</b> thereby activating the electric motor <b>107</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Similarly, referring again to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the control circuitry board <b>108</b> may include a speed control switch <b>119</b>. The top portion <b>102</b> of the housing <b>101</b> may include a corresponding actuatable button (not shown) formed in a top surface of the top portion <b>102</b> of the housing <b>101</b>. Additionally, a pressure pad <b>120</b> may be formed in the top surface of the cover <b>115</b>. Upon an application of pressure to the pressure pad <b>120</b> by a user, a corresponding pressure may be applied to the button which may then contact the speed control switch <b>119</b> thereby changing a vibrational speed of the electric motor <b>107</b>. Subsequent activations of the speed control switch <b>119</b> may progressively change the vibrational speed of the electric motor <b>107</b>, for example, from a high speed to a medium speed to a low speed then returning to the high speed. Any number of different speeds and speed change increments may be employed without departing from the scope of the present disclosures.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">As noted above, the device <b>100</b> may be configured to receive a sponge insert <b>111</b>. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> and <b>3</b>-<b>6</b></figref>, the external body <b>112</b> may define a recess <b>121</b> configured to receive a portion of the sponge insert <b>111</b>. For example, the recess <b>121</b> may be configured as a channel in the external body <b>112</b> which passes from a first rear corner of the external body <b>112</b>, around the front corner <b>110</b> of the external body <b>112</b>, to a right rear corner of the external body <b>112</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, the sponge insert <b>111</b> may have a U-shape or V-shape corresponding to a perimeter of the device <b>100</b> into which the recess <b>121</b> is formed. However, other shapes for the perimeter of the device <b>100</b>, recess <b>121</b> and sponge insert <b>111</b> (e.g., rectilinear, rounded, enclosed circular, etc.) may be employed without departing from the scope of the present disclosures.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>3</b>-<b>4</b></figref>, one or more flexible fibrous projections <b>122</b> may extend from the top and/or bottom interior surface of the recess <b>121</b>. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>-<b>7</b></figref>, progressive insertion of the sponge insert <b>111</b> into the recess <b>121</b> of the external body <b>112</b> is shown. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>, as the sponge insert <b>111</b> is inserted into the recess <b>121</b>, the fibrous projections <b>122</b> may flex to apply additional pressure the surface of the sponge insert <b>111</b> and/or interact with the pores of the sponge insert <b>111</b> so as to secure the sponge insert <b>111</b> within the recess <b>121</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>5</b> and <b>7</b></figref>, upon full insertion of the sponge insert <b>111</b> into the recess <b>121</b>, a cleansing solution (e.g., a tea tree based natural cleanser), may be applied to the sponge insert <b>111</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>, the sponge insert <b>111</b> may be constructed of any biocompatible material that will expand upon an application of a liquid. For example, the sponge insert <b>111</b> may include products such as those marketed by Absorene Manufacturing Company, Inc. of St. Louis, Mo. Such expansion of the sponge insert <b>111</b> may serve to further secure the sponge insert <b>111</b> within the recess <b>121</b> and provide additional working surface area of the sponge insert <b>111</b> to be used when a user performs personal cleansing. Further, as noted above, the sponge insert <b>111</b> may have a form factor (e.g., a rounded V-shape) which provides at least one corner <b>123</b> corresponding to the front corner <b>110</b> of the external body <b>112</b>. Such a form factor provides a perimeter shape of the sponge insert <b>111</b> which allows a user to bring the device <b>100</b> into contact with the varying surfaces of a user's face. Specifically, the sponge insert <b>111</b> may be dimensioned to have a rounded corner having a sufficiently small profile (e.g., as a function of the pointedness of the edges of the sponge insert <b>111</b>) to effectively contact a user's meibomian glands, nasal sidewall, nasal sura-alar crease, medial and lateral canthus, and eyelids.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The foregoing descriptions of specific embodiments of the present invention have been presented for purposes of illustration and description. They are not intended to be exhaustive or to limit the invention to the precise forms disclosed, and obviously many modifications and variations are possible in light of the above teaching. The embodiments were chosen and described in order to best explain the principles of the invention and its practical application, to thereby enable others skilled in the art to best utilize the invention and various embodiments with various modifications as are suited to the particular use contemplated. It is intended that the scope of the invention be defined by the Claims appended hereto and their equivalents.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A personal cleansing device comprising:
<claim-text>a body portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an electric motor disposed within the body portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>control circuitry configured for control of operation of the electric motor; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a recess defined in the body portion and configured to receive at least one sponge insert.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The personal cleansing device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the body portion includes:
<claim-text>an internal housing portion configured to contain the electric motor; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an external body portion disposed at least partially around the internal housing portion.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The personal cleansing device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the electric motor includes:
<claim-text>a vibrating component configured to induce vibration of the personal cleansing device.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The personal cleansing device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the vibrating component includes:
<claim-text>a mass asymmetrically distributed around a drive shaft of the electric motor.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The personal cleansing device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the control circuitry includes:
<claim-text>a user-activatable electric motor power control interface.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The personal cleansing device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the control circuitry includes:
<claim-text>a user-activatable electric motor speed control interface.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The personal cleansing device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>one or more fibers projecting from one or more surfaces internal to the recess defined in the body portion.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The personal cleansing device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>the sponge insert.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
