<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225489A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230707" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225489</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17894390</doc-number>
<date>20220824</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>17</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>45</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>45</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>021</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>45</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>2200</main-group>
<subgroup>0516</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="tgeiv925vcxp2">Secure Convenient Smartphone Holster</invention-title>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>63299982</doc-number>
<date>20220116</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Gostev</last-name>
<first-name>Anatoli</first-name>
<address>
<city>San Jose</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Gostev</last-name>
<first-name>Anatoli</first-name>
<address>
<city>San Jose</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">This patent describes a holster case for smartphones and similar gadgets. This holster is intended to be attached to a pants pocket although it can also be attached to any part of clothing. The holster provides an easy, single motion, one hand operation to store and retrieve the phone. It provides protection from accidental knock-off, fall-out or grab-and-run theft.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="71.63mm" wi="167.39mm" file="US20230225489A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="184.32mm" wi="160.44mm" file="US20230225489A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="223.10mm" wi="143.76mm" file="US20230225489A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="202.52mm" wi="161.04mm" file="US20230225489A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading level="1" id="h-0001">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">Not Applicable</p>
<heading level="1" id="h-0002">STATEMENT REGARDING FEDERALLY SPONSORED RESEARCH OR DEVELOPMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Not Applicable</p>
<heading level="1" id="h-0003">REFERENCE TO SEQUENCE LISTING, A TABLE, OR A COMPUTER PROGRAM LISTING COMPACT DISC APPENDIX</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Not Applicable</p>
<heading level="1" id="h-0004">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Carrying a smartphone has certain inconveniences. It can be carried in a pocket, a bag or in a case on a belt. Carrying it in a pocket is inconvenient especially when sitting down or driving a car. Carrying it in a bag requires carrying the bag itself and is inconvenient opening the bag and finding the phone in it for quick immediate need, e.g., to answer a phone call. Carrying it on a belt is also inconvenient due to interference with clothing (e.g., a jacket or a sweater) and discomfort of sitting down, driving and using a safety belt. This invention is addressing these problems by means of a holster style smartphone case which can be securely attached to a pants pocket. Its design provides a convenient single motion move to store and retrieve the phone.</p>
<heading level="1" id="h-0005">BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">This invention is a holster style smartphone case attachable to a clothing pocket.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The holster is attached to a pocket by means of a secure clip. The security of the clip is achieved by a secure latch. If the case is pulled out of pocket without releasing the latch, the latch grabs the pocket fabric and prevents detaching the clip from the pocket. The latch is located inside the pocket and can be easily accessed by the owner but cannot be easily accessed by others or accidentally hit.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The smartphone case consists of two halves - upper and lower ones. The upper half has the pocket clip described above. The lower part is attached to the upper one in such a way that the case can be stretched by pulling the lower part down. This is done by means of tubes/rails and springs, rubber bands or bungee cords. The phone is inserted into the case by stretching the case, inserting the phone between the brackets on the lower and upper halves and releasing it. The phone is securely kept in place by brackets on the lower and upper halves. This mechanism allows fast an easy phone storage and retrieval.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">There may be a hidden catch under the case which prevents phone retrieval without deactivating it. It can be easily accessed by the owner, e.g., by a pinky finger while retrieving the phone in a single motion. It cannot be accidentally hit or easily accessed by others. This prevents grab-and-run theft or accidental knock-offs.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading level="1" id="h-0006">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE SEVERAL VIEWS OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> shows the sideview of the case with the pocket clip security latch locked.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> shows the sideview of the case with the pocket clip latch released allowing for the holster removal.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> shows the case with upper and lower halves connected by tubes with bungee cord inside.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> shows the case extended for phone insertion/removal.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> shows a better view of the pocket clip and the latch locked.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> shows a better view of the pocket clip and the latch released.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading level="1" id="h-0007">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">This invention describes a secure holster style smartphone carrying case, which can be attached to a pants pocket. Sideview of the holster is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>. The holster consists of the upper half <b>1</b> and the lower half <b>2</b> connected by sliding tubes. The upper half has two outer tubes <b>5</b>. The lower half has two inner tubes <b>6</b>. The inner tubes of the lower half slide inside the outer tubes of the upper half. The lower and upper halves are held together by an elastic bungee cord <b>7</b>, which allows the case to be extended along the sliding tubes as the cord stretches. The upper and lower halves have L-shaped brackets <b>3</b> and <b>4</b>, which hold the smartphone in place. The phone is inserted by pushing it into the lower half, extending the case, sliding the phone between the brackets and releasing it.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>3</b> and <b>4</b></figref> show a better view of the case consisting of upper half <b>1</b> and lower half <b>2</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> shows the case extended for phone insertion/removal.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">There may be a safety catch <b>17</b> accessed under the phone, e.g., by a pinky finger. This safety catch will prevent the phone removal without being disactivated. This catch can be conveniently accessed by the owner but cannot be easily accessed by others or accidentally knocked off. The safety catch is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>3</b> and <b>4</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The upper half has a spring-loaded pocket clip <b>8</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> and <b>2</b></figref>. The clip is attached to the case by the shaft <b>9</b> and loaded by the spring <b>10</b>. The clip has the slot <b>11</b> in which the front fabric of the pocket is inserted. The clip has a spring-loaded security latch <b>12</b>, which when locked prevents the holster from being accidentally or maliciously removed from the pocket. The latch is attached to the clip by the shaft <b>13</b> and loaded by the spring <b>14</b>. The latch grabs and holds the pocket fabric in the slot by teeth <b>15</b>. The latch can be released by pulling on its handle <b>16</b>. This latch is shown locked in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> shows the latch being released and the holster can be removed from the pocket. The latch can be conveniently accessed by a thumb.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">A better view of the pocket clip <b>8</b> and the security latch <b>12</b> is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>5</b> and <b>6</b></figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> shows the handle of the latch pulled and the latch released.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A smartphone case which can be securely attached to a clothing pocket, a piece of fabric, a strap, a loop or a belt.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. A smartphone case designed for secure smartphone keeping and yet for smartphone removal and insertion with a simple motion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. A security latch which grabs the fabric and prevents the holster from being removed without deactivating the latch.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. A safety catch which prevents the phone from being removed from the case without deactivating this catch.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. An extendable smartphone case having two parts linked together by sliding tubes/rails or guides and held together by springs, elastic bands or bungee cords.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
