<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225447A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225447</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18009977</doc-number>
<date>20220323</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>202110439605.0</doc-number>
<date>20210423</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>42</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>42</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>B</section>
<class>65</class>
<subclass>H</subclass>
<main-group>2701</main-group>
<subgroup>174</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>B</section>
<class>65</class>
<subclass>H</subclass>
<main-group>2404</main-group>
<subgroup>66</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>B</section>
<class>65</class>
<subclass>H</subclass>
<main-group>2404</main-group>
<subgroup>721</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>B</section>
<class>65</class>
<subclass>H</subclass>
<main-group>2404</main-group>
<subgroup>5391</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>B</section>
<class>65</class>
<subclass>H</subclass>
<main-group>2404</main-group>
<subgroup>512</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>B</section>
<class>65</class>
<subclass>H</subclass>
<main-group>2557</main-group>
<subgroup>33</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e61">MATERIAL PICKUP MECHANISM FOR AUTOMATIC HAT-MAKING PRODUCTION LINE EQUIPMENT</invention-title>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>QINGDAO QIANFENG CAPART INT'L CORP</orgname>
<address>
<city>Qingdao</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>WANG</last-name>
<first-name>Aimei</first-name>
<address>
<city>Qingdao</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>QINGDAO QIANFENG CAPART INT'L CORP</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Qingdao</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/CN2022/082563</doc-number>
<date>20220323</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c12-date><date>20221212</date></us-371c12-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A material pickup mechanism for automatic hat-making production line equipment includes an installation seat, a servo motor, and a rotating seat. A control box is arranged on one side of the installation seat through bolts. The servo motor is arranged at a bottom end of the installation seat through a positioning plate and positioning screw nails. The rotating seat is arranged at an output shaft of the servo motor through bolts. Top and bottom ends of the rotating seat are both connected with an installation plate through a fixed shaft. Adjusting holes are formed at a top of the installation plate. A hollow screw penetrates the adjusting hole. A bottom of the hollow screw is connected with an air outlet end of a sucking disc. The material pickup mechanism can continuously pick up materials to improve production efficiency. It is convenient to adjust positions between sucking discs.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="135.89mm" wi="116.92mm" file="US20230225447A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="191.52mm" wi="118.96mm" file="US20230225447A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="72.31mm" wi="58.34mm" file="US20230225447A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO THE RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is the national phase entry of International Application No. PCT/CN2022/082563, filed on Mar. 23, 2022, which is based upon and claims priority to Chinese Patent Application No. 202110439605.0, filed on Apr. 23, 2021, the entire contents of which are incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="tail"?>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates to the technical field of material pickup mechanisms, and in particular, to a material pickup mechanism for automatic hat-making production line equipment.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Hats are a kind of clothing worn on the head, most of which can cover the entire top of the head and are mainly used to protect the head. Some hats have protruding edges to prevent from the sunshine. Hats can also be used to dress up, as well as protect hairstyles and cover baldness. Hats can be of different types, such as berets, and flat caps. Wearing a hat has different cultures in different regions, which is especially important in Western cultures, because wearing a hat was a symbol of social status in the past. In the prior art, materials need to be picked up by a material pickup mechanism on automatic production line equipment during hat production, and there is a lack of automatic and fast special equipment capable of picking up the materials. In addition, the prior material pickup mechanism has low work efficiency and is inconvenient to operate.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The prior material pickup mechanism on automatic hat-making production line equipment has the following shortcomings: 1, the material pickup mechanism on automatic hat-making production line equipment cannot continuously pick up the materials to improve production efficiency; 2, it is inconvenient to adjust positions between sucking discs, and adsorb and fix different sizes of cloth; and 3, it is inconvenient for remote control. Therefore, a material pickup mechanism for automatic hat-making production line equipment is provided.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">An objective of the present disclosure is to provide a material pickup mechanism for automatic hat-making production line equipment to solve problems in the background art.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">To achieve the above objective, the technical solution adopted by the present disclosure is:</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">A material pickup mechanism for automatic hat-making production line equipment includes a power protector, an installation seat, a servo motor, and a rotating seat. A control box is arranged on one side of the installation seat through bolts. The servo motor is arranged at a bottom end of the installation seat through a positioning plate and positioning screw nails. The rotating seat is arranged at an output shaft of the servo motor through bolts. Top and bottom ends of the rotating seat are both connected with an installation plate through a fixed shaft. Adjusting holes are formed at a top of the installation plate. A hollow screw penetrates the adjusting hole. A bottom of the hollow screw is connected with an air outlet end of a sucking disc.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Further, an uninterruptible power supply (UPS) may be arranged on one side of an inner wall of the control box through screw nails. The power protector may be arranged at a lower end of the UPS through bolts. A programmable logic controller (PLC) may be arranged at a lower end of the power protector through a clamping groove. Output and input terminals of the PLC may be respectively connected with an input terminal of the servo motor and an output terminal of the UPS through wires. The PLC controller is used to automatically control a rotation angle and speed of the servo motor, thereby driving the rotating seat to rotate. After the first piece of cloth is sucked, the rotating seat drives the installation plate to rotate through the servo motor, and after rotating in place, the second piece of cloth is sucked to complete suction of the two pieces of cloth.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Further, the hollow screw may be fixed in the adjusting hole through a clamping nut, and a connecting sleeve may be arranged at a top of the hollow screw.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Further, a bottom of the sucking disc may be adhered with an arc adsorption plate through a polyurethane adhesive, and an air intake hole may be formed at a center of the arc adsorption plate. Using the arc adsorption plate, the adhesion is high, and the material pickup effect is improved.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Further, the sucking disc at a bottom of the installation plate may be specifically arranged in four groups.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Further, an output terminal of the power protector may be connected with an input terminal of a UPS through a wire. The power protector integrates three-phase voltage display, overvoltage protection, undervoltage protection, phase loss protection, and phase sequence protection, which has the characteristics of complete functions, stable performance, and simple operation, and has a good protective effect on the UPS.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Further, a wireless switch may be arranged on the other side of an inner wall of the control box through screw nails, and the wireless switch may be connected with the servo motor through a wire.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Further, a waterproof layer may be arranged on an inner surface layer of the control box, and the waterproof layer may be a polytetrafluoroethylene (PTFE) coating, such that the waterproof effect in the control box is effective at preventing moisture from entering the control box and damaging internal electronic elements.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Compared with the prior art, the present disclosure has the following beneficial effects:</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">1. The material pickup mechanism for automatic hat-making production line equipment of the present disclosure uses the connecting sleeve to connect a suction hose of an external vacuum pump body. When the vacuum pump body is working, a negative pressure state is generated in the sucking disc, and through the four groups of sucking discs at the bottom of the installation plate, the hat-making cloth is quickly adsorbed and fixed. The PLC controller is used to automatically control the rotation angle and speed of the servo motor, thereby driving the rotating seat to rotate. After the first piece of cloth is sucked, the rotating seat drives the installation plate to rotate through the servo motor, and after rotating in place, the second piece of cloth is sucked to complete suction of the two pieces of cloth, such that the material pickup is completed automatically, which improves the production efficiency of the automatic hat-making production line.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">2. According to the material pickup mechanism for automatic hat-making production line equipment of the present disclosure, the clamping nut on the hollow screw is unscrewed to adjust a position of the hollow screw in the adjusting hole to adjust relative positions of the four groups of sucking discs, control an adsorption range, and realize adsorption and fixation of different sizes of hat-making cloth. The wireless switch is used to connect external smartphone to remotely control opening and closing of the servo motor, which is highly intelligent and easy to operate.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">3. According to the material pickup mechanism for automatic hat-making production line equipment of the present disclosure, the power protector integrates three-phase voltage display, overvoltage protection, undervoltage protection, phase loss protection, and phase sequence protection, which has the characteristics of complete functions, stable performance, and simple operation, and has a good protective effect on the UPS.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a schematic diagram of an overall structure of a material pickup mechanism for automatic hat-making production line equipment of the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a cross-sectional view of a sucking disc of the material pickup mechanism for automatic hat-making production line equipment of the present disclosure; and</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a cross-sectional view of a control box of the material pickup mechanism for automatic hat-making production line equipment of the present disclosure.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Reference numerals: <b>1</b>, an installation seat; <b>2</b>, a servo motor; <b>3</b>, a rotating seat; <b>4</b>, a fixed shaft; <b>5</b>, an installation plate; <b>6</b>, a sucking disc; <b>7</b>, a control box; <b>8</b>, an adjusting hole; <b>9</b>, a hollow screw; <b>10</b>, a clamping nut; <b>11</b>, a connecting sleeve; <b>12</b>, an air intake hole; <b>13</b>, an arc adsorption plate; <b>14</b>, a wireless switch; <b>15</b>, a UPS; <b>16</b>, a power protector; and <b>17</b>, a PLC.</p>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In order to make the technical means, creative features, objectives to be achieved, and efficacy achieved by the present disclosure easy to understand, the disclosure will be further described below in combination with specific embodiments.</p>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">Embodiment I</heading>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, a material pickup mechanism for automatic hat-making production line equipment includes a power protector <b>16</b>, an installation seat <b>1</b>, a servo motor <b>2</b>, and a rotating seat <b>3</b>. A control box <b>7</b> is arranged on one side of the installation seat <b>1</b> through bolts. The servo motor <b>2</b> is arranged at a bottom end of the installation seat <b>1</b> through a positioning plate and positioning screw nails. The rotating seat <b>3</b> is arranged at an output shaft of the servo motor <b>2</b> through bolts. Top and bottom ends of the rotating seat <b>3</b> are both connected with an installation plate <b>5</b> through a fixed shaft <b>4</b>. Adjusting holes <b>8</b> are formed at a top of the installation plate <b>5</b>. A hollow screw <b>9</b> penetrates the adjusting hole <b>8</b>. A bottom of the hollow screw <b>9</b> is connected with an air outlet end of a sucking disc <b>6</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">A UPS <b>15</b> is arranged on one side of an inner wall of the control box <b>7</b> through screw nails. The power protector <b>16</b> is arranged at a lower end of the UPS <b>15</b> through bolts. A PLC <b>17</b> is arranged at a lower end of the power protector <b>16</b> through a clamping groove. Output and input terminals of the PLC <b>17</b> are respectively connected with an input terminal of the servo motor <b>2</b> and an output terminal of the UPS <b>15</b> through wires.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">In the present embodiment, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, the PLC controller <b>17</b> is used to automatically control a rotation angle and speed of the servo motor <b>2</b>, thereby driving the rotating seat <b>3</b> to rotate. After the first piece of cloth is sucked, the rotating seat <b>3</b> drives the installation plate <b>5</b> to rotate through the servo motor <b>2</b>, and after rotating in place, the second piece of cloth is sucked to complete suction of the two pieces of cloth.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The hollow screw <b>9</b> is fixed in the adjusting hole <b>8</b> through a clamping nut <b>10</b>, and a connecting sleeve <b>11</b> is arranged at a top of the hollow screw <b>9</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">In the present embodiment, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, the clamping nut <b>10</b> on the hollow screw <b>9</b> is unscrewed to adjust a position of the hollow screw <b>9</b> in the adjusting hole <b>8</b> to adjust relative positions of the four groups of sucking discs <b>6</b>, control an adsorption range, and realize adsorption and fixation of different sizes of hat-making cloth.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">A bottom of the sucking disc <b>6</b> is adhered with an arc adsorption plate <b>13</b> through a polyurethane adhesive, and an air intake hole <b>12</b> is formed at a center of the arc adsorption plate <b>13</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">In the present embodiment, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, using the arc adsorption plate <b>13</b>, the adhesion is high, and the material pickup effect is improved.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The sucking disc <b>6</b> at a bottom of the installation plate <b>5</b> is specifically arranged in four groups.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">An output terminal of the power protector <b>16</b> is connected with an input terminal of a UPS <b>15</b> through a wire.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">In the present embodiment, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, the power protector <b>16</b> integrates three-phase voltage display, overvoltage protection, undervoltage protection, phase loss protection, and phase sequence protection, which has the characteristics of complete functions, stable performance, and simple operation, and has a good protective effect on the UPS <b>15</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">A wireless switch <b>14</b> is arranged on the other side of an inner wall of the control box <b>7</b> through screw nails, and the wireless switch <b>14</b> is connected with the servo motor <b>2</b> through a wire.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">In the present embodiment, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, the wireless switch <b>14</b> is used to connect external smartphone to remotely control opening and closing of the servo motor <b>2</b>, which is highly intelligent and easy to operate.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">A waterproof layer is arranged on an inner surface layer of the control box <b>7</b>, and the waterproof layer is a PTFE coating.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">In the present embodiment, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, the waterproof layer is the PTFE coating, such that the waterproof effect in the control box <b>7</b> is effective at preventing moisture from entering the control box <b>7</b> and damaging internal electronic elements.</p>
<heading id="h-0008" level="1">Embodiment II</heading>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, a material pickup mechanism for automatic hat-making production line equipment includes a power protector <b>16</b>, an installation seat <b>1</b>, a servo motor <b>2</b>, and a rotating seat <b>3</b>. A control box <b>7</b> is arranged on one side of the installation seat <b>1</b> through bolts. The servo motor <b>2</b> is arranged at a bottom end of the installation seat <b>1</b> through a positioning plate and positioning screw nails. The rotating seat <b>3</b> is arranged at an output shaft of the servo motor <b>2</b> through bolts. Top and bottom ends of the rotating seat <b>3</b> are both connected with an installation plate <b>5</b> through a fixed shaft <b>4</b>. Adjusting holes <b>8</b> are formed at a top of the installation plate <b>5</b>. A hollow screw <b>9</b> penetrates the adjusting hole <b>8</b>. A bottom of the hollow screw <b>9</b> is connected with an air outlet end of a sucking disc <b>6</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">A UPS <b>15</b> is arranged on one side of an inner wall of the control box <b>7</b> through screw nails. The power protector <b>16</b> is arranged at a lower end of the UPS <b>15</b> through bolts. A PLC <b>17</b> is arranged at a lower end of the power protector <b>16</b> through a clamping groove. Output and input terminals of the PLC <b>17</b> are respectively connected with an input terminal of the servo motor <b>2</b> and an output terminal of the UPS <b>15</b> through wires.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">In the present embodiment, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, the PLC controller <b>17</b> is used to automatically control a rotation angle and speed of the servo motor <b>2</b>, thereby driving the rotating seat <b>3</b> to rotate. After the first piece of cloth is sucked, the rotating seat <b>3</b> drives the installation plate <b>5</b> to rotate through the servo motor <b>2</b>, and after rotating in place, the second piece of cloth is sucked to complete suction of the two pieces of cloth.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The hollow screw <b>9</b> is fixed in the adjusting hole <b>8</b> through a clamping nut <b>10</b>, and a connecting sleeve <b>11</b> is arranged at a top of the hollow screw <b>9</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">In the present embodiment, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, the clamping nut <b>10</b> on the hollow screw <b>9</b> is unscrewed to adjust a position of the hollow screw <b>9</b> in the adjusting hole <b>8</b> to adjust relative positions of the four groups of sucking discs <b>6</b>, control an adsorption range, and realize adsorption and fixation of different sizes of hat-making cloth.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">A bottom of the sucking disc <b>6</b> is adhered with an arc adsorption plate <b>13</b> through a polyurethane adhesive, and an air intake hole <b>12</b> is formed at a center of the arc adsorption plate <b>13</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">In the present embodiment, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, using the arc adsorption plate <b>13</b>, the adhesion is high, and the material pickup effect is improved.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The sucking disc <b>6</b> at a bottom of the installation plate <b>5</b> is specifically arranged in four groups.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">An output terminal of the power protector <b>16</b> is connected with an input terminal of a UPS <b>15</b> through a wire.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">In the present embodiment, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, the power protector <b>16</b> integrates three-phase voltage display, overvoltage protection, undervoltage protection, phase loss protection, and phase sequence protection, which has the characteristics of complete functions, stable performance, and simple operation, and has a good protective effect on the UPS <b>15</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">A wireless switch <b>14</b> is arranged on the other side of an inner wall of the control box <b>7</b> through screw nails, and the wireless switch <b>14</b> is connected with the servo motor <b>2</b> through a wire.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">In the present embodiment, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, the wireless switch <b>14</b> is used to connect external smartphone to remotely control opening and closing of the servo motor <b>2</b>, which is highly intelligent and easy to operate.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">A waterproof layer is arranged on an inner surface layer of the control box <b>7</b>, and the waterproof layer is a silicone coating.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">In the present embodiment, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, the waterproof layer is the silicone coating, such that the waterproof effect in the control box <b>7</b> is effective at preventing moisture from entering the control box <b>7</b> and damaging internal electronic elements.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">It should be noted that the material pickup mechanism for automatic hat-making production line equipment of the present disclosure uses the connecting sleeve <b>11</b> to connect a suction hose of an external vacuum pump body during working. When the vacuum pump body is working, a negative pressure state is generated in the sucking disc <b>6</b>, and through the four groups of sucking discs <b>6</b> at the bottom of the installation plate <b>5</b>, the hat-making cloth is quickly adsorbed and fixed. The PLC controller <b>17</b> is used to automatically control the rotation angle and speed of the servo motor <b>2</b>, thereby driving the rotating seat <b>3</b> to rotate. After the first piece of cloth is sucked, the rotating seat <b>3</b> drives the installation plate <b>5</b> to rotate through the servo motor <b>2</b>, and after rotating in place, the second piece of cloth is sucked to complete suction of the two pieces of cloth, such that the material pickup is completed automatically, which improves the production efficiency of the automatic hat-making production line. The clamping nut <b>10</b> on the hollow screw <b>9</b> is unscrewed to adjust a position of the hollow screw <b>9</b> in the adjusting hole <b>8</b> to adjust relative positions of the four groups of sucking discs <b>6</b>, control an adsorption range, and realize adsorption and fixation of different sizes of hat-making cloth. The wireless switch <b>14</b> is used to connect external smartphone to remotely control opening and closing of the servo motor <b>2</b>, which is highly intelligent and easy to operate. The power protector <b>16</b> integrates three-phase voltage display, overvoltage protection, undervoltage protection, phase loss protection, and phase sequence protection, which has the characteristics of complete functions, stable performance, and simple operation, and has a good protective effect on the UPS <b>15</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">The above display and describe the basic principles, main features and advantages of the present disclosure. It should be understood by a person skilled in the art that the present disclosure is not limited by the aforementioned embodiments. The aforementioned embodiments and the description only illustrate the principles of the present disclosure. Various changes and modifications may be made to the present disclosure without departing from the spirit and scope of the present disclosure. Such changes and modifications all fall within the claimed scope of the present disclosure. The protection scope of the present disclosure is defined by the appended claims and equivalents thereof.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A material pickup mechanism for automatic hat-making production line equipment, comprising a power protector, an installation seat, a servo motor, and a rotating seat, wherein a control box is arranged on one side of the installation seat through first bolts, the servo motor is arranged at a bottom end of the installation seat through a positioning plate and positioning screw nails, the rotating seat is arranged at an output shaft of the servo motor through second bolts, a top end of the rotating seat and a bottom end of the rotating seat are both connected with an installation plate through a fixed shaft, adjusting holes are formed at a top of the installation plate, a hollow screw penetrates one adjusting hole of the adjusting holes, and a bottom of the hollow screw is connected with an air outlet end of a sucking disc.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The material pickup mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein an uninterruptible power supply (UPS) is arranged on a first side of an inner wall of the control box through first screw nails, the power protector is arranged at a lower end of the UPS through third bolts, a programmable logic controller (PLC) is arranged at a lower end of the power protector through a clamping groove, and an output terminal of the PLC and an input terminal of the PLC are respectively connected with an input terminal of the servo motor and an output terminal of the UPS through first wires.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The material pickup mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the hollow screw is fixed in the one adjusting hole through a clamping nut, and a connecting sleeve is arranged at a top of the hollow screw.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The material pickup mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein a bottom of the sucking disc is adhered with an arc adsorption plate through a polyurethane adhesive, and an air intake hole is formed at a center of the arc adsorption plate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The material pickup mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the sucking disc at a bottom of the installation plate is arranged in four groups.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The material pickup mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein an output terminal of the power protector is connected with an input terminal of a UPS through a wire.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The material pickup mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein a wireless switch is arranged on a second side of the inner wall of the control box through second screw nails, and the wireless switch is connected with the servo motor through a second wire.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The material pickup mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein a waterproof layer is arranged on an inner surface layer of the control box, and the waterproof layer is a polytetrafluoroethylene (PTFE) coating.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
