<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225549A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225549</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18007723</doc-number>
<date>20210519</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>31</main-group>
<subgroup>54</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>31</main-group>
<subgroup>56</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>31</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>31</main-group>
<subgroup>42</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>31</main-group>
<subgroup>46</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>31</main-group>
<subgroup>545</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>31</main-group>
<subgroup>56</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>31</main-group>
<subgroup>007</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>31</main-group>
<subgroup>42</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20180801</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>31</main-group>
<subgroup>469</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">MODULAR BREW SYSTEMS</invention-title>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation-in-part>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>16890202</doc-number>
<date>20200602</date>
</document-id>
<parent-status>PENDING</parent-status>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18007723</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation-in-part>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Starbucks Corporation</orgname>
<address>
<city>Seattle</city>
<state>WA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>VENKATAKRISHNAN</last-name>
<first-name>Natarajan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Bellevue</city>
<state>WA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="01" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>GORMLEY</last-name>
<first-name>Joseph Emil</first-name>
<address>
<city>Mercer Island</city>
<state>WA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/US2021/033185</doc-number>
<date>20210519</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c12-date><date>20221201</date></us-371c12-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A modular brewing system is described for providing hot water and managing power to multiple brew tower modules using a single centralized boiler and power management module so as to limit the number of high-power circuits required in a coffeehouse or store. The boiler and power management module manages power of components of the centralized boiler assembly and any brew tower modules connected thereto, including the boiler heaters, the grinder motors, and the brew chamber heaters.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="135.21mm" wi="98.38mm" file="US20230225549A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="226.40mm" wi="148.84mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225549A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="217.76mm" wi="158.24mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225549A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="223.27mm" wi="175.68mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225549A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="205.32mm" wi="134.28mm" file="US20230225549A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="159.26mm" wi="169.50mm" file="US20230225549A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a continuation-in-part of U.S. application Ser. No. 16/890,202 filed Jun. 2, 2020, the entire content of which is hereby incorporated by reference herein.</p>
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="tail"?>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Coffeehouses typically include a commercial brewing machine capable of preparing coffee beverages for customers. These coffeehouses can experience different levels of consumer demand at certain times of the day or as the popularity of the coffeehouse grows. Adapting to the fluctuating demands is often complex and difficult to address.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a schematic block diagram illustrative of an embodiment of a modular brew system including a single boiler and power management module operatively coupled to two brew tower modules.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>A</figref> is a perspective view of an embodiment of a modular brew system including a single boiler and power management module operatively coupled to two brew tower modules.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>B</figref> is a perspective view of an embodiment of a modular brew system including a single boiler and power management module operatively coupled to a single brew tower module.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a schematic block diagram illustrative of an example electronic control implementation of a modular brew system.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is a flow diagram illustrative of an embodiment of a routine implemented by a controller of the boiler and power management module for managing power and operation of a modular brew system.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is a schematic block diagram illustrative of an example power management implementation of a modular brew system.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Generally described, this disclosure is directed to a modular beverage preparation system (e.g., modular coffee brewing system) for use in a commercial or public facility or venue that prepares beverage products (e.g., coffee or tea) for customers, such as a coffeehouse, coffee shop, juice store, smoothie store, retail store, restaurant, parlor, bar, food stall, and/or the like. Consumer demand at these beverage preparation locations (e.g., coffeehouses or stores) can fluctuate greatly as the location becomes more popular over time or at different times of the day. A beverage preparation system can include several components that each may require a relatively large amount of power to operate. At least in certain countries, the large amount of power required may necessitate installation of upgraded high-power (e.g., 220 V, 50 A) circuits/outlets wired to an electrical control panel because the amount of power required to operate the beverage preparation system is more than a standard 110 V outlet (which is standard in the United States, for example) can provide. If multiple conventional beverage preparation systems are required in a single location (e.g., a single coffeehouse or store) due to consumer demand, the requisite power to operate and control the components of each separate conventional system may require each separate conventional system to be powered by a separate high-power circuit/outlet because a single high-power (e.g., 220V, 50 A) circuit/outlet may not be capable of providing sufficient power to simultaneously power the multiple conventional systems during times of high consumer demand. In locations with high throughput, or high consumer demand, it can be imperative that multiple brew systems be operated simultaneously to prevent customers from having to wait too long for their beverages to be prepared, which could drive away customers.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Because of the large amount of power typically required by the conventional beverage preparation systems, it can be difficult to adapt to increases in consumer demand at an established retail location, which typically has an existing power infrastructure that is not able to be quickly or cheaply upgraded or modified to add additional power resources (e.g., additional high-power circuits/outlets). Adding additional power infrastructure can require substantial remodeling and renovation, which can require significant expense and a disruption to existing business during the remodeling and renovation. In addition to additional power infrastructure requirements, adding additional independent and stand-alone beverage preparation machines could take up valuable space in an already-crowded preparation area.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In accordance with embodiments described herein, a modular coffee brewing system includes a boiler assembly (which typically requires a significant portion of the total power consumption of a coffee brewing system), as well as the power management and control functionality of the modular coffee brewing system, in a single base module, device, or unit. This base module, or centralized device or unit, can then be operatively connected to multiple brew tower modules, devices or units, that each include the rest of the structural components and functionality of a coffee brewing system (e.g., hopper assembly, grinder assembly, brew assembly, etc.). The base module (e.g., via the boiler assembly) is configured to supply hot water to, and operational control (including power management) of, multiple coffee brew tower modules. Because of the centralized boiler and power management structures and functions in the base module, the modular brew systems described herein may only require use of a single high-power (e.g., 220 V, 50 A) circuit/outlet to power multiple brew tower modules operating simultaneously, which allows for increased output without requiring installation of additional high-power circuits/outlets. Accordingly, significant expense and disruption to existing retail business can be avoided and the modular system may easily adapt to fluctuations in consumer demand and physical store limitations or constraints.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In accordance with several embodiments of the disclosure, a modular beverage preparation system (e.g., modular coffee brewing system) may provide one or more of the following advantages or benefits: (i) flexibility and adaptability to meet fluctuating consumer demands, (ii) reduced space requirements as additional beverage preparation equipment is added to meet increasing demands, (iii) reduced overall costs, complexity and time required to adapt to the fluctuating consumer demands, (iv) ease and reduced inconvenience when replacing or fixing defective components of the beverage preparation equipment; and/or (v) reduction in need to install additional high-power circuits, especially at an already-established facility in which installation of additional high-power circuits would require substantial remodeling and reconstruction, thereby greatly increasing expense and disruption to existing business.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> illustrates a schematic block diagram of an embodiment of a modular brew system <b>100</b>. The modular brew system <b>100</b> includes a centralized base module comprising a boiler and power management module <b>103</b> configured to generate hot water, and control operation and manage power of, the modular brew system <b>100</b>, including any (e.g., one, two, three, four, or more) brew tower modules <b>102</b>A, <b>102</b>B operatively coupled to the boiler and power management module <b>103</b>. Operative coupling between the boiler and power management module <b>103</b> and the brew tower modules <b>102</b> may include fluid coupling through fluid conduits (e.g., water hoses) and wired communicative coupling through input/output ports and/or communication cables capable of transmitting and receiving data and/or power. In some configurations, wireless communicative coupling over a wireless communications network (e.g., using personal area networks, local area networks, inductive links, etc.) may be used instead of, or in addition to, wired communicative coupling. The wireless communications may involve exchanging of data and/or power via short-wavelength (e.g., ultra-high frequency (UHF) or super high frequency (SHF)) radio waves, or inductive coils.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The base module, e.g., boiler and power management module <b>103</b>, includes a controller <b>105</b> (which includes and provides centralized control and power management electronics and functionality) and a centralized boiler assembly <b>110</b> (which may require a significant percentage of the overall power consumption due to the multiple heating elements used to heat the water) for the combined modular brew system <b>100</b>. The centralized structural and functional features of the boiler and power management module <b>103</b> advantageously allows for multiple brew tower modules <b>102</b> to simultaneously be run on a single high power circuit/outlet (e.g., circuit providing at least 200 V and 50 A of power) during times of high demand and for a single brew tower module to be run in times of low demand. In accordance with several implementations, the brew tower modules are not powered separately by an electrical outlet.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The control and power management electronics of the controller <b>105</b> may include circuit breakers, DC power supplies, printed circuit board assemblies or other circuitry, relays or other electronic switching devices, microcontrollers, application-specific integrated circuits, and/or software code modules (such as power management algorithms stored in memory) executed by one or more microcontrollers or processors or circuitry. The code modules may be stored in any type of computer-readable medium or other computer storage device, such as read-only memory, flash memory, random-access memory, and/or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The boiler assembly <b>110</b> may include one or more boilers configured to generate and supply heated water for preparing hot beverages (e.g., coffee beverages). There may be one, two, three, or more than three boilers in the boiler assembly <b>110</b>. Each boiler may include one or more heating elements configured to heat water within fluid supply lines or reservoirs to a desired brewing temperature (e.g., 190 to 200 degrees Fahrenheit) and maintain the desired brewing temperature. The heating elements can include one or more devices that use electrical energy to generate and/or remove heat. For example, the devices can include, but are not limited to, resistance wire, etched foil, coils, induction heater, radiator, heat exchanger, magnetron, thermoelectric device, Peltier cooler, compressor, etc. The boiler and power management module <b>103</b> may include multiple fluid conduits (e.g., water hoses) configured to be operatively coupled to a respective fluid inlet port of a brew tower module <b>102</b>. The fluid conduits may receive water from a central water supply or reservoir system of the facility or venue in which the brewing system <b>100</b> resides. The materials used for the fluid conduits (e.g., water hoses) may be metal, polymer, or carbon-based. The end connectors of the fluid conduits may be rapid-connect-type connectors or threaded connectors. The fluid conduits (e.g., end connectors) and/or fluid reservoir(s) in the boiler and power management module <b>103</b> may include air release vents adapted to enable priming of the water connection. The fluid conduits (e.g., end connectors), fluid reservoir(s) in the boiler and power management module <b>103</b>, and/or central system water supply outlets may include shutoff valves adapted to quickly shut off water supply to prevent water drips or leakages during connection and disconnection.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Each brew tower module <b>102</b> includes (e.g., consists essentially of) a hopper assembly <b>115</b>A, <b>115</b>B, a grinder assembly <b>120</b>A, <b>120</b>B, and a brew assembly <b>125</b>A, <b>125</b>B. Each hopper assembly <b>115</b> may include multiple hoppers for storing different types of coffee beans to produce different types of coffee beverages. In some implementations, the hopper assembly <b>115</b> may consist of a single hopper. The one or more hoppers may be refillable. The one or more hoppers may supply an appropriate amount of coffee beans to the grinder assembly <b>120</b>. Each grinder assembly <b>120</b> may be configured to grind the coffee beans into grounds of an appropriate, or a particular, particle size. The grounds may then be delivered to the brew assembly <b>125</b>, where they are combined with hot water supplied by the boiler assembly <b>110</b> of the boiler and power management module <b>103</b>. The brew assembly <b>125</b> may be configured to brew the coffee beverage according to a defined recipe or formula for the desired beverage (e.g., certain brew time duration, temperature, pressure, ingredients, flavors, etc.). For example, the brew assembly <b>125</b> may be configured to extract the coffee from the grounds and hot water using a vacuum applied to a brew chamber, as is performed by the CLOVERS brewing machines used commercially by the Applicant. The brew chamber may include one or more heating elements to heat and/or maintain a temperature of the beverage during brewing and/or prior to dispensing.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The brew assembly <b>125</b> may incorporate one or more filters that may require periodic replacement (e.g., after each single-serve beverage portion is prepared or after multiple single-serve beverage portions are prepared). The brewed coffee beverage is then dispensed into a cup or other beverage holder by a dispensing assembly (e.g., spout or tap). The hopper assembly <b>115</b>, grinder assembly <b>120</b>, and brew assembly <b>125</b> may incorporate any of the operational and/or structural features of the corresponding assemblies described in Applicant's U.S. Pat. No. 9,930,987, which is incorporated by reference herein.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In accordance with the illustrated embodiments, the brew tower modules <b>102</b> advantageously do not include a boiler assembly <b>110</b> or a controller <b>105</b>. The illustrated embodiments of the brew tower modules <b>102</b> also are not configured to be directly connected to a high-power circuit in a stand-alone manner and are not configured to be directly connected to a building water supply. In some configurations, the brew tower modules <b>102</b> receive their power and water only from the base boiler and power management module <b>103</b> (e.g., are not powered by a separate electrical circuit/outlet) and cannot operate independently of the base boiler and power management module <b>103</b>. In some configurations, the brew tower modules <b>102</b> may each include one, some, or all of the structural and/or functional features of the controller <b>105</b> instead of, or in addition to, the boiler and power management module <b>103</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The boiler and power management module <b>103</b> is configured to operatively connect to each brew tower module <b>102</b> through one or more fluid conduits (e.g., water hoses), communication cables (e.g., data cables), and/or power cables <b>101</b>. In some embodiments, the boiler and power management module <b>103</b> is configured to operatively connect to each brew tower module <b>102</b> through a single water hose, a single power cable, and a single data cable. The power cable and data cable may be combined into a single integrated communications cable providing both power and data transfer capability. Multiples of the various hoses or cables may be used as desired and/or required.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The boiler and power management module <b>103</b> may control initiation of the brewing process in each connected brew tower module <b>102</b>. The boiler and power management module <b>103</b> and/or the brew tower modules <b>102</b> may include user inputs (e.g., buttons, switches) configured to receive input from a user that may be used to prepare a desired beverage (e.g., input regarding size of the beverage, type of beverage, etc.). The boiler and power management module <b>103</b> may include one or more sensors configured to sense the number of brew tower modules connected to it. The boiler and power management module <b>103</b> may be configured to manage the overall modular system power based on the number of brew tower modules connected so that the overall modular system <b>100</b> can operate on a single high power circuit (e.g., voltage level of at least 200 V and current of at least 50 A).</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The boiler and power management module <b>103</b> and the brew tower modules <b>102</b> are relatively light in mass due to the presence of fewer components in each module compared to a conventional brew tower system that includes all of the components of the boiler and power management module and a brew tower module in a single combined system. Thus, the modules of the modular brew system <b>100</b> are easier for technicians to install in coffee houses or store locations. For example, the mass of the boiler and power management module <b>103</b> may be around 80 pounds compared to a mass of around 200 pounds for a conventional combined brew system (e.g., about 40% of the mass). Because the system <b>100</b> is modular, it is relatively easy to break the system <b>100</b> apart into separate modules for accessibility for maintenance and moving. In addition, because the system <b>100</b> is modular, it allows for convenient removal of one of the brew tower modules <b>102</b> for maintenance while still keeping a brewing system in place to service the customers. The modularity allows a service technician to swap out a brew tower module <b>102</b> with another prepared brew tower module <b>102</b> to limit down time and otherwise avoid inconvenience and disruption to existing business.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>A</figref> illustrates a perspective view of an embodiment of a modular brew system <b>200</b> in which two brew tower modules <b>202</b>A, <b>202</b>B are operatively coupled to the base boiler and power management module <b>203</b>. The modular brew system <b>200</b> and its component modules <b>202</b>, <b>203</b> may include the structural and functional features described above in connection with the schematic block diagram of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, and vice-versa. For example, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>A and <b>2</b>B</figref> and as described above in connection with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, the brew tower modules, devices, or structural units <b>202</b> may include a hopper assembly <b>215</b>, a grinder assembly <b>220</b>, and a brew assembly <b>225</b>, and a dispensing assembly <b>226</b>, which each may include both external and internal components. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>B</figref> illustrates an embodiment of the modular system <b>200</b> at a time when a single brew tower module <b>202</b>A is operatively coupled to the boiler and power management module <b>203</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The modular brew system <b>200</b> is advantageously designed for long-term flexibility. In accordance with several implementations, the modular brew system <b>200</b> is designed around the boiler assembly <b>210</b> so it is possible to just have a boiler assembly <b>210</b> that provides hot water (e.g., via a hot water tap <b>227</b> of the boiler assembly <b>210</b>) without any brew tower modules <b>202</b> connected to the boiler and power management module <b>203</b>. In some implementations, the water pressure is between 20 psi and 40 psi (between about 1.4 bar and 2.8 bar). The boiler assembly <b>210</b> may optionally include a pressure regulator.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The boiler assembly <b>210</b> may be configured to provide water simultaneously to the hot water tap of the boiler assembly <b>210</b> and to any connected brew tower modules <b>202</b> (or at least two brew tower modules at a time). The water may be provided to each brew tower module (and optionally to the hot water tap of the boiler assembly <b>210</b> as well) at a rate of between 1 oz/s and 5 oz/s (e.g., between 1 oz/s and 3 oz/s, between 2 oz/s and 4 oz/s, between 3 oz/s and 5 oz/s, 1 oz/s, 1.5 oz/s, 2 oz/s, 2.5 oz/s, 3 oz/s, 3.5 oz/s, 4 oz/s, 4.5 oz/s, 5 oz/s, at least 2 oz/s). In some implementations, all fluid outlets out of the boiler assembly manifold have the same flow rate. In some implementations, the flow rates may differ, as desired and/or required. The boiler assembly <b>210</b> may optionally include a system of restrictor valves to facilitate control of different flow rates to different brew tower modules <b>202</b>. The pressure and/or flow rate to the brew tower modules <b>202</b> may be different or adjusted based on the type of beverage to be prepared or based on how the beverage contents (e.g., coffee or tea) are delivered to the brew tower modules <b>202</b>. For example, if the beverage is to be prepared using grounds or granules, then the pressure and/or flow rate may be higher than if the beverage is to be prepared from packaged filter bags. Beverages prepared using filter bags may be prepared using lower pressure and/or flow rates so as to prevent rupturing of the filter bags. If the beverage to be prepared is pre-processed, then the pressure and/or flow rate may be even lower than the pressure and/or flow rate applied for beverages prepared using filter bags.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The boiler and power management module <b>203</b> may be used in conjunction with a reverse French press system; however, any cooking or beverage preparation system that requires hot water could be attached to the boiler and power management module <b>203</b> (e.g., espresso, tea brewing, soup, etc.). For example, the boiler and power management module <b>203</b> may be used for extracting flavor from fresh solid ingredients (such as lemon, mint, lemon grass, cucumber, etc.) into a liquid-based beverage or broth. Hot water from the boiler and power management module <b>203</b> may also be used for reconstituting soluble ingredients from powder to liquid form. The boiler and power management module <b>203</b> is configured to allow a brew tower module to be attached on either side of the boiler and power management module housing (e.g., left or right in a vertical configuration) or one brew tower module on each side. More than two (e.g., three or four) brew tower modules may be configured to be connected in some implementations. Other liquid-based preparation modules (e.g., espresso, tea brewing, soup, etc.) different than the brew tower modules described and illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>, <b>2</b>A and <b>2</b>B</figref> may be compatible for attachment and operation with the boiler and power management module <b>203</b> for store flexibility.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a schematic block diagram illustrating an example implementation of electronic control and power management of a modular brew system <b>300</b> (e.g., the modular brew systems described herein). Only a single brew tower module <b>302</b> is illustrated for simplicity; however, two or more brew tower modules may be controlled by the boiler and power management module <b>303</b>. The modular brew system <b>300</b> and its component modules <b>302</b>, <b>303</b> may include the structural and functional features described above in connection with the systems <b>100</b>, <b>200</b> and modules <b>102</b>, <b>103</b>, <b>202</b>, <b>203</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>, <b>2</b>A and <b>2</b>B</figref>; and vice-versa. As described above, the modules <b>302</b>, <b>303</b> may comprise devices or structural units or towers including external and internal components (e.g., a physical housing and mechanical and electrical hardware). As shown, the boiler and power management module <b>303</b> is the only module or component of the modular brew system <b>300</b> connected to a high-power electrical circuit/outlet <b>304</b> (e.g., via a power connection such as an electrical plug and electrical cable with appropriate wiring). In accordance with several implementations, the brew tower modules are not powered by a separate electrical circuit/outlet (e.g., high-power or low-power circuit/outlet).</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">In some configurations, the boiler and power management module <b>303</b> is configured to be powered by a high power circuit <b>304</b> having a voltage level of at least 200 V (e.g., 208 V, 220 V, 230 V, 240 V or more) and a current level of at least 50 A (e.g., 50 A, 100 A, 150 A or more). In some implementations, the voltage level may range from 100 V to 208 V or from 110 V to 220 V and the current level may range from 10 A to 50 A. In one implementation, the electrical circuit/outlet <b>304</b> is configured to provide power of 220 V and 50 A. Other voltage and amperage combinations may be used as desired and/or required in other implementations.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The illustrated embodiment of the boiler and power management module <b>303</b> includes a circuit breaker/main power bus <b>305</b>, a power conversion/power supply module <b>306</b>, a master controller <b>307</b>, an electronic switching device <b>308</b>, one or more boilers <b>310</b>, a speaker <b>309</b>, and one or more input/output devices <b>311</b> (e.g., touch screen user interface, lights and/or valves). The illustrated embodiment of the brew tower module <b>302</b> includes a power conversion/power supply module <b>312</b>, a brew chamber heater <b>313</b>, a grinder <b>320</b>, a motor drive controller <b>314</b>, and an input/output interface controller <b>316</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The power conversion/power supply modules <b>306</b>, <b>312</b> of the boiler and power management module <b>303</b> and the brew tower module <b>302</b> are each electrically coupled to the circuit breaker/main power bus <b>305</b>. The circuit breaker/main power bus <b>305</b> may be coupled to the power connector (e.g., electrical outlet plug and electrical cable) coupled to the high power circuit <b>304</b>. The circuit breaker and main power bus <b>305</b> may include separate modules/circuitry for the circuit breaker and bus functions or may be integrated into a single module. The power conversion modules <b>306</b>, <b>312</b> may comprise DC power supplies and/or other electrical circuitry adapted to convert AC power to DC power (e.g., transformer-based linear converter or switch mode power supply, AC-to-DC converter). The DC power supply <b>306</b> of the boiler and power management module <b>303</b> provides power to the master controller <b>307</b> and the DC power supply <b>312</b> of the brew tower module <b>302</b> provides power to the controllers <b>314</b>, <b>316</b> of the brew tower module <b>302</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The master controller <b>307</b> is communicatively coupled, and sends control signals, to the boilers <b>310</b>, the electronic switching device <b>308</b>, the speaker <b>309</b>, and the input/output devices <b>311</b> of the boiler and power management module <b>303</b>, and to the motor drive controller <b>314</b> of the brew tower module <b>302</b>. The master controller <b>307</b> is also communicatively coupled to the input/output interface controller <b>316</b> of the brew tower module <b>302</b> that controls input and output devices (such as a touch screen user interface and display, sensors and lights) via a data cable to facilitate input/output communication and control. The input devices may include a touch screen user interface/display adapted to receive user inputs and to display textual and/or graphical options for the user to select from and/or textual/graphical output for the user to read and/or see (e.g., status information, alerts, etc.).</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The motor drive controller <b>314</b> may control drivers of stepper motors or other motors or powered mechanical components operating within the brew tower module <b>302</b>. The master controller <b>307</b> can be used for high-level functionality, such as, but not limited to, detecting the number of brew tower modules connected to the boiler and power management module <b>303</b>, allocating power amongst the modules <b>302</b>, <b>303</b> of the system <b>300</b>, activating/de-activating the heating elements of the boiler assembly <b>310</b> and the brew chamber heater <b>313</b>, inter-system communication, safety protocols, etc. For example, because the boiler assembly <b>310</b> may have multiple heaters, the master controller <b>307</b> may shut off one or more of the heaters as needed to increase (e.g., maximize) power provided to connected brew tower modules <b>302</b> while they need more power for operation, thereby increasing (e.g., maximizing) the amount of coffee beverages that are produced during peak demand times. The master controller <b>307</b> may control the water temperature. When water is not to ideal brewing temperature, the master controller <b>307</b> may not allow the brew tower modules <b>302</b> to prepare beverages or hot water to be dispensed by the boiler assembly <b>310</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The master controller <b>307</b> can determine the presence of brew tower modules <b>302</b> in a variety of ways. For example, the master controller <b>302</b> can query a resistor value in the brew tower modules <b>302</b> or can sense an amount of current that is being drawn by brew tower modules <b>302</b>. The master controller <b>307</b> can also detect the presence of the brew tower modules <b>302</b> by querying the communication link between the brew tower module(s) <b>302</b> and the master controller <b>307</b> for a response. In addition, the master controller <b>302</b> can sense the water pressure or flow rate in the fluid conduits or water connection hoses and may make a determination of the presence of a brew tower module <b>302</b> based on the sensed water pressure or flow rate.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">In some embodiments, each brew tower module <b>302</b> can include a resistor that can be checked, even when the brew tower module is deactivated. Accordingly, using an ohmmeter, the master controller <b>307</b> can query the resistor value of the brew tower modules <b>302</b>. If the sensed resistor value satisfies an activated system resistor threshold, the master controller <b>307</b> can determine that a brew tower module <b>302</b> is operatively connected. The process can be repeated until the master controller <b>307</b> determines the number of brew tower modules <b>302</b> operatively connected. The activated system resistor threshold can be determined based on a resistor installed on each brew tower module <b>302</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">In certain embodiments, the boiler and power management module <b>303</b> can include an ammeter that can be used to detect the amount of current being drawn from brew tower modules <b>302</b>. Using the ammeter, if the master controller <b>307</b> determines that an activated system current threshold is satisfied, the master controller <b>307</b> can determine that a brew tower module <b>302</b> is operatively connected. If the sensed current does not satisfy the activated system current threshold, the master controller <b>307</b> can determine that there is not a brew tower module <b>302</b> connected. The activated system current threshold can be determined based on an amount of current that is drawn by brew tower modules <b>302</b> when deactivated. The amount of current drawn by a brew tower module <b>302</b> when deactivated can be set during manufacturing or installation. For example, the brew tower modules <b>302</b> can be designed to draw a very small current to power some features of the brew tower module <b>302</b>, even when the brew tower module <b>302</b> is deactivated.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">It will be understood that additional methods can be used to detect the presence of brew tower modules <b>302</b>. For example, in some implementations, the master controller <b>302</b> simply receives control signals from the brew tower modules <b>302</b> indicating connectivity.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">In some implementations, if the master controller <b>307</b> determines that a brew tower module <b>302</b> is operatively connected or disconnected, it can alert a user. The master controller <b>307</b> can alert the user via a visual and/or audible alert (e.g., light and/or sound) or an electronic communication (e.g., via a touch screen user interface of the boiler and power management module <b>303</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The master controller <b>307</b> may have stored in memory power management algorithms containing instructions that, when executed, effectively manage power received from the high power circuit <b>304</b> (e.g., via a power connector/power connection, such as a plug adapted to be inserted into an electrical outlet and an electrical cable) so as to facilitate simultaneous operation of multiple brew tower modules <b>302</b>. The master controller <b>307</b> manages power usage by the heating elements of the centralized boiler assembly <b>210</b> and power usage by the heating elements of the brew chambers and motors of the grinding assembly (e.g., grinders) in the brew tower modules. The centralized power management and modular configuration facilitates running the modular brew system <b>300</b> with one high-power (e.g., 50 A, 220 V) circuit. Because the master controller <b>307</b> of the centralized boiler and power management module <b>303</b> controls the power, it simplifies the safety circuit for the combined electrical system including the brew tower modules <b>302</b>. In accordance with several embodiments, the centralized power management allows for maximization of the power coming out of the electrical outlet (e.g., 220 V, 50 A high-power circuit <b>304</b>) by diverting power from one or more of the multiple heating elements of the boiler assembly <b>210</b> to the power demands of the connected brew tower modules (e.g., brew chamber heaters or grinder motors).</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The electronic switching device <b>308</b> may include any number of switching devices (e.g., solid-state relay bank transistor, field-effect transistors (FETs), bi-polar junction transistors (BJTs), mechanical relays, triodes for alternating current (TRIACs), etc.) that toggles on and off various components (e.g., heating elements, mechanical elements) of the boilers <b>310</b>, the brew chamber heater <b>313</b>, or grinder <b>320</b> based on control signals received from the master controller <b>307</b>. The master controller <b>307</b> is configured to receive inputs from the brew tower module <b>302</b> to facilitate controlled power management of the overall modular system <b>300</b>, including providing controlled power signals to the brew tower module(s) <b>302</b>. The hoppers <b>315</b>, grinders <b>320</b>, boilers <b>310</b>, and brew assemblies <b>325</b> may incorporate the functional and/or structural features of the corresponding hoppers, grinders, boilers, brew assemblies described herein or in U.S. Pat. No. 9,930,987.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">It will be understood that each boiler and power management system <b>303</b> and each brew tower module <b>302</b> can include fewer or more components as desired. In various embodiments, the controllers <b>314</b>, <b>316</b> can be implemented as a single controller or as separate controllers. The respective controllers <b>307</b>, <b>314</b>, <b>316</b> can be implemented using one or more printed circuit board assemblies, microcontrollers, microprocessors, field programmable gate arrays (FPGAs), application-specific integrated circuits (ASICs), programmable logic device (PLDs), and/or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Turning to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>, a flow diagram illustrative of an embodiment of a routine <b>450</b> implemented by the master controller <b>307</b> of the boiler and power management module <b>303</b> is provided for managing power and operation of the brew tower(s) operatively coupled to the boiler and power management module <b>303</b>. At Block <b>452</b>, the master controller <b>307</b> receives input indicative of power resource requirements or consumption from the I/O interface controller <b>316</b> of each of the brew tower modules <b>302</b> operatively connected to the boiler and power management module <b>303</b>. At Block <b>454</b>, the master controller <b>307</b> executes power management algorithms to efficiently manage power and operation of the overall modular system <b>300</b> based on the received input. At Block <b>456</b>, the master controller <b>307</b> generates control signals to the boilers <b>310</b>, the electronic switching device <b>308</b>, and the motor drive controller <b>314</b> to control operation of the heating elements of the boilers <b>310</b>, the heating elements of the brew chamber heater <b>313</b>, mechanical components of the grinder <b>320</b>, and/or other power consuming components. Power to the various components may be continuously adjusted (e.g., increased, decreased, or shut off) to allocate power resources most efficiently.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is a schematic block diagram illustrating an example schematic implementation <b>500</b> of input and output signals between various components of the modular brew system to facilitate control and power management of the modular brew system (e.g., systems <b>100</b>, <b>200</b>, <b>300</b>) described herein. The power management scheme is adapted to facilitate efficient management of power between the power-consuming components of the brew tower units, or modules, and the centralized boiler unit, or module. The schematic block diagram of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> includes the main power unit <b>305</b> (e.g., circuit breaker/main power bus) and the main controller <b>307</b> (as first shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>). The schematic block diagram of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> further includes four boiler relays corresponding to four water heaters and two grinder relays. The relays may be components of the electronic switching device <b>308</b> shown in, and described in connection with, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> (e.g., solid state relay bank). The main controller <b>307</b> is configured to generate control signals to the relays to control operation and power to (e.g., start, stop, adjust operational parameters of) the water heaters in the boiler and power management module <b>203</b>, <b>303</b> and the grinder motors in the brew tower modules <b>202</b>, <b>302</b>. The main controller <b>307</b> is configured to receive input signals from boiler sensors indicative of operation and/or parameters associated with the boilers <b>310</b> (e.g., water temperature, power requirements). The boiler sensors may be examples of the I/O devices <b>311</b> schematically illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>. The main power unit <b>305</b> is configured to provide power to the relays and to various components of the brew tower modules <b>202</b>, <b>302</b> as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> (e.g., motor drive controller <b>314</b> and I/O interface controller <b>316</b>). As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, the main controller <b>307</b> is also configured to send and receive signals from the brew tower modules <b>202</b>, <b>302</b> to facilitate power management.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">In accordance with several implementations, upon startup of the boiler and power management module <b>203</b>, <b>303</b>, power is allocated to the water heaters of the boiler assembly <b>110</b>, <b>210</b>, <b>310</b> until the water reaches a desired temperature (e.g., a desired brewing, cooking, heating, boiling, or threshold temperature) as determined by the boiler sensors shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>). After the water heaters reach the desired temperature, power may be diverted to brew chamber heaters in any brew tower modules connected to the boiler and power management module. In a steady state, power may be applied to one or more of the water heaters in the boiler assembly of the boiler and power management module as needed to keep water temperature at the desired temperature. Power may also be applied to the brew chamber heaters as needed in any connected brew tower modules.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">During brewing operation, power may be diverted to the grinder assembly of any connected brew tower modules that have been activated to brew a beverage (e.g., coffee). Power may be terminated to the brew chamber heaters and water heaters in the boiler assembly while any grinding assemblies are active to conserve power. The master controller <b>307</b> may be configured to delay brewing if the water and brew chambers are not at a desired brewing temperature. The master controller <b>307</b> may deactivate or disable a dispensing assembly or a hot water tap <b>227</b> of the boiler and power management module until all the boilers of the boiler assembly have reached a desired temperature. The prepared beverage (e.g., coffee) may be dispensed by the one or more brew tower modules once hot water is available. Brewing operations may have priority over dispensing of hot water through the hot water tap <b>227</b> such that hot water may not be dispensed through the hot water tap <b>227</b> during brewing operations.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="2">Concluding Language</heading>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Although mainly described with respect to a coffee brewing system and a coffeehouse or store environment, it will be understood that the embodiments described herein can have wide applicability in modular cooking/beverage preparations systems that manage power and provide certain centralized structure and functionality requiring significant power. As used herein, the term &#x201c;beverage,&#x201d; in addition to having its ordinary meaning, can include, among other things, any liquid or substantially liquid substance or product having a flowing quality such as juices, coffee beverages, teas, frozen yogurt, beer, wine, cocktails, liqueurs, spirits, cider, soft drinks, flavored water, energy drinks, soups, broths, combinations of the same, or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The use of the term &#x201c;module&#x201d; herein should not be interpreted as requiring implementation as a purely software-based code module but, as illustrated and described herein, can represent a physical unit or structural modular component capable of modular assembly (e.g., physical, electrical, and/or communicative coupling) to another physical unit or structural base component. For example, the boiler and power management modules and the brew tower modules described herein may comprise modular structural devices or towers that include external housings and internal structural components as described herein.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">All of the processes described herein may be embodied in, and fully automated via, software code modules executed by one or more specialized computers or processors. The code modules may be stored in any type of computer-readable medium or other computer storage device. Some or all the methods may alternatively be embodied in specialized computer hardware. In addition, the components referred to herein may be implemented in hardware, software, firmware or a combination thereof. A software module can reside in RAM memory, flash memory, ROM memory, EPROM memory, EEPROM memory, registers, hard disk, a removable disk, a CD-ROM, or any other form of non-transitory computer-readable storage medium known in the art. An exemplary storage medium can be coupled to the processor such that the processor can read information from, and write information to, the storage medium. In the alternative, the storage medium can be integral to the processor. The processor and the storage medium can reside in an ASIC. The ASIC can reside in a user terminal. In the alternative, the processor and the storage medium can reside as discrete components in a user terminal.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">Conditional language such as, among others, &#x201c;can,&#x201d; &#x201c;could,&#x201d; &#x201c;might&#x201d; or &#x201c;may,&#x201d; unless specifically stated otherwise, are otherwise understood within the context as used in general to convey that certain embodiments include, while other embodiments do not include, certain features, elements and/or steps. Thus, such conditional language is not generally intended to imply that features, elements and/or steps are in any way required for one or more embodiments or that one or more embodiments necessarily include logic for deciding, with or without user input or prompting, whether these features, elements and/or steps are included or are to be performed in any particular embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Conjunctive language such as the phrase &#x201c;at least one of X, Y and Z,&#x201d; unless specifically stated otherwise, is otherwise understood with the context as used in general to convey that an item, term, etc. may be either X, Y or Z. Thus, such conjunctive language is not generally intended to imply that certain embodiments require at least one of X, at least one of Y and at least one of Z to each be present.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Some embodiments have been described in connection with the accompanying drawings. However, the figures are not drawn to scale. Distances, angles, etc. are merely illustrative and do not necessarily bear an exact relationship to actual dimensions and layout of the devices illustrated. Components can be added, removed, and/or rearranged. Further, the disclosure herein of any particular feature, aspect, method, property, characteristic, quality, attribute, element, or the like in connection with various embodiments can be used in all other embodiments set forth herein.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">Any process descriptions, elements or blocks in the flow diagrams described herein and/or depicted in the attached figures should be understood as potentially representing modules, segments, or portions of code which include one or more executable instructions for implementing specific logical functions or elements in the process. Alternate implementations are included within the scope of the embodiments described herein in which elements or functions may be deleted, executed out of order from that shown, or discussed, including substantially concurrently or in reverse order, depending on the functionality involved as would be understood by those skilled in the art. Moreover, in certain embodiments, acts or events can be performed concurrently, e.g., through multi-threaded processing, interrupt processing, or multiple processors or processor cores or on other parallel architectures, rather than sequentially. In addition, different tasks or processes can be performed by different machines and/or computing systems that can function together. Execution in a cloud computing environment in some embodiments supports a multiplicity of conditions to be computed contemporaneously.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">The various illustrative logical and schematic blocks and algorithms described in connection with the embodiments disclosed herein can be implemented or performed by a machine, such as a processor, a digital signal processor (DSP), an application specific integrated circuit (ASIC), a field programmable gate array (FPGA) or other programmable logic device, discrete gate or transistor logic, discrete hardware components, or any combination thereof designed to perform the functions described herein. A processor can be a microprocessor, but in the alternative, the processor can be a controller, microcontroller, or state machine, combinations of the same, or the like. A processor can also be implemented as a combination of computing devices, e.g., a combination of a DSP and a microprocessor, a plurality of microprocessors, one or more microprocessors in conjunction with a DSP core, or any other such configuration. A computing environment can include any type of computer system, including, but not limited to, a computer system based on a microprocessor, a mainframe computer, a digital signal processor, a portable computing device, a personal organizer, a device controller, and a computational engine within an appliance, to name a few.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">In some embodiments, the modular brew system comprises one or more of the following: means for heating water (e.g., a boiler assembly), means for grinding coffee beans (e.g., a grinder assembly), means for storing coffee beans (e.g., one or more hoppers), means for brewing a coffee beverage using the grounds and heated water (e.g., a brew assembly including a brew chamber), means for dispensing a prepared coffee beverage (e.g., tap or spout), means for managing power of the modular brew system (e.g., controller or processor), etc.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">In some embodiments, the modular brew system comprises various features that are present as single features (as opposed to multiple features). For example, in one embodiment, the system includes a single brew tower module, a single hopper, a single boiler, etc. Multiple features or components are provided in alternate embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">It should be emphasized that many variations and modifications may be made to the above-described embodiments, the elements of which are to be understood as being among other acceptable examples. All such modifications and variations are intended to be included herein within the scope of this disclosure.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A method of facilitating brewing of coffee using a modular brew system, the method comprising:
<claim-text>heating water in a boiler assembly of a base module of the modular brew system;</claim-text>
<claim-text>supplying a first portion of the heated water to a first brew chamber of a first brew tower module of the modular brew system to facilitate preparation of a first coffee beverage within the first brew chamber of the first brew tower module,</claim-text>
<claim-text>supplying a second portion of the heated water to a second brew chamber of a second brew tower module of the modular brew system to facilitate preparation of a second coffee beverage within the second brew chamber of the second brew tower module,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first brew tower module, the second brew tower module, and the base module comprise separate structural units; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>managing power allocation supplied by a single high power circuit between the base module, the first brew tower module, and the second brew tower module from the base module.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first brew tower module and the second brew tower module each comprise a grinder assembly configured to grind coffee beans into grounds of a particular size.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein supplying the first portion of the heated water to the first brew chamber comprises delivering at least 2 ounces of heated water per second to the first brew chamber and wherein supplying the second portion of the heated water to the second brew chamber comprises delivering at least 2 ounces of heated water per second to the second brew chamber.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein managing the power allocation is performed by a master controller of the base module.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein managing the power allocation comprises diverting power from one or more heating elements of the boiler assembly of the base module to one or more components of at least one of the first brew tower module and the second brew tower module.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first brew tower module and the second brew tower module are not powered separately by an electrical outlet.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein managing the power allocation comprises operating the first brew tower module and the second brew tower module simultaneously.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. A modular coffee brewing system comprising:
<claim-text>a first coffee brew tower module comprising a hopper, a grinder, and a brew chamber;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second coffee brew tower module comprising a hopper, a grinder, and a brew chamber; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a single boiler and power management module operatively coupled to the first coffee brew tower module and the second coffee brew tower module,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the boiler and power management module comprises:
<claim-text>a boiler configured to supply hot water to the brew chamber of each of the first coffee brew tower module and the second coffee brew tower module; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a controller configured to control and manage power provided to each of the first coffee brew tower module and the second coffee brew tower module,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the power provided to each of the first coffee brew tower module and the second coffee brew tower module is supplied by a single power circuit electrically coupled to the boiler and power management module.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the first coffee brew tower module and the second coffee brew tower module do not comprise a boiler.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the first coffee brew tower module and the second coffee brew tower module cannot operate independently without the boiler and power management module.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein first coffee brew tower module and the second coffee brew tower module cannot be powered by a separate electrical outlet.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the first coffee brew tower module and the second coffee brew tower module are configured to operate simultaneously.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the boiler is configured to simultaneously provide at least 2 ounces of hot water per second to each of the first coffee brew tower module and the second coffee brew tower module.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the controller is configured to divert power from one or more heating elements of the boiler to one or more components of the first coffee brew tower module or the second coffee brew tower module via a solid state relay bank.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the modular coffee brewing system is configured to operate using a single high power circuit configured to provide a voltage level of at least 200 V and a current level of at least 50 A.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. A coffee brewing module configured to supply hot water and manage power delivery to a first coffee brew tower module comprising a grinder and a brew chamber and a second coffee brew tower module comprising a brew chamber and a grinder, the brewing module comprising:
<claim-text>a boiler assembly configured to supply hot water to the brew chamber of each of the first coffee brew tower module and the second coffee brew tower module; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a controller configured to control and manage power provided to each of the first coffee brew tower module and the second coffee brew tower module,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the power provided to each of the first coffee brew tower module and the second coffee brew tower module is supplied by a single power circuit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. The coffee brewing module of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the boiler assembly is configured to simultaneously provide at least 2 ounces of hot water per second to each of the first coffee brew tower module and the second coffee brew tower module.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. The coffee brewing module of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the controller is configured to divert power from one or more heating elements of the boiler to one or more components of the first coffee brew tower module or the second coffee brew tower module via a solid state relay bank.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. The coffee brewing module of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the power circuit is configured to provide a voltage level of at least 200 V and a current level of at least 50 A.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. The coffee brewing module of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, further comprising two water supply conduits, with each of the two water supply conduits configured to be coupled to a respective one of the first coffee brew tower module and the second coffee brew tower module.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
