<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225282A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225282</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17575769</doc-number>
<date>20220114</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>17</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>16</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>55</main-group>
<subgroup>105</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>16</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>55</main-group>
<subgroup>11</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>F</section>
<class>16</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>55</main-group>
<subgroup>105</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>F</section>
<class>16</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>55</main-group>
<subgroup>1141</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Short milk tube vent plug for a dairy animal milker unit</invention-title>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>GEA Farm Technologies, Inc.</orgname>
<address>
<city>Romeoville</city>
<state>IL</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hedlund</last-name>
<first-name>Nathan V.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Galesville</city>
<state>WI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An air vent plug assembler and milker unit short milk tube having an air vent plug assembly to improve milk flow characteristics through the short milk tube. The short milk tube includes a wall with an upstream end and a downstream end and defining a milk passage bore extending between the upstream end and the downstream end. The wall defines a vent plug mounting hole. A vent plug extends through the vent plug mounting hole and includes a cap, a shaft joined to the cap, and a barbed end joined to the shaft, the vent plug defining a vent passage to at least partially vent the milk passage bore. A flow dimple is defined in the barbed end and disposed in the milk passage bore.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="93.30mm" wi="145.80mm" file="US20230225282A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="151.55mm" wi="116.67mm" file="US20230225282A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="221.74mm" wi="147.83mm" file="US20230225282A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="224.87mm" wi="85.17mm" file="US20230225282A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="218.95mm" wi="117.69mm" file="US20230225282A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="203.54mm" wi="141.31mm" file="US20230225282A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="217.25mm" wi="146.05mm" file="US20230225282A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="202.95mm" wi="134.87mm" file="US20230225282A1-20230720-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="179.92mm" wi="89.58mm" file="US20230225282A1-20230720-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="221.49mm" wi="97.45mm" file="US20230225282A1-20230720-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="212.43mm" wi="101.60mm" file="US20230225282A1-20230720-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="216.15mm" wi="97.79mm" file="US20230225282A1-20230720-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00012" num="00012">
<img id="EMI-D00012" he="219.79mm" wi="115.15mm" file="US20230225282A1-20230720-D00012.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00013" num="00013">
<img id="EMI-D00013" he="219.79mm" wi="114.55mm" file="US20230225282A1-20230720-D00013.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD AND BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This invention relates generally to milker units for milking dairy animals, and more particularly to a milker unit short milk tube with an improved vent plug to maintain proper vacuum in the short milk tube with reduced interference to milk flow through the short milk tube.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Milker units for milking dairy animals include teat cup assemblies for attaching to a dairy animal's teats. In the case of cows, there are four teat cup assemblies that are each joined to a common milk collection claw and bowl assembly via a short milk tube. Each teat cup assembly includes a shell (teat cup) with a flexible liner. Each teat cup assembly is joined to the milk claw and collection bowl assembly via a short milk tube. These are the basic elements of a milker unit. The milker units are connected to long milk tubes through which milk flows to a central milk collection system for the dairy.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">In the teat cup assembly, the liner fits inside the shell and a vacuum chamber is defined between the shell and the liner. A pulsating vacuum is applied to the vacuum chamber to move the liner in and out of compression (massaging) contact with a dairy animal teat that is in the liner. The pulsating vacuum in the pulsation chamber is opposed by a constant vacuum inside of the liner. The pulsating vacuum is applied through a pulsation connection in the side of the shell and the constant vacuum is applied through a milk hose connected to the liner. The milk hose vacuum also draws milk from the liner into the short milk tube, the milking claw and collection bowl, and through the long milk tube, and into the milk collection system. Vacuum systems have high energy costs and should be maintained and operated to be as efficient as possible.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The shell and liner are fitted together in a coaxial relationship and a mouthpiece of the liner fits over the top of the shell so that the mouthpiece, and not the shell, contacts the animal. The mouthpiece provides a vacuum seal against the teat of the animal being milked. The vacuum seal and the constant vacuum through the liner hold the teat cup assembly on the dairy animal and allow the constant vacuum to draw the milk down. The liner also includes a barrel joined to the mouthpiece and into which the animal's teat extends during milking. The teat is massaged by the liner barrel by the pulsating vacuum. Various barrel designs have been developed to improve cow comfort and milking efficiency, but other factors, such as vacuum levels affect animal comfort and even milking times.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The liner is adequately secured in the shell because the upper mouthpiece of the liner is engaged with an upper end of the shell, and a locking ring of the liner is engaged with a lower end of the shell. In a typical shell and liner assembly, the liner will even be somewhat tensioned in an axial direction because of the opposing engagements at the top and bottom of the shell.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Short milk tubes extending from the bottom of the liner often include vent holes to balance or limit the amount of vacuum applied to the shell liner for cow comfort and to improve milk flow through the short milk tube. Typically, the short milk tube vent hole is drilled or formed in the relatively soft short milk tube material. The softer material bends in use and can be plugged, so a vent plug of a relatively rigid or robust material is inserted in the vent hole to ensure reliable venting. The milking claw also typically has a vent hole, but liner milk tube vents offer the benefit of being closer to the teat end for improved and consistent milk flow, and to provide redundancy in case a vent does become clogged.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In the dairy environment, the plugs are exposed to liner twisting and impact forces that can damage or remove the plug, or tear the liner hole. Obviously, such damage limits the useful life of the short milk tube, which increases capital and maintenance costs.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The vent plug is relatively rigid and includes a vent passage that formed in a predetermined size to ensure adequate and predictable venting. The vent passage should be sized appropriately to avoid excessive vacuum on the animal teat and thereby ensure dairy animal comfort. Nonetheless, too much ventilation can cause foaming of the milk, turbulence in milk flowing through the short milk tube, and breakdown of fat globules in milk. Breaking up fat globules in milk can result in rancidity and reduces milk shelf life.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Importantly, excess venting through the vent passage wastes vacuum that must be generated by the central vacuum pump. Even small increases in vacuum requirements increase energy costs for operating vacuum pumps. Vacuum energy costs are a major cost in a dairy operation. Thus, venting a short milk tube can have benefits in cow comfort, but can also lead to wasted energy for vacuum pumps, cause foaming in the milk, and damage to milk fat.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">As stated, turbulence in milk flowing through a short milk tube (and elsewhere in the milking equipment) should be kept to a minimum to avoid foaming and damage to fat globules in the milk. Excess foaming is unacceptable because it can enter and foul the vacuum system and affect milk pump efficiency downstream in the dairy system.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Foam in milk can also interfere with various types of sensors that monitor milk volume and quality. Effectiveness of sensors such as those using capacitance, induction, and light are all reduced by the presence of foam milk.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Sizing the vent passage is also not necessarily intuitive or easily derived. First, the vent plug must be molded to fairly tight tolerances, and a needle is typically used inside the plastic molding form to create the vent passage. The needle diameter used in some forming operations can be no smaller than about 0.6 mm in diameter to avoid a risk of breaking the form needle. Of course, increasing needle diameter could result in the vent passage being too large and cause excessive vacuum in the short milk tube.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Further, the length of the vent passage can have a dramatic effect on the amount of air that can pass through such a small vent passage. The length relative to the small diameter of the vent passage can restrict air flow if it is too long, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The barbed end of the vent plug causes turbulence, but it is necessary because the vent plugs must be installed through the short milk tube vent hole, and they must remain securely in place without tearing the short milk tube. So, the vent plugs include a barbed end that is pushed through the vent hole causing the short milk tube to stretch out and then engage a vent plug shaft once the barbed end is through the vent hole. Of course, the vent plug is disposed into the milk flow path, so the vent plug actually causes problems, as described above.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Simply reducing the profile of the barbed end in a milk flow path can cause further problems because the length of the vent passage can have a dramatic impact on air flow through the vent passage, as explained above.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Another issue arises when vent plug passages are clogged by dirt and debris in the harsh dairy environment. Clogged plugs can be cleared, but they waste valuable operator time. Liners are replaced on a regular basis, but the vent plug should not be causing premature failure of the liner.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Thus, there is needed a relatively inexpensive short milk tube and vent plug arrangement that provides adequate venting, is robust, resists clogging, and minimizes interference of milk flow.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The present invention is directed to a vent plug that reduces interference with milk flowing through a short milk tube while controlling the balance of vacuum in the short milk tube. The vent plug of the invention includes a barbed end and that minimizes its profile in the milk flow path and reduces turbulence of the milk as it flows over the barbed end. The reduced flow profile and improved flow characteristics of the barbed end reduces milk foaming and damage to the milk fat. The invention also maintains a controlled vent to the short milk tube to balance the need to vent the tube without wasting vacuum pump energy. In addition, milking efficiency can improve by maintaining proper vacuum level close to the animal teat end during milking. Milking efficiency in this context can include shorter milking times without increasing vacuum pump energy requirements.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">A short milk tube in accordance with the present invention includes a short milk tube having a wall with an upstream end and a downstream end to define a milk passage bore extending between the upstream end and the downstream end. The wall also defines a vent plug mounting hole extending into the milk passage bore. A vent plug extends through the vent plug mounting hole, and the vent plug includes a cap, a shaft joined to the cap, a barbed end joined to the shaft, and defines a vent passage to at least partially vent the short milk tube bore. The barbed end defines at least one flow dimple that enables the barbed end to pass through the vent hole in the short milk tube, secure the vent plug in place, and result in improved milk flow past the barbed end.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The short milk tube can also include a vent plug seat lip extending outwardly above the short milk tube barrel wall to a first dimension and is at least partially surrounding the vent plug cap. The cap can include a debris barrier at least partially surrounding the vent passage and extending away from the cap to the first dimension. This arrangement limits collection of the debris between the lip and the cap, and provides a barrier against debris that could otherwise clog the vent passage. The outwardly extending vent cap debris barrier can also define a portion of the vent passage that can be used to improve air flow through the vent passage.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In some embodiments of the present invention, the flow dimple is an oval-shaped recess extending in a radial direction with rounded shoulders. A second flow dimple spaced apart from the flow dimple can also be included. The space in between flow dimples provides a smooth surface that slides on the short milk tube wall as the barbed end is pushed through the vent plug mounting hole during installation.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The shaft of the vent plug preferably includes a fillet adjacent to the cap to reduce wear on the short milk tube as the vent plug is installed and the short milk tube flexes, bends, and bears on the fillet and shaft during use.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The short milk tube wall can also include an interior vent seat in an inner wall surface, and the vent plug barbed end is at least partially disposed in the vent plug recess to further reduce milk flow interference. An exterior vent plug seat can be included, and can be recessed in an outer surface of the wall to at least partially receive the vent plug cap.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Also, in some embodiments, the vent passage includes a first portion with a first flow diameter and a second portion with a second flow diameter. The first portion is adjacent to a cap end and is relatively small to reduce the chance of debris entering the vent passage, while the second flow diameter extending toward the barbed end is relatively large, so that any debris that does enter the vent passage can pass through or at least not completely block the vent passage.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The short milk tube can also include a lip joined to and extending away from the wall, and at least partially surrounding the vent plug mounting hole, and with a lip overlay portion joined to the lip and extending at least partially over the vent cap. The cap can also define a debris dome extending outwardly from the cap to an extent that matches the outward extent of the lip, so that any debris that collects within the lip will not be as likely to plug the vent passage in the vent plug.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The invention is also directed to a vent plug, which can be used with a number of different short milk tube designs. In this embodiment, the invention is directed to a vent plug for a short milk tube wall having an upstream end and a downstream end, and the wall defines a vent plug mounting hole into the milk passage bore, and the vent plug includes: a cap, a shaft joined to the cap, and a barbed end joined to the shaft, and defines a vent passage to at least partially vent the milk passage bore and the barbed end defines a flow dimple at least partially disposed in the milk passage bore.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The vent plug can include a debris dome extending away from the shaft and through which the vent passage extends. The debris dome reduces the chance that debris can enter the vent passage.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Also, the flow dimple can be at least partially defined by rounded shoulders. Additional flow dimples can be included, and the barbed end can include a portion for being disposed in an inner vent plug seat in a short milk tube.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The short milk tube shaft can also include a fillet adjacent to the cap to better mate with the short milk tube vent hole and reduce stress concentrations that can damage the short milk tube wall.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The vent plug vent passage can include a first portion with a first flow diameter and a section portion with a second flow diameter and the first diameter is preferably smaller and that the second diameter to assist in keeping the vent passage open if debris enters the vent plug passage.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Further, features and advantages of the invention are described below and depicted herein.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a perspective view of a milker unit with a vent plug arrangement in accordance with the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a perspective view of a teat cup assembly shell liner having a vent plug arrangement in accordance with the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a side cross-sectional view of the shell liner with the vent plug arrangement of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is a cross-sectional view of a short milk tube with an air vent plug mounting hole;</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is a cross-sectional view of a short milk tube with an air vent plug mounting hole with a lip and vent stiffener;</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is a perspective view of an exterior vent plug seat for receiving the vent plug of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> is a front view of the exterior vent plug seat of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> is a front view of a vent plug arrangement in accordance with the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref> is an upper perspective view of an interior vent plug seat in accordance with the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref> is a front view of the interior vent plug seat of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b></figref> is a cross-sectional side view of the short milk tube with the vent plug arrangement;</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>12</b></figref> is a cross-sectional side view of the short milk tube and vent plug;</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>13</b></figref> is a cross-sectional end view of the liner with short milk tube vent plug arrangement;</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>14</b></figref> is a cross-sectional view of the liner and vent plug arrangement of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>13</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>15</b></figref> is an upper perspective view of a vent plug in accordance with the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>16</b></figref> is a lower perspective view of the vent plug of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>15</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>17</b></figref> is a side view of the vent plug of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>15</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>18</b></figref> is a top view of the vent plug of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>15</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>19</b></figref> is a bottom view of the vent plug of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>15</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>20</b></figref> is a side cross-sectional view of the short milk tube with an air vent plug and milk flow lines;</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>21</b></figref> is a side cross-sectional view of a prior art short milk tube vent plug and illustrating milk flow lines;</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">In the following detailed description of the drawings, the same reference numeral will be used to identify the same or similar elements in each of the figures.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">For context, illustrated generally in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a traditional milker unit <b>30</b> having (from upstream to downstream) a shell <b>32</b>, a teat cup liner <b>34</b> disposed in the shell <b>32</b>, a short milk tube <b>38</b> joined to or formed integrally with the teat cup liner <b>34</b>, a milking claw <b>42</b>, and a milk bowl <b>44</b> at its downstream end <b>118</b>. There is one shell <b>32</b>, liner <b>34</b>, and short milk tube <b>38</b> (teat cup assembly <b>36</b>) for each teat of the dairy animal. The milking claw <b>42</b> and milk bowl <b>44</b> collect milk from all of the short milk tubes <b>38</b>. The objective of the milker unit <b>30</b> is to draw milk away from the dairy animal teats, out of a milk bowl outlet <b>45</b>, and into the central dairy milk lines (not illustrated), reduce the amount of milk flowing back toward the teat, and reduce the amount of air drawn into the central dairy milk line when vacuum is being applied through the milker unit <b>30</b>. All of these objectives must be done while ensuring dairy animal comfort. Once the milk reaches the central dairy lines, it is pumped through a chiller and into a storage tank. (Not illustrated.)</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">During milking, a dairy animal teat is inserted through an upper teat opening <b>96</b> of the teat cup liner <b>34</b>. Just before and during milking, a constant vacuum is applied inside the milker unit <b>30</b> to attach the liner <b>34</b> and shell <b>32</b> to the teat and then draw milk through the liner <b>34</b>, the short milk tube <b>38</b>, the milking claw <b>42</b> and the bowl <b>44</b>, and out of the milk bowl outlet <b>45</b>. The weight of the milker unit <b>30</b> is supported by the teats because of the constant vacuum being applied inside the milker unit <b>30</b>. Nonetheless, excessive vacuum in the milker unit <b>30</b> could cause dairy animal discomfort and even damage animal teats.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The shell <b>32</b> (sometimes referred to in the art as a &#x201c;teat cup&#x201d;) is a relatively rigid cup typically made of stainless steel or other suitable material. The teat cup liner <b>34</b> is disposed inside the shell <b>32</b>, and a pulsation chamber is defined in the space between the shell <b>32</b> and the liner <b>34</b>. A distribution manifold for vacuum is mounted on the milking claw <b>42</b> connects a vacuum supply from a long pulsation hose to the short pulsation hoses <b>50</b> connected to each teat shell (cup) <b>32</b>. The pulsation acting on the pulsation chamber moves the liner <b>34</b> in and out of contact with the animal teat to milk the animal. A hanger <b>60</b> is also provided on the milking claw <b>42</b> to support the milker unit <b>30</b> from a milker unit detacher mechanism (not illustrated) when not milking.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a perspective view of a shell liner <b>34</b> (sometimes referred to herein as simply a &#x201c;liner&#x201d;). The shell liner <b>34</b> includes a mouthpiece <b>74</b> defining a teat opening <b>96</b>, (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>) a liner barrel <b>80</b> joined to the mouthpiece <b>74</b> and extending downwardly as depicted, an upper locking ring <b>84</b>, and a lower locking ring <b>88</b> spaced apart from the upper locking ring <b>84</b> to define a shell-engaging annular recess <b>86</b> and a lower locking ring <b>88</b>. The upper locking ring <b>84</b> defines a number of alignment recesses <b>90</b>, as seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">The liner <b>34</b> can also include an integral short milk tube <b>38</b> joined to the barrel <b>80</b> and having a teat claw connecting end <b>70</b>. The short milk tube <b>38</b> is an optional extension of the liner <b>34</b>, and in other embodiments, the short milk tube <b>38</b> can be a separate item that extends between the liner <b>34</b> to the milk collecting bowl <b>44</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">As depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> and <b>2</b></figref> for example, the liner <b>34</b> mouthpiece <b>74</b> can be of a type and shape described and depicted in U.S. Pat. No. 8,113,145, which is incorporated herein by reference, but other mouthpiece shapes and sizes can be used with the present invention. As depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> and <b>2</b></figref>, the mouthpiece <b>74</b> generally includes an upper surface <b>94</b> that interfaces with a teat and udder of a dairy animal to form a comfortable seal that minimizes loss of vacuum from the inside of the liner <b>34</b> through the teat opening <b>96</b>, so that the liner <b>34</b> and other components do not prematurely detach during milking.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">The mouthpiece <b>74</b> further includes a downwardly extending skirt <b>98</b> that extends downward and is spaced apart from the liner barrel <b>80</b> so that an upper end of the shell <b>32</b> (described below) can fit between the liner barrel <b>80</b> and the mouthpiece skirt <b>98</b>, (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>) when assembled. The mouthpiece skirt <b>98</b> can also include an alignment mark to aid in assembly.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">Preferably, and as illustrated, the teat claw connecting end <b>70</b> includes an end connector <b>72</b> of the type described and depicted in U.S. patent application Ser. No. 16/946,646, which is incorporated herein by reference, but other types of short milk tube connector ends can be used with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">The liner barrel <b>80</b> defines a longitudinal axis <b>82</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b> and <b>3</b></figref>) and the liner barrel <b>80</b>, itself, can have any desired cross-sectional shape including, round, oval, triangular, square, and the shape illustrated in the figures, for example. Typically, the liner barrel <b>80</b> shape is selected to optimize animal comfort and milking efficiency. The liner barrel <b>80</b> (the portion inside the shell <b>32</b>) illustrated herein can have walls and corners (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, for example) that can be of uniform thickness or have varied thicknesses to control collapse of the barrel wall during pulsation and milking for dairy animal comfort or for simplifying manufacturing. Any desired barrel cross-sectional shape can be used with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">The liner barrel <b>80</b>, and particularly the upper locking ring <b>84</b> of the liner <b>34</b>, preferably defines two pairs of alignment recesses <b>90</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>) to be engaged by the shell keys (not illustrated) formed in the shell <b>32</b>. Although it is preferred to include the upper locking ring <b>84</b>, it is not necessary, and the alignment recesses <b>90</b> can be formed in any part of the liner barrel <b>80</b>, but preferably in the lower end of the liner barrel <b>80</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">Once the liner <b>34</b> is installed, it is preferably tensioned somewhat along the longitudinal axis <b>82</b>, due to the relative size of the shell <b>32</b> and the liner barrel <b>80</b>. This is sometimes referred to as &#x201c;pretensioning&#x201d; and it improves liner performance. A second alignment feature can be formed in the lower locking ring <b>88</b> or elsewhere to avoid twisting the liner barrel <b>80</b> during installation.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">As seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>5</b> through <b>18</b></figref>, for example, the short milk tube <b>38</b> of the present invention includes a short milk tube wall <b>106</b>, having an exterior surface <b>108</b>, an interior surface <b>110</b>, and a milk passage bore <b>112</b> between an upstream end <b>116</b> of the short milk tube <b>106</b>, and a downstream end <b>118</b> of the milk tube <b>106</b>. As stated above, the short milk tube <b>38</b> is vented closely to the teat end to maintain a near constant vacuum close to the teat end for efficient milking. The degree to which the short milk tube <b>38</b> is vented preferably achieves a constant vacuum for animal comfort and steady milk flow through the short milk tube <b>34</b>, and avoids excess ventilation that wastes vacuum pump energy and efficiency.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">The air vent plug mounting hole <b>120</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b> and <b>5</b></figref>) extends through a short milk tube wall <b>106</b> to control and limit the amount of vacuum applied to the portion of the liner <b>34</b> inside the shell <b>32</b> (the barrel <b>80</b>), and the animal teat, and to improve milk flow through the short milk tube <b>38</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>3</b> and <b>4</b></figref> illustrate examples of the short milk tube <b>38</b> with an air vent plug assembly <b>138</b> in which the air vent plug mounting hole <b>120</b> is surrounded, at least partially, by an air vent plug seat <b>122</b> in accordance with the present invention. The air vent plug seat <b>122</b> preferably includes an exterior vent plug seat <b>124</b>, an interior vent plug seat <b>126</b>, and a lip <b>128</b> extending outwardly a distance &#x201c;d&#x201d; (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b> and <b>5</b></figref>) from the short milk tube <b>38</b>. The lip <b>128</b> can also include a lip overlay <b>130</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>11</b> and <b>12</b></figref>), and a stiffener <b>132</b> to control localized bending in the short milk tube <b>38</b> and distortion of the vent plug seat <b>122</b>. The use of a lip overlay <b>128</b> can be beneficial in maintaining the vent plug <b>140</b> in position. Nonetheless, the type of material used to mold the short milk tube <b>38</b> can determine whether such a lip overlay <b>128</b> can be formed easily. For example, in silicone liners, a lip overlay can be formed, but when the block rubber is used, a lip overlay is not used.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">In preferred embodiments, the lip <b>128</b> and stiffeners <b>132</b> include drain gaps <b>136</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b> and <b>7</b></figref>, for example) for draining fluids and solid debris that might otherwise accumulate in the space inside the lip <b>128</b> and around an air vent plug <b>140</b>. The air vent plug assembly <b>138</b> includes at least the vent plug seat <b>122</b>, the air vent plug mounting hole <b>120</b>, and the air vent plug <b>140</b>, as seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>11</b> and <b>12</b></figref>, where no stiffener is present.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">In the present invention, the air vent plug mounting hole <b>120</b> is preferably formed simultaneously with the formation of the short milk tube <b>38</b> in a tapered shape, as seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b> and <b>5</b></figref> for example, or drilled after forming. A tapered or rounded portion <b>129</b> can be included to facilitate molding and assembly. The air vent plug mounting hole <b>120</b> is preferably located at an area of increased short milk tube wall thickness <b>154</b>. (See <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>12</b></figref>, for example) Other methods for forming the air vent plug mounting hole are also possible.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">As seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>11</b>, <b>12</b>, <b>13</b>, <b>14</b>, <b>20</b>, and <b>21</b></figref>, the air vent plug mounting hole <b>120</b> is preferable mated with the air vent plug <b>140</b> in size to enable the vent plug <b>140</b> to be inserted without tearing the wall <b>106</b>, and still provides a substantially fluid tight seal against the air vent plug <b>140</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">The air vent plug <b>140</b> includes a cap <b>144</b>, a shaft <b>146</b>, and a barbed end <b>148</b> through which a defined vent passage <b>150</b> is formed. The air vent plug <b>140</b> is used to ensure that the vent passage <b>150</b> remains open and is of a predetermined size. The air vent plug <b>140</b> is made of a relatively rigid or robust material (such as Grilamid TR90, for example), as compared to the more flexible material used for the short milk tube <b>38</b>, to ensure that the vent passage <b>150</b> remains open and is a consistent vent opening size. Preferably, the vent plug shaft <b>146</b> is sized to substantially match the thickness of the short milk tube wall <b>106</b>, or is slightly shorter than the wall <b>106</b> thickness to ensure a snug fit. Additionally, to reduce stress concentrations on the short milk tube wall <b>106</b> at the air vent plug mounting hole <b>120</b>, a cap fillet <b>152</b>, and a barbed end fillet <b>155</b> are formed in the shaft <b>146</b>, as illustrated.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">The air vent plug cap <b>144</b>, as illustrated, includes a notch <b>145</b> that results from the forming process, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>17</b> to <b>19</b></figref>, but the notch <b>145</b> is not necessary for the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">To further ensure a good mating surface between the short milk tube <b>38</b> and the air vent plug <b>140</b>, the air plug vent seat <b>122</b> preferably includes the exterior vent plug seat <b>124</b> shaped and sized to mate with the underside of the vent plug cap <b>144</b>. For example, the exterior vent plug seat <b>124</b> can be a recess with a flat bottom to match the underside of the vent plug cap <b>144</b>, (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b></figref>, for example) as opposed to an arcuate surface of the short milk tube wall <b>106</b> mating with a flat plug surface on the underside of the vent plug cap <b>144</b>, or any other desired part of the air vent plug <b>140</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">Also preferably, and as seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>11</b> and <b>12</b></figref>, the interior vent plug seat <b>126</b> is shaped and sized to mate with the barbed end <b>148</b> on the air vent plug <b>140</b>, and to provide a reliable bearing surface on which the barbed end <b>148</b> can bear and provide reliable connection with the air vent plug <b>140</b>. Preferably, the interior vent plug seat <b>126</b> is also flat (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>11</b> and <b>12</b></figref>) to mate with the barbed end <b>148</b>, and as seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>9</b> and <b>10</b></figref>, it can include an upstream recessed flow transition channel <b>156</b> upstream from the air vent plug <b>140</b> or a downstream recessed flow transition channel <b>158</b> or both to form a smoother flow transition toward and away from the barbed end <b>148</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">The portion of the short milk tube wall <b>106</b> in which the air vent plug seat <b>122</b> is formed can be thicker <b>154</b> than other portions of the short milk tube wall <b>106</b> for strength and to provide material in which to form the upstream recessed flow transition channel <b>156</b> and the downstream recessed flow transition channel <b>158</b>, and to reduce bending in the area of the air vent plug assembly <b>138</b>. (See <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>12</b>, <b>20</b>, and <b>21</b></figref>, for example.) A thicker short milk tube wall <b>106</b> can also resist tearing of the material when the barbed end <b>148</b> is pushed through the air vent plug mounting hole <b>120</b> during installation. The air vent plug <b>140</b> is typically not removed once it is installed.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">As seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>11</b>, <b>12</b>, <b>20</b>, and <b>21</b></figref>, the vent plug barbed end <b>148</b> extends into the short milk tube <b>38</b> milk passage bore <b>112</b>. Any obstacle in the milk passage bore <b>112</b> can interfere with milk flow by slowing the flow, causing turbulence, and creating a surface for milk residue and backwashing fluids to collect. Nonetheless, the barbed end <b>148</b> is necessary to secure the air vent plug <b>140</b> to the short milk tube barrel wall <b>106</b>. Without it, the air vent plug <b>140</b> can be dislodged and the vent plug mounting hole <b>120</b> may not be sufficient by itself to maintain proper vacuum levels in the short milk tube <b>38</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">To reduce interference of the milk flow, the present invention includes a barbed end <b>148</b> with at least one, but preferably, a number of flow dimples <b>160</b> formed in a surface over which milk flows. (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>15</b> to <b>19</b></figref>.) The flow dimples <b>160</b> reduce the contact surface that milk is exposed to as it flows by, and therefore, improves milk flow and also reduces turbulence in the milk, as depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>20</b></figref>. The flow dimples <b>160</b> are formed on the barbed end <b>148</b> at a position to be exposed to milk flow through the milk passage bore <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">In the illustrated embodiment, the flow dimples <b>160</b> are spaced-apart, and are oval-shaped with rounded shoulders <b>162</b> with sliding surfaces <b>164</b> in between the flow dimples <b>160</b>. The flow dimples <b>160</b> are preferably uniformly spaced apart, but the number, shape, and spacing of the flow dimples <b>160</b> can be modified and still be within the scope of the present invention. The flow dimples <b>160</b> preferably extend along the barbed end <b>148</b> between the vent passage <b>150</b> and an angular surface <b>166</b> that serves as a transition region between the flow dimples <b>160</b> and a recess ring <b>170</b> that is preferably disposed in a recessed interior vent plug seat <b>126</b> of the short milk tube wall <b>106</b>. The recess ring <b>170</b> can fit snuggly in the recessed interior vent plug seat <b>126</b> or, preferably, there is space around the recess ring <b>170</b> so that the rinsing fluids could reach the recess ring <b>170</b> for improved sanitation. This shape helps prevent milk collecting in the interior vent plug seat <b>126</b> and next to the air vent plug <b>140</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">In addition, the barbed end <b>148</b> must be shaped to be pressed through the air vent plug mounting hole <b>120</b> without tearing the short milk tube <b>106</b>. Thus, the barbed end <b>148</b> must not stretch the short milk tube hole <b>120</b> beyond a yield point for the material, but it must be large enough to hold the air vent plug <b>140</b> in place. The sliding surfaces <b>164</b> between the flow dimples <b>160</b> assist in this process by providing a uniform and smooth surface to stretch the air vent plug mounting hole <b>120</b> without stress concentrations or high friction. Further, the barbed end <b>148</b> is preferably shaped to provide a low profile and not extend into the short milk tube wall <b>106</b> and interfere with milk flow. Thus, the shape for insertion and the holding force necessary to maintain the air vent plug <b>140</b> in place, is as illustrated.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">The flow dimples <b>160</b> are enough by themselves to improve flow characteristics for milk flowing past the barbed end <b>148</b>. Nonetheless, the rounded shoulders <b>162</b>, the angular surface <b>166</b>, the use of a recess ring <b>170</b> disposed in the interior vent plug seat <b>126</b>, and the transition channels <b>156</b> and <b>158</b>, each and in combination with each other, and the flow dimples <b>160</b> improve milk flow characteristics through the short milk tube <b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">To further enhance flow characteristics, the barbed end can be formed in a lower profile shape, but this translates into a reduced vent passage length which can affect the degree to which the short milk tube <b>34</b> is vented.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>20</b> and <b>21</b></figref> illustrate the differences in milk flow between the prior art (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>21</b></figref>) and the present invention (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>20</b></figref>). In the prior art, an air vent plug <b>200</b> is disposed in a short milk tube wall <b>202</b>. The barbed end <b>210</b> extends into a milk flow path <b>214</b> a distance D<b>1</b>, disrupts the flow, as seen in the flow lines <b>216</b>, and causes turbulence <b>220</b> in a thick wake <b>222</b> downstream from the barbed end <b>210</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">The present invention (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>20</b></figref>), has the barbed end <b>148</b> described above, which extends only a distance D<b>2</b> into the milk flow path to create flow path <b>228</b>. The flow dimples <b>160</b> create a turbulence boundary layer <b>230</b> over the barbed end <b>148</b>, and only a thin wake <b>234</b> with reduced turbulence <b>236</b> is created. This results in increased laminar flow, and promotion of higher flow rates and higher quality milk, as explained above.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>12</b> and <b>14</b></figref>, the air vent passage <b>150</b> preferably includes a first portion <b>151</b> adjacent to the cap <b>144</b> and a second portion <b>153</b> adjacent to the barbed end <b>148</b>. A tapered transition portion <b>157</b> is preferably used to ease the flow transition between the first portion <b>151</b> and the second portion <b>153</b>. Preferably, the transition portion <b>157</b> is tapered at about 60&#xb0;, but other angles are possible. In the illustrated embodiment, the first portion <b>151</b> has a relatively small diameter and the second portion has a relatively large diameter, but it is possible to reverse this arrangement or to have both portions the same diameter.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">Air flow amounts and rates are dependent on the length and diameter of the air vent passage <b>150</b>, and in particular, the first portion <b>151</b>. For example, a preferred air vent passage <b>150</b> is about 9.6 mm long from the top of the cap <b>144</b> to the bottom of the barbed end <b>148</b>. The primary air flow controlling portion is the first portion <b>151</b>, and it is preferably about 0.6 mm in diameter and between about 0.99 mm and about 2.5 mm long, and more preferably between about 1.6 mm and about 2.5 mm long. The second portion <b>153</b> is preferably about 0.9 mm in diameter and accounts for the remaining length of the air vent passage <b>150</b> length. Further, the second portion <b>153</b> is preferably tapered outward slightly as it extends through the barbed end <b>148</b> to facilitate molding and the other air flow and anti-clog features described herein. In one embodiment, the taper is about 0.9 mm to about 1.00 mm at the open end.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">The term &#x201c;about&#x201d; is used herein to allow for variances in molding operations and material properties. For example, a diameter of 0.60 mm could vary by plus or minus 0.1 mm.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">The first portion <b>151</b> can limit the size and amount of debris that can enter the air vent passage <b>150</b>, and the second portion <b>153</b> can provide an ample air passage even when some debris enters the second portion <b>153</b>. Further, the small debris entering the first portion <b>151</b> will more easily pass through the larger second portion <b>153</b>, so that it is less likely the air vent passage <b>150</b> will be clogged.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">As stated above, the exterior vent seat <b>124</b> can also include a lip <b>128</b> that extends outwardly a distance d (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>11</b> and <b>12</b></figref>) from the short milk tube barrel wall <b>106</b>. Preferably, the lip <b>128</b> is spaced slightly apart from the vent plug mounting hole <b>120</b>, so that the cap <b>144</b> of the air vent plug <b>140</b> is in contact with the lip <b>128</b> when the air vent plug <b>140</b> is inserted in the vent plug mounting hole <b>120</b>. The lip <b>128</b> protects the air vent plug <b>140</b> from impact forces and helps retain the air vent plug <b>140</b> if the short milk tube is twisted.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">Preferably, the lip <b>128</b> can also include an overlay portion <b>130</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>11</b> and <b>12</b></figref>) that extends over the cap <b>144</b> and enhances protection and retention of the air vent plug <b>140</b>. An adverse effect of this arrangement is that dirt and debris that can lodge around the air vent plug <b>140</b>. The cross section of the lip <b>128</b> and lip overlay portion <b>130</b> preferably matches the shape of the air vent plug <b>140</b>, as seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>11</b> and <b>12</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">A debris dome <b>174</b> is preferably added to the cap <b>144</b> to extend outwardly from the cap <b>144</b> so that the total dimension of the cap <b>144</b> and debris dome <b>174</b> is substantially the same as the distance d, which is the distance the lip <b>128</b> extends from the short milk tube wall <b>106</b>. The debris dome <b>174</b> therefore minimizes the chance for dirt and debris to lodge around the vent plug mounting hole <b>120</b> and air vent plug <b>140</b>. The debris dome <b>174</b> can extend outwardly more or less than the distance d and still serve this function.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">As seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b> and <b>7</b></figref>, the illustrated air vent seat <b>122</b> includes an optional stiffener <b>132</b> extending away from the air vent seat <b>122</b> to at least partially control the degree and direction of localized flexing of the short milk tube wall <b>106</b> during installation and use. Preferably, the stiffener <b>132</b> extends away from the air vent seat <b>122</b> in at least one direction. The stiffener <b>132</b>, as illustrated, extends away in a lateral direction at a greater amount than in a longitudinal direction to provide some flexibility of the lip <b>128</b> in a longitudinal direction while resisting more lateral flexing. Resisting lateral flexing improves protection for the air vent plug seat <b>122</b> and air vent plug <b>140</b>. A greater degree of flexing in the longitudinal direction permits greater longitudinal flexing of the short milk tube <b>38</b> during use and installation and to allow dirt and debris to drain from inside around the air vent plug mounting hole <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">The debris dome <b>174</b> also proved an extension to the vent passage <b>150</b> that can offset the loss of the vet passage length that results when the barned end <b>148</b> is used with a reduced profile (shorter) in the milk flow path.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">The stiffener <b>132</b> can extend above the surface of the short milk tube <b>38</b>, either on an internal surface or an external surface, as illustrated. The stiffener <b>132</b> can also be flush with the surface of the short milk tube <b>38</b> and be made of different and more rigid material than is used in the short milk tube <b>38</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">The stiffener <b>132</b> can be any desired shape to compliment the shape of the vent or the vent plug or accommodate forces that are expected to act on the short milk tube <b>38</b> and control bending as desired. There may even be multiple parts or rows of lips or there may be lips of different heights to protect the vent plug mounting hole <b>120</b> and air vent plug <b>140</b> from impact from different directions. The stiffener <b>132</b> can even aid in resisting twisting of the short milk tube <b>38</b> around the longitudinal axis <b>82</b> of the short milk tube <b>38</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">Although depicted as being positioned close to the vent, the lip <b>128</b> can be spaced apart from the air vent plug mounting hole <b>120</b> to allow an operator to grab the vent plug cap <b>144</b> for removal, if necessary.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">Preferably, the liner <b>34</b> is made of silicone, and the air vent plug <b>140</b> is made of Grilamid TR90, but any other suitable liner material, and preferably approved by the Food and Drug Administration, can be used.</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">The foregoing detailed description of the drawings is provided for a better understanding of the present invention. Nothing therein is intended to unduly limit the scope of the following claims and no unnecessary limitations should be read into the following claims.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A short milk tube comprising:
<claim-text>a wall with an upstream end and a downstream end and defining a milk passage bore extending between the upstream end and the downstream end, and the wall defines a vent plug mounting hole;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a vent plug extending through the vent plug mounting hole and including a cap, a shaft joined to the cap, and a barbed end joined to the shaft, and defining a vent passage to at least partially vent the milk passage bore; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a flow dimple defined in the barbed end and disposed in the milk passage bore.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The short milk tube of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the flow dimple is an oval-shaped recess with rounded shoulders.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The short milk tube of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the barbed end further defines a second flow dimple spaced apart from the flow dimple and disposed in the milk passage bore.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The short milk tube of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the barbed end further defines a plurality of additional flow dimples disposed in the milk passage bore.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The short milk tube of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the shaft includes a fillet adjacent to the cap.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The short milk tube of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the vent passage includes a first portion with a first vent diameter and a second portion with a second vent diameter.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The short milk tube of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the vent passage includes a first portion with a first vent diameter adjacent to a cap end, and a second portion with a second vent diameter adjacent to a barbed end, and the second vent diameter is larger than the first vent diameter.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The short milk tube of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, and further comprising:
<claim-text>a vent plug seat lip extending outwardly above the wall to a first dimension and at least partially engaged with the vent plug cap.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The short milk tube of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, and further comprising:
<claim-text>a vent plug seat lip extending outwardly above the wall to a first dimension and at least partially engaged with the vent plug cap, and wherein the cap includes a debris</claim-text>
<claim-text>barrier at least partially surrounding the vent passage and extending away from the cap to the first dimension.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The short milk tube of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, and wherein the wall further defines:
<claim-text>an interior vent plug recess defined in an inner wall surface, and the vent plug barbed end is at least partially disposed in the interior vent plug recess.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The short milk tube of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the wall defines an exterior vent seat in which the cap is at least partially disposed, and an interior vent seat in which the barbed end is at least partially disposed.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The short milk tube of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the wall defines an exterior vent seat in which the cap is at least partially disposed, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an interior vent seat in which the barbed end is at least partially disposed, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the interior vent seat defines an upstream flow channel.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. The short milk tube of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the wall defines an inner wall surface defining:
<claim-text>an upstream transition channel; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an interior vent plug seat downstream from the upstream transition channel.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The short milk tube of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the wall defines an inner wall surface defining:
<claim-text>a downstream transition channel; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an interior vent plug seat upstream from the downstream transition channel.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. The short milk tube of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the wall defines an inner wall surface defining:
<claim-text>an upstream transition channel;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a downstream transition channel; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an interior vent plug seat disposed between the upstream transition channel and the downstream transition channel.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. A vent plug for a short milk tube barrel having a wall with an upstream end and a downstream end and defining a milk passage bore, and the wall defines a vent plug mounting hole into the milk passage bore, the vent plug comprising:
<claim-text>a cap, a shaft joined to the cap, and a barbed end joined to the shaft, and defining a vent passage to at least partially vent the milk passage bore and a flow dimple defined by the barbed end and disposed to be positioned in the milk passage bore.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. The vent plug of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the vent plug cap includes a debris dome extending away from the shaft and through which the vent passage extends.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. The vent plug of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the flow dimple is at least partially defined by rounded shoulders.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. The vent plug of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the barbed end further defines a second flow dimple spaced apart from the flow dimple and disposed to be positioned in a milk passage bore.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. The vent plug of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the barbed end further defines a plurality of additional flow dimples spaced apart from one another.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text><b>21</b>. The vent plug of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the shaft includes a fillet adjacent to the cap.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text><b>22</b>. The vent plug of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the vent passage includes a first portion with a first flow diameter and a section portion with a second flow diameter.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text><b>23</b>. The vent plug <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the vent passage includes a first portion with a first flow diameter adjacent to a cap end, and a second portion with a second flow diameter adjacent to a barbed end.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
