<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225529A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225529</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17578711</doc-number>
<date>20220119</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>17</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>9</main-group>
<subgroup>10</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>9</main-group>
<subgroup>1081</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>2009</main-group>
<subgroup>1018</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Pillow with Rod-Shaped Insert</invention-title>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lee</last-name>
<first-name>Ryan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Fort Lee</city>
<state>NJ</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lee</last-name>
<first-name>Ryan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Fort Lee</city>
<state>NJ</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A pillow with a removable rod-shaped insert is described herein. The rod-shaped insert is removably insertable into a cavity and/or trough within the pillow. Both the rod-shaped insert and the cavity and/or trough are substantially semi-circular at each vertically oriented cross-section thereof. The cavity includes an opening in a side of the pillow opposite a side thereof which is in contact with a user's head and/or body. The rod-shaped insert has a plurality of parallel ridges on at least one outer surface thereof and extends between both lateral sides of the pillow.</p>
<p id="p-0002" num="0000">In some configurations, the rod-shaped insert is a single substantially planar structure which is folded into a substantially semi-circular shape. In some configurations, the rod-shaped insert has an internal removably-insertable structure.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="107.70mm" wi="158.75mm" file="US20230225529A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="236.56mm" wi="184.07mm" file="US20230225529A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="234.19mm" wi="175.85mm" file="US20230225529A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="229.45mm" wi="190.16mm" file="US20230225529A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="234.78mm" wi="175.09mm" file="US20230225529A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="222.33mm" wi="155.53mm" file="US20230225529A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="192.53mm" wi="186.52mm" file="US20230225529A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="194.06mm" wi="174.50mm" file="US20230225529A1-20230720-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE DISCLOSED TECHNOLOGY</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0001">The disclosed technology relates to pillows, and more specifically to pillows with inserts for correcting pain.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0002">Neck pain plagues a significant amount of people. One common method of treating this pain is through use of a specialized pillow, such as one which provides a higher level of firmness or contains massaging ridges. Unfortunately, these pillows may be expensive, and one may be required to purchase multiple pillows to accommodate variations within one's own sleeping pattern.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0003">Thus, there is a need for a single pillow capable of being adapted for varying pain treatment needs. This and other problems are solved by embodiments of the disclosed technology, as described below.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE DISCLOSED TECHNOLOGY</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0004">A therapeutic pillow of embodiments of the disclosed technology includes a pillow with a trough therein, and a removably insertable insert. The trough extends linearly across a longest horizontal extent of a bottom side of the pillow. The insert has a rounded surface corresponding to a shape of the trough, and is removably insertable into the trough. An area circumscribed by the trough and by an opening thereof is substantially in a shape of a semi-circular prism. A distance between a deepest point of the trough and the bottom side is substantially less than half of a distance between, and substantially more than a third of a distance between, a top side of the pillow and the bottom side thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0005">In some embodiments, the pillow is in a shape of a rounded rectangular prism. Its top and bottom sides may be opposite each other, and may be largest sides of the rounded rectangular prism. A majority of bottom top side, in embodiments, extends on a first side of the trough, while a minority thereof extends on a second side of the trough.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0006">In various embodiments, when the insert is removably inserted within the trough, a top-most portion of thereof is substantially flush with the deepest point of the trough and a bottom-most portion thereof is substantially parallel with the top side of the pillow.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0007">In various embodiments of the disclosed technology, substantially every vertical cross-section of the insert is in a shape of a semicircle. Each semi-circular shape may include two extended legs with a curved portion there-between. Every said vertical cross-section of the insert, in embodiments, is in a plane substantially perpendicular to a plane of the top and/or bottom side and/or each of longer lateral sides of the pillow, and substantially parallel to a plane of each of shorter lateral sides of the pillow.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0008">A height of the trough may be substantially equal to a height of the insert. Furthermore, a shape of the trough may substantially correspond to a shape of the insert, allowing the insert to be insertable within said trough such that substantially every part thereof is surrounded by the trough and/or the opening thereof within a plane of the bottom side of the pillow.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0009">The &#x201c;height&#x201d; of the trough is defined as a distance, in a plane parallel to the left and right sides of the pillow, between a point of the trough closest to the top side of the pillow and a central point of an opening of the trough within the bottom side of the pillow. The &#x201c;height&#x201d; of the insert is defined as a distance, in a plane parallel to the left and right sides of the pillow when the insert is inserted within the trough, between a point of the insert closest to a point of the trough closest to the top side of the pillow and a point substantially between a most-extended point of each extended leg.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0010">In some embodiments, a most-extended point of each extended leg of the insert contacts a surface opposite a user's head at at least one point thereof while the user's head rests on the therapeutic pillow. In further embodiments, a most-extended point of each extended leg of the insert is configured to contact a surface opposite a user's neck at at least one point thereof while the user's head rests on the therapeutic pillow.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0011">The insert may be made of and/or include foam, and may be textured such that the insert remains stationary relative to the therapeutic pillow while unequal pressure is applied to each of the extended legs resulting from friction between the textured surface of the insert and the surface of the trough.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0012">In embodiments of the disclosed technology, a face of the pillow which includes the trough is substantially smooth but for the trough. In other embodiments, a face of the pillow containing the trough is substantially smooth but for the trough and for indicia on the pillow.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0013">In some embodiments, the above-described therapeutic pillow further includes a pillowcase with a trough and a zipper. The pillowcase trough may substantially correspond in size and shape to the trough of the pillow. A distance between the zipper and a face of the pillowcase which includes the trough is, in some embodiments, greater than a distance between the zipper and a face of the pillowcase opposite the face containing the trough.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0014">A radius of curvature of edges of the top side may be smaller than a radius of curvature of edges of the bottom side.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0015">The insert, in various embodiments, is configured to contact a surface opposite a user's head at at least one point thereof while the user's head rests on the therapeutic pillow.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0016">Described differently, a therapeutic pillow kit includes a pillow, a pillowcase, and a plurality of inserts. The pillow contains a linear hollow in a shape of a prism. The pillowcase has a sleeve in a location thereon corresponding to a location of the linear hollow. The inserts have shapes partially or wholly corresponding to the shape of the linear hollow. The sleeve is configured to accommodate each of the inserts, and each insert is removably insertable into each of the linear hollow and the sleeve.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0017">Each insert, in some embodiments, is in a shape of a ridged and/or smooth triangular and/or semi-circular prism. In other embodiments, each insert is in a shape of a rectangular prism with substantially identical folds at each vertical cross section thereof. &#x201c;Vertical&#x201d; is defined as a plane substantially parallel to both the right side and the left side of the pillow when the insert is removably inserted within the trough. Furthermore, each insert may have a hollow portion at each vertical cross section thereof. In various embodiments, each insert includes an internal linear hollow in a shape of a prism, and an internal insert removably insertable therein. The internal insert may be made of a same and/or a different material as the insert, and a same internal insert may be usable for multiple inserts.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0018">Any device or step to a method described in this disclosure can comprise or consist of that which it is a part of, or the parts which make up the device or step. The term &#x201c;and/or&#x201d; is inclusive of the items which it joins linguistically and each item by itself.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0021" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> shows a top and left perspective view of a therapeutic pillow and insert of embodiments of the disclosed technology.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> shows a top and left cutaway perspective view thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> shows a bottom and right perspective view thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> shows a bottom and right cutaway perspective view thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> shows a top plan of a therapeutic pillow, pillowcase, and insert of embodiments of the disclosed technology.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> shows a front elevation view thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> shows a bottom plan of a therapeutic pillow and insert of embodiments of the disclosed technology.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> shows a right side elevation view thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref> shows a right side cross-sectional elevation view thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref> shows a right side cross-sectional elevation cutaway view thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b></figref> shows a top and left perspective view of a therapeutic pillow and separated insert of embodiments of the disclosed technology.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>12</b></figref> shows a bottom and right perspective view thereof.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF EMBODIMENTS OF THE DISCLOSED TECHNOLOGY</heading>
<p id="p-0033" num="0031">A pillow with a removable rod-shaped insert is described herein. The rod-shaped insert is removably insertable into a cavity and/or trough within the pillow. Both the rod-shaped insert and the cavity and/or trough are substantially semi-circular at each vertically oriented cross-section thereof. The cavity includes an opening in a side of the pillow opposite a side thereof which is in contact with a user's head and/or body. The rod-shaped insert has a plurality of parallel ridges on at least one outer surface thereof and extends between both lateral sides of the pillow.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0032">In some configurations, the rod-shaped insert is a single substantially planar structure which is folded into a substantially semi-circular shape. In some configurations, the rod-shaped insert has an internal removably-insertable structure.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0033">Embodiments of the disclosed technology will become more clear in view of the following discussion of the figures.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> shows a top and left perspective view of a therapeutic pillow and insert of embodiments of the disclosed technology. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> shows a top and left cutaway perspective view thereof. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> shows a bottom and right perspective view thereof. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> shows a bottom and right cutaway perspective view thereof. The pillow <b>10</b>, as shown, is in a shape of a rectangular prism with rounded edges and corners. The pillow <b>10</b> is compressible along substantially any axis passing there-through. A top surface <b>20</b> of the pillow <b>10</b> is substantially seamlessly connected to rounded corners and edges at each edge and each corner thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0035">The pillow <b>10</b> has a left side <b>30</b> and a right side <b>40</b>, each of which include a substantially planar section at a substantial midpoint between the top side <b>20</b> and a bottom side <b>50</b>. The substantially planar sections are substantially opposite each other and are substantially parallel to each other. An upper portion of each of left side <b>30</b> and right side <b>40</b> (defined as a portion thereof which is relatively close and/or adjacent to top side <b>20</b>) is connected substantially seamlessly to top side <b>20</b> by way of a rounded edge.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0036">The pillow <b>10</b> has a front side <b>60</b> and a back side <b>70</b>, each of which include a substantially planar section at a substantial midpoint between the top side <b>20</b> and the bottom side <b>50</b>. The substantially planar sections are substantially opposite each other and are substantially parallel to each other. An upper portion of each of front side <b>60</b> and back side <b>70</b> (defined as a portion thereof which is relatively close and/or adjacent to top side <b>20</b>) is connected substantially seamlessly to top side <b>20</b> by way of a rounded edge. A left-most side of each of front side <b>60</b> and back side <b>70</b> (defined as a portion thereof which is relatively close and/or adjacent to left side <b>30</b>) is connected substantially seamlessly to left side <b>30</b> by way of a rounded corner. A right-most side of each of front side <b>60</b> and back side <b>70</b> (defined as a portion thereof which is relatively close and/or adjacent to right side <b>40</b>) is connected substantially seamlessly to left side <b>40</b> by way of a rounded corner.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0037">The bottom side <b>50</b> of the pillow <b>10</b> has a trough <b>80</b>, with an insert <b>90</b> removably insertable therein. The trough <b>80</b> is in a substantial shape of a semi-circular prism extending linearly along a line substantially parallel to each of front size <b>60</b> and back size <b>70</b>. The trough <b>80</b> is substantially uniformly shaped throughout, such that substantial each cross section thereof in a plane parallel to left side <b>30</b> and right side <b>40</b> is of a substantially same semi-circular shape. The tough <b>80</b> includes an opening within bottom side <b>50</b> corresponding to a substantially widest section of each semi-circular cross-section. The trough <b>80</b> further includes a semi-circular opening on a left-most side and a right-most side thereof within left side <b>30</b> and right side <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0038">A lower portion of each of front side <b>60</b> and back side <b>70</b> (defined as a portion thereof which is relatively close and/or adjacent to bottom side <b>50</b>) is connected substantially seamlessly to bottom side <b>50</b> by way of a rounded edge. A lower portion of each of left side <b>30</b> and right side <b>40</b> (defined as a portion thereof which is relatively close and/or adjacent to bottom side <b>50</b>) is connected substantially seamlessly to bottom side <b>50</b> and/or the opening on the respective side of trough <b>80</b> by way of a rounded edge.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>5</b> through <b>8</b></figref> show the insert within the trough. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> shows a top plan of a therapeutic pillow, pillowcase, and insert of embodiments of the disclosed technology. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> shows a front elevation view thereof. A pillowcase <b>100</b>, in the embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, surrounds a substantial majority of the pillow <b>10</b> and the insert <b>90</b>. The pillowcase <b>100</b>, in the embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>, surrounds a substantial majority of the pillow <b>10</b> and extends within the trough <b>80</b>, such that the insert <b>90</b> is removably insertable within the trough <b>90</b> while remaining external to the pillowcase <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0040">In various embodiments, the pillowcase <b>100</b>, or a minority portion thereof, may be made of a resilient and stretchable material, such that a portion of the pillowcase <b>100</b> corresponding to the bottom side <b>50</b> is substantially planar when the pillowcase <b>100</b> covers the pillow <b>10</b> in isolation, is substantially reversibly stretched outwardly when the pillowcase <b>100</b> covers the pillow <b>10</b> and the insert <b>90</b> (such that the respective portion pillowcase <b>100</b> is still capable of and adapted to be lying substantially planarly against the bottom side <b>50</b> when the pillowcase <b>100</b> covers the pillow <b>10</b> in isolation), and is substantially reversibly stretched inwardly when the pillowcase <b>100</b> covers the pillow <b>10</b> and the insert <b>90</b> is inserted within the trough <b>80</b> externally thereto (such that the respective portion pillowcase <b>100</b> is still capable of lying substantially planarly against the bottom side <b>50</b> when the pillowcase <b>100</b> covers the pillow <b>10</b> in isolation).</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0041">In other embodiments, the pillowcase <b>100</b> is configured such that a portion thereof corresponding to the trough <b>80</b> lies substantially flat there-against when the pillowcase <b>100</b> surrounds the pillow <b>10</b>, regardless of the whether the insert <b>90</b> has been inserted into the trough <b>80</b>. In some embodiments, the pillowcase includes holes corresponding to sides of the trough <b>80</b> within the left side <b>30</b> and/or the right side <b>40</b>, such that the insert <b>90</b> may be removably inserted within the trough <b>80</b> and the pillowcase <b>100</b> while the pillowcase <b>100</b> surrounds the pillow <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> shows a bottom plan of a therapeutic pillow and insert of embodiments of the disclosed technology. In the embodiment shown the insert <b>90</b>. In the embodiment shown, the insert <b>90</b> is configured to lie within the trough <b>80</b> such that substantially no part of the insert <b>90</b> extends outwardly past a plane of a bottom side <b>50</b> of the pillow <b>10</b>. In other embodiments, the insert <b>90</b> may be configured to lie within the trough <b>80</b> such that a substantial minority of the insert <b>90</b> extends outwardly past a plane of a bottom side <b>50</b> of the pillow <b>10</b>. The insert <b>90</b> may further be reversibly compressible such that the insert <b>90</b>, when compressed by normal force of a person lying and/or sitting on the insert <b>90</b> or a combination of the insert <b>90</b> and the pillow <b>10</b>, substantially no part of the insert <b>90</b> extends outwardly past a plane of a bottom side <b>50</b> of the pillow <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0043"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref> shows a right side cross-sectional elevation view thereof. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref> shows a right side cross-sectional elevation cutaway view thereof. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b></figref> shows a top and left perspective view of a therapeutic pillow and separated insert of embodiments of the disclosed technology. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>12</b></figref> shows a bottom and right perspective view thereof. In the embodiment shown, the insert <b>90</b> is in a shape of a substantially planar structure folded to form a substantially semi-circular shape. This semi-circular shape substantially corresponds to that of an internal surface of the trough <b>80</b>. In other embodiments, the insert <b>90</b> may be substantially any shape, or a substantially planar structure folded in substantially any shape, such that the insert <b>90</b> fits within the semi-circular shape of the internal surface of the trough <b>80</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0044">The insert <b>90</b>, in the embodiment shown, has a substantially smooth surface at all points thereof. In other embodiments, the insert <b>90</b> may have protrusions, such as grooves, spikes, or bumps, or any combination thereof, as necessary for therapeutic and/or massage purposes. In further embodiments, the insert <b>90</b> may have an inner insert and a plurality of outer inserts, such that each outer insert is attachable to the inner insert, and each combination of inner and outer insert is removably insertable within the trough <b>80</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0045">The insert <b>90</b>, in embodiments of the disclosed technology, is made of a material with a greater rigidity than a material of the pillow <b>10</b> and/or of a lower compressibility than than a material of the pillow <b>10</b>. In some embodiments, when the insert <b>90</b> is inserted within the trough <b>80</b>, a half of the pillow <b>10</b> that surrounds the trough <b>80</b> and the insert <b>90</b> has a greater rigidity than the rest of the pillow <b>10</b>. In other embodiments, when the insert <b>90</b> is inserted within the trough <b>80</b>, a minority of the pillow <b>10</b> that surrounds the trough <b>80</b> and the insert <b>90</b> has a greater rigidity than the rest of the pillow <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0046">In various embodiments, the opening of the trough <b>80</b> within the bottom side <b>50</b> may have an opening of a width (in a plane extending between a point on front side <b>60</b> and a corresponding point on back side <b>70</b>) which is less than a width of the trough <b>80</b> in the same plane. The opening may be deformable, such that its width may be widened to allow the insert <b>90</b> to be inserted therein. The opening, when not deformed, has a width that is less than a width of the insert <b>90</b>. In some embodiments, one or both of the openings of trough <b>80</b> within left side <b>30</b> and right side <b>40</b> may have removable and/or permanent covers, such that when the covers are in palace, the insert <b>90</b> is held at substantially a same point between the left side <b>30</b> and the right side <b>40</b>. In other embodiments, the trough <b>80</b> may have any other method of holding the insert <b>90</b> substantially in a same place such that the insert <b>90</b> is removable.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0047">For purposes of this disclosure, the term &#x201c;substantially&#x201d; is defined as &#x201c;at least 95% of&#x201d; the term which it modifies.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0048">Any device or aspect of the technology can &#x201c;comprise&#x201d; or &#x201c;consist of&#x201d; the item it modifies, whether explicitly written as such or otherwise.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0049">When the term &#x201c;or&#x201d; is used, it creates a group which has within either term being connected by the conjunction as well as both terms being connected by the conjunction.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0050">While the disclosed technology has been disclosed with specific reference to the above embodiments, a person having ordinary skill in the art will recognize that changes can be made in form and detail without departing from the spirit and the scope of the disclosed technology. The described embodiments are to be considered in all respects only as illustrative and not restrictive. All changes that come within the meaning and range of equivalency of the claims are to be embraced within their scope. Combinations of any of the methods and apparatuses described hereinabove are also contemplated and within the scope of the invention.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A therapeutic pillow comprising:
<claim-text>a pillow with a trough therein, said trough extending linearly across a longest horizontal extent of a bottom side of said pillow; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an insert, comprising a rounded surface corresponding to a shape of said trough, removably insertable into said trough;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein an area circumscribed by said trough and by an opening thereof is substantially in a shape of a semi-circular prism;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a distance between a deepest point of said trough and said bottom side is substantially less than half of a distance between, and substantially more than a third of a distance between, a top side of said pillow and said bottom side.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The therapeutic pillow of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said pillow is in a shape of a rounded rectangular prism;
<claim-text>wherein said top side and said bottom side are opposite each other and are largest sides of said rounded rectangular prism;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a majority of said bottom side extends on a first side of said trough and a minority of said bottom side extends on a second side of said trough.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The therapeutic pillow of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein when said insert is removably inserted within said trough, a top-most portion of said insert is substantially flush with said deepest point of said trough and a bottom-most portion of said insert is substantially parallel with said bottom side of said pillow.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The therapeutic pillow of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein substantially every vertical cross-section of said insert is in a shape of a semi-circle comprising two extended legs with a curved portion there-between;
<claim-text>wherein every said vertical cross-section of said insert is in a plane substantially perpendicular to a plane of said top side and/or said bottom side and/or each of longer lateral sides of said pillow and substantially parallel to a plane of each of shorter lateral sides of said pillow.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The therapeutic pillow of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein a height of said trough is substantially equal to a height of said insert.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The therapeutic pillow of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein a shape of said trough substantially corresponds to a shape of said insert such that said insert is insertable within said trough such that every point thereof is within an area surrounded by said trough and/or an opening thereof.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The therapeutic pillow of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein a most-extended point of each said extended legs of said insert contacts surface opposite a user's head at at least one point thereof while said user's head rests on said therapeutic pillow.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The therapeutic pillow of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein a most-extended point of each said extended leg of said insert is configured to contact a surface opposite a user's neck at at least one point thereof while said user's head rests on said therapeutic pillow.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The therapeutic pillow of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein said insert is textured such that unequal pressure is applied to a user by portions of said pillow corresponding to portions of said pillow in contact with said insert and/or with textured portions of said insert.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The therapeutic pillow of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein a face of said pillow comprising said trough is substantially smooth but for said trough;
<claim-text>wherein a rigidity of said insert is greater than a rigidity of said pillow.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The therapeutic pillow of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein a face of said pillow containing said trough is substantially smooth but for said trough and for indicia thereon;
<claim-text>wherein when said insert is inserted within said trough, a rigidity of a portion of said top side of said pillow corresponding to a horizontal location of said insert is greater than a rest of said top side of said pillow.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The therapeutic pillow of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, further comprising a pillowcase comprising:
<claim-text>a trough substantially corresponding in size and shape to said trough of said pillow; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a zipper;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a distance between said zipper and a face of said pillowcase comprising said trough is greater than a distance between said zipper and a face of said pillowcase opposite said face containing said trough.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. The therapeutic pillow of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein a radius of curvature of edges of said bottom side is smaller than a radius of curvature of edges of said top side.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The therapeutic pillow of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said insert is configured to contact a surface opposite a user's head at at least one point thereof while said user's head rests on said therapeutic pillow.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. A therapeutic pillow kit comprising:
<claim-text>a pillow with a linear hollow in a shape of a prism therein;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pillowcase with a sleeve in a location thereon corresponding to a location of said linear hollow; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of inserts with shapes partially or wholly corresponding to said shape of said linear hollow;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said sleeve is configured to accommodate each of said inserts;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein each said insert is removably insertable into each of said linear hollow and said sleeve.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. The therapeutic pillow kit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein each said insert comprises a ridged and/or smooth triangular and/or semi-circular prism;
<claim-text>wherein said insert comprises a first material and said pillow comprises a second material;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a rigidity of said first material is greater than a rigidity of said second material.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. The therapeutic pillow kit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein each said insert comprises a rectangular prism with substantially identical folds at each vertical cross section thereof.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. The therapeutic pillow kit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein each said insert comprises a hollow portion at each vertical cross section thereof.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. The therapeutic pillow kit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein each said insert comprises:
<claim-text>an internal linear hollow in a shape of a prism; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an internal insert removably insertable into said internal linear hollow.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. The therapeutic pillow kit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein said internal insert is made of a same and/or a different material as said insert;
<claim-text>wherein a same internal insert is usable for multiple said inserts;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein, when said insert is inserted within said trough, a portion of said pillow surrounding said insert is more rigid than a rest of said pillow.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
