<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225625A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225625</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17580406</doc-number>
<date>20220120</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>17</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>0225</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>022</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>0235</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>16</class>
<subclass>H</subclass>
<main-group>40</main-group>
<subgroup>63</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>0225</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>02233</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>0235</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>742</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>02225</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20180101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>G</section>
<class>16</class>
<subclass>H</subclass>
<main-group>40</main-group>
<subgroup>63</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>2503</main-group>
<subgroup>045</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>7203</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Dual Mode Non-Invasive Blood Pressure Management</invention-title>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Spacelabs Healthcare L.L.C.</orgname>
<address>
<city>Snoqualmie</city>
<state>WA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Gilham</last-name>
<first-name>Jeffrey Jay</first-name>
<address>
<city>Sammamish</city>
<state>WA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="01" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Gopalakrishnan</last-name>
<first-name>Nishant</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kirkland</city>
<state>WA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The present specification describes methods and systems for on-inflate non-invasive blood pressure (NIBP) measurement suitable for cuffs of various sizes. In embodiments, an adapter hose connecting the cuff to the NIBP device is dynamically identified. Embodiments provide a restriction in at least one of the valves in the NIBP device to enable a controlled release of air from the device during the cuff inflation process.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="108.46mm" wi="158.75mm" file="US20230225625A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="207.35mm" wi="165.27mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225625A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="232.83mm" wi="165.69mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225625A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="228.43mm" wi="114.81mm" file="US20230225625A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="238.68mm" wi="159.68mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225625A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="236.64mm" wi="165.10mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225625A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present specification relates generally to monitoring physiological parameters and more specifically to methods and systems for obtaining blood pressure measurements and/or monitoring blood pressure using measurements from a non-invasive blood pressure (NIBP) device.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Non-invasive blood pressure (NIBP) is an important physiological parameter measured in nearly every bedside monitor that is sold world-wide. For ambulatory blood pressure (ABP) measurements, NIBP measurement capability is deployed within small wearable recorders to obtain serial measurements on patients over the course of their daily activity. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, a conventional ambulatory blood pressure measurement system <b>100</b> is shown. The system <b>100</b> comprises a cuff <b>115</b>, a tubing <b>110</b> that places an air bladder within the cuff <b>115</b> in air communication with an air pump positioned within a housing <b>105</b>. Valves <b>120</b> are positioned to be able to selectively release air from the cuff <b>115</b> air bladder. The housing <b>105</b> further comprises a measurement system that detects pressure oscillations emanating from the cuff <b>115</b> and generates a blood pressure measurement, comprising a diastole measurement and systole measurement. Diastole and systole refer to when the heart muscles relax and contract, with the period of relaxation being diastole and the period of contraction being systole, and the balance there-between determines a person's blood pressure.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Traditional NIBP measurements are obtained by rapidly inflating a flexible cuff, such as cuff <b>115</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, positioned around a limb of a patient. The rapid inflation is achieved using a pump to direct air into the cuff and the pump action is maintained until the cuff pressure is elevated to pressure level that is significantly above a standard blood pressure systole value and is sometimes identified by monitoring the patient's pulse and continuing to inflate the cuff to about 30 mm Hg above the point where the patient's pulse disappears. In measurements made using the oscillometric method, the patient's pulse does not actually disappear as it does in measurements made using the auscultatory method, which are performed by clinicians with a stethoscope. In some devices, the rapid inflation is achieved using a pump to direct air into the cuff, maintaining the pump action until the cuff pressure is elevated to a pressure level that is significantly above a previous measurement. In an example, if the last measurement for a patient was 120/80, the device inflates to the previous systolic plus 35 mm Hg (thus, 155 mm Hg in this example). Once that increased pressure level is reached, the air pump is turned off, and the cuff is deflated in a controlled, step-down manner. The cuff pressure is lowered in small pressure increments of typically at or around 8 millimeters mercury (mm Hg). At each step, measurements of pressure oscillations are made. Oscillations in the cuff corresponding to arterial pulses are then analyzed to determine blood pressure. The point of maximal oscillation corresponds to the mean intra-arterial pressure. During step deflate, measurements are taken for a target blood pressure that is either a default value depending on patient type or is based on a previous measurement.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Conventional NIBP devices typically include two valves that control the bleeding of air from a cuff. In general, each valve is configured such that, when activated, the valve is in a closed position, thereby making the cuff air-tight, and, when power is removed or when the valve is deactivated, the valve transitions to an open state, thereby allowing air to flow out of the cuff. Two valves are typically used because the first one functions as the actual deflation mechanism while the second valve functions as a backup in case the first valve fails. Additionally, the second valve may be used to provide a mechanism for clearing or removing the pressure from the cuff more rapidly upon completing the measurement.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Another approach to NIBP measurements is to use an &#x201c;on-inflate&#x201d; system. In an on-inflate system, measurements are made during cuff inflation, as opposed to a conventional step-deflate NIBP system in which measurements are only made after the cuff has been fully inflated and is in the process of being deflated. A specialized pneumatic arrangement between valves and a pump enables controlled inflation and deflation of an interior chamber in the cuff The principal advantages of on-inflate measurement include faster measurement, lower maximum cuff pressure, and reduced ambient noise from the pump. Since the pump operates at a reduced RPM to operate the device and inflate the cuff slowly, the pump is also relatively quiet compared with a traditional full speed measurement. These features, both alone and in combination, provide a more comfortable experience for the patient because the &#x201c;squeeze&#x201d; on the arm is reduced in intensity and duration and the loud noise from the pump during full-speed operation is minimized. The on-inflate measurement methods and devices are less traumatic for use with children, and patients with frail physical structures. In addition, clinicians are able to obtain faster measurements, typically on the order of 30% faster.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">While on-inflate NIBP devices are able to provide the benefits of speed and comfort to patients, for small cuff sizes, such as small adults (cuff size of 12 cm&#xd7;22 cm) or children (ranging from 4 cm&#xd7;8 cm to 9 cm&#xd7;18 cm), the task of controlling the speed of inflation is challenging. The rate of inflation may be varied by adjusting the speed or revolutions per minute (RPM) of the pump. The pump speed may be further modified using the applied drive voltage across the terminals of the pump since the pump RPM increases with an increase in the applied voltage. A voltage threshold is associated with a current pressure in each NIBP device, below which the pump is unable to turn or is in a &#x2018;deadhead&#x2019; state. Any voltage applied to about 10% above the threshold may be considered to induce a low RPM for the pump. With smaller cuffs, the pump speed is required to be low to give an effective inflation rate of 3 to 6 mm Hg per pulse. At this low flow rate, the pump tends to be unstable because an applied voltage is near a lower limit of how slow the pump can turn. The instability makes it challenging to control the inflation rate of small cuffs reliably. Additionally, when the pump RPM is low, meaning that is it is within range of 10% above the deadhead threshold, frequency of the pump perturbations approaches the upper frequency of the range of interest for pulse identification (10 Hz) and the noise from the pump begins to obscure the signal of interest (pulses). Therefore, the magnitude of perturbations to the pressure signal from the pump can obscure the pulse signal that are being attempted to be measured with the NIBP device.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Therefore, there is a need for methods and systems of non-invasive blood pressure measurement that are able to overcome the one or more deficiencies of the current standard and on-inflate NIBP devices. In particular, there is a need for NIBP systems that can operate at low flow rates while maintaining a substantially constant inflation rate. There is also a need for NIBP systems that can reliably generate the requested constant flow rate for small cuff sizes. There is also a need for NIBP systems that minimize frequencies of pump perturbations approaches when operating a pump at an applied voltage that is at or near the lower voltage limit for the pump.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The following embodiments and aspects thereof are described and illustrated in conjunction with systems, tools and methods, which are meant to be exemplary and illustrative, not limiting in scope.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The present specification discloses a blood pressure monitoring system, comprising: a housing; a controller located within the housing; a pump located within the housing, wherein the pump is in electrical communication with the controller and wherein the controller is configured to activate the pump and deactivate the pump; a pressure sensor and analysis system located within the housing, wherein the pressure sensor and analysis system is in data communication with the controller; a first hose defined by a first inner diameter; a first cuff configured to connect to the first hose; a second hose defined by a second inner diameter; a second cuff configured to connect to the second hose; a cuff connector adapted to be coupled to the first hose or the second hose; and at least two valves positioned within the housing, wherein a first valve of the at least two valves is configured to enable a first air flow rate and a second valve of the at least two valves is configured to enable a second air flow rate, wherein the controller is adapted to operate at least one or both of the first and second valves based on whether the cuff connector is coupled to the first hose and the first cuff or the cuff connector is coupled to the second hose and the second cuff.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Optionally, the first inner diameter of the first hose is greater than the second inner diameter of the second hose. Optionally, the cuff connector is coupled to the first hose or the second hose through at least one adapter. Optionally, the first cuff is configured to fit around a limb of an adult patient or a pediatric patient. Optionally, the second cuff is configured to fit around a limb of a neonate patient.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Optionally, at least one of the first cuff or the second cuff is configured to wrap around a limb of a patient wherein at least one of the first cuff or the second cuff is in air flow communication with the pump and configured to receive air when the pump is activated by the controller.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Optionally, the first valve and the second valve are identical, and a restrictor is configured to restrict air flow in the flow path of the first valve. Optionally, the first valve is smaller than the second valve so that air flow through the first valve is restricted compared to air flow through the second valve. Optionally, during a deflation of the second cuff, the controller is configured to cause the first valve to be open for at least a portion of said deflation. Optionally, during a deflation of the second cuff, the controller is configured to cause the first valve and the second valve to be open for at least a portion of said deflation.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Optionally, the cuff connector comprises a female rectus connector.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Optionally, the blood pressure monitoring system further comprises a monitor to display information about at least one of a blood pressure measurement, a status of the first hose connected to the first cuff, a status of the second hose connected to the second cuff, a status of the first cuff or the second cuff being coupled to the cuff connector, and/or whether an adapter is attached to the cuff connector.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The present specification also discloses a method of determining a blood pressure of a patient using a non-invasive blood pressure (NIBP) device, wherein the NIBP device comprises a controller positioned within a housing, a cuff connector, a first hose having a first inner diameter, adapted to be connected to a first cuff and configured to be coupled to the cuff connector, a second hose having a second inner diameter, adapted to be connected to a second cuff and configured to be coupled to the cuff connector, a pump in fluid communication with the cuff connector, and at least two valves where a first valve of the at least two valves is configured to enable a first air flow rate in an open configuration and a second valve of the at least two valves is configured to enable a second air flow rate in an open configuration, wherein the first air flow rate is lower than the second air flow rate, the method comprising: coupling at least one of the first cuff or the second cuff to the cuff connector; applying the first cuff or the second cuff to a limb of a person; operating the controller to determine whether the cuff connector is coupled to the first cuff or the second cuff; operating the controller to activate the pump, wherein, upon activation, the pump directs air into the first cuff or the second cuff positioned on the limb of the person; and operating the controller to open and/or close the first valve and/or the second valve based on whether the first cuff or the second cuff is coupled to the cuff connector and based on whether the controller is causing the first cuff to inflate or deflate or the second cuff to inflate or deflate.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Optionally, the method further comprises operating the controller to determine if the first hose is connected to the first cuff or if the second hose is connected to the second cuff.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Optionally, the first inner diameter of the first hose is greater than the second inner diameter of the second hose.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Optionally, the cuff connector is coupled to the first hose or the second hose through at least one adapter.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Optionally, the first cuff is configured to fit around a limb of an adult patient or a pediatric patient and the second cuff is configured to fit around a limb of a neonate patient. Optionally, during an inflation of the first cuff, wherein the first cuff is fit around the limb of the adult patient, the controller is configured to cause the first valve and the second valve to be closed during said inflation. Optionally, wherein when the determining the blood pressure is performed during an inflation of the first cuff, and wherein the first cuff is fit around the limb of the pediatric patient, the controller is configured to cause the first valve to be at least partially open and the second valve to be closed during said inflation. Optionally, wherein when the determining the blood pressure is performed during a deflation of the second cuff, the controller is configured to cause the first valve to be opened at least during a portion of said deflation. Optionally, when the determining the blood pressure is performed during a deflation of the first cuff, the controller is configured to cause the first valve and the second valve to be opened.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Optionally, the method further comprises detecting pressure oscillations in the first cuff or the second cuff during one of the inflation or the deflation of the first cuff or the second cuff to determine a blood pressure of the person.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Optionally, the method further comprises, when the controller is causing the first cuff to inflate or the second cuff to inflate, identifying an anomaly and using the controller to cause at least one of the first valve or the second valve to close during a step-deflation process. Optionally, operating the controller to determine if the first cuff is coupled to the cuff connector or the second cuff is coupled to the cuff connector comprises: opening the first valve; operating the pump for a first period of time; measuring a first amplitude of an air pressure pulse generated by the operating the pump after the first period of time; operating the pump for a second period of time; measuring a second amplitude of an air pressure pulse generated by the operating the pump after the second period of time; calculating a function of the first amplitude and the second amplitude; and determining, based on an output of the function, at least one of whether at least one of the first hose or the second hose is coupled to the cuff connector, whether at least one of the first hose or the second hose is kinked, whether the first hose is connected to the first cuff, or whether the second hose is connected to the second cuff.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Optionally, the function is an average of the first amplitude and the second amplitude. Optionally, each of the first time period and the second time period ranges from 10 milliseconds to 100 milliseconds and is preferably 50 milliseconds. Optionally, the method further comprises a time gap between the first period of time and the second period of time. Optionally, operating the pump comprises operating at a duty cycle in a range equal to 90% to 100%. Optionally, determining if the first hose is connected to the first cuff or if the second hose is connected to the second cuff comprises: opening the first valve and the second valve for the first time period; operating the pump at a duty cycle in a range of 30% to 50% after the first time period; measuring the first amplitude; and determining, based on the first amplitude, at least one of whether the first hose is connected to the first cuff or whether the second hose is connected to the second cuff. Optionally, the determining comprises concluding that the first hose is connected to the first cuff if the amplitude has a first value or the second hose is connected to the second cuff if the amplitude has a second value, wherein the first value is less than the second value.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The aforementioned and other embodiments of the present specification shall be described in greater depth in the drawings and detailed description provided below.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">These and other features and advantages of the present specification will be appreciated, as they become better understood by reference to the following detailed description when considered in connection with the accompanying drawings, wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> depicts a conventional NIBP system;</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> provides a schematic diagram of an exemplary blood pressure measurement system in accordance with one embodiment of the specification;</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref> is a flowchart illustrating an exemplary sequence of operations performed to confirm cuff connection, in accordance with the embodiments of the present specification;</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>B</figref> is a flowchart showing a first set of steps in an exemplary blood pressure measurement method in accordance with one embodiment of the invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>C</figref> is a flowchart showing a second set of steps in an exemplary blood pressure measurement method in accordance with one embodiment of the invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">In various embodiments, the present specification provides methods and systems for monitoring physiological characteristics of a patient using a non-invasive blood pressure (NIBP) monitoring device. The NIBP device performs the measurement in two modes. The mode is selected on the basis of the patient. The device verifies that the selected mode corresponds to the type of cuff that is used for the selected patient. In operation, an adapter with two hoses is removably attached to a cuff connector of the NIBP device. A first hose is configured to connect to a cuff for NIBP measurement of an adult/pediatric patient, whereas the second hose is configured to interface with a cuff for a neonate patient. Each hose has a different inner diameter that offers different resistance to air flow through them. The different resistance is detected by the NIBP system to determine/confirm if an adult/pediatric type patient is connected or a neonatal type patient is connected. Before every measurement, a check is performed to confirm if an adapter is present and if it is, then to confirm that it is connected to the correct type of cuff that matches the patient settings on a monitor integrated with the NIBP device. If the adapter is not attached or the wrong hose is attached to a cuff, then a measurement will not be taken and a message is communicated to the user about the mismatch.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Additionally, once the NIBP device is enabled to identify whether the patient is an adult/pediatric patient or a neonatal patient, the measurement method is adjusted to measure using either a step-deflate process or an on-inflate process. Therefore, embodiments of the NIBP system can perform measurements with both normal adult/pediatric cuffs in one mode and for neonatal cuffs which are very small, in another mode. Measurements in the neonatal mode are performed using a conventional inflation and step-deflation process. In one embodiment, a pneumatic arrangement of the NIBP device has a specially designed, restricted flow-path configuration that enables a controlled deflation appropriate for small neo-natal cuff sizes. The restricted flow-path makes it easier to control the step-deflation process and obtain accurate pressure control for the small neonatal cuffs. In addition, a faster operation of the pump also causes pneumatic noise from the pump to shift to a higher frequency and away from the pulse signal of interest where it can be more effectively filtered out. Measurements in the adult/pediatric mode can be performed either using on-inflate or step-deflate process of NIBP measurement. In some embodiments, the on-inflate measurement mode is preferably used for speed and comfort and the step-deflate mode is preferred for adult/pediatric measurements as a fallback if the on-inflate measurement is unsuccessful.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The present specification is directed towards multiple embodiments. The following disclosure is provided in order to enable a person having ordinary skill in the art to practice the invention. Language used in this specification should not be interpreted as a general disavowal of any one specific embodiment or used to limit the claims beyond the meaning of the terms used therein. The general principles defined herein may be applied to other embodiments and applications without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention. Also, the terminology and phraseology used is for the purpose of describing exemplary embodiments and should not be considered limiting. Thus, the present invention is to be accorded the widest scope encompassing numerous alternatives, modifications and equivalents consistent with the principles and features disclosed. For purpose of clarity, details relating to technical material that is known in the technical fields related to the invention have not been described in detail so as not to unnecessarily obscure the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">In the description and claims of the application, each of the words &#x201c;comprise&#x201d; &#x201c;include&#x201d; and &#x201c;have&#x201d;, and forms thereof, are not necessarily limited to members in a list with which the words may be associated. It should be noted herein that any feature or component described in association with a specific embodiment may be used and implemented with any other embodiment unless clearly indicated otherwise.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">In some embodiments, the system includes at least one processor (not shown) to control the operation of the entire system and its components. It should further be appreciated that the at least one processor is capable of processing programmatic instructions, has a memory capable of storing programmatic instructions, and employs software comprised of a plurality of programmatic instructions for performing the processes described herein. In one embodiment, the at least one processor is a computing device capable of receiving, executing, and transmitting a plurality of programmatic instructions stored on a volatile or non-volatile computer readable medium. Thus, in various embodiments, a computing device may be employed to receive and process data signals and may include an input/output controller, at least one communication interface and a system memory. The system memory may include at least one random access memory (RAM) and at least one read-only memory (ROM). These elements are in communication with the processor or central processing unit (CPU) to enable operation of the computing device.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">In embodiments, the system is coupled to at least one display, which displays information about at least one patient parameter and the operation of the system, by means of a GUI. The GUI also presents various menus that allow users to configure settings according to their requirements.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In various embodiments, the computing device may be a conventional standalone computer or alternatively, the functions of the computing device may be distributed across a network of multiple computer systems and architectures. In some embodiments, execution of a plurality of sequences of programmatic instructions or code, which are stored in one or more non-volatile memories, enable or cause the CPU of the computing device to perform or enable various functions, processes and algorithms, such as, for example, obtaining blood pressure measurements and/or monitoring blood pressure using measurements from a non-invasive blood pressure (NIBP) device. In alternate embodiments, hard-wired circuitry may be used in place of, or in combination with, software instructions for implementation of the processes of systems and methods described in this application. Thus, the systems and methods described are not limited to any specific combination of hardware and software.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">In embodiments, the present specification provides an NIBP device configured to interface with a cuff to measure physiological parameters of an adult or a pediatric patient, as well as a relatively smaller cuff that is configured for a neonatal patient. The device is further configured to enable BP measurements of the different types of patients using different methods.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> illustrates an NIBP device or system <b>200</b> configuration in accordance with some embodiments of the present specification. A controller <b>204</b>, which comprises one or more electrical circuits, memory, and processors integrated on to one or more printed circuit boards, may be positioned in an enclosure or a housing <b>202</b>. A display or a monitor <b>206</b>, such as a touch-screen display, may also be integrated with the system <b>200</b>. In some embodiments, the display <b>206</b> may enable a user to input patient settings, to select a mode of operation for the system <b>200</b>, display the mode selected by the system <b>200</b>, and communicate anomalies or matches that are identified by the system <b>200</b>, in addition to the measurements monitored by the system <b>200</b>. The housing <b>202</b> further comprises an air pump <b>210</b> and a pressure sensor and analysis system <b>213</b>, which may also comprise one or more electrical circuits, memory, and processors integrated on to one or more printed circuit boards. Both of the air pump <b>210</b> and pressure sensor and analysis system <b>213</b> are in electrical communication with the controller <b>204</b> and monitor <b>206</b>. The pressure sensor and analysis system <b>213</b> is located within a manifold <b>208</b> that provides a path for air pumped by the pump <b>210</b> to reach at least two valves <b>218</b> and <b>220</b>. The pressure sensor and analysis system creates an analog voltage corresponding to the air pressure that develops in the manifold <b>208</b>, which analog voltage is sampled by analog to digital converters so as to provide a measure of the pressure. The pressure sensor and analysis system <b>213</b> is also in communication with the controller <b>204</b>. The controller <b>204</b> is configured to execute an on-inflation blood pressure management process, as described below.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The NIBP system <b>200</b> includes a single front panel connector port <b>216</b> (which in an embodiment is a female rectus connector port), a first adapter hose <b>212</b> and a second adapter hose <b>214</b>. In embodiments, the proximal end of either the first adapter hose <b>212</b> or the second adapter hose <b>214</b> is connected to a port of connector <b>216</b>. In an embodiment, a distal end of first adapter hose <b>212</b> is configured to connect to a cuff for adult/pediatric patients, whereas a distal end of second adapter hose <b>214</b> is configured for interfacing with a cuff for neonatal measurement. In embodiments, because neonatal cuffs have different pressure safety limits (approximately 150 mmHg versus 300 mmHg for adults) and a different adapter at the cuff end, second adapter hose <b>214</b> is used for neonatal use while first adapter hose <b>212</b> is for adult use. In embodiments, the adapter positioned on the neonatal cuff has a smaller diameter than that on the adult cuff. Neonatal adapter hose <b>214</b> has a smaller inner diameter and is narrower than the adult adapter hose <b>212</b> which has a relatively larger inner diameter. In some embodiments, the first adapter hose <b>212</b> and second adapter hose <b>214</b> have equal lengths. In some embodiments, the first adapter hose <b>212</b> and second adapter hose <b>214</b> have lengths that are not equal relative to one another. In some embodiments, the first adapter hose <b>212</b> and the second adapter hose <b>214</b> each have a length ranging from <b>6</b> feet to <b>10</b> feet. In embodiments, first adapter hose <b>212</b> and second adapter hose <b>214</b> plug into the common cuff connector port <b>216</b> on the front panel of the system <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Adapter hose <b>212</b> and adapter hose <b>214</b> have different inner diameters and present different flow resistances to the system <b>200</b>. In an embodiment, adapter hose <b>212</b>, for use with adults, has an inner diameter of &#x215b; inch. In an embodiment, adapter hose <b>214</b>, for use in a neonatal setting, has an inner diameter of 1/16 inch. Prior to operating the system <b>200</b> for a measurement, a check is performed by pumping air from pump <b>210</b> and measuring the flow resistance, which is measured by the pressure sensor and analysis system <b>213</b>. In embodiments, NIBP system <b>200</b> has at least two pressure transducers to be &#x201c;fault tolerant&#x201d; to ensure that if one transducer fails, the second (backup) transducer does not allow unsafe pressures to be applied to the patient. The measured flow resistance is taken as an indicator that a cuff is appropriately connected to the adapter, and the type of the hose (<b>212</b> or <b>214</b>) to which that cuff is connected. The type of adapter hose is used as the basis to either select a mode of operating the system <b>200</b> or to validate a mode selected by the user in patient settings. If the system <b>200</b> detects that neither adapter hose <b>212</b> nor adapter hose <b>214</b> is attached to a cuff, or the wrong type of adapter hose is attached, then a measurement is not taken. A message is displayed on the monitor <b>206</b> to inform the user regarding the mismatch.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Upon connecting the housing <b>202</b> to the cuff, via cuff connector <b>216</b>, the pump <b>210</b> is activated to direct air into the cuff. The pump <b>210</b> is controlled by modulating a voltage that is applied across the terminals of the pump <b>210</b>. As the duty cycle is increased the pump <b>210</b> is given more &#x201c;throttle&#x201d; by increasing the applied voltage. Inflation of the cuff is controlled with a first valve <b>218</b> and a second valve <b>220</b>, which, in an embodiment are high flow valves. First valve <b>218</b> and second valve <b>220</b> are provided in the path of the pumped air, within manifold <b>208</b>, from the pump <b>210</b> to the cuff connector <b>216</b> that directs air into the cuff connected via either first adapter hose <b>212</b> or second adapter hose <b>214</b>. In some embodiments, the first valve <b>218</b> and second valve <b>220</b> have identical structures. In an embodiment, an inlet of first valve <b>218</b> is modified with a flow restrictor <b>222</b>, which enables a now restricted first flow valve <b>218</b> to perform similarly to a valve designed with a narrow orifice for more precise control of flow through the first valve <b>218</b>. In some embodiments, one of the valves, such as first valve <b>218</b> is configured with a narrow flow path relative to the high-flow valve <b>220</b>. By way of example, when unrestricted, first valve <b>218</b> is a high flow valve and has an inner diameter ranging from 0.04 to 0.08 inches, and preferably approximately 0.066 inches and when restricted, the inner diameter of first valve <b>218</b> is reduced to a diameter ranging from 0.005 inches to 0.020 inches, and preferably approximately 0.012 inches.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The cuff, connected through connector <b>216</b>, is rapidly inflated at a full speed of the pump <b>210</b>, to a pressure of 50 mmHg. In an embodiment, 12V pumps are used, therefore 12V are applied to the pump to obtain maximum RPM. A lower effective applied voltage below 12V would operate the pump at a lower speed. During inflation, the pressure sensor and analysis module <b>213</b> captures a pressure waveform at 220 Hz. The module obtains a derivative of the pressure, and subsequently applies a low pass filter to create a derivative waveform with a frequency below 10 Hz. Several features are extracted from the pressure and the low pass filtered derivative waveform. In embodiments, some exemplary features that are extracted are presented in Table 1:</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0000">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00001" num="00001">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="28pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="42pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="147pt" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="3" rowsep="1">TABLE 1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="3" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>S No.</entry>
<entry>Feature</entry>
<entry>Details</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>Time 40</entry>
<entry>time to hit 40 mmHg from 30 mmHg</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>2</entry>
<entry>Time 50</entry>
<entry>time to hit 50 mmHg from 40 mmHg</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>3</entry>
<entry>Sum 40 to 50</entry>
<entry>sum (pressure from 40 mmHg to 50 mmHg)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>4</entry>
<entry>Sum 30 to 40</entry>
<entry>sum (pressure from 30 mmHg to 40 mmHg)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>5</entry>
<entry>LPF 30 to 40</entry>
<entry>sum (low pass filtered derivative from pressure &#x3e;30 </entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>mmHg and &#x3c;40 mmHg)/</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>(time to hit 40 mmHg from 30 mmHg)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>6</entry>
<entry>LPF 40 to 50</entry>
<entry>sum (low pass filtered derivative from pressure &#x3e;30 </entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>mmHg and &#x3c;40 mmHg)/</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>(time to hit 40 mmHg from 30 mmHg)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="3" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0043">Hose Detection and Cuff Size Determination</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0044"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref> illustrates an exemplary method, implemented by system <b>200</b>, for identifying a connection of either adapter hose <b>212</b> or adapter hose <b>214</b> and thus, a type of cuff connected thereto. The presence and/or type of cuff attached can be detected by detecting the presence and type of an adapter hose. The adapter hose detection process is initiated during the start of each blood pressure measurement. When a measurement is requested, the system automatically checks to make sure a hose is present and that it matches the patient type, as described below. If there is no hose, a first error-type message is displayed and no measurement is taken. If the wrong adapter hose is detected, a second error-type message is displayed. The hose detection process involves a primary hose detection phase and a secondary hose detection phase. As stated earlier, second adapter hose <b>214</b> is relatively smaller than first adapter hose <b>212</b>, where the second adapter hose <b>214</b>, having a smaller inner diameter is configured to interface with a neonate cuff. First adapter hose <b>212</b> is configured to interface with a cuff used in adult or pediatric NIBP.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0045">Referring simultaneously to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b> and <b>3</b>A</figref>, at step <b>302</b>, the primary phase is initiated by opening first valve <b>218</b>, fitted with flow restrictor <b>222</b>, and closing valve <b>220</b>, which, in an embodiment, is a high flow valve. In embodiments, first flow valve <b>218</b> fitted with flow restrictor <b>222</b> is referred to as a restricted valve. At step <b>304</b>, a first pressure pulse is generated within manifold <b>208</b> by operating the pump <b>210</b> at a 100% duty cycle for a first time period. In an embodiment, the pump <b>210</b> is operated for a first time period ranging from 10 milliseconds to 100 milliseconds, and preferably 50 milliseconds (ms). At step <b>306</b>, a first pulse amplitude of the first pulse generated is measured after waiting a short duration, as the pressure continues to rise for that duration, which is roughly equivalent to a couple of samples after the pump <b>210</b> is turned off. In some embodiments, the time period for waiting is in a range of 20 to 40 ms. The measured pressure, measured by the pressure sensor and analysis system <b>213</b>, is indicative of flow resistance resulting from back pressure generated by either first adapter hose <b>212</b> or second adapter hose <b>214</b>, which is connected to a cuff on its distal end. At step <b>308</b>, after the amplitude of the first pulse is measured, the system <b>200</b> generates a second pulse by operating the pump for a second time period, ranging from 20 milliseconds to 100 milliseconds, and preferably 50 milliseconds (ms). In some embodiments, the first and second time periods are of equal duration, which is preferably 50 ms. At step <b>310</b>, an amplitude of the second pulse generated is measured after waiting a short duration after the pump <b>210</b> is turned off. In some embodiments, the short duration is in a range of 20 to 40 ms. At step <b>312</b>, the controller processes the recorded amplitude of the first pulse and the second pulse to obtain an average pulse amplitude. The average pulse amplitude value is used to determine a type of adapter hose and/or a state of hose that is connected to cuff connector <b>216</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0046">In some embodiments, an average value of greater than 40 mm Hg indicates that the connected hose is kinked. In embodiments, an average value ranging between 20 and 40 mmHg indicates that second adapter hose <b>214</b> (neonatal) is connected. Further, an average value that is less than 20 mmHg and greater than or equal to 3.5 mmHg indicates that first adapter hose <b>212</b> (adult) is connected. Additionally, an average value of less than 3.5 mmHg indicates that no hose is connected to connector <b>216</b>. When no hose is connected, the amplitudes of the first pulse and the second pulse, used for calculating the average, agree within 1 mmHg. When first adapter hose <b>212</b> is connected, the amplitudes of the first pulse and the second pulse, used for calculating the average, agree within 10 mm Hg. When second adapter hose <b>214</b> is connected, the amplitudes of the first pulse and the second pulse, used for calculating the average, agree within 10 mm Hg. It should be noted that a large difference between the amplitudes of the first pulse and second pulse may indicate that the recorded data is unreliable. In this case, the primary phase of the hose detection process may be repeated. In some embodiments, the primary phase of the detection process is repeated for a maximum of two times after which a failure to identify the cuff/hose combination is reported. At step <b>314</b>, the average pulse amplitude is used to determine whether either of first adapter hose <b>212</b> or second adapter hose <b>214</b> is connected to a cuff at its distal end, and if connected, which hose/cuff combination has been detected.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0047">In embodiments, the average pulse amplitude is compared to pre-defined threshold values of pulse amplitude that are stored by the controller <b>204</b>. In some embodiments, the pre-defined threshold values are derived by measuring the amplitudes of the pulses in prototypes and by ensuring an adequate margin to reasonably identify all the states. The first pulse amplitude and the second pulse amplitude may also be compared. In embodiments, controller <b>204</b> is configured to compare the average pulse amplitude to pre-defined threshold values for pulse height/amplitude to identify whether the first adapter hose <b>212</b> or the second adapter hose <b>214</b> is connected to the cuff. The neonate adapter hose <b>214</b> results in a larger pulse amplitude when compared to the adult adapter hose <b>212</b>, due to the smaller volume afforded for air flow as a result of its smaller inner diameter.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0048">Additionally, in another scenario, if neither first adapter hose <b>212</b> nor second adapter hose <b>214</b> is connected to a cuff, the average pulse amplitude recorded will have a very small value. In yet another scenario, if there is a kink or other anomaly in either first adapter hose <b>212</b> or second adapter hose <b>214</b>, the average pulse amplitude recorded will be of a large value. Exemplary values for the various scenarios are noted above.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0049">Once the connection and presence of a cuff is detected, the system <b>200</b> performs the second phase. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>B</figref> is a flowchart illustrating an exemplary sequence of the process performed by system <b>200</b> in the second phase, in accordance with some embodiments of the present specification. At step <b>320</b>, both first valve <b>218</b> and second valve <b>220</b> are opened initially for a time period, whereafter both first valve <b>218</b> and second valve <b>220</b> are closed. In embodiments, the time period may be within a range of 10 to 20 milliseconds (ms). In one embodiment, the first valve <b>218</b> and second valve <b>220</b> are opened for 15.6 ms. At step <b>322</b>, pump <b>210</b> is pulsed at a duty cycle in a range of 30% to 50%, and preferably at 40%, while valves <b>218</b> and <b>220</b> are open. At step <b>324</b>, the pressure pulse amplitude that is observed is recorded. At step <b>326</b>, the recorded pulse amplitude is compared to the average pulse amplitude observed during the primary detection phase. As described above with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref>, the first phase identifies whether a hose (first adapter hose <b>212</b> or second adapter hose <b>214</b>) is connected. Here, the second phase is used to determine the type of hose (first adapter hose <b>212</b> or second adapter hose <b>214</b>) that is connected. At step <b>328</b>, if the pulse amplitude is smaller than the average pulse amplitude measured in the primary phase, then a &#x201c;failure to detect&#x201d; the adapter hose is reported. Thus, if there is no agreement between the primary and secondary determinations, the measurement is aborted.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0050">Additionally, a measurement is not completed if either adapter hose that is being measured is kinked or flawed, resulting in irregular or skewed back pressure. In an embodiment, the user is informed by an audio, visual, or a combination of an audio-visual alert. The visual alert may be in the form of a message that is displayed on monitor <b>206</b>. The user may physically examine the hose to check whether a cuff is connected to a hose and that it is not kinked.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0051">At step <b>330</b>, if the pulse amplitude is equal to or greater than the average pulse amplitude of the primary phase, then the pulse is compared to pre-defined thresholds to determine one of several different cuff connections. In some embodiments, if the pulse amplitude is less than 25 mmHg then the connected hose is identified as first adapter hose <b>212</b>, and if the pulse amplitude is greater than or equal to 25 mmHg then then connected hose is identified as second adapter hose <b>214</b>. The adult adapter hose <b>212</b> results in a pulse of lower amplitude compared to that of the neonate adapter hose <b>214</b>. At step <b>332</b>, at the end of the secondary hose detection phase, the system <b>200</b> reports the type of adapter hose identified. In some embodiments, the process described in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>3</b>A and <b>3</b>B</figref>, is completed in less than one second. The system <b>200</b> then proceeds to NIBP measurement based on the type of cuff that is connected to it. The methods of measurement differ between first adapter hose <b>212</b>/associated cuff and second adapter hose <b>214</b>/associated cuff.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0052">NIBP Measurement</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0053">If, upon completing the secondary phase of detection, it is determined that an adapter hose is connected to the corresponding cuff for the selected mode of measurement (as provided in the patient settings), then, at step <b>340</b>, the measurement commences as described in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>C</figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>C</figref> illustrates an exemplary method, performed by system <b>200</b>, based on identification of the adapter hose and thus cuff type (small corresponding to a neonatal cuff and connected to second adapter hose <b>214</b>, or large corresponding to an adult/pediatric cuff and connected to first adapter hose <b>212</b>), in accordance with the embodiments of the present specification.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0054">At step <b>342</b>, the patient type and adapter hose type are identified according to the process described in context of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>3</b>A, <b>3</b>B, and <b>3</b>C</figref>. Referring simultaneously to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b> and <b>3</b>C</figref>, if, at step <b>342</b>, it is determined that hose <b>212</b> is connected to its corresponding cuff for an adult/pediatric patient, the method proceeds to step <b>344</b>. At step <b>344</b>, an on-inflate measurement of BP is performed. During the measurement, both valves <b>218</b> and <b>220</b> remain closed. Since first adapter hose <b>212</b> is larger than second adapter hose <b>214</b> (wherein the second adapter hose is designed for neo-natal patients), first adapter hose <b>212</b> may support a range of cuff sizes. First adapter hose <b>212</b> may have a corresponding cuff size ranging from a small cuff size for adults and pediatric patients or children, which is still larger than the cuff sizes available for neo-natal patients to a relatively larger cuff size appropriate for an adult. Therefore, it is also desirable to be able to distinguish between an adult and a pediatric patient while connected to first adapter hose <b>212</b>. The NIBP measurement method differs for an adult patient and for a pediatric patient. For smaller cuff sizes, such as for pediatric use/children, optionally in some cases, the restricted valve <b>218</b> is left open during on-inflate measurement to allow for better pump control.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0055">As such, an additional step may be used to determine the size of the cuff (whether adult or pediatric), when connected to first adapter hose <b>212</b>. A pediatric cuff has a small cuff volume relative to an adult cuff. The distinction between an adult and a pediatric cuff size is determined based upon an amount of time it takes to inflate the cuff through first adapter hose <b>212</b> from zero to a low target pressure. The longer the time it takes, the larger the cuff, which corresponds to an adult size cuff. If, at step <b>346</b>, an anomaly is identified in the measurement, then the system <b>200</b> may optionally proceed to step <b>352</b> to perform a measurement using step-deflation, as a check method. The anomaly may be identified if the pressure measurement is irregular. At step <b>356</b>, the measurement using the step-deflation method is performed with valve <b>218</b> closed and valve <b>220</b> closed until they are both opened to the next &#x201c;step&#x201d; during the measurement. When the measurement is completed, both valves <b>218</b> and <b>220</b> are opened and the pressure is released. In case there is no anomaly at step <b>346</b>, the on-inflate measurement of step <b>344</b> is completed at step <b>350</b>. As stated before, if the cuff size is determined to be for a child (pediatric), the on-inflate measurement is performed with the restricted flow valve <b>218</b> open. Keeping valve <b>218</b> open simulates a &#x201c;small leak&#x201d; and allows the pump to run a little faster, where it is easier to control. In addition, the pump noise (pneumatic) does not interfere with the measurement. On the other hand, if the cuff size is determined to be larger than for a child (pediatric) then the restricted valve <b>218</b> is closed during the on-inflate measurement. In some embodiments, an algorithm is used to analyze the pressure pulse amplitudes observed during cuff inflation to determine blood pressure. In some embodiments, the time it takes to inflate the cuff is also monitored. In embodiments, a robust estimate of the maximum pulse amplitude is obtained, so that the measurement is reliable (assuming real world conditions) and is not a product of motion artifact or any other disturbance. In embodiments, an estimate of systolic pressure is determined where the pulse amplitude achieves approximately 50% of the pulse maximum. Similarly, diastolic pressure is estimated when the pulse amplitude reaches approximately 75% of its peak value.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0056">However, if at step <b>342</b> it is identified that hose <b>214</b> is connected to its corresponding cuff for a neonate patient, the method proceeds to step <b>352</b> to initiate measurement using step-deflation. Since the step-deflation measurement is for a neonate patient, at step <b>358</b>, first valve <b>218</b> is opened and second valve <b>220</b> is closed during the bleed steps of the measurement, when the air is enabled to leak or bleed out during a deflation step. The valve <b>218</b> that is left open during the measurement of blood pressure is configured with a flow restriction structure <b>222</b> positioned within the exhaust path of the valve <b>218</b>. In some embodiments, the exhaust path of the valve <b>218</b> is configured with a controlled orifice, fitted with the restriction structure <b>222</b>, which in turn enables control of the speed of inflation by limiting the amount of air that is released during inflation and deflation. In some embodiments, a size of the orifice of the exhaust path of valve <b>218</b>, when open, is configured to be 0.012 inch. In embodiments, the restriction structure <b>222</b> is sized such that in the event that second valve <b>220</b> fails after the measurement, the restricted path would still allow a cuff to safely deflate within an allowed margin of the regulatory standards. In embodiments, the regulatory standard is specified in terms of the amount of time it takes an inflated system to get to 15 mm Hg based on a volume of 500 mL, which may be on the order of 30 seconds. In embodiments, the limitation in the exhaust path of the open valve <b>218</b> is configured so that the path may doubly serve as a viable backup pressure relief while enabling the pump to operate at a higher RPM.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0057">When restricted, second valve <b>218</b> enables the pump <b>210</b> to operate at a higher RPM than is usually done with devices known in the art. The operation of pump <b>210</b> at a higher RPM is controlled by the controller. Fast operation of the pump <b>210</b> enables pneumatic noise from the pump <b>210</b> to shift to a higher frequency and away from the pulse signal of interest where it can be more effectively filtered out. The restricted path enabled by valve <b>218</b> makes it easier to control the step-deflation process and obtain accurate pressure control for the small neonatal cuffs. Measurements in the adult/pediatric mode can be performed either using on-inflate or step-deflate process of NIBP measurement. In some embodiments, the on-inflate measurement mode is preferably used for speed and comfort and the step-deflate mode is preferred for adult/pediatric measurements as a fallback if the on-inflate measurement is unsuccessful (an anomaly is reported). At step <b>360</b>, the measurements are communicated to the user. In some embodiments, the measured data is displayed on monitor <b>206</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0058">The above examples are merely illustrative of the many applications of the system of present invention. Although only a few embodiments of the present invention have been described herein, it should be understood that the present invention might be embodied in many other specific forms without departing from the spirit or scope of the invention. Therefore, the present examples and embodiments are to be considered as illustrative and not restrictive, and the invention may be modified within the scope of the appended claims.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>We claim:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A blood pressure monitoring system, comprising:
<claim-text>a housing;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a controller located within the housing;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pump located within the housing, wherein the pump is in electrical communication with the controller and wherein the controller is configured to activate the pump and deactivate the pump;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pressure sensor and analysis system located within the housing, wherein the pressure sensor and analysis system is in data communication with the controller;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first hose defined by a first inner diameter;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first cuff configured to connect to the first hose;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second hose defined by a second inner diameter;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second cuff configured to connect to the second hose;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a cuff connector adapted to be coupled to the first hose or the second hose; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least two valves positioned within the housing, wherein a first valve of the at least two valves is configured to enable a first air flow rate and a second valve of the at least two valves is configured to enable a second air flow rate, wherein the controller is adapted to operate at least one or both of the first and second valves based on whether the cuff connector is coupled to the first hose and the first cuff or the cuff connector is coupled to the second hose and the second cuff.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The blood pressure monitoring system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first inner diameter of the first hose is greater than the second inner diameter of the second hose.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The blood pressure monitoring system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the cuff connector is coupled to the first hose or the second hose through at least one adapter.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The blood pressure monitoring system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the first cuff is configured to fit around a limb of an adult patient or a pediatric patient.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The blood pressure monitoring system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the second cuff is configured to fit around a limb of a neonate patient.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The blood pressure monitoring system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein at least one of the first cuff or the second cuff is configured to wrap around a limb of a patient and wherein at least one of the first cuff or the second cuff is in air flow communication with the pump and configured to receive air when the pump is activated by the controller.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The blood pressure monitoring system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the first valve and the second valve are identical, and wherein a restrictor is configured to restrict air flow in the flow path of the first valve.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The blood pressure monitoring system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the first valve is smaller than the second valve so that air flow through the first valve is restricted compared to air flow through the second valve.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The blood pressure monitoring system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref> wherein, during a deflation of the second cuff, the controller is configured to cause the first valve to be open for at least a portion of said deflation.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The blood pressure monitoring system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref> wherein, during a deflation of the second cuff, the controller is configured to cause the first valve and the second valve to be open for at least a portion of said deflation.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The blood pressure monitoring system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the cuff connector comprises a female rectus connector.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The blood pressure monitoring system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> further comprising a monitor to display information about at least one of a blood pressure measurement, a status of the first hose connected to the first cuff, a status of the second hose connected to the second cuff, a status of the first cuff or the second cuff being coupled to the cuff connector, and/or whether an adapter is attached to the cuff connector.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. A method of determining a blood pressure of a patient using a non-invasive blood pressure (NIBP) device, wherein the NIBP device comprises a controller positioned within a housing, a cuff connector, a first hose having a first inner diameter, adapted to be connected to a first cuff and configured to be coupled to the cuff connector, a second hose having a second inner diameter, adapted to be connected to a second cuff and configured to be coupled to the cuff connector, a pump in fluid communication with the cuff connector, and at least two valves where a first valve of the at least two valves is configured to enable a first air flow rate in an open configuration and a second valve of the at least two valves is configured to enable a second air flow rate in an open configuration, wherein the first air flow rate is lower than the second air flow rate, the method comprising:
<claim-text>coupling at least one of the first cuff or the second cuff to the cuff connector;</claim-text>
<claim-text>applying the first cuff or the second cuff to a limb of a person;</claim-text>
<claim-text>operating the controller to determine whether the cuff connector is coupled to the first cuff or the second cuff;</claim-text>
<claim-text>operating the controller to activate the pump, wherein, upon activation, the pump directs air into the first cuff or the second cuff positioned on the limb of the person; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>operating the controller to open and/or close the first valve and/or the second valve based on whether the first cuff or the second cuff is coupled to the cuff connector and based on whether the controller is causing the first cuff to inflate or deflate or the second cuff to inflate or deflate.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, further comprising operating the controller to determine if the first hose is connected to the first cuff or if the second hose is connected to the second cuff.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the first inner diameter of the first hose is greater than the second inner diameter of the second hose.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the cuff connector is coupled to the first hose or the second hose through at least one adapter.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the first cuff is configured to fit around a limb of an adult patient or a pediatric patient and wherein the second cuff is configured to fit around a limb of a neonate patient.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein, during an inflation of the first cuff, wherein the first cuff is fit around the limb of the adult patient, the controller is configured to cause the first valve and the second valve to be closed during said inflation.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein when the determining the blood pressure is performed during an inflation of the first cuff, wherein the first cuff is fit around the limb of the pediatric patient, the controller is configured to cause the first valve to be at least partially open and the second valve to be closed during said inflation.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein when the determining the blood pressure is performed during a deflation of the second cuff, the controller is configured to cause the first valve to be opened at least during a portion of said deflation.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text><b>21</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein when the determining the blood pressure is performed during a deflation of the first cuff, the controller is configured to cause the first valve and the second valve to be opened.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text><b>22</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, further comprising detecting pressure oscillations in the first cuff or the second cuff during one of the inflation or the deflation of the first cuff or the second cuff to determine a blood pressure of the person.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text><b>23</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, further comprising, when the controller is causing the first cuff to inflate or the second cuff to inflate, identifying an anomaly and using the controller to cause at least one of the first valve or the second valve to close during a step-deflation process.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024" num="00024">
<claim-text><b>24</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein operating the controller to determine if the first cuff is coupled to the cuff connector or the second cuff is coupled to the cuff connector comprises:
<claim-text>opening the first valve;</claim-text>
<claim-text>operating the pump for a first period of time;</claim-text>
<claim-text>measuring a first amplitude of an air pressure pulse generated by the operating the pump after the first period of time;</claim-text>
<claim-text>operating the pump for a second period of time;</claim-text>
<claim-text>measuring a second amplitude of an air pressure pulse generated by the operating the pump after the second period of time;</claim-text>
<claim-text>calculating a function of the first amplitude and the second amplitude;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining, based on an output of the function, at least one of whether at least one of the first hose or the second hose is coupled to the cuff connector, whether at least one of the first hose or the second hose is kinked, whether the first hose is connected to the first cuff, or whether the second hose is connected to the second cuff.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025" num="00025">
<claim-text><b>25</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00024">claim 24</claim-ref>, wherein the function is an average of the first amplitude and the second amplitude.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026" num="00026">
<claim-text><b>26</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00024">claim 24</claim-ref>, wherein each of the first time period and the second time period ranges from 10 milliseconds to 100 milliseconds and is preferably 50 milliseconds.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027" num="00027">
<claim-text><b>27</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00024">claim 24</claim-ref>, further comprising a time gap between the first period of time and the second period of time.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028" num="00028">
<claim-text><b>28</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00024">claim 24</claim-ref>, wherein operating the pump comprises operating at a duty cycle in a range equal to 90% to 100%.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029" num="00029">
<claim-text><b>29</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00024">claim 24</claim-ref>, wherein determining if the first hose is connected to the first cuff or if the second hose is connected to the second cuff comprises:
<claim-text>opening the first valve and the second valve for the first time period;</claim-text>
<claim-text>operating the pump at a duty cycle in a range of 30% to 50% after the first time period;</claim-text>
<claim-text>measuring the first amplitude;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining, based on the first amplitude, at least one of whether the first hose is connected to the first cuff or whether the second hose is connected to the second cuff.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030" num="00030">
<claim-text><b>30</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00029">claim 29</claim-ref>, wherein the determining comprises concluding that the first hose is connected to the first cuff if the amplitude has a first value or the second hose is connected to the second cuff if the amplitude has a second value, wherein the first value is less than the second value.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
