<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225525A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225525</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18097815</doc-number>
<date>20230117</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>9</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>9</main-group>
<subgroup>0207</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>9</main-group>
<subgroup>0261</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">DUVET</invention-title>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>63299671</doc-number>
<date>20220114</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="obligated-assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Purple Innovation, LLC</orgname>
<address>
<city>Lehi</city>
<state>UT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Pettit</last-name>
<first-name>Janae Lois</first-name>
<address>
<city>Pleasant Grove</city>
<state>UT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="01" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ah Loo</last-name>
<first-name>Arthur McConkie</first-name>
<address>
<city>Clearfield</city>
<state>UT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A duvet includes a duvet cover and an insert. The duvet cover includes a base and a top that that are secured to each other along fewer than three full edges (e.g., along one full edge and an adjacent part of one or two adjacent edge; along two full, adjacent edges; etc.). An upper surface of the top of the duvet cover may lack visible seams and fasteners. An interior surface of a base of the duvet cover may engage a surface of an insert positioned within a receptacle of the duvet cover, over the base (e.g., with touch fasteners, etc.). Methods for using duvet covers and duvets are also disclosed.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="108.97mm" wi="158.75mm" file="US20230225525A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="254.17mm" wi="165.78mm" file="US20230225525A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="257.39mm" wi="123.61mm" file="US20230225525A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="219.20mm" wi="121.16mm" file="US20230225525A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">A claim for priority to the Jan. 14, 2022 filing date of U.S. Provisional Patent Application No. 63/299,671, titled DUVET (&#x201c;the '671 Provisional Application&#x201d;), is hereby made pursuant to 35 U.S.C. &#xa7; 119(e). The entire disclosure of the '671 Provisional Application is hereby incorporated herein.</p>
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="tail"?>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">This disclosure relates generally to duvets and, more specifically, to duvets with covers that include bases and tops that are secured to each other along fewer than three full edges. An upper surface of a duvet cover of this disclosure may lack visible seams and fasteners. An interior surface of a base of the duvet cover may engage a surface of an insert positioned within a receptacle of the duvet cover, over the base. Methods for using duvet covers and duvets are also within the scope of this disclosure.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">RELATED ART</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">A duvet is a soft quilt that provides insulation for an individual. A duvet typically includes a duvet cover that removably receives an insert, such as a comforter or quilt. When used with a feather and/or down comforter, a duvet cover provides a barrier that prevents feathers within the comforter from scratching or poking an individual who uses the comforter. In addition, since a duvet cover can be removed from the comforter or other bedding, a duvet cover can be laundered frequently (e.g., with a bottom bed sheet), thus enabling individuals to use duvets without top bed sheets.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Conventionally, duvet covers have been configured as bags, with a base and a top that are sewn together along a bottom edge and two side edges, while the base and top are at least partially separable along a top edge of the duvet. Such a configuration may make it somewhat difficult to place a conventional duvet over a comforter or other bedding.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Since conventional duvet covers merely serve as covers for comforters or other bedding and duvet covers are separate from the bottom bed sheet, making a bed requires that the duvet be spread out over the mattress in the same manner as a bed spread, but often with the additional requirement that the relative positions of the duvet and the comforter or other bedding therein be adjusted to provide the duvet with a pleasing appearance in which the base and top of the duvet are properly superimposed about all of the edges of the duvet and the comforter or other bedding is spread out within the interior of the duvet.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In one aspect, a duvet according to this disclosure includes a duvet cover with a base and a top that are sewn or otherwise secured to each other along fewer than three complete edges. In some embodiments, the top of the duvet cover may be permanently secured to the base of the duvet cover along an entirety of their bottom edges and along substantially an entirety of one side edge; the other side edges and the top edges of the top and base of the duvet may be removably securable to each other (e.g., with zipper halves, buttons and corresponding button holes, touch fasteners, ties, snaps, etc.). In other embodiments, the top of the duvet cover may be permanently secured to the base of the duvet cover along an entirety of their bottom edges and portions (e.g., bottom portions) of their side edges; remaining portions of the side edges and the top edges of the top and base of the duvet cover may be removably securable to each other (e.g., with zipper halves, buttons and corresponding button holes, touch fasteners, ties, snaps, etc.). Such configurations may enable the duvet cover to be removed from a comforter or other bedding more readily than a conventional duvet cover and simplify that process of positioning or repositioning the duvet cover over the comforter or other bedding.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In another aspect, a fastening system is designed to an insert, such as a comforter or other bedding, within a duvet cover. The fastening system may include cooperating fasteners on the insert and the base of the duvet cover. More specifically, fasteners (e.g., strips of touch fasteners, etc.) may be provided on a bottom surface of the insert, adjacent to edges of the bottom surface of the insert, while complementary fasteners (e.g., pieces of touch fasteners that can engage or be engaged by the strips of touch fasteners on the insert, etc.) may be provided adjacent to edges of the interior surface or upper surface of the base of the duvet cover. Thus, as the insert is properly arranged (i.e., bottom surface down) and positioned within a receptacle of the duvet cover, the fasteners on the insert can engage or be engaged by the inserts on the interior surface or upper surface of the base of the duvet cover to hold the insert in place within the duvet cover.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The duvet cover may include standard ties in the corners of its receptacle and corners of the insert may include loops to ensure that the duvet cover and the insert are compatible with conventionally configured components of a duvet (i.e., the duvet cover with a conventionally configured insert, the insert with a conventionally configured duvet cover).</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Other aspects of the disclosed subject matter, as well as features and advantages of various aspects of the disclosed subject matter, should become apparent to those of ordinary skill in the art through consideration of the preceding disclosure, the accompanying images, and the appended claims.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In the drawings:</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a perspective view of an embodiment of a duvet of this disclosure, including a duvet cover and an insert;</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a perspective view of another embodiment of a duvet;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a top view of an embodiment of a base of a duvet cover of a duvet of this disclosure, showing an upper surface or inner surface of the base and an embodiment of insert fasteners on the upper surface;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is a top view of another embodiment of a base of a duvet cover of a duvet of this disclosure, showing an upper surface or inner surface of the base and an embodiment of fasteners on the upper surface;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is a bottom view of an embodiment of an insert of this disclosure, showing fasteners on a bottom surface of the insert; and</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is a partial cross-sectional view depicting the manner in which fasteners of the insert of the duvet and fasteners of the base of the duvet cover of the duvet cooperate to secure the insert in place within a receptacle of the duvet cover.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The images and text that accompany this disclosure provide details of some non-limiting embodiments of duvets according to this disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, an embodiment of a duvet <b>10</b> is depicted. The duvet <b>10</b> may include a duvet cover <b>20</b> and an insert <b>60</b>. The duvet cover <b>20</b> is made to be positioned over the insert <b>60</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The duvet <b>10</b> may have a shape and size that facilitate is use with and provide an aesthetically pleasing cover on a particular size mattress. In various embodiments, the shape and dimensions of the duvet <b>20</b> may be appropriate for use on a king size bed (e.g., a standard king, a California king, etc.), a queen size bed, a full size bed, a twin bed, an extra long (XL) twin bed, etc. A king size duvet <b>10</b> may have dimensions of about 108 inches (about 275 cm) (e.g., width, etc.) by about 100 inches (about 250 cm) (e.g., length, etc.). A queen size or full size duvet <b>10</b> may have dimensions of about 90 inches (about 230 cm) (e.g., width, etc.) by about 95 inches (about 240 cm) (e.g., length, etc.). A twin duvet may have dimensions of about 63 inches (about 160 cm) (e.g., width, etc.) by about 92 inches (about 235 cm) (e.g., length, etc.).</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">As illustrated, the duvet cover <b>20</b> includes a top <b>30</b> and a base <b>40</b>. The top <b>30</b> and base <b>40</b> are superimposed with each other, with a receptacle <b>28</b> defined between the top <b>30</b> and base <b>40</b>. A configuration of the receptacle <b>28</b> (e.g., its shape, dimensions, etc.) enable it to receive the insert <b>60</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The top <b>30</b> of the duvet cover <b>20</b> includes an outer surface <b>31</b> and an inner surface <b>32</b>. The outer surface <b>31</b> and the inner surface <b>32</b> are opposite from each other. The outer surface <b>31</b> may define an upper surface <b>21</b> of the duvet cover <b>20</b>. The inner surface <b>32</b> may partially define the receptacle <b>28</b> of the duvet cover <b>20</b>. The top <b>30</b> also includes a plurality of edges <b>33</b>, <b>34</b>, <b>35</b> (not shown), and <b>36</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Edge <b>33</b> of the top <b>30</b> of the duvet cover <b>20</b> may comprise a bottom edge of the top <b>30</b> of the duvet cover <b>20</b>, with a first end <b>33</b><i>e</i><sub>1 </sub>and a second end <b>33</b><i>e</i><sub>2 </sub>(not shown). Edge <b>34</b> may comprise a first side edge of the top <b>30</b>, with a top end <b>34</b><i>e</i><sub>t </sub>and a bottom end <b>34</b><i>e</i><sub>b</sub>. Edge <b>35</b> (not shown) may comprise a second side edge of the top <b>30</b>, with a top end <b>35</b><i>e</i><sub>t </sub>and a bottom end <b>35</b><i>e</i><sub>b </sub>(not shown). Edge <b>36</b> may comprise a top edge of the top <b>30</b>, with a first end <b>36</b><i>e</i><sub>1 </sub>and a second end <b>36</b><i>e</i><sub>2</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The first end <b>33</b><i>e</i><sub>1 </sub>of the bottom edge <b>33</b> may be adjoined to the bottom end <b>34</b><i>e</i><sub>b </sub>of the first side edge <b>34</b>. The second end <b>33</b><i>e</i><sub>2 </sub>(not shown) of the bottom edge <b>33</b> may be adjoined to the bottom end <b>35</b><i>e</i><sub>b </sub>(not shown) of the second side edge <b>35</b>. The top end <b>34</b><i>e</i><sub>t </sub>of the first side edge <b>34</b> may be adjoined to the first end <b>36</b><i>e</i><sub>1 </sub>of the top edge <b>36</b>, with the first side <b>34</b> edge extending perpendicularly from the first end <b>36</b><i>e</i><sub>1 </sub>of the top edge <b>36</b>. The top end <b>35</b><i>e</i><sub>t </sub>of the second side edge <b>35</b> may be adjoined to the second end <b>36</b><i>e</i><sub>2 </sub>of the top edge <b>36</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The first side edge <b>34</b> and second side edge <b>35</b> (not shown) may be arranged or extend parallel to each other and perpendicular to the bottom edge <b>33</b> and the top edge <b>36</b>. The bottom edge <b>33</b> and top edge <b>36</b> may be arranged or extend parallel to each other and perpendicular to the first side edge <b>34</b> and second side edge <b>35</b> (not shown).</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The base <b>40</b> of the duvet cover <b>20</b> includes an outer surface <b>41</b> and an inner surface <b>42</b>. The outer surface <b>41</b> and the inner surface <b>42</b> are opposite from each other. The outer surface <b>41</b> may define a lower surface <b>22</b> of the duvet cover <b>20</b>. The inner surface <b>42</b> may partially define the receptacle <b>28</b> of the duvet cover <b>20</b>. The base <b>40</b> also includes a plurality of edges <b>43</b>, <b>44</b>, <b>45</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>), and <b>46</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Edge <b>43</b> of the base <b>40</b> of the duvet cover <b>20</b> may comprise a bottom edge of the base <b>40</b> of the duvet cover <b>20</b>, with a first end <b>43</b><i>e</i><sub>1 </sub>and a second end <b>43</b><i>e</i><sub>2 </sub>(not shown). Edge <b>44</b> may comprise a first side edge of the base <b>40</b>, with a top end <b>44</b><i>e</i><sub>t </sub>and a bottom end <b>44</b><i>e</i><sub>b</sub>. Edge <b>45</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>) may comprise a second side edge of the base <b>40</b>, with a top end <b>45</b><i>e</i><sub>t </sub>and a bottom end <b>45</b><i>e</i><sub>b </sub>(<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>). Edge <b>46</b> may comprise a top edge of the base <b>40</b>, with a first end <b>46</b><i>e</i><sub>1 </sub>and a second end <b>46</b><i>e</i><sub>2</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The first end <b>43</b><i>e</i><sub>1 </sub>of the bottom edge <b>43</b> may be adjoined to the bottom end <b>44</b><i>e</i><sub>b </sub>of the first side edge <b>44</b>. The second end <b>43</b><i>e</i><sub>2 </sub>(not shown) of the bottom edge <b>43</b> may be adjoined to the bottom end <b>45</b><i>e</i><sub>t </sub>(<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>) of the second side edge <b>45</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>). The top end <b>44</b><i>e</i><sub>t </sub>of the first side edge <b>44</b> may be adjoined to the first end <b>46</b><i>e</i><sub>1 </sub>of the top edge <b>46</b>, with the first side <b>44</b> edge extending perpendicularly from the first end <b>46</b><i>e</i><sub>1 </sub>of the top edge <b>46</b>. The top end <b>45</b><sub>t </sub>of the second side edge <b>45</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>) may be adjoined to the second end <b>46</b><i>e</i><sub>2 </sub>of the top edge <b>46</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The first side edge <b>44</b> and second side edge <b>45</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>) may be arranged or extend parallel to each other and perpendicular to the bottom edge <b>43</b> and the top edge <b>46</b>. The bottom edge <b>43</b> and top edge <b>46</b> may be arranged or extend parallel to each other and perpendicular to the first side edge <b>44</b> and second side edge <b>45</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">At least one edge <b>33</b> of the top <b>30</b> of the duvet cover <b>20</b> and a corresponding edge <b>43</b> of the base <b>40</b> of the duvet cover <b>20</b> are permanently adjoined to each other to define a coupled edge <b>23</b> of the duvet cover <b>20</b>. The coupled edge <b>23</b> may comprise a fold in fabric that defines at least portions of the top <b>30</b> and the base <b>40</b>. Alternatively, the coupled edge <b>23</b> may be defined by sewing, adhering, bonding, or otherwise securing edge <b>33</b> of the top <b>30</b> to edge <b>43</b> of the base <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">In some embodiments, such as that depicted by <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, an adjacent coupled edge <b>25</b> of the duvet cover <b>20</b> may be defined by permanently securing corresponding (e.g., superimposed, etc.) edges <b>34</b> and <b>44</b> of the top <b>30</b> and base <b>40</b>, respectively, of the duvet cover <b>20</b> to each other. For example, substantially an entirety of the edge <b>35</b> (not shown) of the top <b>30</b> or an entirety of edge <b>35</b> (not shown) may be permanently secured to a same length (i.e., substantially an entirety or an entirety) of edge <b>45</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>) of the base <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The remaining edges of the duvet cover <b>20</b>, which edges may be referred to as &#x201c;fastening edges <b>24</b> and <b>26</b>,&#x201d; may have configurations that enable the edges <b>34</b> and <b>44</b>, <b>36</b> and <b>46</b> of the top <b>30</b> and base <b>40</b>, respectively, to be removably secured or reversibly to each other. For example, edges <b>34</b> and <b>44</b>, <b>36</b> and <b>46</b> may include cooperating elements of a fastener <b>27</b> (e.g., zipper halves, buttons and corresponding button holes, touch fasteners, ties, snaps, etc.), which may enable edges <b>34</b> and <b>44</b> and/or edges <b>36</b> and <b>46</b> to be selectively coupled to and uncoupled from each other.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">In other embodiments, like that shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, a duvet cover <b>20</b>&#x2032; may include a coupled edge <b>23</b>&#x2032; with a partially coupled edge <b>24</b>&#x2032;, <b>25</b>&#x2032; adjacent to each side of the coupled edge <b>24</b>&#x2032;. Each partially coupled edge <b>24</b>&#x2032;, <b>25</b>&#x2032; may include a coupled portion <b>24</b><i>c</i>&#x2032;, <b>25</b><i>c</i>&#x2032; (not shown) defined by a portion of the length of an edge <b>34</b>&#x2032;, <b>35</b>&#x2032; of the top <b>30</b>&#x2032; of the duvet cover <b>20</b>&#x2032; nearest to a corresponding end of the coupled edge <b>23</b>&#x2032; that is secured to a corresponding (e.g., superimposed, etc.) portion of the lengths of an edge <b>44</b>&#x2032;, <b>45</b>&#x2032; (not shown) of the base <b>40</b>&#x2032; of the duvet cover <b>20</b>&#x2032;. Without limitation, the coupled portion <b>24</b><i>c</i>&#x2032;, <b>25</b><i>c</i>&#x2032; (not shown) of each partially coupled edge <b>24</b>&#x2032;, <b>25</b>&#x2032; may comprise a tenth of the length of the coupled edge <b>24</b>&#x2032;, <b>25</b>&#x2032;, an eighth of its length, a sixth of its length, a fifth of its length, a fourth of its length, a third of its length, half of its length, etc., but not substantially all or all of its length.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The remainder of the length of the partially coupled edge <b>24</b>&#x2032;, <b>25</b>&#x2032; is defined by portions of the lengths of edges <b>34</b>&#x2032; and <b>44</b>&#x2032;, <b>35</b>&#x2032; and <b>45</b>&#x2032; (not shown) that may be selectively coupled to and uncoupled from each other, or removably secured or reversibly secured to each other, which portions may referred to as &#x201c;fastening portions <b>24</b><i>f</i>, <b>25</b><i>f</i>&#x201d; of the partially coupled edge <b>24</b>&#x2032;, <b>25</b>&#x2032;. Cooperating elements of one or more fasteners <b>27</b>&#x2032; (e.g., zipper halves, buttons and corresponding button holes, touch fasteners, ties, snaps, etc.) may enable the fastening portions <b>24</b><i>f </i>and <b>25</b><i>f </i>(partially shown) to be selectively opened (by uncoupling appropriate portions of edges <b>34</b>&#x2032; and <b>44</b>&#x2032; and/or edges <b>35</b>&#x2032; and <b>45</b>&#x2032; (not shown) from each other) or closed (by coupling appropriate portions of edges <b>34</b>&#x2032; and <b>44</b>&#x2032; and/or edges <b>35</b>&#x2032; and <b>45</b>&#x2032; (not shown) to each other).</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Likewise, the remaining edge <b>26</b>&#x2032; of the duvet cover <b>20</b>&#x2032;, which edge may be referred to as a &#x201c;fastening edge <b>26</b>&#x2032;,&#x201d; may have a configuration that enables the edges <b>36</b>&#x2032; and <b>46</b>&#x2032; of the top <b>30</b>&#x2032; and base <b>40</b>&#x2032;, respectively, of the duvet cover <b>20</b>&#x2032; to be removably secured or reversibly secured to each other. For example, edges <b>36</b>&#x2032; and <b>46</b>&#x2032; may include cooperating elements of one or more fasteners <b>27</b>&#x2032; (e.g., zipper halves, buttons and corresponding button holes, touch fasteners, ties, snaps, etc.), which may enable the edges <b>36</b>&#x2032; and <b>46</b>&#x2032; to be selectively coupled to and uncoupled from each other.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, the inner surface <b>42</b> of an embodiment of the base <b>40</b> of the duvet cover <b>20</b> is shown. Fasteners <b>50</b>, <b>52</b> are positioned over and carried by the inner surface <b>42</b> at or adjacent to the edges <b>43</b>, <b>44</b>, <b>45</b>, and <b>46</b> of the base <b>40</b>. The fasteners <b>50</b>, <b>52</b> may be touch fasteners, such as the hook elements of a so-called &#x201c;hook and loop&#x201d; touch fastener (e.g., VELCRO brand hook <b>42</b>A, etc.), with hooks that face in the same direction as the inner surface <b>42</b> of the base <b>40</b> (i.e., upwardly). Fasteners <b>50</b> may comprise strips that are positioned adjacent to corners of the base <b>40</b> and extend diagonally between each pair of adjoined edges <b>43</b> and <b>44</b>, <b>44</b> and <b>45</b>, <b>45</b> and <b>46</b>, <b>46</b> and <b>43</b> that form the corners of the base <b>40</b> (e.g., at 45&#xb0; angles to each pair of adjoined edges <b>43</b> and <b>44</b>, <b>44</b> and <b>45</b>, <b>45</b> and <b>46</b>, <b>46</b> and <b>43</b>; etc.). The ends of the fasteners <b>50</b> may be secured to the base <b>40</b> in a manner that defines a loop at each corner of the duvet cover <b>40</b>. In some embodiments, fastening elements of the fasteners <b>50</b> (e.g., hooks, etc.) may be located on both surfaces of the fasteners <b>50</b>, which may enable each fastener <b>50</b> to engage a complementary fastener (e.g., the binding <b>68</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> and described in further detail below, etc.) regardless of whether the complementary fastener is positioned over or under the fastener <b>50</b>. Fasteners <b>52</b> may be positioned more centrally and may be spaced apart at intermediate locations along each edge <b>43</b>, <b>44</b>, <b>45</b>, and <b>46</b> of the base <b>40</b>. As illustrated, each fastener <b>52</b> may have the shape of half a regular hexagon, or a &#x201c;half hex&#x201d; shape. By securing the fasteners <b>50</b>, <b>52</b> to the base <b>40</b> of the duvet cover <b>20</b>, any stitching, adhesives, or bonding that secures each fastener <b>50</b>, <b>52</b> to the base <b>40</b> may be hidden from view, under the duvet <b>10</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>) when the duvet <b>10</b> is placed over a mattress (not shown).</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> depicts another embodiment of a base <b>40</b>&#x2033; of a duvet cover <b>20</b>&#x2033;, showing an inner surface <b>42</b>&#x2033; of the base <b>40</b>&#x2033;. Fasteners <b>50</b>&#x2033; are positioned over the inner surface <b>42</b>&#x2033; at or adjacent to the edges <b>43</b>&#x2033;, <b>44</b>&#x2033;, <b>45</b>&#x2033;, and <b>46</b>&#x2033; of the base <b>40</b>&#x2033;, at corners of the base <b>40</b>&#x2033; and at intermediate locations along the length of each edge <b>43</b>&#x2033;, <b>44</b>&#x2033;, <b>45</b>&#x2033;, <b>46</b>&#x2033; of the base <b>40</b>&#x2033;. In some embodiments, each fastener <b>50</b>&#x2033; may be secured to the base <b>40</b>&#x2033; at a location (e.g., an edge, etc.) closest to its corresponding edge(s) <b>43</b>&#x2033;, <b>44</b>&#x2033;, <b>45</b>&#x2033;, <b>46</b>&#x2033;, while other portions (e.g., more centrally located portions, etc.) of the fastener <b>50</b>&#x2033; may remain unsecured to the base <b>40</b>&#x2033;, providing a tab. A fastener <b>50</b>&#x2033; that comprises a tab that may lie against the inner surface <b>42</b>&#x2033; in a first orientation, be moved (e.g., hingedly, etc.), and reoriented (e.g., upside-down, etc.) in a second orientation. Each fastener <b>50</b>&#x2033; may be secured to (e.g., sewn into, glued into, bonded within, etc.) a seam of its corresponding edge(s) <b>43</b>&#x2033;, <b>44</b>&#x2033;, <b>45</b>&#x2033;, <b>46</b>&#x2033;.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Each fastener <b>50</b>&#x2033; may comprise a touch fastener, such as the hook element of a so-called &#x201c;hook and loop&#x201d; touch fastener (e.g., VELCRO brand hook <b>42</b>A, etc.), with hooks that face in the same direction as the inner surface <b>42</b>&#x2033; of the base <b>40</b>&#x2033; (i.e., upwardly). In some embodiments, the engaging features (e.g., hooks, etc.) of each fastener <b>50</b>&#x2033; may also be oriented toward, or face the inner surface <b>42</b>&#x2033; of the base <b>40</b>&#x2033;.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">In some embodiments, the base <b>40</b>, <b>40</b>&#x2032;, <b>40</b>&#x2033; and the top <b>30</b>, <b>30</b>&#x2032; of the duvet cover <b>20</b>, <b>20</b>&#x2032;, <b>20</b>&#x2033; may comprise a single piece of fabric, with a fold defining an edge (e.g., the bottom edge <b>23</b>, <b>23</b>&#x2032;) of the duvet cover <b>20</b>, <b>20</b>&#x2032;, <b>20</b>&#x2033;.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">In various embodiments, the top <b>30</b>, <b>30</b>&#x2032; of the duvet cover <b>20</b>, <b>20</b>&#x2032;, <b>20</b>&#x2033; lacks visible seams or fasteners.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">With returned reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, along with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, the insert <b>60</b> of the duvet <b>10</b> includes a first surface <b>61</b> and a second surface <b>62</b>. Additionally, the insert <b>60</b> includes edges <b>63</b>, <b>64</b>, <b>65</b>, and <b>66</b>. Edge <b>63</b> may comprise a bottom edge, edge <b>64</b> may comprise a first side edge, edge <b>65</b> may comprise a second side edge, and edge <b>66</b> may comprise a top edge. The insert <b>60</b> may comprise any suitable insert for a duvet, such as a comforter, a blanket, or other bedding that will provide an individual with a desired amount of thermal insulation as the individual covers themselves with the duvet <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, a binding <b>68</b> may be provided over and carried by peripheral portions of the second surface <b>62</b> of the insert <b>60</b>, at or adjacent to one or more edges <b>63</b>, <b>64</b>, <b>65</b>, <b>66</b> (e.g., all edges, portions of all edges, opposite edges, portions of opposite edges, etc.) of the insert <b>60</b>. The binding <b>68</b> may comprise a fastener that cooperates with (e.g., engages, may be engaged by, etc.) fasteners <b>50</b>, <b>52</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>), <b>50</b>&#x2033; (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>) on the inner surface <b>42</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>), <b>42</b>&#x2033; (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>) on the base <b>40</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>), <b>40</b>&#x2033; (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>) of the duvet cover <b>20</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>), <b>20</b>&#x2033; (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>). In embodiments where the fasteners <b>50</b>, <b>52</b>, <b>50</b>&#x2032; comprise touch fasteners, such as hooks of hook and loop touch fasteners, the binding <b>68</b> may comprise complementary touch fasteners (e.g., loops, such as VELCRO brand loop <b>3905</b>, hooks, etc.) that may face in the same direction as the second surface <b>62</b> of the insert <b>60</b>. Thus, the fasteners of the binding <b>68</b> may be oriented to engage the fasteners <b>50</b>, <b>52</b>, <b>50</b>&#x2032; as the second surface <b>62</b> of the insert <b>60</b> is properly positioned over (e.g., in alignment with, etc.) and placed against the inner surface <b>42</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>), <b>42</b>&#x2033; (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>) of the base <b>40</b>, <b>40</b>&#x2033;. In the depicted embodiment, the binding <b>68</b> may have a width of about a half an inch (about 1.25 cm)&#xb1;0.0625 inch (about 2 mm).</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">In some embodiments, the binding <b>68</b> may wrap around one or more edges <b>63</b>, <b>64</b>, <b>65</b>, <b>66</b> of the insert <b>60</b>, with a portion of the binding <b>68</b> extending over a peripheral portion of the first surface <b>61</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>) of the insert <b>60</b>. Such an arrangement may provide the first surface <b>61</b> with the same appearance as the second surface <b>62</b>, such as that shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>. In such embodiments, the binding <b>68</b> may also secure the first surface <b>61</b> of the insert <b>60</b>, when the insert <b>60</b> is properly positioned over (e.g., in alignment with, etc.) the base <b>40</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>), <b>40</b>&#x2033; (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>), to the inner surface <b>42</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>), <b>42</b>&#x2033; (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>) of the base <b>40</b>, <b>40</b>&#x2033;.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">As an alternative to including a binding <b>68</b> or other fasteners at or adjacent to its edges <b>63</b>, <b>64</b>, <b>65</b>, <b>66</b>, the first surface <b>61</b> and/or second surface <b>62</b> of the insert <b>60</b> may be at least partially formed from a fabric (e.g., a fabric with loops, etc.) that can engage or be engaged by the fasteners <b>50</b>, <b>52</b> <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>), <b>50</b>&#x2033; (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>) on the inner surface <b>42</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>), <b>42</b>&#x2033; (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>) of the base <b>40</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>), <b>40</b>&#x2033; (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>) of the duvet cover <b>20</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>), <b>20</b>&#x2033; (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is a partial cross-sectional view depicting the manner in which the binding <b>68</b> of the insert <b>60</b> of the duvet <b>10</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>) and fasteners <b>50</b>, <b>52</b> of the base <b>40</b> of the duvet cover <b>20</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>) of the duvet <b>10</b> cooperate to secure the insert <b>60</b> in place within a receptacle <b>28</b> of the duvet cover <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">With reference again returned to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> and <b>2</b></figref>, a method for assembling a duvet <b>10</b> may include opening (e.g., unzipping, unbuttoning, unsnapping, etc.) fasteners <b>27</b>, <b>27</b>&#x2032; to open fastening edges <b>24</b>, <b>26</b>, <b>26</b>&#x2032; and/or partially coupled edges <b>24</b>&#x2032;, <b>25</b>&#x2032; of the duvet cover <b>20</b>, <b>20</b>&#x2032;.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">With the fastening edges <b>24</b>, <b>26</b>, <b>26</b>&#x2032; and/or partially coupled edges <b>24</b>&#x2032;, <b>25</b>&#x2032; open, the receptacle <b>28</b>, <b>28</b>&#x2032; of the duvet cover <b>20</b>, <b>20</b>&#x2032; may be accessed. In some embodiments, the top <b>30</b>, <b>30</b>&#x2032; of the duvet cover <b>20</b>, <b>20</b>&#x2032; may be pulled or folded over itself to expose a maximum portion of the inner surface <b>42</b>, <b>42</b>&#x2032; of the base <b>40</b>, <b>40</b>&#x2032; of the duvet cover <b>20</b>, <b>20</b>&#x2032;.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The insert <b>60</b> may then be aligned with the base <b>40</b>, <b>40</b>&#x2032; of the duvet cover <b>20</b>, <b>20</b>&#x2032;, positioned within the receptacle <b>28</b>, <b>28</b>&#x2032; of the duvet cover <b>20</b>, <b>20</b>&#x2032; and secured in place over the inner surface <b>42</b>, <b>42</b>&#x2032; of the base <b>40</b>, <b>40</b>&#x2032;. With added reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>3</b>-<b>6</b></figref>, In embodiments where the insert <b>60</b> includes one or more fasteners, such as the binding <b>68</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, the fastener of the insert <b>60</b> may be positioned over the fasteners <b>50</b>, <b>52</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>), <b>50</b>&#x2032; (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>) on the inner surface <b>42</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>), <b>42</b>&#x2032; (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>) of the base <b>40</b>, <b>40</b>&#x2032; of the duvet cover <b>20</b>, <b>20</b>&#x2032;. The fastener(s) of the insert <b>60</b> may be coupled to the fasteners <b>50</b>, <b>52</b>, <b>50</b>&#x2032; of the base <b>40</b>, <b>40</b>&#x2032;. In embodiments where the fastener(s) of the insert <b>60</b> and the fasteners <b>50</b>, <b>52</b>, <b>50</b>&#x2032; of the base <b>40</b>, <b>40</b>&#x2032; comprise touch fasteners, the fastener(s) of the insert <b>60</b> and the fasteners <b>50</b>, <b>52</b>, <b>50</b>&#x2032; of the base <b>40</b>, <b>40</b>&#x2032; may be secured to each other by simply placing them against each other or by additionally pressing them together.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">Once the insert <b>60</b> has been secured in place over the base <b>40</b>, <b>40</b>&#x2032; of the duvet cover <b>20</b>, <b>20</b>&#x2032;, the top <b>30</b>, <b>30</b>&#x2032; of the duvet cover <b>20</b>, <b>20</b>&#x2032; may be pulled over the insert <b>60</b>. The opening fasteners <b>27</b>, <b>27</b>&#x2032; may then be closed (e.g., zipped, buttoned, snapped, etc.) to close fastening edges <b>24</b>, <b>26</b>, <b>26</b>&#x2032; and/or partially coupled edges <b>24</b>&#x2032;, <b>25</b>&#x2032; of the duvet cover <b>20</b>, <b>20</b>&#x2032;.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">With continued reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>-<b>6</b></figref>, a method of removing a duvet cover <b>20</b>, <b>20</b>&#x2032; from an insert <b>60</b> of a duvet <b>10</b>, <b>10</b>&#x2032; may include opening (e.g., unzipping, unbuttoning, unsnapping, etc.) fasteners <b>27</b>, <b>27</b>&#x2032; to open fastening edges <b>24</b>, <b>26</b>, <b>26</b>&#x2032; and/or partially coupled edges <b>24</b>&#x2032;, <b>25</b>&#x2032; of the duvet cover <b>20</b>, <b>20</b>&#x2032;.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">With the fastening edges <b>24</b>, <b>26</b>, <b>26</b>&#x2032; and/or partially coupled edges <b>24</b>&#x2032;, <b>25</b>&#x2032; open, the receptacle <b>28</b>, <b>28</b>&#x2032; of the duvet cover <b>20</b>, <b>20</b>&#x2032; and the insert <b>60</b> therein may be accessed. In some embodiments, the top <b>30</b>, <b>30</b>&#x2032; of the duvet cover <b>20</b>, <b>20</b>&#x2032; may be pulled or folded over itself to expose a maximum portion of the insert <b>60</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The insert <b>60</b> may then be pulled out of the receptacle <b>28</b>, <b>28</b>&#x2032; of the duvet cover <b>20</b>, <b>20</b>&#x2032;, away from the inner surface <b>42</b>, <b>42</b>&#x2032; of the base <b>40</b>, <b>40</b>&#x2032; of the duvet cover <b>20</b>, <b>20</b>&#x2032;. In embodiments where the insert <b>60</b> includes one or more fasteners, such as the binding <b>68</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, the fastener of the insert <b>60</b> may be disengaged from the fasteners <b>50</b>, <b>52</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>), <b>50</b>&#x2032; (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>) on the inner surface <b>42</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>), <b>42</b>&#x2033; (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>) of the base <b>40</b>, <b>40</b>&#x2032; of the duvet cover <b>20</b>, <b>20</b>&#x2032;. In embodiments where the fastener(s) of the insert <b>60</b> and the fasteners <b>50</b>, <b>52</b>, <b>50</b>&#x2032; of the base <b>40</b>, <b>40</b>&#x2032; comprise touch fasteners, the fastener(s) of the insert <b>60</b> and the fasteners <b>50</b>, <b>52</b>, <b>50</b>&#x2032; of the base <b>40</b>, <b>40</b>&#x2032; may disengage each other simply by pulling them away from each other.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Once the insert <b>60</b> has been removed from the receptacle <b>28</b>, <b>28</b>&#x2032; of the duvet cover <b>20</b>, <b>20</b>&#x2032;, the duvet cover <b>20</b>, <b>20</b>&#x2032; may be cleaned (e.g., washed, dry cleaned, etc.) and then replaced on the insert <b>60</b>. Alternatively, another duvet cover <b>20</b>, <b>20</b>&#x2032; may be assembled with the insert <b>60</b>. The reassembled duvet <b>10</b>, <b>10</b>&#x2032; may then be placed over and used on a mattress.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">Although this disclosure provides many specifics, these should not be construed as limiting the scope of any of the claims that follow, but merely as providing illustrations of some embodiments of elements and features of the disclosed subject matter. Other embodiments of the disclosed subject matter, and of their elements and features, may be devised which do not depart from the spirit or scope of any of the claims. Features from different embodiments may be employed in combination. Accordingly, the scope of each claim is limited only by its plain language and the legal equivalents thereto.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A duvet, comprising:
<claim-text>a duvet cover including:
<claim-text>a base including:
<claim-text>a top edge with a first end and a second end;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first side edge with a top end and a bottom end, the top end of the first side edge adjoined to the first end of the top edge, the first side edge extending perpendicularly from the first end of the top edge;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second side edge with a top end and a bottom end, the top end of the second side edge adjoined to the second end of the top edge, the second side edge extending perpendicularly from the second end of the top edge; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a bottom edge with a first end and a second end, the first end of the bottom edge adjoined to the bottom end of the first side edge, the second end of the bottom edge adjoined to the bottom end of the second side edge, the bottom edge oriented perpendicularly to the first side edge and the second side edge;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a top including:
<claim-text>a top edge with a first end and a second end, the top edge positionable over and reversibly securable to the top edge of the base;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first side edge with a top end and a bottom end, the top end of the first side edge adjoined to the first end of the top edge, the first side edge extending perpendicularly from the first end of the top edge, the first side edge positionable over the first side edge of the base;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second side edge with a top end and a bottom end, the top end of the second side edge adjoined to the second end of the top edge, the second side edge extending perpendicularly from the second end of the top edge, the second side edge positionable over the second side edge of the base, at least portion of the second side edge reversibly securable to a corresponding portion of the second side edge of the base; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a bottom edge with a first end and a second end, the first end of the bottom edge adjoined to the bottom end of the first side edge, the second end of the bottom edge adjoined to the bottom end of the second side edge, the bottom edge oriented perpendicularly to the first side edge and the second side edge, the bottom edge superimposed with and permanently secured to the bottom edge of the base; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a receptacle between the base and the top; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>an insert positionable within the receptacle of the duvet cover.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The duvet of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein a portion of the first side edge of the top of the duvet cover is permanently secured to a corresponding portion of the first side edge of the base of the duvet cover.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The duvet of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein a portion of the second side edge of the top of the duvet cover is permanently secured to a corresponding portion of the second side edge of the base of the duvet cover.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The duvet of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein an entirety of the first side edge of the top of the duvet cover is superimposed with and permanently secured to the first side edge of the base of the duvet cover.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The duvet of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the top of the duvet cover is reversibly securable to the base of the duvet cover with fasteners that are not visible when the top is superimposed over the base.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The duvet of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the base and the top of the duvet cover comprise a single piece of fabric, with a fold defining the bottom edge of the base of the duvet cover and the bottom edge of the top of the duvet cover.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The duvet of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the top of the duvet cover lacks visible seams or fasteners.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The duvet of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein an inner surface of the base of the duvet cover carries a plurality of fasteners and a surface of the insert carries at least one fastener complementary to the plurality of fasteners of the base.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The duvet of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the fasteners of the base of the duvet cover comprise touch fasteners positioned at spaced apart locations at or adjacent to a periphery of the inner surface of the base of the duvet cover.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The duvet of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the touch fasteners comprise tabs with opposite surfaces that comprise fastening elements.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The duvet of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one fastener of the insert comprises a binding comprising a touch fastener at or adjacent to a periphery of the insert.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The duvet of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one fastener of the insert comprises a fabric of the insert.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. A duvet cover, comprising:
<claim-text>a base including:
<claim-text>a top edge with a first end and a second end;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first side edge with a top end and a bottom end, the top end of the first side edge adjoined to the first end of the top edge, the first side edge extending perpendicularly from the first end of the top edge;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second side edge with a top end and a bottom end, the top end of the second side edge adjoined to the second end of the top edge, the second side edge extending perpendicularly from the second end of the top edge; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a bottom edge with a first end and a second end, the first end of the bottom edge adjoined to the bottom end of the first side edge, the second end of the bottom edge adjoined to the bottom end of the second side edge, the bottom edge oriented perpendicularly to the first side edge and the second side edge;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a top including:
<claim-text>a top edge with a first end and a second end, the top edge positionable over and reversibly securable to the top edge of the base;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first side edge with a top end and a bottom end, the top end of the first side edge adjoined to the first end of the top edge, the first side edge extending perpendicularly from the first end of the top edge, the first side edge positionable over and reversibly securable to the first side edge of the base;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second side edge with a top end and a bottom end, the top end of the second side edge adjoined to the second end of the top edge, the second side edge extending perpendicularly from the second end of the top edge, the second side edge positionable over the second side edge of the base, at least portion of the second side edge superimposed with and permanently secured to a corresponding portion of the second side edge of the base; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a bottom edge with a first end and a second end, the first end of the bottom edge adjoined to the bottom end of the first side edge, the second end of the bottom edge adjoined to the bottom end of the second side edge, the bottom edge oriented perpendicularly to the first side edge and the second side edge, the bottom edge superimposed with and permanently secured to the bottom edge of the base; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a receptacle defined between the base and the top.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The duvet cover of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein an entirety of the second side edge of the top is superimposed with and permanently secured to the second side edge of the base.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. The duvet cover of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the top is reversibly securable to the base with fasteners that are not visible when the top is superimposed over the base.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. The duvet cover of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the base and the top comprise a single piece of fabric, with a fold defining the bottom edge of the base and the bottom edge of the top.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. The duvet cover of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the top lacks visible seams or fasteners.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. A duvet, comprising:
<claim-text>a duvet cover including:
<claim-text>a base including:
<claim-text>an inner surface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an outer surface opposite from the inner surface and defining a lower outer surface of the duvet cover; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one fastener secured to the inner surface of the base, adjacent to a periphery of the inner surface; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a top including:
<claim-text>an inner surface; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an outer surface opposite from the inner surface and defining an upper outer surface of the duvet cover; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a receptacle defined between the inner surface of the base and the inner surface of the top; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>an insert positionable within the receptacle of the duvet cover and including:
<claim-text>at least fastener secured to a surface of the insert adjacent to a periphery of the insert.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. The duvet of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one fastener of the duvet cover and the at least one fastener of the insert comprise complementary fasteners.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. The duvet of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein the complementary fasteners comprise complementary touch fasteners.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text><b>21</b>. The duvet of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00020">claim 20</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one fastener of the duvet cover comprises a plurality of touch fasteners positioned at spaced apart locations around the periphery of the inner surface of the base of the duvet cover.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text><b>22</b>. The duvet of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00021">claim 21</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of touch fasteners comprise tabs that may be moved between at least two orientations.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text><b>23</b>. The duvet of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00022">claim 22</claim-ref>, wherein the tabs include fastening features on opposite surfaces thereof.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024" num="00024">
<claim-text><b>24</b>. The duvet of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00021">claim 21</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of touch fasteners have half hex shapes.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025" num="00025">
<claim-text><b>25</b>. The duvet of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00021">claim 21</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of touch fasteners define loops at corners of the inner surface of the base of the duvet cover.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026" num="00026">
<claim-text><b>26</b>. The duvet of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00021">claim 21</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one touch fastener of the insert comprises a binding on the periphery of the insert.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027" num="00027">
<claim-text><b>27</b>. The duvet of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00026">claim 26</claim-ref>, wherein the binding extends over peripheral portions of opposite surfaces of the periphery of the insert.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028" num="00028">
<claim-text><b>28</b>. The duvet of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein the top of the duvet cover lacks visible seams or fasteners.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
