<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225443A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225443</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18149894</doc-number>
<date>20230104</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>42</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>24</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>42</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>24</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Button Accessory for Hat, Beanie, or Cap</invention-title>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>63301184</doc-number>
<date>20220120</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Eckdish</last-name>
<first-name>Joshua</first-name>
<address>
<city>W. Simsbury</city>
<state>CT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="01" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Eckdish</last-name>
<first-name>Lauren</first-name>
<address>
<city>W. Simsbury</city>
<state>CT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Eckdish</last-name>
<first-name>Joshua</first-name>
<address>
<city>W. Simsbury</city>
<state>CT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="01" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Eckdish</last-name>
<first-name>Lauren</first-name>
<address>
<city>W. Simsbury</city>
<state>CT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A button accessory that attaches to a hat, beanie, or cap and provides an anchor for the elastic loop straps of the commonly used facemask. The button accessory includes an internal button and an external button connected together through the fabric of the hat, beanie, or cap. In order to make the connection between the internal button and the external button, a post is attached to the internal button, and its distal end penetrates through the fabric of the hat. The external button has a post grip mechanism that engages the post to secure the button accessory to the hat, beanie, or cap. A pom attachment accessory provides for interchanging poms on a standard hat, beanie, or cap. A pom button is attached to the pom. A post button has a post that protrudes from the inside to the outside of the hat, beanie, or cap. The pom button engages the protruding post protruding post of a post button thereby releasably attaching the pom to the hat, beanie, or cap.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="201.93mm" wi="158.75mm" file="US20230225443A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="231.22mm" wi="173.57mm" file="US20230225443A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="230.63mm" wi="161.29mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225443A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="232.07mm" wi="152.99mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225443A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="234.87mm" wi="163.41mm" file="US20230225443A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="230.46mm" wi="142.92mm" file="US20230225443A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="242.99mm" wi="157.82mm" file="US20230225443A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="237.32mm" wi="146.81mm" file="US20230225443A1-20230720-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="208.20mm" wi="156.04mm" file="US20230225443A1-20230720-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CLAIM OF PRIORITY</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims priority from U.S. Provisional Patent Application Ser. No. 63/301,184, filed Jan. 20, 2022, which is incorporated herein in its entirety.</p>
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="tail"?>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">This invention generally relates to a button accessory that attaches to a hat, beanie, or cap. More particularly, the invention relates to a button accessory that facilitates the attachment of a facemask with elastic loop straps to the hat, beanie, or cap to hold the facemask in place on a user's face. In another embodiment of the button accessory, the button accessory releasably attaches a pom to the top of the hat, beanie, or cap.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">A commonly used facemask includes a face cover portion that covers the nose and mouth of the user and elastic loop straps. The elastic loop straps stretch from the face cover portion of the facemask to extend around the ears of the user in order to secure the facemask in place. The connection between the user's ears and the elastic loop straps becomes difficult when the user dons a hat, beanie, or cap that covers the user's ears. The situation is further complicated if the user wears spectacles.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Attaching the elastic loop straps to the user's ears require the removal and replacement of the hat, beanie or cap. Removal of the elastic loop straps from the user's ears requires careful manipulation so that the elastic loop straps do not become entangled with the bows of a user's spectacles.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In order to add style to a hat, beanie, or cap, a pom is often attached to the top of the hat, beanie, or cap. Typically the pom is permanently affixed to the top thereby limiting the range of colors and styles of the pom. In some instances, specialized beanies exist that have a fastener permanently fixed to the top of the beanie. A series of poms with a matching fastener can then be exchanged with the specialized beanie in order to create different looks. The exchanging of various poms, however, is only available for the specialized beanie with the permanent fastener.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In order to overcome the difficulties relating to the attachment and removal of the elastic loop straps of the facemask to and from the user's ears, the current invention is a button accessory that attaches to a hat, beanie, or cap and provides an anchor for the elastic loop straps of the commonly used facemask. More particularly, the button accessory includes an internal button and an external button connected together through the fabric of the hat, beanie, or cap. In order to make the connection between the internal button and the external button, a post is attached to the internal button, and its distal end penetrates through the fabric of the hat, beanie, or cap. The post has an engagement mechanism along its length. The external button has a post grip mechanism that grips the engagement mechanism of the post to secure the button accessory to the hat, beanie, or cap. The attachment of the external button to the post may include a frictional fit between the post and an opening in the external button, grooves on the post and a clamp embedded in the external button, or external threads on the post and internal threads embedded in the external button.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The internal button has a head side surface that is adjacent the user's head when the button accessory is fitted to the hat, beanie, or cap, and the hat, beanie, or cap is worn by the user. The head side surface is generally soft and flexible in order to assure comfort where the inside surface contacts the user's head. The head side surface may be printed or embossed with suitable designs or text. The internal button also has an internal fabric side surface that is adjacent the fabric of the hat, beanie, or cap when the button accessory is attached to the hat, beanie, or cap.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The external button has an outer side surface that is configured so that the distal end of the post is covered to ensure that the post does not come in contact with a user or others once the button accessory is in place on the hat, beanie, or cap. The outer side surface may be printed or embossed with suitable designs or text to enhance the aesthetic or commercial value of the button accessory. The external button also has an internal fabric side surface that is adjacent the fabric of the hat, beanie, or cap when the button accessory is attached to the hat, beanie, or cap.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Once the button accessory is in place on the hat, beanie, or cap, the user simply wraps the elastic loop straps of the commonly used facemask around the external button thereby holding the facemask in place on the user's face.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In a second embodiment, the present invention includes a pom attachment accessory that releasably secures a pom to the top the hat, beanie, or cap. Particularly, the pom attachment accessory includes a post button and a pom button. The post button includes a base with an extending post. The post includes a securing mechanism that may include external threads, an external friction surface, or an enlarged snap-like head. The pom button includes openings to secure the pom button to a pom and a post gripping mechanism that engages the securing mechanism of the post and may include internal threads, an internal friction surface, or a snap-like receptacle.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In use, the user can secure a number of different poms to a standard hat, beanie, or cap to produce different fashion effects. The user pushes the post of the post button through the top of the hat, beanie, or cap from the inside out thereby exposing the post. The user then pushes or threads the post gripping mechanism with its attached pom onto the post to secure the pom to the hat, beanie, or cap. The pom can then be removed and interchanged with a different pom having a compatible pom button.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Further objects, features and advantages will become apparent upon consideration of the following detailed description of the invention when taken in conjunction with the drawings and the appended claims.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a side perspective view of a beanie and a facemask with a button accessory for attaching the facemask to the beanie in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is an outside surface perspective view of an external button of the button accessory for attaching the facemask to the beanie in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is an outside surface elevation view of the external button of the button accessory for attaching the facemask to the beanie in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is a side elevation view of the external button of the button accessory for attaching the facemask to the beanie in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is a section view of the external button of the button accessory for attaching the facemask to the beanie as seen along line <b>5</b>-<b>5</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is a fabric side surface elevation view of the external button of the button accessory for attaching the facemask to the beanie in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> is a fabric side surface perspective view of an internal button of the button accessory for attaching the facemask to the beanie in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> is a head side surface perspective view of the internal button of the button accessory for attaching the facemask to the beanie in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref> is a fabric side surface elevation view of the internal button of the button accessory for attaching the facemask to the beanie in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref> is a side elevation view of the internal button of the button accessory for attaching the facemask to the beanie in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b></figref> is an exploded side elevation view of the button accessory in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>12</b></figref> is a side elevation view of the button accessory attached to a hat, beanie, or cap in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>13</b></figref> is a front perspective view of a beanie porn attachment accessory with a detachable, interchangeable porn in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>14</b></figref> is a bottom plan view of a porn button in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>15</b></figref> is a section view of the porn button as seen along line <b>15</b>-<b>15</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>14</b></figref> in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>16</b></figref> is a side elevation view of a post button in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>17</b></figref> is an exploded side elevation view of the porn button accessory in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>18</b></figref> is a side elevation view of the porn button accessory attached to a beanie in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>19</b></figref> is an enlarged side elevation view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>18</b></figref> in accordance with the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> illustrates a button accessory <b>20</b> used to attach a facemask <b>12</b> to a beanie <b>10</b> constructed of a fabric <b>11</b>. While <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> shows a beanie <b>10</b>, the button accessory <b>20</b> will function equally well for a hat or cap, such as a baseball cap. The facemask <b>12</b> is a commonly used facemask with a face cover portion <b>14</b> for covering a user's nose and mouth and elastic loop straps <b>16</b> for attaching the facemask <b>12</b> to the ears of a user. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, the elastic loop straps <b>16</b> are connected to the button accessories <b>20</b> attached to either side of the beanie <b>10</b> adjacent the user's ears. The button accessory <b>20</b> comprises an internal button <b>22</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>7</b>-<b>10</b></figref>) and an external button <b>34</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>-<b>6</b></figref>). The button accessory <b>20</b> can be placed at any position on the beanie <b>10</b> to accommodate the particular user and the particular facemask <b>12</b> being used. If conditions change, the button accessory <b>20</b> can be removed from its position and repositioned on the beanie <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>7</b>-<b>10</b></figref> show details of the internal post button <b>22</b>. The internal post button <b>22</b> has a circular base <b>23</b> with a head side surface <b>30</b> and an internal fabric side surface <b>32</b>. A button post <b>24</b> extends from the base <b>23</b> and has a distal end <b>28</b>. The distal end <b>28</b> is pointed in order to penetrate the fabric <b>11</b> of the beanie <b>10</b>. The button post <b>24</b> has an engagement mechanism <b>26</b>. For the button post <b>24</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>7</b>-<b>10</b></figref>, the engagement mechanism <b>26</b> is the outer surface of the button post <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>-<b>6</b></figref> show details of the external button <b>34</b>. The external button <b>34</b> has a circular external button base <b>35</b> with an external fabric side surface <b>44</b> and an outer side surface <b>42</b>. The external button <b>34</b> also has a post gripping mechanism <b>36</b> in the form of an inwardly tapering hole <b>37</b>. A flange <b>46</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b> and <b>5</b></figref>) encircles the inwardly tapered hole <b>37</b> and extends outward from the external fabric side surface <b>44</b>. The flange <b>46</b> provides a space to accommodate the elastic loop straps <b>16</b> of the facemask <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b></figref> is an exploded view of the button accessory <b>20</b>. As previously stated, the button accessory <b>20</b> includes a circular internal button <b>22</b> and a circular external button <b>34</b>. When in place on the beanie <b>10</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>12</b></figref>), the internal button <b>22</b> is positioned inside the beanie <b>10</b> and the external button <b>34</b> is positioned on the outside of the beanie <b>10</b> with the beanie fabric <b>11</b> sandwiched between the internal button <b>22</b> and the exterior button <b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>11</b> and <b>12</b></figref>, the internal button <b>22</b> has a soft flexible head side surface <b>30</b> and an internal fabric side surface <b>32</b>. When the button accessory <b>20</b> is attached to the beanie <b>10</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>12</b></figref>), the head side surface <b>30</b> of the internal button <b>22</b> is in contact with the user's head. Consequently, the head side surface <b>30</b> is soft and flexible to assure comfort for the user. Further, when the button accessory <b>20</b> is attached to the beanie <b>10</b>, the internal fabric side surface <b>32</b> of the internal button <b>22</b> is in contact with the fabric <b>11</b> of the beanie <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">With continuing reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>11</b> and <b>12</b></figref>, the internal button <b>22</b> has a post <b>24</b> extending outwardly from the internal fabric side surface <b>32</b>. The post <b>24</b> has a pointed distal end <b>28</b> so that the post <b>24</b> can penetrate through the fabric <b>11</b> of the beanie <b>10</b>. The post <b>24</b> has an engagement mechanism <b>26</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b></figref>) located between the distal end <b>28</b> and the internal fabric side surface <b>32</b>. For example, the engagement mechanism <b>26</b> can take the form of a friction surface, grooves, or threads.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>11</b> and <b>12</b></figref>, the external button <b>34</b> has an external fabric side surface <b>44</b> and an outer side surface <b>42</b>. The outer side surface <b>42</b> of the external button <b>34</b> is composed of a printable surface on which designs or text <b>48</b> can be printed or embossed with text <b>48</b> or a design (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>). A post grip mechanism <b>36</b> is embedded at the center of the external button <b>34</b>. The post grip mechanism <b>36</b> can take the form of an opening with an internal friction surface for engaging the engagement mechanism <b>26</b> on the post <b>24</b>, a clamp for engaging the engagement mechanism <b>26</b> on the post <b>24</b>, or internal threads for engaging the engagement mechanism <b>26</b> on the post <b>24</b>. The outer side surface <b>42</b> of external button <b>34</b> also has a protective center cover <b>40</b> to assure that the pointed distal end <b>28</b> of the post <b>24</b> does not extend beyond the outer side surface <b>42</b> to create a hazard for the user or others.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">In a second embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>13</b>-<b>19</b></figref>, the present invention includes a pom attachment accessory <b>52</b> that secures a pom <b>50</b> to the top the beanie <b>10</b>. Particularly, the pom attachment accessory <b>52</b> includes a post button <b>60</b> and a pom button <b>54</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>16</b></figref> shows the details of the post button <b>60</b> that is attached to the top of the beanie <b>10</b>. Particularly, the post button <b>60</b> has a base <b>64</b> with the protruding post <b>62</b>. The post button <b>60</b> is positioned inside the top of the beanie <b>10</b> with the post <b>62</b> protruding upward from and out of the top of the beanie <b>10</b>. The post button <b>60</b> further has a securing mechanism which as shown includes an enlarged snap-like head <b>68</b>. Other securing mechanisms include, for example, external threads or external friction surface.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>14</b>-<b>15</b></figref> show the details of the pom button <b>54</b> that is attached to the pom. Particularly, the pom button <b>54</b> has a base <b>56</b> with openings <b>56</b>. The openings <b>56</b> are used to secure the pom button <b>54</b> to the pom <b>50</b>, such as by stitching. The pom button <b>54</b> further has a post gripping mechanism <b>58</b>, which in this case is a reduced cross-section receptacle that engages the enlarged snap-like head <b>68</b> of the post button <b>60</b>. Again other gripping mechanisms, for example, include internal threads or internal friction surface.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>16</b>-<b>18</b></figref>, the post button <b>60</b> includes a base <b>64</b> with an extending post <b>62</b>. The post <b>62</b> includes a securing mechanism <b>66</b> in the form of an enlarged snap-like head <b>68</b>. The securing mechanism <b>66</b>, however, may include external threads or a friction surface.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">In use, the user can secure a number of different poms <b>50</b> with an attached pom attachment accessory <b>52</b> to a standard hat, beanie, or cap <b>10</b> to produce different fashion effects. The user pushes the post <b>62</b> of the post button <b>60</b> through the top of the beanie <b>10</b> from the inside out thereby exposing the post <b>62</b>. The user then pushes the post gripping mechanism <b>58</b> with its attached pom <b>50</b> onto the post <b>62</b> to secure the pom <b>50</b> to the beanie <b>10</b> by means of the enlarged snap-like head <b>68</b> and the snap-like receptacle <b>70</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">While this invention has been described with reference to preferred embodiments thereof, it is to be understood that variations and modifications can be affected within the spirit and scope of the invention as described herein and as described in the appended claims.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>We claim:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A button accessory for a hat, beanie, or cap for securing a facemask to a user, wherein the hat, beanie, or cap is made of a fabric and the facemask has a face cover portion and elastic loop straps, the button accessory comprising:
<claim-text>a. an internal button including:
<claim-text>i. a head side surface to be positioned adjacent the user's head;</claim-text>
<claim-text>ii. an internal fabric side surface to be positioned adjacent the fabric of the hat, beanie, or cap; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>iii. a post attached to and extending away from the internal fabric side surface, the post including:
<claim-text>(a) a distal end for penetrating the fabric; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) an engagement mechanism adjacent the distal end; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>b. an external button including:
<claim-text>i. an outer side surface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>ii. an exterior fabric side surface; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>iii. a post grip mechanism for engaging the distal end of the post; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the elastic loop straps of the facemask engage the external button to hold the facemask in place.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The button accessory according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the outer side surface of the external button is printed or embossed.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The button accessory according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the engagement mechanism of the post includes external threads, a friction surface, or an enlarged snap-like head.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The button accessory according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the post gripping mechanism includes internal threads, and internal friction surface, or a snap-like receptacle.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The button accessory according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the external button includes a central flange to accommodate the straps of the facemask.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. A pom attachment accessory for a hat, beanie, or cap for providing interchangeable poms for a standard hat, beanie, or cap, wherein the hat, beanie, or cap is made of a fabric, the pom attachment accessory comprising:
<claim-text>a. an internal post button including:
<claim-text>i. a base to be positioned inside the parent or beanie adjacent a user's head;</claim-text>
<claim-text>ii. a post extending away from the base, the post including:
<claim-text>(a) a distal end for penetrating the fabric in protruding from the hat, beanie, or cap; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) a securing mechanism adjacent the distal end; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>b. an external pom button with an attached pom, the pom button including a post gripping mechanism for engaging the distal end of the post.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The pom attachment accessory according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the securing mechanism of the post includes external threads, a friction surface, or an enlarged snap-like head.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The button accessory according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the post gripping mechanism includes internal threads, and internal friction surface, or a snap-like receptacle.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
