<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225298A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225298</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18158545</doc-number>
<date>20230124</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>SG</country>
<doc-number>10201804724U</doc-number>
<date>20180604</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>61</main-group>
<subgroup>10</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>63</main-group>
<subgroup>04</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20170101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>61</main-group>
<subgroup>10</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>63</main-group>
<subgroup>04</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e61">AQUATIC FARMING IN INTERMODAL CONTAINERS</invention-title>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>16972244</doc-number>
<date>20201204</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11589561</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18158545</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Temasek Life Sciences Laboratory Limited</orgname>
<address>
<city>Singapore</city>
<country>SG</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>SG</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Goh</last-name>
<first-name>Chin Heng</first-name>
<address>
<city>Singapore</city>
<country>SG</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Temasek Life Sciences Laboratory Limited</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Singapore</city>
<country>SG</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The present invention generally relates to an aquatic farming system (<b>200</b>) comprising one or more stacked levels of an array of one or more aquatic farming modules (<b>100</b>). Each aquatic farming module (<b>100</b>) comprises an intermodal container (<b>102</b>) comprising a pair of opposing side walls (<b>104</b>) and a pair of opposing end entrances (<b>106</b>), and a housing structure (<b>110</b>) disposed in the intermodal container (<b>102</b>) and extending between the side walls (<b>104</b>) thereof. The aquatic farming module (<b>100</b>) further comprises a set of access doors (<b>130</b>) disposed at one or both end entrances (<b>106</b>) of the intermodal container (<b>100</b>), the access doors (<b>130</b>) actuatable planarly for selectively opening/closing the respective end entrances (<b>106</b>). Selective opening/closing of the end entrances (<b>106</b>) of the intermodal containers (<b>102</b>) in each stacked level facilitates user accessibility to the housing structures (<b>110</b>) in said stacked level for farming aquatic organisms.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="103.21mm" wi="152.57mm" file="US20230225298A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="132.67mm" wi="154.43mm" file="US20230225298A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="229.53mm" wi="124.97mm" file="US20230225298A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="119.21mm" wi="168.15mm" file="US20230225298A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="231.06mm" wi="119.72mm" file="US20230225298A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="158.58mm" wi="152.23mm" file="US20230225298A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="133.43mm" wi="122.60mm" file="US20230225298A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention claims the benefit of Singapore Patent Application No. 10201804724U filed on 4 Jun. 2018, which is incorporated in its entirety by reference herein.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention generally relates to aquatic farming. More particularly, the present invention describes various embodiments of an aquatic farming system having aquatic farming modules and intermodal containers in stacked levels for farming aquatic organisms.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Fisheries around the world are facing declining amounts of wild fish stocks, resulting in less fish being harvested from the oceans. Many rivers and seas are being polluted with industrial and agricultural waste, and this has led to toxic algal blooms that have killed fishes being grown for food. Toxic or harmful algal blooms are organisms that can severely lower oxygen levels and release toxins into natural waters, and kill marine life. Rising sea temperatures further exacerbate the situation, limiting aquaculture production or aquatic farming to meet ever increasing human population. Urbanization is also taking away traditional farming land for industrialization and housing purposes. This has a significant negative impact on countries that have a small land area and at the same time an increasing population. This means that aquatic farming must be conducted on a small land area and at increasing densities to produce enough aquatic organisms for consumption.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Various methods have been used to grow fish in tanks on land. Many of these tanks are built by casting in heavy cement and require expensive structural support. They are also purpose-built for specific locations and cannot be easily relocated. As these tanks are permanently located on land, they require large amounts of water for daily changes to maintain good water conditions for fish grown in the tanks.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">U.S. Pat. No. 9,089,113 describes a food production system housed in one or more intermodal shipping containers. Multiple containers can be stacked vertically, end-to-end, or side-to-side. Each container may be provided with one or more access doors. However, the doors merely permit user accessibility to the respective container and hinder user accessibility to other containers that are stacked together.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Therefore, in order to address or alleviate at least one of the aforementioned problems and/or disadvantages, there is a need to provide an improved aquatic farming system.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">According to an aspect of the present invention, there is an aquatic farming system comprising a set of aquatic farming modules arranged in one or more stacked levels, each stacked level comprising an array of one or more aquatic farming modules. Each aquatic farming module comprises an intermodal container comprising a pair of opposing side walls and a pair of opposing end entrances, and a housing structure disposed in the intermodal container and extending between the side walls thereof. The housing structure comprises a first compartment for storing water and aquatic organisms, and a second compartment adjacent to the first compartment for installing a set of water treatment mechanisms to treat the water in the first compartment. The aquatic farming module further comprises a set of access doors disposed at one or both end entrances of the intermodal container, the access doors actuatable planarly for selectively opening/closing the respective end entrances. For each stacked level of aquatic farming modules, selective opening/closing of the end entrances of the intermodal containers in said stacked level facilitates user accessibility to the housing structures in said stacked level for farming the aquatic organisms.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In some embodiments, each access door comprises a roller shutter coupled to an upper portion of the respective end entrance, the roller shutter actuatable vertically at the respective end entrance. In one embodiment, each aquatic farming module may further comprise one or more external access platforms integrally formed with or permanently attached to the housing structure or intermodal container. Each external access platform may be attached to the housing structure or intermodal container by a hinge component such that the external access platform is rotatable about a lateral hinge axis. In another embodiment, each aquatic farming module may further comprise one or more external access platforms coupleable to bottom portions of the end entrances of the intermodal container.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In some embodiments, each housing structure further comprises multiple structural elements forming the first and second compartments. The structural elements in each housing structure may comprise a first longitudinal panel adjacent to one side wall of the intermodal container and bounding the first compartment, and a second longitudinal panel adjacent to the other side wall of the intermodal container and bounding the second compartment. The structural elements in each housing structure may further comprise a third longitudinal panel interposing the first and second longitudinal panels to separate the first and second compartments.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In some embodiments, the structural elements in each housing structure further comprise one or more first partition panels dividing the first compartment into a plurality of first sub-compartments for storing a plurality of groups of aquatic organisms. The first partition panels may be removably installed in the first compartment for selectively dividing the first compartment into the first sub-compartments. The structural elements in each housing structure may further comprise one or more second partition panels dividing the second compartment into a plurality of second sub-compartments for installing the water treatment mechanisms. Each second partition panel may comprise an opening for connecting the water treatment mechanisms to one another.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In some embodiments, the structural elements in each housing structure comprise a platform panel disposed on the second compartment to facilitate user accessibility through the intermodal container. The structural elements in each housing structure may be welded to one another. The structural elements may comprise a polyethylene or polypropylene material.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In some embodiments, each aquatic farming module further comprises a protective layer lining interior surfaces of the intermodal container. The protective layer may comprise a corrosion-resistant material, such as epoxy or polyurethane.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In some embodiments, the aquatic farming system further comprises a set of external systems connectable to the housing structures via the end entrances of the intermodal containers. The aquatic farming system may further comprise a set of external modules arranged with the aquatic farming modules for housing the external systems. The external systems may comprise a water recycling system and/or waste recycling system.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">An advantage of the present invention is that multiple aquatic farming modules can be arranged together in arrays and stacked levels to reduce spatial footprint. The modular configuration of the aquatic farming system allows each aquatic farming module to be easily replaced and the aquatic farming system to be relocated. Multiple aquatic farming modules provides greater capacity to farm large amounts of aquatic organisms, thereby increasing food production for people.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">An aquatic farming system according to the present invention is thus disclosed herein. Various features, aspects, and advantages of the present invention will become more apparent from the following detailed description of the embodiments of the present invention, by way of non-limiting examples only, along with the accompanying drawings.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is an illustration of a perspective view of an aquatic farming module, in accordance with various embodiments of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is an illustration of a perspective view of an interior of the aquatic farming module, in accordance with various embodiments of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is an illustration of an opposite perspective view of the interior of the aquatic farming module, in accordance with various embodiments of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is an illustration of a top planar view of the interior of the aquatic farming module, in accordance with various embodiments of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is an illustration of an end view of the interior of the aquatic farming module, in accordance with various embodiments of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is an illustration of an opposite end view of the interior of the aquatic farming module, in accordance with various embodiments of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> is an illustration of a perspective view of an aquatic farming system, in accordance with various embodiments of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> is an illustration of a lateral view of another aquatic farming system, in accordance with various embodiments of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">In the present invention, depiction of a given element or consideration or use of a particular element number in a particular figure or a reference thereto in corresponding descriptive material can encompass the same, an equivalent, or an analogous element or element number identified in another figure or descriptive material associated therewith. The use of &#x201c;/&#x201d; in a figure or associated text is understood to mean &#x201c;and/or&#x201d; unless otherwise indicated.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">As used herein, the terms &#x201c;comprising&#x201d;, &#x201c;including&#x201d;, &#x201c;having&#x201d;, and the like do not exclude the presence of other components/elements/features than those listed in an embodiment. Recitation of certain components/elements/features in mutually different embodiments does not indicate that a combination of these components/elements/features cannot be used in an embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">As used herein, the terms &#x201c;a&#x201d; and &#x201c;an&#x201d; are defined as one or more than one. The term &#x201c;set&#x201d; corresponds to or is defined as a non-empty finite organization of elements that mathematically exhibits a cardinality of at least one (e.g. a set as defined herein can correspond to a unit, singlet, or single element set, or a multiple element set), in accordance with known mathematical definitions. The recitation of a particular numerical value or value range herein is understood to include or be a recitation of an approximate numerical value or value range.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">For purposes of brevity and clarity, descriptions of embodiments of the present invention are directed to an aquatic farming system in accordance with the drawings. While aspects of the present invention will be described in conjunction with the embodiments provided herein, it will be understood that they are not intended to limit the present invention to these embodiments. On the contrary, the present invention is intended to cover alternatives, modifications and equivalents to the embodiments described herein, which are included within the scope of the present invention as defined by the appended claims. Furthermore, in the following detailed description, specific details are set forth in order to provide a thorough understanding of the present invention. However, it will be recognized by an individual having ordinary skill in the art, i.e. a skilled person, that the present invention may be practiced without specific details, and/or with multiple details arising from combinations of aspects of particular embodiments. In a number of instances, known systems, methods, procedures, and components have not been described in detail so as to not unnecessarily obscure aspects of the embodiments of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">In various representative or exemplary embodiments of the present invention with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, there is an aquatic farming module or unit <b>100</b> for farming aquatic organisms including aquatic plants and animals. For example, the aquatic farming module <b>100</b> is configured for farming aquatic animals such as fish, crustaceans, and other aquatic species.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The aquatic farming module <b>100</b> comprises an intermodal container <b>102</b>. The intermodal container <b>102</b> is a large standardized shipping container for intermodal freight transport and may also be referred to as a freight container or ISO container. The intermodal container <b>102</b> may be of various standardized sizes, such as 20-foot or 40-foot. For example, a 20-foot intermodal container has an approximate length of 6 meters, an approximate width of 2.4 meters, and an approximate height of 2.6 meters. A 40-foot intermodal container is twice the length of the 20-foot version but with the same width and height. Other standardized sizes may be used depending on the interior space required for the aquatic farming module 100, such as 40-foot high-cube or 45-foot high-cube.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The intermodal container <b>102</b> comprises a pair of opposing side walls <b>104</b> extending longitudinally along the length of the intermodal container <b>102</b>. The intermodal container <b>102</b> further comprises a pair of opposing end entrances <b>106</b> extending laterally along the width of the intermodal container <b>102</b>. The end entrances <b>106</b> are selectively openable/closeable to facilitate user accessibility into the intermodal container <b>102</b>. Users of the aquatic farming module <b>100</b> may comprise working personnel, e.g. operators and maintenance staff, and visitors from the general public who wants to see how aquatic organisms are farmed from the aquatic farming module <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The intermodal container <b>102</b> is made of corrugated sheet metal with a galvanized iron or mild steel material. The intermodal container <b>102</b> further comprises eight corner castings <b>108</b> positioned at the eight corners of the intermodal container <b>102</b>. The corner castings <b>108</b> provide lifting and securing points for the intermodal container <b>102</b>, such as for transportation. Further, the corner castings <b>108</b> allow the intermodal container <b>102</b> to be connected to other intermodal containers <b>102</b> side-by-side or end-to-end. Yet further, the corner castings <b>108</b> are configured to withstand stacking loads when multiple intermodal containers <b>102</b> are stacked vertically. The corner castings <b>108</b> may be made from a steel material that is casted or forged.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">In some embodiments, the aquatic farming module <b>100</b> further comprises a protective layer lining interior surfaces of the intermodal container <b>102</b>. As the intermodal container <b>102</b> is made of galvanized iron or mild steel material which is prone to corrosion/rust, the protective layer protects the interior surfaces of the intermodal container <b>102</b> from corrosion/rusting and mitigates the risk of the aquatic organisms being contaminated by corrosive substances/rust. The aquatic farming module <b>100</b> may be used in a seawater environment, such as on ships or barges, and seawater or saltwater tends to facilitate corrosion. The protective layer may comprise a corrosion-resistant or anti-corrosion material such as epoxy or polyurethane.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The aquatic farming module <b>100</b> further comprises a housing structure <b>110</b> disposed in the intermodal container <b>102</b> and extending between the side walls <b>104</b> of the intermodal container <b>102</b>. In one embodiment, the housing structure <b>110</b> abuts and adheres to the side walls <b>104</b>. In another embodiment, the housing structure <b>110</b> partially abuts the side walls <b>104</b> without adhering thereto. In yet another embodiment, the housing structure <b>110</b> is adjacent to, but without abutting/adhering, the side walls <b>104</b>, such that small spaces are formed between the housing structure <b>110</b> and the side walls <b>104</b>. The small spaces allow for thermal expansion and contraction of the intermodal container <b>102</b> and housing structure <b>110</b> when the aquatic farming module <b>100</b> is subjected to different environmental conditions. Disposing the housing structure <b>110</b> close to the side walls <b>104</b> maximizes the available space in the housing structure <b>110</b> so that more aquatic organisms can be farmed.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Further with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, the housing structure <b>110</b> comprises a first compartment <b>112</b> for storing water and aquatic organisms. The housing structure <b>110</b> further comprises a second compartment <b>114</b> adjacent to the first compartment <b>112</b> for installing a set of water treatment mechanisms to treat the water in the first compartment <b>112</b>. The housing structure <b>110</b> further comprises multiple structural elements forming the first compartment <b>112</b> and second compartment <b>114</b>. Alternatively, the first compartment <b>112</b> and second compartment <b>114</b> may be formed as an integrated structure or formed integrally with the intermodal container <b>102</b>. The structural elements comprise a floor panel forming the base of the housing structure <b>110</b>, including that of the first compartment <b>112</b> and second compartment <b>114</b>. The floor panel distributes the weight or load of the first compartment <b>112</b> and second compartment <b>114</b> over the floor/base of the intermodal container <b>102</b>. The housing structure <b>110</b> may be fastened or secured to the floor/base of the intermodal container <b>102</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Further with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>, the structural elements further comprise a first longitudinal panel <b>116</b> adjacent to one side wall <b>104</b> of the intermodal container <b>102</b> and bounding the first compartment <b>112</b>, and a second longitudinal panel <b>118</b> adjacent to the other side wall <b>104</b> of the intermodal container <b>102</b> and bounding the second compartment <b>114</b>. In one embodiment, the first longitudinal panel <b>116</b> and second longitudinal panel <b>118</b> are attached to the respective side walls <b>104</b>, such as by an adhesive. In another embodiment, the first longitudinal panel <b>116</b> and second longitudinal panel <b>118</b> partially abuts the respective side walls <b>104</b> without adhering thereto. In yet another embodiment, the first longitudinal panel <b>116</b> and second longitudinal panel <b>118</b> are adjacent to, but without abutting, the respective side walls <b>104</b>. Small spaces are thus formed between the side walls <b>104</b> and the first longitudinal panel <b>116</b> and second longitudinal panel <b>118</b> to allow for thermal expansion and contraction in different environmental conditions. Disposing the first longitudinal panel <b>116</b> and second longitudinal panel <b>118</b> adjacent close to the respective side walls <b>104</b> maximizes the available space in the first compartment <b>112</b> and second compartment <b>114</b> so that more aquatic organisms can be farmed.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The structural elements further comprise a third longitudinal panel <b>120</b> interposing the first longitudinal panel <b>116</b> and second longitudinal panel <b>118</b> to separate the first compartment <b>112</b> and second compartment <b>114</b>. The structural elements further comprise some lateral panels <b>122</b> bounding the first compartment <b>112</b>. Particularly, the first compartment <b>112</b> is bounded by the first longitudinal panel <b>116</b>, third longitudinal panel <b>120</b>, and lateral panels <b>122</b>. In one embodiment, the lateral panels <b>122</b> also bound the second compartment <b>114</b> such that the second compartment <b>114</b> forms an L-shaped profile adjacent to the first compartment <b>112</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>. One or more of the lateral panels <b>122</b> may be reinforced, such as with structural bracings, as the lateral panels <b>122</b> are not positioned adjacent to a structural component of the intermodal container <b>102</b>, unlike the first longitudinal panel <b>116</b> and second longitudinal panel <b>118</b> which are positioned adjacent to the side walls <b>104</b>. The braced lateral panels <b>122</b> improve the structural integrity and reduce bulging of the first compartment <b>112</b> and second compartment <b>114</b>, especially when a large amount of water is stored in the first compartment <b>112</b> which can exert stronger loads on the lateral panels <b>122</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">In some embodiments, the structural elements further comprise one or more first partition panels dividing the first compartment <b>112</b> into a plurality of first sub-compartments for storing a plurality of groups of aquatic organisms. For example, one first sub-compartment is configured for storing fishes and another first sub-compartment is configured for storing crustaceans such as prawns and shrimps. In one embodiment, the first partition panels are permanently installed in the first compartment <b>112</b>, such as by welding or adhesive. In another embodiment, the first partition panels are removably installed in the first compartment <b>112</b> for selectively dividing the first compartment <b>112</b> into the first sub-compartments. Appropriate structural elements, such as grooves or receptacles, may be provided to receive and install the first partition panels. The first partition panels may be installable at different parts of the first compartment <b>112</b> to control the volumes of the first sub-compartments. For example, smaller aquatic organisms such as shrimps can be stored in a smaller first sub-compartment, while larger aquatic organisms such as fishes can be stored in a larger first sub-compartment.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">In some embodiments, the structural elements further comprise one or more second partition panels dividing the second compartment <b>114</b> into a plurality of second sub-compartments for installing the water treatment mechanisms. Specifically, each second sub-compartment is configured for installing one or more of the water treatment mechanisms. In one embodiment, the second partition panels are permanently installed in the second compartment <b>114</b>, such as by welding or adhesive. In another embodiment, the second partition panels are removably installed in the second compartment <b>114</b> for selectively dividing the second compartment <b>114</b> into the second sub-compartments. Appropriate structural elements, such as grooves or receptacles, may be provided to receive and install the second partition panels. The second partition panels may be installable at different parts of the second compartment <b>114</b> to control the volumes of the second sub-compartments based on the sizes of the water treatment mechanisms to be installed.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Each second partition panel optionally comprises an opening for connecting the water treatment mechanisms to one another, such as by fluid communication channels through the openings for water communication across the water treatment mechanisms. The structural elements may further comprise a platform panel <b>114</b>A disposed on the second compartment <b>114</b> to facilitate user accessibility through the intermodal container <b>102</b>. The platform panel <b>114</b>A provides a working platform that allows users, e.g. working personnel, to walk on and go across the intermodal container <b>102</b>, such as to access the first compartment <b>112</b> for introducing/removing aquatic organisms and monitoring the habitat conditions for the aquatic organisms. In one embodiment, the platform panel <b>114</b>A has an approximate length of 4.5 meters and an approximate width of 0.8 meters, and is at an approximate height of 0.7 meters, the dimensions corresponding to that of the second compartment <b>114</b>. At this height, the platform panel <b>114</b>A can provide the users with sufficient height/ceiling space to comfortably walk across the intermodal container <b>102</b>, given that the height of the intermodal container <b>102</b> is approximately 2.6 meters. The platform panel <b>114</b>A may comprise a grated structure made of a corrosion-resistant material, such as a steel grating. Optionally, the platform panel <b>114</b>A is lined a corrugated/textured/non-slip surface.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">In some embodiments, the structural elements in the housing structure <b>110</b> are permanently attached or fixed to one another, such as by welding or adhesive. In some other embodiments, the structural elements are removably attached or fastened to one another, such as by mechanical fasteners or other known coupling mechanisms. Each structural element is appropriately dimensioned, such as panel thicknesses, depending on the loading conditions for the housing structure <b>110</b>. The housing structure <b>110</b>, or more specifically the structural elements thereof, comprises a material that is safe for aquatic organisms and/or that is corrosion-resistant as the aquatic farming module <b>100</b> may be used in a seawater environment. Some non-limiting examples of the aquatic-safe material include polyethylene, polypropylene, acrylic, glass, polycarbonate, and fiberglass. Preferably, the aquatic-safe material is high-density polyethylene (HDPE).</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">As stated above, the first compartment <b>112</b> is configured for storing water and aquatic organisms. The water may be freshwater or seawater depending on the species of aquatic organisms. The aquatic organisms may be fishes and crustaceans, such as prawns and shrimps, that can be bred or farmed for food production. The first compartment <b>112</b> may also be referred to as an aquaculture/aquafarming compartment or tank. The top portion of the first compartment <b>112</b> may be open or uncovered, allowing for easier monitoring of the habitat conditions for the aquatic organisms and the quality of water, as well as for easier monitoring and harvesting of the aquatic organisms. The top portion of the first compartment <b>112</b> may optionally be covered, such as by a netting, to prevent the aquatic organisms from jumping out of the water and/or control illumination in the water. In one embodiment, the first compartment <b>112</b> has an approximate length of 4.5 meters, an approximate width of 1.5 meters, and of sufficient height to store an approximate water height of 1 meter.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">As stated above, the second compartment <b>114</b> is configured for installing a set of water treatment mechanisms to treat the water in the first compartment <b>112</b>. In one embodiment, the second compartment <b>114</b> has an approximate length of 4.5 meters, an approximate width of 0.8 meters, and an approximate height of 0.7 meters. A recirculating aquaculture system (RAS) is known to be used for treating water to maintain a healthy environment for aquatic organisms, such as in home-based aquaria. The RAS retains, treats, and reuses the water within the system. For example, the water in the RAS flows from a fish tank through a treatment process and is then returned to the tank. The RAS has components, such as filtration mechanisms, that treat the water by decomposing organic waste matter biologically and removing the waste matter mechanically. Usually, when the waste matter is removed from the water, some of the water is also removed from the RAS, resulting in some water loss. The RAS reduces ammonia toxicity in the water, maintains clean water, and provides a suitable habitat for fishes.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">In some embodiments, the water treatment mechanisms installed in the second compartment <b>114</b> constitute a RAS that treats the water according to a series of treatment processes to maintain desired water quality and provide a suitable habitat/environment for the aquatic organisms. Although some water is loss through the treatment processes, the water loss is usually minimal at around 2% of the amount in the RAS per day. This is achievable by using high surface area biological growth media and high efficiency nitrifying bacteria strains. The water treatment mechanisms comprise a water monitoring and control device to monitor the water quality and the habitat/environment conditions for the aquatic organisms. The treatment processes include, but are not limited to, biological, mechanical, chemical, disinfection, aeration, and temperature treatment processes.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">In one embodiment as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>, the water treatment mechanisms further comprise a biological treatment mechanism <b>124</b> located in the portion of the second compartment <b>114</b> adjacent to the side wall <b>104</b>. The water treatment mechanisms further comprise other treatment mechanisms for the mechanical, chemical, disinfection, aeration, and temperature treatment processes. The other treatment mechanisms are collectively referred to as non-biological treatment mechanisms <b>126</b> and are located in the portion of the second compartment adjacent to the end entrance <b>106</b>. The water treatment mechanisms further comprise a water pump <b>128</b> located between the biological treatment mechanism <b>124</b> and the non-biological treatment mechanisms <b>126</b>. The water pump <b>128</b> controls water communication or flow from the biological treatment mechanism <b>124</b> towards the non-biological treatment mechanisms <b>126</b>, thereby recirculating the water in the first compartment <b>112</b> in an anticlockwise direction as shown by arrows in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>. In another embodiment two or more parallel water pumps maybe used for fault tolerance or redundancy in case one of the water pumps fail or becomes faulty during operation. The water treatment mechanisms further comprise channels, pipes, and/or valves to control water communication across the water treatment mechanisms. It will be appreciated that the water treatment mechanisms may be positioned differently to rearrange the treatment processes and/or to recirculate the water differently, such as in a clockwise direction instead.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">In one embodiment, the water pump <b>128</b> pumps and discharges waste water from the first compartment <b>112</b> to the biological treatment mechanism <b>124</b> for performing the biological treatment process. The biological treatment mechanism <b>124</b> comprises a screen mesh that filters and removes large particles in the waste water such as uneaten food and solid waste matter. The biological treatment mechanism <b>124</b> then treats the waste water by converting toxic ammonia in the water, which is excreted by aquatic organisms such as fishes, into nitrate which is less toxic. Certain communities or strains of bacteria may be used in the biological treatment mechanism <b>124</b> to nitrify the ammonia. Partial denitrification occurs in anoxic regions within the biological treatment mechanism <b>124</b> where nitrate is further processed to nitrogen gas and released to the environment. The biological treatment mechanism <b>124</b> may be configured to perform the aeration treatment process to aerate the water with air to thereby remove dissolved carbon dioxide and to dissolve oxygen to reoxygenate the water. Fresh oxygen is required by the aquatic organisms to metabolize food and grow, and also by the bacteria communities in the biological treatment mechanism <b>126</b>. Optionally, if seawater is stored in and discharged from the first compartment <b>112</b>, a foam fractionator is included in the biological treatment mechanism <b>124</b> to remove foamable organic matter from the water.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The water pump <b>128</b> then pumps the biologically-treated water from the biological treatment mechanism <b>124</b> to the non-biological treatment mechanisms <b>126</b> for performing the other treatment processes. In the mechanical treatment process, the non-biological treatment mechanisms <b>126</b> comprise mechanical filters for removing particulate matter from the water. The mechanical filters may remove particulate matter as small as 25 microns. The mechanical filters may comprise sand filters, particle filters, and/or drum filters. Optionally, in the chemical treatment process, the non-biological treatment mechanisms <b>126</b> monitor and control the pH or acidity/alkalinity of the water. For example, nitrification of the ammonia in the biological treatment mechanism <b>124</b> reduces the pH of the water, making the water more acidic. Keeping the pH in a suitable range, such as 5.0 to 9.0 for freshwater, maintains the health of aquatic organisms as well as the biological treatment mechanism <b>124</b>. The acidity/alkalinity of the water may be controlled by adding sodium hydroxide or hydrogen bicarbonate or other suitable buffers. In the disinfection treatment process, the non-biological treatment mechanisms <b>126</b> uses ultraviolet radiation and/or ozone treatment to reduce bacteria and/or viruses in the biologically-treated, mechanically-treated, and optionally chemically-treated water, thereby disinfecting the water.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The non-biological treatment mechanisms <b>126</b> may be configured to perform another aeration treatment process. Optionally, in the temperature treatment process, the non-biological treatment mechanisms <b>126</b> comprise a heating mechanism to control the temperature of the water. The heating mechanism may comprise a submerged heater, heat pump, chiller, and/or heat exchanger. The temperature treatment process maintains an optimal temperature for farming the aquatic organisms, such as to maximize fish production. It will be appreciated that the treatment processes may be performed in different sequences or in tandem with one another. The water pump <b>128</b> returns the treated water to the first compartment <b>112</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>. Optionally, the first compartment <b>112</b> is installed with a number of in-tank air diffusers to sufficiently aerate the water stored in the first compartment <b>112</b> for aquatic organisms to live and grow.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">The aquatic farming module <b>100</b> further comprises a set of access doors <b>130</b> disposed at one or both end entrances <b>106</b> of the intermodal container <b>102</b>. The access doors <b>130</b> are actuatable planarly, i.e. parallel to the plane of the end entrances <b>106</b>, for selectively opening and/or closing the respective end entrances <b>106</b>. Selective opening/closing of the end entrances <b>106</b> of the intermodal container <b>102</b> facilitates user accessibility to the housing structure <b>110</b> for farming the aquatic organisms. In one embodiment, the access doors <b>130</b> are manually operated. In another embodiment, the access doors <b>130</b> are connected to an access control system that automates actuation of the access doors <b>130</b>, such as by motorized mechanisms. The access control system may provide an override function that allows the access doors <b>130</b> to be manually operated.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">In one example, both access doors <b>130</b> are actuated to close the end entrances <b>106</b> and are optionally locked to prevent user accessibility to the housing structure <b>110</b>, such as to provide a controlled environment/habitat for the aquatic organisms and/or to prevent unauthorized access into the intermodal container <b>102</b>. In another example, one or both access doors <b>130</b> are actuated to open the end entrances <b>106</b> to expose the housing structure <b>110</b> and aquatic organisms to an ambient environment. The one or both open end entrances <b>106</b> allow for free movement into and out of the intermodal container <b>102</b>, such as by users who wants to monitor the habitat conditions for the aquatic organisms as well as the quality of water in the first compartment <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">In one embodiment, one or both access doors <b>130</b> comprise a roller shutter coupled to an upper portion of the respective end entrance <b>106</b>. The roller shutter is actuatable vertically downwards at the respective end entrance <b>106</b> parallel to the plane thereof to selectively open/close the respective end entrance <b>106</b>. The roller shutter may also be referred to as a roller door or sectional overhead door. In another embodiment, one or both access doors <b>130</b> comprise a folding door coupled to side edges of the respective end entrance <b>106</b>. The folding door is actuatable laterally at the respective end entrance <b>106</b> parallel to the plane thereof (leftwards and/or rightwards) to selectively open/close the respective end entrance <b>106</b>. The folding door comprises multiple door panels that are slideable so that the door panels can be compacted together.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">In some embodiments, the aquatic farming module <b>100</b> further comprises one or more external access platforms <b>132</b> integrally formed with or permanently attached to the housing structure <b>110</b> or the intermodal container <b>102</b>. The external access platforms <b>132</b> extend longitudinally outside of the end entrances <b>106</b> of the intermodal container <b>102</b>. In one embodiment, each external access platform <b>132</b> is attached to the housing structure <b>110</b>/intermodal container <b>102</b> by a hinge component such that the external access platform <b>132</b> is rotatable about a lateral hinge axis.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">In some embodiments, the aquatic farming module <b>100</b> further comprises one or more external access platforms <b>132</b> coupleable to bottom portions of the end entrances <b>106</b> of the intermodal container <b>102</b>. In one embodiment, the aquatic farming module <b>100</b> comprises a pair of external access platforms <b>132</b> stored in the intermodal container <b>102</b>. The external access platforms <b>132</b> can be removably coupled to the respective pairs of bottom corner castings <b>108</b> at the respective end entrances <b>106</b>. Each external access platform <b>132</b> comprises appropriate attachments/coupling mechanisms for removably coupling to the respective pair of bottom corner castings <b>108</b>. The external access platforms <b>132</b> may be made of a lightweight material with sufficient structural integrity, such that they can be easily coupled and can withstand the weight of users walking on the external access platforms <b>132</b> to enter/exit the intermodal container <b>102</b>. In one embodiment, each external access platform <b>132</b> has an approximate length of 1.2 meters and an approximate width of 2.4 meters. The external access platforms <b>132</b> may be made of galvanized iron or mild steel material with corrosion-resistant coating.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">In some embodiments, the aquatic farming module <b>100</b> further comprises one or more external access ladders coupleable to the top and bottom portions of the entrances <b>106</b> of the intermodal container <b>102</b>, and/or coupleable to the edges of the external access platforms <b>130</b>. The external access ladders and end entrances <b>106</b>/external access platforms <b>132</b> comprise appropriate attachments/coupling mechanisms for removably coupling the external access ladders to the end entrances <b>106</b>/external access platforms <b>132</b>. The external access ladders may be used by working personnel to access the upper portion of the aquatic farming module <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">In various representative or exemplary embodiments of the present invention with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref>, there is an aquatic farming system <b>200</b> comprising a set of aquatic farming modules or units <b>100</b> arranged in one or more stacked levels. Each stacked level comprises an array of one or more aquatic farming modules <b>100</b>. An array comprises one or more rows and one or more columns of aquatic farming modules <b>100</b> to form a single stacked level. Each row of aquatic farming modules <b>100</b> extends along the widths thereof when the aquatic farming modules <b>100</b> are placed side-by-side. Each column of aquatic farming modules <b>100</b> extends along the lengths thereof when the aquatic farming modules <b>100</b> are placed end-to-end. Notably, a single stacked level with an array of one row and one column is equivalent to a single aquatic farming module <b>100</b>. The aquatic farming system <b>200</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> comprises eight aquatic farming modules <b>100</b> arranged in two stacked levels, each stacked level comprising an array of one row and four columns of the aquatic farming modules <b>100</b>. The aquatic farming modules <b>100</b> may be arranged by known containerization methods used in intermodal freight transport.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Each aquatic farming module <b>100</b> in the aquatic farming system <b>200</b> comprises access doors <b>130</b> for selectively opening/closing the end entrances <b>106</b> of the respective intermodal container <b>102</b>. For each stacked level of aquatic farming modules <b>100</b>, selective opening/closing of the end entrances <b>106</b> of the intermodal containers <b>102</b> in said stacked level facilitates user accessibility to the housing structures <b>110</b> in said stacked level for farming the aquatic organisms.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">In some embodiments as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref>, the end entrances <b>106</b> of the intermodal containers <b>102</b> in both stacked levels are opened. As the intermodal containers <b>102</b> are placed side-by-side, the open end entrances <b>106</b> allow users, such as working personnel, to traverse across the intermodal containers <b>102</b> in one stacked level, thereby allowing the users to access the housing structures <b>110</b> in the same stacked level. Furthermore, if a stacked level has two or more rows of aquatic farming modules <b>100</b>, the open end entrances <b>106</b> allow users to traverse through the intermodal containers <b>102</b> which are positioned end-to-end in different rows. In contrast, conventional intermodal containers have hinged doors, which when opened, hinder user accessibility to the adjacent container. Specifically, the hinged doors in the open state obstruct users who want to access the adjacent container. Moreover, the hinged doors prevent the containers from being positioned end-to-end. Advantageously, the access doors <b>130</b> enable selectively opening/closing of the end entrances <b>106</b> and planar actuation of the access doors <b>130</b> does not hinder or obstruct users from accessing the intermodal containers <b>102</b> in the same stacked level.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Optionally, the aquatic farming modules <b>100</b> comprise external access platforms <b>132</b>. The external access platforms <b>132</b> improve user accessibility to the housing structures <b>110</b> in a stacked level, as users can walk on the external access platforms <b>132</b> and enter the intermodal containers <b>102</b> in the same stacked level.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">In one embodiment, each aquatic farming module <b>100</b> comprises one external access platform <b>132</b> integrally formed with or permanently attached to the housing structure <b>110</b> or the intermodal container <b>102</b> at one end entrance <b>106</b>. Each aquatic farming module <b>100</b> thus has platformed and non-platformed end entrances <b>106</b>. The aquatic farming modules <b>100</b> may be positioned end-to-end in two rows of the array such that the non-platformed end entrances <b>106</b> are facing each other. This minimizes the space between the aquatic farming modules <b>100</b> and allows users to easily walk across. Alternatively, the aquatic farming modules <b>100</b> may be positioned end-to-end in two rows of the array such that non-platformed entrances <b>106</b> face platformed entrances <b>106</b>, allowing for more space between the aquatic farming modules <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">In one embodiment, each aquatic farming module <b>100</b> comprises two external access platforms <b>132</b> integrally formed with or permanently attached to the housing structure <b>110</b> or the intermodal container <b>102</b> at both end entrances <b>106</b>. The aquatic farming modules <b>100</b> may be positioned end-to-end in two rows of the array such that the platformed end entrances <b>106</b> are facing each other. Alternatively, the aquatic farming modules <b>100</b> may be positioned in a single row of the array.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">In one embodiment, each aquatic farming module <b>100</b> comprises one or more external access platforms <b>132</b> attached to the housing structure <b>110</b>/intermodal container <b>102</b> by hinge components such that the external access platforms <b>132</b> are rotatable about lateral hinge axes. The external access platforms <b>132</b> may be released via the lateral hinge axes as desired to allow access into the intermodal container <b>102</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">In one embodiment, each aquatic farming module <b>100</b> comprises one or more external access platforms <b>132</b> coupleable to bottom portions of the end entrances <b>106</b> of the intermodal container <b>102</b>. The external access platforms <b>132</b> are stored in the intermodal container <b>102</b> and coupled to the end entrances <b>106</b> as desired to allow access into the intermodal container <b>102</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">In one embodiment as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref>, the aquatic farming system <b>200</b> comprises two aquatic farming modules <b>100</b>&#x2014;a lower aquatic farming module <b>100</b><i>a </i>and an upper aquatic farming module <b>100</b><i>b </i>stacked on top. The lower aquatic farming module <b>100</b><i>a </i>and upper aquatic farming module <b>100</b><i>b </i>comprise a lower intermodal container <b>102</b><i>a </i>and upper intermodal container <b>102</b><i>b</i>, respectively. The lower aquatic farming module <b>100</b><i>a </i>comprises a lower external access platform <b>132</b><i>a </i>coupled to the bottom portion of the lower intermodal container <b>102</b><i>a</i>. The upper aquatic farming module <b>100</b><i>b </i>comprises an upper external access platform <b>132</b><i>b </i>coupled to the bottom portion of the upper intermodal container <b>102</b><i>b</i>. Each of the lower and upper external access platforms <b>132</b><i>a </i>and <b>132</b><i>b </i>comprises a coupling mechanism <b>134</b>, such as removable locking pins, for coupling to the lower and upper intermodal containers <b>102</b><i>a </i>and <b>102</b><i>b</i>, respectively. The aquatic farming system <b>200</b> additionally comprises a set of support braces <b>202</b> coupling the upper external access platform <b>132</b><i>b </i>to the lower intermodal container <b>102</b><i>a</i>. The support braces <b>202</b> may be positioned towards both side walls <b>104</b>. The support braces <b>202</b> comprise a coupling mechanism <b>204</b>, such as removable locking pins, for coupling to the vertical side beams of the lower intermodal container <b>102</b><i>a</i>. The support braces <b>202</b> support the upper external access platform <b>132</b><i>b </i>and reduces its cantilever effect. The lower external access platform <b>132</b><i>a </i>is supported by the ground. The aquatic farming system <b>200</b> additionally comprises a safety rail <b>206</b> coupled to an external edge of the upper external access platform <b>132</b><i>b</i>. The safety rail <b>206</b> mitigates risk of a user falling from the upper external access platform <b>132</b><i>b</i>. The safety rail <b>206</b> may have a minimum height to comply with safety regulations. For example, the safety rail <b>206</b> has an approximate height of 1.1 meters. The external access platforms <b>132</b><i>a </i>and <b>132</b><i>b</i>, support braces <b>202</b>, and safety rail <b>206</b> are removable, by decoupling the respective coupling mechanisms, and are stored in the intermodal containers <b>102</b> when the aquatic farming modules <b>100</b> are not in use, such as during transportation of the aquatic farming modules <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">More optionally, the aquatic farming modules <b>100</b> comprise external access ladders coupleable to the edges of the external access platforms <b>132</b>. The external access ladders facilitate user accessibility between stacked levels. For example, users may use the external access ladders to go between the lower stacked level and upper stacked level. The external access ladders, together with the access doors <b>130</b> and external access platforms <b>132</b>, advantageously facilitate user accessibility into the intermodal containers <b>102</b> and to the housing structures <b>110</b> in all stacked levels for farming the aquatic organisms in all the aquatic farming modules <b>100</b> of the aquatic farming system <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">In some embodiments, the aquatic farming system <b>200</b> further comprises a set of external systems connectable to the housing structures <b>110</b> via the end entrances <b>106</b> of the intermodal containers <b>102</b>. The aquatic farming system <b>200</b> may comprise a set of external modules or units for housing the external systems. Each external module may comprise an intermodal container such that the external modules can be arranged together with the aquatic farming modules <b>100</b> in the arrays and stacked levels to form an integrated aquatic farming system <b>200</b>. The external systems may comprise a water recycling system for supplying water to the aquatic farming modules <b>100</b>, such as to replenish water loss from the RAS, and for removing waste water from the aquatic farming modules <b>100</b>. The external systems may comprise a waste recycling system for recycling organic waste matter from the aquatic farming modules <b>100</b>. The organic waste matter may be recycled and repurposed into fertilizers. The external systems may comprise a hydroponics system for growing and farming plants, e.g. vegetables, for food production. Fertilizers repurposed from the organic waste matter may be reused in the hydroponics system. Accordingly, the aquatic farming system <b>200</b> may operate as an integrated aquaponics and hydroponics food production system.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">As described in various embodiments herein, the aquatic farming system <b>200</b> comprises a set of aquatic farming modules or units <b>100</b>, each of which is self-reliant and can function on its own to grow and farm aquatic organisms to produce food for consumption by people. The aquatic farming system <b>100</b> may comprise a single or standalone aquatic farming module <b>100</b>. The aquatic farming system <b>100</b> may alternatively comprise multiple aquatic farming modules <b>100</b> that can be arranged together in arrays and stacked levels, similar to containerizations in intermodal freight transport.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">Due to the modular configuration of the aquatic farming system <b>200</b>, each aquatic farming module <b>100</b> can be easily replaced, such as after prolonged usage and/or wear and tear, especially if the intermodal container <b>102</b> is severely corroded/rusted. Moreover, the aquatic farming system <b>200</b> can be disassembled and reassembled, allowing it to be relocated elsewhere as desired. Each aquatic farming module <b>100</b> comprises an intermodal container <b>102</b> which is of a standard size, allowing the aquatic farming module <b>100</b> to be transported using known means of transporting ISO or shipping containers.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">The aquatic farming system <b>200</b> with multiple aquatic farming modules <b>100</b> provides greater capacity to grow, farm, and harvest large amounts of aquatic organisms, thereby increasing food production for people. As the aquatic farming modules <b>100</b> can be vertically stacked, the aquatic farming system <b>200</b> can be located on a small land area, improving efficient use of available land areas. This is particularly advantageous to countries where available land areas are scarce. The aquatic farming system <b>200</b> is thus suitable for use in urban cities or underutilized urban spaces. Urban cities tend to have lower carbon footprint as there is fewer industrial facilities, such as factories and power plants, which are commonly located further away from the populated cities. Using the aquatic farming system <b>200</b> in urban cities improves the freshness of the farmed aquatic organisms as they can be grown with minimal industrial pollution. There is also more control over the aquatic farming and the quantity/quality of aquatic organisms as compared to traditionally farming like in ponds and sea cages. The aquatic farming system <b>200</b> can also be used on freight transport, such as ships and barges, out at sea where there is even less pollution, further ensuring the freshness and quality of the farmed aquatic organisms.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">In the foregoing detailed description, embodiments of the present invention in relation to an aquatic farming system are described with reference to the provided figures. The description of the various embodiments herein is not intended to call out or be limited only to specific or particular representations of the present invention, but merely to illustrate non-limiting examples of the present invention. The present invention serves to address at least one of the mentioned problems and issues associated with the prior art. Although only some embodiments of the present invention are disclosed herein, it will be apparent to a person having ordinary skill in the art in view of this invention that a variety of changes and/or modifications can be made to the disclosed embodiments without departing from the scope of the present invention. Therefore, the scope of the invention as well as the scope of the following claims is not limited to embodiments described herein.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-01-20" num="01-20">
<claim-text><b>1</b>-<b>20</b>. (canceled)</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text><b>21</b>. A containerizable aquatic farming system comprising:
<claim-text>a set of aquatic farming modules arranged in one or more stacked levels, each stacked level comprising an array of one or more aquatic farming modules, each aquatic farming module comprising:
<claim-text>an intermodal shipping container comprising a pair of opposing side walls and a pair of opposing end entrances; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a housing structure disposed in the intermodal shipping container and extending between the side walls thereof, the housing structure comprising:
<claim-text>a first compartment for storing water and aquatic organisms;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second compartment adjacent to the first compartment and for installing a set of water treatment mechanisms in the second compartment to treat the water in the first compartment; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a platform panel disposed on the second compartment to facilitate user accessibility through the intermodal shipping container; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a set of access doors disposed at one or both end entrances of the intermodal shipping container for user accessibility into the intermodal shipping container, the access doors actuatable planarly for selectively opening/closing the respective end entrances,</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein for each stacked level of aquatic farming modules, selective opening/closing of the end entrances of the intermodal shipping containers in said stacked level facilitates user accessibility to the housing structures in said stacked level for farming the aquatic organisms.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text><b>22</b>. The aquatic farming system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00021">claim 21</claim-ref>, wherein the platform panel covers the water treatment mechanisms in the second compartment.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text><b>23</b>. The aquatic farming system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00021">claim 21</claim-ref>, each access door comprising a roller shutter coupled to an upper portion of the respective end entrance, the roller shutter actuatable vertically at the respective end entrance.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024" num="00024">
<claim-text><b>24</b>. The aquatic farming system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00021">claim 21</claim-ref>, each aquatic farming module further comprising one or more external access platforms integrally formed with or permanently attached to the housing structure or intermodal shipping container.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025" num="00025">
<claim-text><b>25</b>. The aquatic farming system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00024">claim 24</claim-ref>, wherein each external access platform is attached to the housing structure or intermodal shipping container by a hinge component such that the external access platform is rotatable about a lateral hinge axis.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026" num="00026">
<claim-text><b>26</b>. The aquatic farming system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00021">claim 21</claim-ref>, each aquatic farming module further comprising one or more external access platforms coupleable to bottom portions of the end entrances of the intermodal shipping container.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027" num="00027">
<claim-text><b>27</b>. The aquatic farming system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00021">claim 21</claim-ref>, wherein each housing structure comprises:
<claim-text>a first longitudinal panel adjacent to one side wall of the intermodal shipping container and bounding the first compartment; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second longitudinal panel adjacent to the other side wall of the intermodal shipping container and bounding the second compartment.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028" num="00028">
<claim-text><b>28</b>. The aquatic farming system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00027">claim 27</claim-ref>, wherein each housing structure further comprises a third longitudinal panel interposing the first and second longitudinal panels to separate the first and second compartments.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029" num="00029">
<claim-text><b>29</b>. The aquatic farming system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00021">claim 21</claim-ref>, wherein each housing structure comprises one or more first partition panels dividing the first compartment into a plurality of first sub-compartments for storing a plurality of groups of aquatic organisms.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030" num="00030">
<claim-text><b>30</b>. The aquatic farming system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00029">claim 29</claim-ref>, wherein the first partition panels are removably installed in the first compartment for selectively dividing the first compartment into the first sub-compartments.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031" num="00031">
<claim-text><b>31</b>. The aquatic farming system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00021">claim 21</claim-ref>, wherein each housing structure comprises one or more second partition panels dividing the second compartment into a plurality of second sub-compartments for installing the water treatment mechanisms.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032" num="00032">
<claim-text><b>32</b>. The aquatic farming system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00031">claim 31</claim-ref>, each second partition panel comprising an opening for connecting the water treatment mechanisms to one another.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033" num="00033">
<claim-text><b>33</b>. The aquatic farming system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00021">claim 21</claim-ref>, wherein each housing structure comprises panels formed of a polyethylene or polypropylene material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034" num="00034">
<claim-text><b>34</b>. The aquatic farming system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00021">claim 21</claim-ref>, each aquatic farming module further comprising a protective layer lining interior surfaces of the intermodal shipping container, the protective layer comprising a corrosion-resistant material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035" num="00035">
<claim-text><b>35</b>. The aquatic farming system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00034">claim 34</claim-ref>, wherein the corrosion-resistant material is epoxy or polyurethane.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036" num="00036">
<claim-text><b>36</b>. The aquatic farming system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00021">claim 21</claim-ref>, further comprising a set of external systems connectable to the housing structures via the end entrances of the intermodal shipping containers.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037" num="00037">
<claim-text><b>37</b>. The aquatic farming system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00036">claim 36</claim-ref>, further comprising a set of external modules arranged with the aquatic farming modules for housing the external systems.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038" num="00038">
<claim-text><b>38</b>. The aquatic farming system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00037">claim 37</claim-ref>, wherein the external systems comprise a water recycling system and/or waste recycling system.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
