<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225423A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225423</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17580615</doc-number>
<date>20220120</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>17</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>11</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>11</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">SOUL SOXS</invention-title>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Morgan</last-name>
<first-name>John Gagne</first-name>
<address>
<city>Austin</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="01" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Anderson</last-name>
<first-name>Christine Michelle</first-name>
<address>
<city>Austin</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Morgan</last-name>
<first-name>John Gagne</first-name>
<address>
<city>Austin</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="01" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Anderson</last-name>
<first-name>Christine Michelle</first-name>
<address>
<city>Austin</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Fully custom and personalized improved pair of socks that may be produced from a blend of spandex, polyester, cotton, bamboo fibers, copper, nylon, etc. The socks could be produced in various heights such as ankle, crew, mid-calf, etc. The top of the sock would feature a cushioned, no slip edging, etc. In addition, the heel would feature a cushioned, no slip support while cushioned support would rest around the ankle. The main modification of this cushioned sock would deal with the inclusion of pockets, sleeves, openings, etc. upon its outer sole which would allow various materials to be inserted to relieve pain, support, better balance, help plantar fasciitis, and possibly many other health concerns. The inserts may be produced from various materials to accommodate different needs. The inserts, insoles, gel beds, etc. could rest beneath the hell, ball, and arch of the foot. They may be produced from a plethora of material foam, rubber, plastic, with gel interior, etc. In addition, they may be produced in various widths, sizes and shapes, etc. to accommodate different needs. The interior of the pockets, sleeves, openings, etc. could contain gel, adhesive, magnets, etc. they may ensure the insert remained in the proper place for the wearer. Alternatively, the insoles, inserts, footbeds may be held in place by magnets. The inserts may provide support and added comfort for the user's feet and may decrease the amount of back problems, gait issues, foot and leg fatigue, etc. Also envisioning a removable plantar fascist wrap accompanying the SOUL SOXS going from mid high sock to crew that would hold various arch supports in place. The socks could be produced in a plethora of colors and an array of sizes appropriate for wearing by men, women, and children. SOUL SOXS is designed to provide added comfort for the user's feet. This product would comprise of socks containing the support offered by insoles throughout its design. More specifically, these personalized and customizable socks with inserts, insoles, etc. would feature fully customizable from colors, textures, materials, infusions, and could feature cushioned, no-slip area upon the sock's openings, slots, pockets as well as upon the heel. Cushioned ankle support would be incorporated. Pockets, slots would be incorporated to provide inserts for the ball, heel, and arch areas of the toot. The arch area may also contain a removable plantar fasciitis wrap that would anchor the arch support insert. Various types and thickness of insets could be positioned within the pockets. They may be produced with gel, from plastic or rubber, or as expanded foam. When worn, the SOUL SOXS may reduce the incidence of pain and problems within the feet as well as the lower back and other areas of the body. Using this product, the wearer may reduce his incidence of sore feet and other more serious foot ailments. Infusions are fully custom and personalized within designed to provide the wearers with personal, customizable comfort. This product may provide enhanced comfort and relief from pain as it would incorporate support, like an insole within a shoe. While the SOUL SOXS could be worn by a wide array of individuals, it may be of particular appeal to anyone who suffers with arthritis, diabetes, or back pain as well as various foot problems such as bunions, flat feet, hammer toes, heel spurs, plantar fasciitis, gait, neuropathic pain, etc. to individual needs of consumer for a variety of health issues associated with the feet, wellness, health, with essential oils, fragrances for beauty etc. (would be able to control each added infusions)</p>
<p id="p-0002" num="0000">Fully custom socks made from a variety of customized materials, textures, sizes, shapes, designs, etc. that have multiple openings, slots, pockets, gel lining, magnetic bottom (either within sock or on bottom of sock) and within the sock to retain the multiple pieces of footbed, inserts, insoles, and smaller pieces i.e. added layers, textures, materials to both the outer, inner, bottom, top, etc. of the socks as well as the inserts, insoles, footbeds, etc. which would connect by magnets, gel adhesive, gel lining, etc. to make multiple sections of the insert, insole, footbed, as one full insert, insole, footbed, etc. The insert, insole, footbeds, etc. being connected by magnets, gel adhesive, gel lining, etc. to be able to bend with user's foot as more comparable to an athletic shoe being a 1-3 part system, being all custom infusions of Oils i.e. THC, CBD, Plant Based Substances, Non Plant Based Substances, Coconut Oils, Lavender, Varieties of Scents, etc. either directly into the inserts/insoles/footbeds, gel beds etc. that are able to retain the listed above substances, scents, etc. depending on the many different textures, materials, etc. made with but are not limited to polymer materials, 3D printed materials said layers that stay in place or adhere by gel, magnets, gel lining, etc. that can be inserted into an article of footwear e.g. custom socks, hosiery, garment as stated in previous arts fully customizable socks, e.g. colors, textures, materials, as well as fully customizable infusions whether it's any of the below listed substances where and when legal either applied by transdermal type patches within the layers and able to control the amount of , salve, lotion, oil, lavenders, fragrances, Coconut Oils, CBD, delta-9-tetrahydrocannabinol, glycerin, melatonin, etc. (WITHOUT CLAIM to above listed substances all plant-based substances and non-plant substances) from original invention know exactly how much to</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="184.91mm" wi="158.75mm" file="US20230225423A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="248.33mm" wi="192.70mm" file="US20230225423A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="231.39mm" wi="193.04mm" file="US20230225423A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="239.18mm" wi="182.71mm" file="US20230225423A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="160.78mm" wi="173.65mm" file="US20230225423A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="168.57mm" wi="163.07mm" file="US20230225423A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="164.00mm" wi="168.15mm" file="US20230225423A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="248.41mm" wi="191.77mm" file="US20230225423A1-20230720-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="246.80mm" wi="173.40mm" file="US20230225423A1-20230720-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="251.97mm" wi="169.59mm" file="US20230225423A1-20230720-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="242.49mm" wi="169.67mm" file="US20230225423A1-20230720-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="247.90mm" wi="170.01mm" file="US20230225423A1-20230720-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00012" num="00012">
<img id="EMI-D00012" he="245.03mm" wi="174.84mm" file="US20230225423A1-20230720-D00012.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00013" num="00013">
<img id="EMI-D00013" he="243.84mm" wi="171.11mm" file="US20230225423A1-20230720-D00013.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00014" num="00014">
<img id="EMI-D00014" he="213.02mm" wi="153.59mm" file="US20230225423A1-20230720-D00014.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00015" num="00015">
<img id="EMI-D00015" he="185.93mm" wi="186.01mm" file="US20230225423A1-20230720-D00015.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00016" num="00016">
<img id="EMI-D00016" he="136.40mm" wi="173.91mm" file="US20230225423A1-20230720-D00016.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00017" num="00017">
<img id="EMI-D00017" he="187.20mm" wi="155.19mm" file="US20230225423A1-20230720-D00017.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00018" num="00018">
<img id="EMI-D00018" he="243.33mm" wi="147.83mm" file="US20230225423A1-20230720-D00018.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00019" num="00019">
<img id="EMI-D00019" he="254.51mm" wi="161.21mm" file="US20230225423A1-20230720-D00019.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00020" num="00020">
<img id="EMI-D00020" he="250.95mm" wi="191.43mm" file="US20230225423A1-20230720-D00020.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0003" num="0001">This application claims benefit of U.S. Provisional Application No. 63/205,958 filed on Jan. 20, 2021; all of which is incorporated by reference herein.</p>
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="tail"?>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">Field of the Invention</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0002">The present invention relates to Fully custom and personalized improved pair of socks that may be produced from a blend of spandex, polyester, cotton, bamboo fibers, copper, nylon, etc. The socks could be produced in various heights such as ankle, crew, mid-calf, etc. The top of the sock could feature a cushioned, no slip edging, etc. In addition, the heel would feature a cushioned, no slip support while cushioned support would rest around the ankle. The main modification of this cushioned sock would deal with the inclusion of pockets, sleeves, openings, etc. upon its outer sole which would allow various materials to be inserted to relieve pain, support, better balance, help plantar fasciitis, and possibly many other health concerns. The inserts may be produced from various materials to accommodate different needs. The inserts, insoles, gel beds, etc. could rest beneath the hell, ball, and arch of the foot. They may be produced from a plethora of material foam, rubber, plastic, with gel interior, etc. In addition, they may be produced in various widths, sizes and shapes, etc. Lo accommodate different needs. The interior of the pockets, sleeves, openings, etc. could contain gel, adhesive, magnets, etc. they may ensure the insert remained in the proper place for the wearer. Alternatively, the insoles, inserts, footbeds may be held in place by magnets. The inserts may provide support and added comfort for the user's feet and may decrease the amount of back problems, gait issues, foot and leg fatigue, etc. Also envisioning a removable plantar fascist wrap accompanying the SOUL SOXS going from mid high sock to crew that could hold various arch supports in place. The socks could be produced in a plethora of colors and an array of sizes appropriate for wearing by men, women, and children and be fully customizable in infusions, colors, textures, materials, etc. for both the socks and accompanying insoles, footbeds, inserts, gel beds, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0003">&#x201c;SOUL SOXS&#x201d; are being suggested by my because I believe, have worn, and they would fulfill the need for socks designed with a personalized or customizable design to reduce the incidence of soreness, pain, and fatigue within the feet, legs, and back amongst other health issues it could possibly help. The appealing features of SOUL SOXS would be their comfort, durability, reasonable price, and practicality. The inclusion of the pockets, slots, sleeves, etc. that could accept various inserts may provide added comfort and support to protect the user's feet and may save the consumer the money that may have been spent for visits to the podiatrist, general practitioner, or orthopedic surgeon. The &#x201c;SOUL SOXS&#x201d; would provide customizable cushioning and support for the user's feet that could relieve the shock often experienced by the feet and spine when standing, walking, running, etc. This could provide added comfort and may reduce the incidence of back problems as well as sore and swollen feet. Which would work with the wearer's acupuncture points. The various types of inserts may provide support for the arch or heel in a variety of shapes, sizes, textures, etc. The inserts may be produced from a plethora of materials such as with gel interior, expanded foam, rubber, plastic, etc. This practical product could provide the support of insoles without wearing shoes. Thus, a pair of insoles would not require being purchased for every pair of shoes or one pair continually moved from shoe to shoe. The SOUL SOXS could provide support for the feet without the need for shoes which could be of appeal when walking around one's home. This affordable hosiery product could easily be laundered in a washing machine.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">Description of the Prior Art</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0004">SOUL SOXS have been created by myself (John Gagne Morgan and my wife Christine Michelle Anderson) because I believe, have worn, and they would fulfill the need for socks designed with a personalized or customizable design to reduce the incidence of soreness, pain, and fatigue within the feet, legs, and back amongst other health issues it could possibly help. The appealing features of SOUL SOXS would be their comfort, durability, reasonable price, and practicality. The inclusion of the pockets, slots, sleeves, etc. that could accept various inserts may provide added comfort and support to protect the user's feet and may save the consumer the money that may have been spent for visits to the podiatrist, general practitioner, or orthopedic surgeon.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0005">The &#x201c;SOUL SOXS&#x201d; would provide customizable cushioning and support for the user's feet that could relieve the shock often experienced by the feet and spine when standing, walking, running, etc. This could provide added comfort and may reduce the incidence of back problems as well as sore and swollen feet. Which would work with the wearer's acupuncture points. The various types of inserts may provide support for the arch or heel in a variety of shapes, sizes, textures, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0006">The inserts may be produced from a plethora of materials such as with gel interior, expanded foam, rubber, plastic, etc. This practical product could provide the support of insoles without wearing shoes. Thus, a pair of insoles would not require being purchased for every pair of shoes or one pair continually moved from shoe to shoe. The SOUL SOXS could provide support for the feet without the need for shoes which could be of appeal when walking around one's home. This affordable hosiery product could easily be laundered in a washing machine. A deluxe model of the SOUL SOXS may massage the feet while also providing warmth or cooling.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0007">Since SOUL SOXS would represent a modification of an existing product, they would be readily producible. This product could be produced using processes commonly employed in the production of standard socks. The socks could be produced from a blend of spandex, polyester, cotton, bamboo fiber, copper fibers, etc. The cushioned elastic around the top of throughout the sock could be incorporated using standard processes. The pockets, slots, openings, etc. could feature a durable edging for easy access to accommodate the inserts, insoles, footbeds, etc. as they may be produced from plastic, 3D printed materials, rubber, with gel, or expanded foam, etc. 3D printed materials, user would be able to fully customize both the socks and inserts, insoles, footbeds, etc. which costs 0.40 cents a few dollars if that to produce on a lot of these materials, textures, socks, etc. and could sell for many times what it is produced for.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0008">The human foot has 42 muscles, 26 bones, 33 joints, and at least 50 ligaments and tendons made of strong fibrous tissues to keep all the moving parts together. In addition, the foot also contains 250,000 sweat glands. Where infusions of Essential Oils, Vitamins, CBD, THC Deltas, etc. could be infused directly into or onto the skin. The foot is an evolutionary marvel that is capable of handling hundreds of tons of force, the body's weight in motion, every day. Its many parts, including the toes heel, and ball, work in harmony to get individuals from one place to another. But the stress of carrying the body around puts the feet at high risk of injury, more so than other parts of the body. Because the feet are very small compared with the rest of the body the impact of each step exerts tremendous force upon them. This force is about 50 percent greater than the person's body weight. During a typical day, people spend about 4 hours on their feet and take 8,000 to 10,000 steps. This means that the feet support a combined force equivalent to several hundred tons every day.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0009">Many foot problems, including hammertoes, blisters, bunions, corns, and calluses, heel spurs, claw and mallet toes, ingrown toenails, toenail fungus and athlete's foot can develop due to neglect, ill-fitting shoes, inserts, or insoles, and simple wear and tear. The feet may also indicate if the body is under threat from a serious disease. For example, gout will attach the foot joints first.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0010">The foot is a complex anatomical structure that may be affected by disease within the body or the foot itself. The arches of the foot are the primary structures that control the amount of ground force transmitted into the body. The foot serves the following functions supports weight, act as a shock absorber, serves as a lever to propel the leg forward, and helps maintain balance by adjusting the body to uneven surfaces.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0011">Foot pain generally starts in one of three places: the toes, the forefoot, or the hindfoot. Toe problems most often occur because of the pressure imposed by ill-fitting shoes. The forefoot is the front of the foot. Pain originating in this area usually involves the metatarsal or sesamoid bones. The metatarsal bones are the five long bones that extend from the front of the arch to bones in the toe. The sesamoid bones are the two small bones embedded at the top of first metatarsal bone, which connects to the big toe. The hindfoot is the back of the toot. Pain originating in this area can extend from the heel, across the sole (known as the plantar surface), to the ball of the foot (the metatarsophalangeal joint).</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0012">Nearly all causes of foot pain can be grouped under one of three causes. Firs, poorly fitting shoes are a frequent cause of foot pain. High-heeled shoes concentrate pressure on the toes and can aggravate, if not cause problems with the toes. Second, certain medical conditions that cause a disturbance in way a person walks can contribute to foot pain. Included may be diseases or conditions that lead to pain or numbness in the feet (such as diabetes), leg and foot deformities, spinal problems, and neurological disorders such as Parkinson's disease or cerebral palsy. Third, high impact exercising, such as jogging or strenuous aerobics can injure their feet and other parts of the leg. Common injuries include corns, calluses, blisters, muscle cramps, acute knee and ankle injuries, plantar fasciitis, and metatarsalgia.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0013">SOUL SOXS is designed to provide personalized and customizable added comfort for the user's feet. This product would comprise of socks containing the support offered by insoles throughout its design. More specifically, these personalized and customizable socks with inserts, insoles, etc. would feature fully customizable options from colors, textures, materials, infusions, and could feature cushioned, no-slip area upon the sock's openings, slots, pockets as well as upon the heel. Cushioned ankle support would be incorporated. Pockets, slots would be incorporated to provide inserts for the ball, heel, and arch areas of the foot. The arch area may also contain a removable plantar fasciitis wrap that would anchor the arch support insert. Various types and thickness of insets could be positioned within the pockets. They may be produced with gel, from plastic or rubber, or as expanded foam. When worn, the SOUL SOXS may reduce the incidence of pain and problems within the feet as well as the lower back and other areas of the body. Using this product, the wearer may reduce his incidence of sore feet and other more serious foot ailments.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0014">SOUL SOXS may also be of use to individuals with diabetes. According to the American Diabetes Association, there are an estimated 23.1 million individuals in the U.S. who are diagnosed with diabetes; analysts believe another 7.2 million are undiagnosed. The prevalence of older Americans (age 65 and older) remains high, at 25.2 percent (12 million seniors).</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0015">Each year, there are about 1.5 million new cases. Diabetes is most common in American Indians/Alaskan Natives (15.1 percent), followed by Non-Hispanic African Americans (12.7 percent), Hispanics (12.1 percent), Asian Americans (8 percent), and non-Hispanic Caucasians (7.4 percent).</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0016">In addition, it may provide added comfort for anyone with arthritis, at least 54 million adults in the United States reported that a doctor had diagnosed them with arthritis or a related rheumatic condition, according to the Arthritis Foundation. Doctor-diagnosed arthritis is more common in women (26 percent) as compared to men (18 percent). Additionally, in some types of arthritis, such as rheumatoid arthritis, women far outnumber men. Interestingly, nearly 300,000 babies and children have arthritis or a rhematic condition. Arthritis is the leading cause of disability among adults in the U.S. The most common type of arthritis is osteoarthritis. Osteoarthritis affects an estimated 31 million Americans. About two-thirds of adults in the U.S. with arthritis are considered working age (18-64 years). Arthritis is much more prevalent among people who have other chronic conditions. Specifically, 49 percent of adults with heart disease also have arthritis, while 47 percent of adults with diabetes and 31 percent of adults who are obese also have arthritis. By 2040, the number of people expected to have doctor-diagnosed arthritis is estimated to be more than 78 million.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0017">According to the National Center for Complementary and Integrative Health, approximately 1 percent of U.S. adults reported a diagnosis of plantar fasciitis in the 12 months prior to a recent National Health and Wellness Survey. Plantar fasciitis is a progressive degenerative condition that affects the thick bond of tissue covering the bones on the bottom of the foot. This condition has been associated with heel pain, falls, poor quality of life and disability. Plantar fascists is more likely to affect order adults, specifically those ages 45-64 (1.33 percent), while those aged 18 to 44 have the lowest prevalence (0.53 percent).</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0018">Overall prevalence of diagnosed plantar fasciitis with pain was about 0.85 percent. Among the findings of the analysis on characteristics of plantar fasciitis pain, 25 percent responded having severe pain, while 45 percent reported to having moderate pain, and 28 percent had mild pain. More than 61 percent of those diagnosed with plantar fasciitis indicated that they suffer from pain daily, while almost 54 percent reported that their pain interfered with normal work activities at least moderately.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0019">The Secondary Market would consist of various members of the labor force who spend a great deal of time standing or walking. There are approximately 151.44 million Americans (age 16 and older) in the civilian labor force, comprised of 80.57 million men and 70.86 million women aged 16 and older.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0020">This product could be produced in a variety of sizes appropriate for wearing by men, women, and children. It would also be possible to produce this item in an array of colors, textures, materials, infusions, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0021">Infusions are fully custom and personalized within designed to provide the wearers with personal, customizable comfort. This product may provide enhanced comfort and relief from pain as it would incorporate support, like an insole within a shoe. While the SOUL SOXS could be worn by a wide array of individuals, it may be of particular appeal to anyone who suffers with arthritis, diabetes, or back pain as well as various foot problems such as bunions, flat feet, hammer toes, heel spurs, plantar fasciitis, gait, neuropathic pain, etc. to individual needs of consumer for a variety of health issues associated with the feet, wellness, health, with essential oils, fragrances for beauty etc. (would be able to control each added infusions) being all custom infusions of Oils i.e., CBD, Plant Based Substances, Non Plant Based Substances, Coconut Oils, Lavender, Varieties of Scents, etc. either directly into the inserts/insoles/footbeds, gel beds etc. that are able to retain the listed above substances, scents, etc. depending on the variety of different textures, materials, etc. made with but are not limited to polymer materials, 3D printed materials foam, expanded foam, gel, air bubbles, gel bubbles, customizable infusions whether it's any of the below listed substances (where and when legal) either applied by transdermal type patches within the layers of footbed, gel beds, or infused into the materials, layers, textures directly and able to control the amount of , salve, lotion, oil, lavenders, fragrances, Coconut Oils, CBD, delta-9-tetrahydrocannabinol, glycerin, melatonin, etc. (WITHOUT CLAIM to above listed substances and all plant-based substances and non-plant substances)</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0022">According to user wants and needs may be infused manually and be able to reinfuse with said substances above and if so chosen for example directly onto the layers, layer by layer, or dependent on textures and materials that rest in a footbed, inserts, insoles, etc., i.e. infused directly into gel beds that retain Coconut Oils, CBD, Essential Oils, Etc. Just depends on (any of the LISTED SUBSTANCES above could be filled in a plastic, ceramic, recycled materials i.e. baster like syringes with plastic tips that are able to refill, be pre filled depending how much the user needs and wants of MG's for CBD, THC(s) (Delta 8 &#x26; 9), and that is safe, etc. user would be able to use the syringes, basters, etc., that insert dosages directly into the gel bed replacing any empty gel bed that would be prefilled of said plant based substances, non-plant substances, oils, fragrances, etc. pretty much Anything that can be used and infused as ways listed above and below in the arts to the substances that, etc. and for example the syringe, plastic baster, plastic syringe, ceramic syringe with a metal, plastic, ceramic, needle, or anything similar to a medical syringe, etc. could insert directly into gel retaining footbeds, different retaining layers, 3D printed materials, retaining deep heel cups gel beds, or any sizes or any other part of the insole, insert, footbed, that could accept different substances can retain the (ABOVE LISTED SUBSTANCES) such as THC, CBD oils or any type of infusions of Essential Oils etc. The areas of inserts, insoles, footbeds, etc, that retain the actual layers, textures, materials, etc. would be able to be in variety of all different sizes to retain many different MGs of CBD, THC, Essential oils. Fragrances, plant-based substances, non-plant base substances ETC. for example see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref> as seen <b>122</b> could be a certain number of MG of CBD, as <b>124</b> could be an essential oil(s) as <b>126</b> could be a fragrance, etc. as the user would be able to have gel beds, textures, materials pre filled within retaining footbed(s), materials, layers, etc. and or that could roll on straight to textures, i.e. similar to highlighter sized deodorant stick, lip stick sized roller prefilled sticks, where user can manually infuse the layers, textures, materials that lay and rest within the insole, inserts, footbeds, etc. and that come infused to customer's customization on what oils if any they want chosen listed but not limited to CBD, THC, THC Delta 9, Plant Based Substances, Non Plant Based Substances, Etc. and act similar to a Tide White out pens where user directly infuses the layers by rolling on the pens, etc. could know on certain models without diverting from original invention know exactly how much to infuse, how much they infused, and if they want infusions at all.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0025" num="0023">It is an object of the present invention to provide customizable fit for wearer with socks.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0024">It is another object of the present invention to provide added comfort through the inclusion of customizable insoles, inserts, footbeds, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0025">It is a further object of the present invention to provide customizable infusions through both the article of footwear i.e. sock and for the insole, insert, footbed, and any retaining materials, textures, gel beds, etc. for infusions of Essential Oils, CBD, Essential Vitamins, Etc.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0026">These and other objects of the present invention will be apparent from review of the following specification and the accompanying drawings.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0029" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref>. is an overhead view of a pair inserts from perspective of pair of overhead the socks that shows the 1-3 part Insoles shown as <b>102</b>-<b>106</b> connected via magnets by arrows.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>B</figref>. is a is an overhead view of inserts from perspective of pair of socks that shows 1-3 part Insoles connected via magnets, gel lining, and layers that can be retained in the footbed by magnets shown as <b>108</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref>. is a is an overhead view of a pair inserts from perspective of pair of socks that shows 1-3 part Insoles shown as <b>122</b>-<b>126</b> connected via magnets by arrows.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>A</figref>. is a side view of The Soul SoxS depicted in this drawing show article of footwear eg a calf high sock shown as <b>200</b> that has built in extra support <b>222</b> that folds down as shown with arrows pointing down from <b>220</b> into athletic sock and folds back up to mid high all the while providing extra ankle support, cushion, protection, etc. cushioning, padding that is built in for extra support shown as <b>222</b>. It shows the sock <b>200</b> being able to have the main footbed/insert shown as <b>202</b>, <b>204</b> mid foot and <b>206</b> able to retain materials, textures, gels, etc. on the magnetic square, adhesive, magnetic lining, etc. system and strips shown as <b>208</b>, <b>210</b> and <b>212</b>. <b>202</b> would be able to flip and alternate textures on some models i.e., gel to expanding foam, extra cushioned, etc. as <b>204</b> would because it is not the main sole stretching from heel to mid arch. <b>204</b> and <b>206</b> would be able to alternate textures, sizes, shapes, materials,</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>B</figref>. is a side view of The Soul SoxS shows as an article of footwear i.e., a sock shown as <b>240</b> depicted in this drawing show a calf high sock <b>240</b> that has plantar fasciitis wrap shown as <b>248</b> for extra support. The sock also has extra ankle/heel cushioning depicted as <b>250</b>-<b>252</b>. It shows the sock <b>240</b> being able to have the main footbed/insert <b>202</b> able to retain materials, textures, gels, etc. on the magnetic <b>6</b> square system and strips shown as <b>208</b>. <b>202</b> would be able to flip and alternate sides changing textures i.e., gel to expanding foam, extra cushioned, etc. as <b>204</b> would because it is not the main sole stretching from <b>202</b> heel to mid arch. <b>204</b> would be able to alternate sides and change textures, sizes</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref>. The Soul SoxS depicted in this drawing shown as <b>300</b> depict an article of footwear/sock that has received the 6 Layered Support System shown as <b>302</b> and <b>304</b> able to be magnetized, adhered, gel, etc. together. It shows the sock <b>300</b> being able to have the main footbed/insert <b>302</b> able to retain materials, textures, gels, etc. shown as <b>312</b> and <b>314</b>. The textures, materials, gels, etc. would be able to be elevated, layers removed, added, etc. <b>302</b> would be able to flip and alternate sides changing textures i.e., gel to expanding foam, extra cushioned, etc. dependent on the material</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>A-<b>4</b>E</figref> is viewpoint(s) of multiple options for socks from underneath the sock showing openings, slots, pockets, etc. for the retaining insoles, inserts, footbeds, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b>A-<b>5</b>B</figref> is a viewpoint of multiple options for socks from bottom of the sock showing openings, slots, pockets, etc. for retaining insoles, inserts, footbeds, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A-<b>6</b>E</figref> depicts multiple options for Soul SoxS showing sideview(s) of certain models.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>A</figref>. depicts a version of Soul SoxS that is just one solid insert, footbed, insole, made from gel, rubber, expanded foam, etc. shown as <b>720</b>, depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>A</figref>. shows gel lining, gel beds, etc. comprising of infusions such as CBD, THC(s) (Deltas), essential oils, etc. infused throughout the insole and when stepped on will automatically be infused back to user's touch of foot, sweat glands, calluses, etc. may benefit from the wellness of CBD, essential oils, essential vitamins, etc. and <b>740</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>B</figref>. shown overhead as <b>740</b> is depicted as a normal footbed, insert, insole, etc. is shown with medial, lateral arch support like most inserts and Soul SoxS are made with. The heel gel area depicted as <b>724</b> would be able to cup and conform to the ground, surface, etc. that the user is pressing on. The upper area</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0040" num="0038">Other embodiments of the invention will be apparent to those skilled in the art from consideration of the specification and practice of the invention disclosed herein. It is intended that the specification and examples be considered as exemplary only, with a true scope and spirit of the invention being indicated by the following claims. Full custom and personalized improved pair of socks that may be produced from a blend of spandex, polyester, cotton, bamboo fibers, copper, nylon, etc. The socks could be produced in various heights such as ankle, crew, mid-calf, etc. The top of the sock would feature a cushioned, no slip edging, etc. In addition, the heel would feature a cushioned, no slip support while cushioned support could rest around the ankle. The main modification of this cushioned sock would deal with the inclusion of pockets, sleeves, openings, etc. upon its outer sole which would allow various materials to be inserted to relieve pain, support, better balance, help plantar fasciitis, and possibly many other health concerns. The inserts may be produced from various materials to accommodate different needs. The inserts, insoles, gel beds, etc. could rest beneath the hell, ball, and arch of the foot. They may be produced from a plethora of material foam, rubber, plastic, with gel interior, etc. In addition, they may be produced in various widths, sizes and shapes, etc. to accommodate different needs. The interior of the pockets, sleeves, openings, etc. could contain gel, adhesive, magnets, etc. they may ensure the insert remained in the proper place for the wearer. Alternatively, the insoles, inserts, footbeds may be held in place by magnets. The inserts may provide support and added comfort for the user's feet and may decrease the amount of back problems, gait issues, foot and leg fatigue, etc. Also envisioning a removable plantar fasciitis wrap accompanying the SOUL SOXS going from mid high sock to crew that would hold various arch supports in place. The socks could be produced in a plethora of colors and an array of sizes appropriate for wearing by men, women, and children. The concept of Soul SoxS is an improved pair of socks designed to provide wearers with the ability to incorporate support within the sock comprising of an insole/insert/footbed etc. within a shoe. The Inserts may be produced from various materials expanded foam, rubber, plastic, with a gel interior, etc. to accommodate different needs for the consumer for different areas of the foot. The Soul SoxS would be comprising of a pair of socks that may be produced from a blend of spandex, polyester, cotton, nylon, etc. The socks could be produced in various heights, such as ankle, crew, mid-calf, high compression, athletic, also models made with a plantar fasciitis wrap that goes up to calf and folds down for ankle or plantar support going from high sock Multi Layered Soul Compression shown as <b>620</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref>. to low cut sock, etc. The top of the socks would feature a cushioned, no slip edging, in addition, some models of the Soul Sox would have a heel that feature a cushioned no slip support and addition a certain model(s) would have extra cushioned support around the ankle i.e., <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>A-<b>2</b>B</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref>. The main modification of Soul SoxS sock with inserts, insoles, footbeds, etc. would deal with the inclusion of pockets, slots, sleeves, openings, etc. upon its outer sole, heel, arch, mid foot, under toes, etc. The pockets, sleeves, openings, etc. are seen in every model of Soul SoxS and would have gel lining, adhesive, magnets, etc. to hold the 1-3 Part inserts in place. see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A-<b>4</b>B</figref>. As seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref> Article of footwear, sock shown as <b>300</b> would have multiple openings, sleeves, pockets, etc. shown as <b>302</b>-<b>310</b> would be able to accept different articles of materials, textures, sizes, widths, etc. that would attach to the 1-3-part system of inserts/insoles/footbeds etc.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0039">Soul SoxS by entering the pockets, slots, sleeves, openings, etc. <b>306</b> shown as the heel opening, pocket, sleeve, etc. would Ideally be used to take in the main Insert, Footbed, Insole, etc. which starts at the heel to mid arch as shown as <b>302</b> the main insole, insert, footbed, etc. of some models of Soul SoxS. The main Insert, Footbed, insole in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref> depicts a sock shown as <b>100</b> would have 1-3 different pieces with <b>102</b> being the main base support from heel to mid arch, 2<sup>nd </sup>part shown as <b>104</b> would be mid foot right before toes and 3<sup>rd </sup>shown as <b>106</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref> being under the toes. The 3-part system would all come with 6 Layers of Soul Support Technology as seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref>. As seen in that FIGURE, <b>122</b>-<b>126</b> are layered with 6 Layers of Soul Support Technology which includes but not limited to a Bubbly, Checkered Rubber material, infused with Coconut Oil, Essential Vitamins, Essential Oils, THC(Delta 9)Aloe Vera, Shea Butter, etc. or the user would be able to decide what materials, textures, etc. that they want customized through different customizable options and infusions for various fragrances, oils, CBD, etc. for either the Soul SoxS actual sock or whether it's the different materials, textures, etc. that they choose to use in the inserts, insoles, footbeds, etc. although can be customized depending on the consumer wants and needs for textures, sizes, widths of inserts, etc. <b>122</b> would connect to <b>124</b> and or <b>126</b> by magnetic, adhesive, etc. support between each layers of Support or through themselves making one solid insert, footbed, insole if so, chosen by the wearer. All dependent on what sizes, materials, textures, etc. are used in combination of the 1-3-part system for the inserts, insoles, footbeds, etc. to either adhere, magnetize, stick to directly, or one on top of the other, etc. The consumer could always use the main insert, Footbed, insole shown as <b>122</b> by itself as their main base support for the insert while having different textures, materials, sizes, etc. added on through magnets, adhesive, gel, etc. The other parts of Soul SoxS Inserts, insoles, footbeds, etc. shown as <b>124</b> and <b>126</b> could rest in their respective pockets, slots, sleeves, openings, etc. and being all 1 to 3 different parts to the insert, insole, footbed would bend with the consumer's movements and foot. The consumer would be able to flip and alternate the other 3 parts of the Insole between textures, materials, textiles, sizes, shapes, colors etc. on <b>102</b>, <b>104</b> and <b>106</b>. If one side of the insert shown as <b>104</b> was cushioned and the other side of that section of insert could be gel for example. It really depends on what the customer would like to feel and what they see fit for their comfort and relief. Every pair of Soul SoxS comes with Six Layers of Soul Support infused with Coconut Oil, Shea Butter, Aloe Vera, CBD, or whatever the customer chooses etc. as seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref>. Insert/Insoles/Footbed <b>122</b>-<b>126</b> shows the Six Layers of Soul Support Technology which is made of a Honeycomb/Square looking as seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref>. and made from a Bubbly like Rubber materials, textures, etc. infused with odor eating Technology and Coconut Oil, Aloe Vera, Shea Butter, or whatever the customer chooses, etc. Customer would be able to divert from the <b>6</b>Layers of Soul Support to what they see fit, whether it is removing a layer(s) and putting whatever they see fit such as gel, expanded foam, foam, rubber, plastic with a gel interior, etc. without diverting from the main invention. The main base insert shown as <b>102</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref>. starting at heel to mid arch would be able to flip over and alternate between different sides. Some models would just have <b>104</b> and <b>106</b> being able to flip over and alternate sides with <b>102</b> being the main base sole with medial and lateral arch support. <b>102</b>-<b>106</b> would be able to alternate between the 1-6 Layers of Soul Support to a completely different texture, material, size, etc. as mentioned above if so chosen. The 6 Layered Support (6LS) could be different colors, shapes, sizes, textures, etc. and would be held together by magnets, adhesive, gel, layer by layer etc. shown as <b>128</b>-<b>132</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref>. for each layer and each texture, shape, width, etc. to accommodate user needs. The interior of the Soul SoxS pockets, sleeves, openings, would contain a gel lining, magnets, adhesive, etc. to hold the main Footbed, Insole, Inserts, etc. as seen in place in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>B</figref>. <b>108</b>-<b>112</b> as shown have square magnets, adhesive, gel lining etc. shown with squiggly magnetic/adhesive/gel/etc. to hold each layer of the 6Layer Support in place as seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref>. 6 layers are provided dependent on the customer needing 6 or not, they can always go down or up with what the customer desires in textures, sizes, materials, etc. as mentioned above. <b>128</b>-<b>132</b> depicts it would be able to apply any desired texture, material, shape, size etc. without diverting from original invention. Each part from the main base <b>102</b>-<b>106</b> to the other parts of the main footbed/insert and any element, material, texture, etc. applied to those through <b>108</b>-<b>112</b> magnets/adhesive/etc. and added through <b>128</b>-<b>132</b>. Consumer could customize both the Socks and the inserts completely to their liking without diverting from the original invention. Both the Socks and Insert items would be completely customizable in colors, designs, textures, materials, oil infusions, etc.</p>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">SPECIFICATION DESCRIPTION OF INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0042" num="0040">Fully custom and personalized improved pair of socks that may be produced from a blend of spandex, polyester, cotton, bamboo fibers, copper, nylon, etc. The socks could be produced in various heights such as ankle, crew, mid-calf, etc. The top of the sock would feature a cushioned, no slip edging, etc. In addition, the heel would feature a cushioned, no slip support while cushioned support could rest around the ankle. The main modification of this cushioned sock would deal with the inclusion of pockets, sleeves, openings, etc. upon its outer sole which would allow various materials to be inserted to relieve pain, support, better balance, help plantar fasciitis, and possibly many other health concerns. The inserts may be produced from various materials to accommodate different needs. The inserts, insoles, gel beds, etc. could rest beneath the hell, ball, and arch of the foot. They may be produced from a plethora of material foam, rubber, plastic, with gel interior, etc. In addition, they may be produced in various widths, sizes and shapes, etc. to accommodate different needs. The interior of the pockets, sleeves, openings, etc. could contain gel, adhesive, magnets, etc. they may ensure the insert remained in the proper place for the wearer. Alternatively, the insoles, inserts, footbeds may be held in place by magnets. The inserts may provide support and added comfort for the user's feet and may decrease the amount of back problems, gait issues, foot and leg fatigue, etc. Also envisioning a removable plantar fascist wrap accompanying the SOUL SOXS going from mid high sock to crew that would hold various arch supports in place. The socks could be produced in a plethora of colors and an array of sizes appropriate for wearing by men, women, and children.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0041">The concept of Soul SoxS is an improved pair of socks designed to provide wearers with the ability to incorporate support within the sock comprising of an insole/insert/footbed etc. within a shoe. The Inserts may be produced from various materials expanded foam, rubber, plastic, with a gel interior, etc. to accommodate different needs for the consumer for different areas of the foot. The Soul SoxS would be comprising of a pair of socks that may be produced from a blend of spandex, polyester, cotton, nylon, etc. The socks could be produced in various heights, such as ankle, crew, mid-calf, high compression, athletic, also models made with a plantar fasciitis wrap that goes up to calf and folds down for ankle or plantar support going from high sock Multi Layered Soul Compression shown as <b>620</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref>. to low cut sock, etc. The top of the socks would feature a cushioned, no slip edging, in addition, some models of the Soul Sox would have a heel that feature a cushioned no slip support and addition a certain model(s) would have extra cushioned support around the ankle i.e., <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>A-<b>2</b>B</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0042">The main modification of Soul SoxS sock with inserts, insoles, footbeds, etc. would deal with the inclusion of pockets, slots, sleeves, openings, etc. upon its outer sole, heel, arch, mid foot, under toes, etc. The pockets, sleeves, openings, etc. are seen in every model of Soul SoxS and would have gel lining, adhesive, magnets, etc. to hold the 1-3 Part inserts in place. see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A-<b>4</b>B</figref>. As seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref> Article of footwear, sock shown as <b>300</b> would have multiple openings, sleeves, pockets, etc. shown as <b>302</b>-<b>310</b> would be able to accept different articles of materials, textures, sizes, widths, etc. that would attach to the 1-3-part system of inserts/insoles/footbeds etc.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0043">Soul SoxS by entering the pockets, slots, sleeves, openings, etc. <b>306</b> shown as the heel opening, pocket, sleeve, etc. would Ideally be used to take in the main Insert, Footbed, Insole, etc. which starts at the heel to mid arch as shown as <b>302</b> the main insole, insert, footbed, etc. of some models of Soul SoxS. The main Insert, Footbed, insole in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref> depicts a sock shown as <b>100</b> would have 1-3 different pieces with <b>102</b> being the main base support from heel to mid arch, 2<sup>nd </sup>part shown as <b>104</b> would be mid foot right before toes and 3<sup>rd </sup>shown as <b>106</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref> being under the toes. The 3-part system would all come with 6 Layers of Soul Support Technology as seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref>. As seen in that FIGURE, <b>122</b>-<b>126</b> are layered with 6 Layers of Soul Support Technology which includes but not limited to a Bubbly, Checkered Rubber material, infused with Coconut Oil, Essential Vitamins, Essential Oils, THC(Delta 9)Aloe Vera, Shea Butter, etc. or the user would be able to decide what materials, textures, etc. that they want customized through different customizable options and infusions for various fragrances, oils, CBD, etc. for either the Soul SoxS actual sock or whether it's the different materials, textures, etc. that they choose to use in the inserts, insoles, footbeds, etc. although can be customized depending on the consumer wants and needs for textures, sizes, widths of inserts, etc. <b>122</b> would connect to <b>124</b> and or <b>126</b> by magnetic, adhesive, etc. support between each layers of Support or through themselves making one solid insert, footbed, insole if so, chosen by the wearer. All dependent on what sizes, materials, textures, etc. are used in combination of the 1-3-part system for the inserts, insoles, footbeds, etc. to either adhere, magnetize, stick to directly, or one on top of the other, etc. The consumer could always use the main insert, Footbed, insole shown as <b>122</b> by itself as their main base support for the insert while having different textures, materials, sizes, etc. added on through magnets, adhesive, gel, etc. The other parts of Soul SoxS Inserts, insoles, footbeds, etc. shown as <b>124</b> and <b>126</b> could rest in their respective pockets, slots, sleeves, openings, etc. and being all 1 to 3 different parts to the insert, insole, footbed would bend with the consumer's movements and foot. The consumer would be able to flip and alternate the other 3 parts of the Insole between textures, materials, textiles, sizes, shapes, colors etc. on <b>102</b>, <b>104</b> and <b>106</b>. If one side of the insert shown as <b>104</b> was cushioned and the other side of that section of insert could be gel for example. It really depends on what the customer would like to feel and what they see fit for their comfort and relief. Every pair of Soul SoxS comes with Six Layers of Soul Support infused with Coconut Oil, Shea Butter, Aloe Vera, CBD, or whatever the customer chooses etc. as seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref>. Insert/Insoles/Footbed <b>122</b>-<b>126</b> shows the Six Layers of Soul Support Technology which is made of a Honeycomb/Square looking as seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref>. and made from a Bubbly like Rubber materials, textures, etc. infused with odor eating Technology and Coconut Oil, Aloe Vera, Shea Butter, or whatever the customer chooses, etc. Customer would be able to divert from the 6Layers of Soul Support to what they see fit, whether it is removing a layer(s) and putting whatever they see fit such as gel, expanded foam, foam, rubber, plastic with a gel interior, etc. without diverting from the main invention. The main base insert shown as <b>102</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref>. starting at heel to mid arch would be able to flip over and alternate between different sides. Some models would just have <b>104</b> and <b>106</b> being able to flip over and alternate sides with <b>102</b> being the main base sole with medial and lateral arch support. <b>102</b>-<b>106</b> would be able to alternate between the 1-6 Layers of Soul Support to a completely different texture, material, size, etc. as mentioned above if so chosen. The 6 Layered Support(6LS) could be different colors, shapes, sizes, textures, etc. and would be held together by magnets, adhesive, gel, layer by layer etc. shown as <b>128</b>-<b>132</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref>. for each layer and each texture, shape, width, etc. to accommodate user needs. The interior of the Soul SoxS pockets, sleeves, openings, would contain a gel lining, magnets, adhesive, etc. to hold the main Footbed, Insole, Inserts, etc. as seen in place in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>B</figref>. <b>108</b>-<b>112</b> as shown have square magnets, adhesive, gel lining etc. shown with squiggly magnetic/adhesive/gel/etc. to hold each layer of the 6Layer Support in place as seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref>. 6 layers are provided dependent on the customer needing 6 or not, they can always go down or up with what the customer desires in textures, sizes, materials, etc. as mentioned above. <b>128</b>-<b>132</b> depicts it would be able to apply any desired texture, material, shape, size etc. without diverting from original invention. Each part from the main base <b>102</b>-<b>106</b> to the other parts of the main footbed/insert and any element, material, texture, etc. applied to those through <b>108</b>-<b>112</b> magnets/adhesive/etc. and added through <b>128</b>-<b>132</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0044">Consumer could customize both the Socks and the Inserts completely to their liking without diverting from the original invention. Both the Socks and Insert items would be completely customizable in colors, designs, textures, materials, oil infusions, etc. Infusions are fully custom and personalized within designed to provide the wearers with personal, customizable comfort. This product may provide enhanced comfort and relief from pain as it would incorporate support, like an insole within a shoe. While the SOUL SOXS could be worn by a wide array of individuals, it may be of particular appeal to anyone who suffers with arthritis, diabetes, or back pain as well as various foot problems such as bunions, flat feet, hammer toes, heel spurs, plantar fasciitis, gait, neuropathic pain, etc. to individual needs of consumer for a variety of health issues associated with the feet, wellness, health, with essential oils, fragrances for beauty etc. (would be able to control each added infusions)</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0045">Fully custom socks made from a variety of customized materials, textures, sizes, shapes, designs, etc. that have multiple openings, slots, pockets, gel lining, magnetic bottom (either within sock or on bottom of sock) and within the sock to retain the multiple pieces of footbed, inserts, insoles, and smaller pieces i.e. added layers, textures, materials to both the outer, inner, bottom, top, etc. of the socks as well as the inserts, insoles, footbeds, etc. which would connect by magnets, gel adhesive, gel lining, etc. to make multiple sections of the insert, insole, footbed, as one full insert, insole, footbed, etc. The insert, insole, footbeds, etc. being connected by magnets, gel adhesive, gel lining, etc. to be able to bend with user's foot as more comparable to an athletic shoe being a 1-3 part system, being all custom infusions of Oils i.e. THC, CBD, Plant Based Substances, Non Plant Based Substances, Coconut Oils, Lavender, Varieties of Scents, etc. either directly into the inserts/insoles/footbeds, gel beds etc. that are able to retain the listed above substances, scents, etc. depending on the many different textures, materials, etc. made with but are not limited to polymer materials, 3D printed materials said layers that stay in place or adhere by gel, magnets, gel lining, etc. that can be inserted into an article of footwear e.g. custom socks, hosiery, garment as stated in previous arts fully customizable socks, e.g. colors, textures, materials, as well as fully customizable infusions whether it's any of the below listed substances where and when legal either applied by transdermal type patches within the layers and able to control the amount of , salve, lotion, oil, lavenders, fragrances, Coconut Oils, CBD, delta-9-tetrahydrocannabinol, glycerin, melatonin, etc. (WITHOUT CLAIM to above listed substances all plant-based substances and non-plant substances)</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0046">According to consumer's wants and needs may be infused via manually be able to reinfuse with said substances above and if so chosen for example directly onto the layers, layer by layer, or dependent on textures and materials that rest in a footbed, inserts, insoles, etc., i.e. gel beds that retain Coconut Oils, CBD, Essential Oils, Etc. Just depends on (any of the LISTED SUBSTANCES above could be filled in a plastic, ceramic, recycled materials i.e. baster like syringes with plastic needles that are able to refill, be pre filled depending how much the user needs and wants of MG's for CBD, and that is safe, etc. user would be able to use the syringes, basters, etc., that insert dosages directly into the gel bed replacing any empty gel bed plant based substances, non-plant substances, oils, fragrances, etc. pretty much Anything that can be used and infused as ways listed above and below in the arts to the substances that, etc. and for example the syringe, plastic baster, plastic syringe, ceramic syringe with a metal, plastic, ceramic, needle, or anything similar to a medical syringe, etc. could insert directly into gel retaining footbeds, different retaining layers, 3D printed materials, retaining deep heel cups gel beds, or any sizes or any other part of the insole, insert, footbed, that could accept different substances can retain the (ABOVE LISTED SUBSTANCES) such as THC, CBD oils or any type of infusions of Essential Oils etc. The areas of inserts, insoles, footbeds, etc, that retain the actual layers, textures, materials, etc. would be able to be in variety of all different sizes to retain many different MG's of CBD, THC, Essential oils. Fragrances, plant-based substances, non-plant base substances ETC. for example see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref> as seen <b>102</b> could be a certain number of MG of CBD, as <b>104</b> could be an essential oil(s) as <b>106</b> could be a fragrance, etc. as the user would be able to have gel beds, textures, materials pre filled within retaining footbed, materials, layers, etc. that may roll on straight to textures, i.e. similar to highlighter sized deodorant stick, lip stick sized roller prefilled sticks, where user can manually infuse the layers, textures, materials that lay and rest within the insole, inserts, footbeds, etc. and that come infused to customer's customization on what oils if any they want chosen listed but not limited to CBD, THC, THC Delta 9, Plant Based Substances, Non Plant Based Substances, Etc. and act similar to a Tide White out pens where user directly infuses the layers by rolling on the pens, etc. could know on certain models without diverting from original invention know exactly how much to infuse, how much they infused, and if they want infusions at all.</p>
<heading id="h-0008" level="1">FIG. <b>1</b>A</heading>
<p id="p-0049" num="0047">Depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref>. shows an overhead view of the inserts shown as <b>102</b>-<b>106</b> that are occupied by an article of footwear <b>100</b> sock. <b>102</b> is the main part of the insert, insole, footbeds, going to from heel to mid arch, to forefoot <b>104</b> to under toes shown as <b>106</b>, comprising but not limited to made with square magnet, gel, adhesive, etc. shown as <b>108</b>-<b>112</b> to hold down the Six Layers of Soul Support layer by layer i.e. materials, textures, layers, shown as <b>122</b>, <b>124</b>, and <b>126</b>(Depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref>.) that come with every pair of Soul SoxS. The insole, insert, footbed, etc. shown as <b>102</b> would be able to retain many layers of cushioning made of many different materials, textures, gels, sizes, widths, etc. The 6 Layer Support Technology is made of but not limited to a heavy-duty Checkered Rubber lining that conforms to your foot as shown on <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref>, but can be optional or made from whatever texture, material, size, etc. the user prefers. <b>102</b> being the main receiving base would be able to retain many different materials whether its acupuncture points, gel, expanded foam, rubber liners, gel with plastic, etc. As seen in the <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref>, the insole <b>102</b> would be able to magnetize, adhere, stick, etc. to insole, insert, footbed, etc. <b>104</b>. <b>104</b> could be able to be many different textures as well as listed above and is located mid foot in front of arch in between toes. <b>104</b> would be able to have elevated textures, materials, gels, air bubbles, oil infused gel beds, etc. to alleviate whatever wellness, health, gait, etc. the user wants to customize. Insole <b>104</b> would also be able to be completely different textures, materials, sizes, widths, lengths, etc. and magnetize, adhere, gel lining, etc. to <b>102</b> with or without the support of <b>104</b>. Whether it is an expanded foam, gel, ridged material, etc. in substitute of where insole/footbed <b>104</b> and or <b>106</b> would be. Depending on the size the user needs precut to magnetize and accommodate the main insole/foot base <b>102</b>. Depicting sleeves/pockets/entry ways is <b>114</b>-<b>120</b>, each of these would be able to intake and or retain any of the listed footbeds, insoles, etc. adhered together would make one complete insole to <b>102</b>-<b>106</b> insole/insert/footbeds with the main basin <b>102</b> going through entry points with <b>114</b> being most reasonable. <b>114</b>-<b>120</b> would be able to take in other textures, materials, sizes, widths, etc. that magnetize, adhere, etc. to the top of the 1-3 part insert, shown as <b>102</b>-<b>106</b> if so desired by the customer. comprised as square/strips/of magnetic copper etc. Depicted as <b>108</b>-<b>112</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref>. the top part of the inserts/insoles/footbeds etc. shows magnets, adhesive lining, gel lining, etc. as <b>128</b>-<b>132</b> able to retain multiple layers of the Six Layers of Support or whatever texture, material, textile, etc. that the consumer would prefer to use where it could be gel/rubber/expanded foam/foam/etc. in all shapes, sizes, color, widths, lengths, etc. that rest in the respected insoles/inserts/footbeds etc. shown as <b>102</b>-<b>106</b></p>
<heading id="h-0009" level="1">FIG. <b>1</b>B-<b>1</b>C</heading>
<p id="p-0050" num="0048">Depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>B</figref>. shows an overhead view of the inserts, insoles, footbeds, etc. shown as <b>102</b>-<b>106</b> that are occupied by an article of footwear shown as a sock <b>120</b>. <b>102</b> is the main part of the insert, insole, footbeds, shown as <b>102</b>-<b>106</b> made with square magnet, gel, adhesive, etc. shown as <b>108</b>-<b>112</b> to hold down the Six Layers of Soul Support layer by layer shown as <b>122</b>, <b>124</b>, and <b>126</b> (Depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref>.) shows the insole receiving materials, textures, etc. layer by layer and as depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref> shows the 6 Layer Support that come with every pair of Soul SoxS. The insole, insert, footbed, etc. shown as <b>102</b> would be able to retain many layers of cushioning made of many different materials, textures, gels, sizes, widths, etc. The 6 Layer Support Technology is made of but not limited to a heavy-duty Checkered Rubber lining that conforms to your foot as shown on <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref>., but can be optional or made from whatever texture, material, size, etc. the user prefers. <b>102</b> being the main receiving base would be able to retain many different materials whether its acupuncture points, gel, expanded foam, rubber liners, gel with plastic, etc. As seen in the <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref>., the insole <b>102</b> would be able to magnetize, adhere, stick, etc. to insole, insert, footbed, etc. <b>104</b>. <b>104</b> could be able to be many different textures as well as listed above and is located mid foot in front of arch in between toes. <b>104</b> would be able to have elevated textures, materials, gels, air bubbles, oil infused gel beds, etc. to alleviate whatever wellness, health, gait, etc. the user wants to customize. Insole <b>104</b> would also be able to be completely different textures, materials, sizes, widths, lengths, etc. and magnetize, adhere, gel lining, etc. to <b>102</b> with or without the support of <b>104</b>. Whether it is an expanded foam, gel, ridged material, etc. in substitute of where insole/footbed <b>104</b> and or <b>106</b> would be. Depending on the size the user needs precut to magnetize and accommodate the main insole/foot base <b>102</b>. Depicting sleeves/pockets/entry ways is <b>114</b>-<b>120</b>, each of these would be able to intake and or retain any of the listed footbeds, insoles, etc. adhered together would make one complete insole to <b>102</b>-<b>106</b> insole/insert/footbeds with the main basin <b>102</b> going through entry points with <b>114</b> being most reasonable. <b>114</b>-<b>120</b> would be able to take in other textures, materials, sizes, widths, etc. that magnetize, adhere, etc. to the top of the 1-3 part insert, shown as <b>102</b>-<b>106</b> if so desired by the customer. comprised as square/strips/of magnetic copper etc. Depicted as <b>108</b>-<b>112</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref>. the top part of the inserts/insoles/footbeds etc. shows magnets, adhesive lining, gel lining, etc. as <b>128</b>-<b>132</b> able to retain multiple layers of the Six Layers of Support or whatever texture, material, textile, etc. that the consumer would prefer to use where it could be gel/rubber/expanded foam/foam/etc. in all shapes, sizes, color, widths, lengths, etc. that rest in the respected insoles/inserts/footbeds etc. shown as <b>102</b>-<b>106</b>.</p>
<heading id="h-0010" level="1">FIG. <b>2</b>A</heading>
<p id="p-0051" num="0049">The Soul SoxS depicted in this drawing show a calf high sock shown as <b>200</b> that has built in extra support <b>222</b> that folds down as shown with arrows pointing down from <b>220</b> into athletic sock and folds back up to mid high all the while providing extra ankle support, cushion, protection, etc. cushioning, padding that is built in for extra support shown as <b>222</b>. It shows the sock <b>200</b> being able to have the main footbed/insert shown as <b>202</b>, <b>204</b> mid foot and <b>206</b> able to retain materials, textures, gels, etc. on the magnetic square, adhesive, magnetic lining, etc. system and strips shown as <b>208</b>, <b>210</b> and <b>212</b>. <b>202</b> would be able to flip and alternate textures on some models i.e., gel to expanding foam, extra cushioned, etc. as <b>204</b> would because it is not the main sole stretching from heel to mid arch. <b>204</b> and <b>206</b> would be able to alternate textures, sizes, shapes, materials, etc. by flipping over the opposing side and It would come with the 6-layer system throughout <b>202</b>-<b>206</b> as all Soul SoxS do. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>A</figref> opening on heel of sock show as <b>214</b>, mid arch shown as <b>216</b> and front area as <b>218</b> would be able to accept members <b>202</b>-<b>206</b> and be of access to any other type of material, textures, shapes, sizes etc. that attach to <b>202</b>-<b>206</b>. <b>206</b> Is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>B</figref> as the foremost of the foot and would not necessarily need to be used or connected with <b>202</b> and same with <b>204</b>. All dependent on the users' needs and what ails them at the time. <b>220</b> would be able to fold up and down acting as a Mid-Calf Compression Sock then to fold and act as support to the heel, ankle, plantar area, arch, etc. once folded down then in turn act as a crew sock as the consumer pleases as well as the insert, textures, materials, etc. to better hold in place as well as being able <b>222</b>-fold up for even more low/high ankle support/cushioning/etc. depending on what the user needs, feels, customizes, etc.</p>
<heading id="h-0011" level="1">FIG. <b>2</b>B</heading>
<p id="p-0052" num="0050">The Soul SoxS shows an article of footwear i.e., a sock shown as <b>240</b> depicted in this drawing show a calf high sock <b>240</b> that has plantar fasciitis wrap shown as <b>248</b> for extra support. The sock also has extra ankle/heel cushioning depicted as <b>250</b>-<b>252</b>. It shows the sock <b>240</b> being able to have the main footbed/insert <b>202</b> able to retain materials, textures, gels, etc. on the magnetic <b>6</b> square system and strips shown as <b>208</b>. <b>202</b> would be able to flip and alternate sides changing textures i.e., gel to expanding foam, extra cushioned, etc. as <b>204</b> would because it is not the main sole stretching from <b>202</b> heel to mid arch. <b>204</b> would be able to alternate sides and change textures, sizes, shapes, materials, etc. by flipping over the opposing side and It would come with the 6-layer system throughout <b>202</b>-<b>206</b> as all Soul SoxS do. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>B</figref> <b>242</b>-<b>246</b> depicts openings, sleeves, slots, pockets, etc. on heel of sock shown as <b>242</b>to the front part of the sock <b>242</b>-<b>246</b> as shown would be able to accept members <b>202</b>-<b>206</b> and be of access to any other type of material, textures, shapes, sizes etc. that wish to be attached to <b>202</b> and <b>204</b> and any added layers shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>B</figref> as the foremost of the foot and would not necessarily need to be used just always dependent on the user. As shown <b>248</b> Plantar Fasciitis Wrap would be able to hold the insert, textures, materials, etc. in place as well as being able fold up for even more low/high ankle support/cushioning/etc.</p>
<heading id="h-0012" level="1">FIG. <b>3</b>A</heading>
<p id="p-0053" num="0051">The Soul SoxS depicted in this drawing shown as <b>300</b> depict an article of footwear/sock that has received the 6 Layered Support System shown as <b>302</b> and <b>304</b> able to be magnetized, adhered, gel, etc. together. It shows the sock <b>300</b> being able to have the main footbed/insert <b>302</b> able to retain materials, textures, gels, etc. shown as <b>312</b> and <b>314</b>. The textures, materials, gels, etc. would be able to be elevated, layers removed, added, etc. <b>302</b> would be able to flip and alternate sides changing textures i.e., gel to expanding foam, extra cushioned, etc. dependent on the material it is as <b>304</b> would because it is not the main sole stretching from <b>302</b> heel to mid arch. Some models of Soul SoxS come solely with the 1-3-part system and <b>302</b> not being able to alternate sides. <b>304</b> would be able to alternate sides and change textures, sizes, shapes, materials, etc. by flipping over the opposing side and It would come with the 6-layer support system as shown in this FIGURE and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref>. As shown throughout <b>302</b>-<b>304</b> as all Soul SoxS do come with the 6 Layered Support. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref> <b>306</b>-<b>310</b> openings, sleeves, slots, pockets, etc. on heel of sock to the arch shown as <b>308</b> to front part of the sock shown as <b>310</b>. <b>306</b>-<b>310</b> would be able to accept members <b>302</b>-<b>304</b> and be of access to any other type of material, textures, shapes, sizes etc. that wish to be attached to the Main Basin <b>302</b> and <b>304</b> forefoot area and any added layers shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref>. as <b>312</b>-<b>314</b> being able to retain any other type of material, texture, shapes, sizes, etc. as the foremost of the foot and would not necessarily need to be used within a slot, pocket, opening, etc. dependent on the consumers wants and needs. Consumer could always decide materials, gels, etc. as mentioned above without diverting from the materials, gels, etc.</p>
<heading id="h-0013" level="1">FIG. <b>4</b>A-<b>5</b>B</heading>
<p id="p-0054" num="0052">Shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>A</figref> is a <b>400</b> Sock that has 6 options, <b>402</b>-<b>412</b> for openings, slots, pockets, etc. for the Soul SoxS inserts, insoles, footbed, textures, materials, etc. added as shown in previous <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A-<b>1</b>C</figref>. These socks would have flaps/slots shown as <b>404</b> and <b>408</b> in this Figure. They would have gel lining on the interior to hold whatever materials, textures in place. <b>402</b>, <b>406</b>, <b>410</b>, <b>412</b> would all be openings/slots to take in the Soul SoxS inserts, materials, textures, etc. able to take in the main base insert as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref>. <b>122</b> the main base insert would be able to insert in through anyone of the entries listed above and shown throughout <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>A-<b>5</b>B</figref>. shown as Socks <b>400</b>-<b>520</b> Mostly going through the heel for the main base <b>122</b> insert or may go through the <b>404</b> and <b>408</b> middle, <b>406</b> and <b>410</b> sides, <b>412</b> toe areas, etc. Same goes for the remaining parts of the Soul SoxS <b>124</b> and <b>126</b> may as well use the entries listed above. Materials, textures, layers, shapes, sizes, etc. as well go through any one of these slots, pockets, sleeves, etc. shown as <b>422</b>-<b>430</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>B</figref>. and depicted in the <b>420</b> Sock Soul SoxS. Socks <b>400</b>-<b>520</b> would all be able to accept various materials, textures, layers, shapes, sizes, inserts, insoles, footbeds, etc. through the various slots, pockets, sleeves, etc. whether they are stitched, gel lined, spandex type of stretch, copper fibers, magnetic fibers, etc. that all Soul SoxS may be made of and all be in the <b>400</b>-<b>520</b> socks listed above.</p>
<heading id="h-0014" level="1">FIG. <b>6</b>A</heading>
<p id="p-0055" num="0053">Depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref>. is an article of footwear i.e. sock shown as <b>600</b> shows many slots, pockets, openings, etc. depicted as <b>602</b>-<b>608</b> for the front opening shown as <b>602</b> would be by opening at the top of the sock where users foot would enter, and where the opening, slots, pockets, etc. to retain the footbeds, gel beds, insoles, inserts, etc. such as <b>302</b>-<b>306</b>, but not limited to said area if user would like to have The Soul SoxS depicted in this drawing shown as <b>600</b> depict an article of footwear/sock that has received the 6 Layered Support System i.e. inserts, insoles, footbeds, etc. shown as <b>610</b> within the article of footwear <b>600</b> and <b>302</b>-<b>306</b> able to be magnetized, adhered, gel, etc. together. It shows the sock <b>600</b> being able to have the main footbed/insert <b>302</b> able to retain 3D printed materials, textures, gels, etc. shown as <b>312</b> and <b>314</b>. The textures, materials, gels, etc. would be able to be elevated, layers removed, added, etc. <b>302</b> would be able to flip and alternate sides changing textures i.e., gel to expanding foam, extra cushioned, etc. dependent on the material it is as <b>304</b> would because it is not the main sole stretching from <b>302</b> heel to mid arch. Some models of Soul SoxS come solely with the 1-3-part system and <b>302</b> not being able to alternate sides. <b>304</b> would be able to alternate sides in this depiction of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref>. shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref>. and change textures, sizes, shapes, materials, etc. by flipping over the opposing side and It would come with the 6-layer support system as shown in this <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref>. and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref>. As shown throughout <b>302</b>-<b>304</b> as all Soul SoxS do come with the 6 Layered Support which comprises of the honeycomb like material that could be made of various textures with mesh odor eating technology, gel beds infused with Essential Oils, CBD, Fragrances, Lotions, etc. and or personalized to user's liking As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref> <b>602</b>-<b>608</b> openings, sleeves, slots, pockets, etc. on heel of sock shown as <b>604</b> to the arch shown as <b>606</b> to front part of the sock shown as <b>608</b>. <b>602</b>-<b>608</b> would be able to accept members of insoles, inserts, footbeds, etc. (refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref> for depiction of insoles, inserts, footbeds, etc.) <b>610</b> depicts the insert within the article of footwear i.e. sock shown as <b>600</b> with the 6 Layered Support and <b>602</b>-<b>608</b> to be of access to any other type of material, textures, shapes, sizes etc. that wish to be attached to the Main Basin insole, insert, footbed, etc. <b>302</b> and <b>304</b> fore foot area and any added layers shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref>. as <b>312</b>-<b>314</b> being able to retain any other type of material, texture, shapes, sizes, etc. as the foremost of the foot and would not necessarily need to be used within a slot, pocket, opening, etc. dependent on the user's wants and needs or whatever is easiest for entry. User could always decide what is best for what part of foot or section of foot to be treated with textures, materials, gels, etc. as mentioned above without diverting from the original invention. Depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref>. shows <b>612</b> as a cushioned no slip top part of high ankle and compression as <b>614</b> with the built-in arch, ankle padding shown as <b>616</b>. <b>618</b> depicts an arch dividing plantar fasciitis support on the sock. This would give the user more support on said area of foot while providing a dividing line for the 1-3-part insert, insole, footbed, etc. to make it easier to stay in place. <b>620</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref>. (not to be confused with the <b>620</b> depicted as an article of footwear i.c. extra compression sock in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>B</figref>.) would be a deeper heel slot, pocket, etc. with gel lining, magnets, adhesive, etc. to hold above mentioned arts Main Basin insole, insert, footbed, etc. <b>610</b> in place. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref> also depicts <b>620</b> as the front end of the sock for extra built-in toe cushioning. <b>620</b> would be a deeper sectioned slot, pocket, opening, etc. as it is in the heel part of the sock to better hold the insert, insole, footbed, etc. in place and both article of footwear i.e. <b>600</b> sock and <b>610</b> shows the insert, insole, footbed, etc. may retain materials, textures, designs, etc. on the outer surface of the sock through magnets, gel, adhesives, etc.</p>
<heading id="h-0015" level="1">FIG. <b>6</b>B</heading>
<p id="p-0056" num="0054">Shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>B</figref>. is a sock shown as <b>620</b> that has multiple flaps, tabs, no slip cushioned tips shown as <b>622</b>. The no slip flaps, tabs, tips would be able to fold down into sections to provide more support on the upper calf, ankle, plantar area, etc. surfaces. <b>622</b> would fold down to <b>624</b> making an original high single compression into a double compressional mid-calf sock. If the customer were to fold down section <b>624</b> to <b>626</b> shown as the ankle area to make extra cushion. The customer would be able to decide what kind of support they would prefer from he sectioned compression Soul SoxS. Whether it is the Soul Tips, flaps, tabs shown as <b>622</b> being folded down to <b>624</b> to make double compression covering mid-calf or if they wanted to cover the heel opening, slot, pockets, etc. and mid arch area with more cushion and compression shown as <b>628</b> and <b>630</b> respectfully. The consumer would have the choice of having the Soul Flaps shown as <b>622</b> folded all the way down from <b>622</b> towards the heel shown as <b>628</b> to the mid arch shown as <b>630</b> to front foot shown as <b>632</b> covering the insole, insert, footbeds, shown as <b>634</b> and <b>636</b> and any materials, textures, gels, etc. added to magnets, adhesive, etc. shown as <b>638</b> and <b>640</b> on the bare footbed, insoles, inserts, etc. The inserts are shown with squared magnets to hold 6 Layers of Soul Support Technology. The consumer could always decide the texture, color, sizes, shapes, etc. for their inserts shown as <b>634</b> and <b>636</b>. The arrows on <b>634</b> and <b>636</b> indicate that they can flip and alternate sides going from texture to texture whether it is a regular foot insert with expanded foam to gel lining for example. <b>634</b> and <b>636</b> could magnetize together if so, chosen by the wearer, whether it is stuck directly to it through the 6 layers or Soul Support or one on top of the other through magnets, adhesive, etc. All depends on what the wearer feels on each foot or section of foot. Ideally the main insert <b>634</b> would go through the heel opening, slot, pocket, etc. shown as <b>638</b>. Depends on practicality of the shape, size, width, material, insert, etc. on which entries shown as <b>628</b>-<b>632</b> would go into.</p>
<heading id="h-0016" level="1">FIG. <b>6</b>C</heading>
<p id="p-0057" num="0055">Depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>C</figref>. is an article of footwear i.e. ankle cut sock shown as <b>640</b> and shows many slots, pockets, openings, etc. depicted as <b>642</b>-<b>648</b> for the front opening shown as <b>642</b> would be by opening at the top of the sock where users foot would enter, and where the opening, slots, pockets, etc. to retain the footbeds, gel beds, insoles, inserts, etc. such as depicted as <b>302</b>-<b>306</b> In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref>., but not limited to said area if user would like to have The Soul SoxS depicted in this drawing shown as <b>640</b> depict an article of footwear/sock that has received the 6 Layered Support System i.e. inserts, insoles, footbeds, etc. shown as <b>656</b> within the article of footwear <b>600</b> and footbeds, insoles, inserts, etc. shown as <b>302</b>-<b>306</b> able to be magnetized, adhered, gel, etc. together. It shows the sock <b>640</b> being able to have the main footbed/insert <b>302</b> able to retain 3D printed materials, textures, gels, etc. shown as <b>312</b> and <b>314</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref>. The textures, materials, gels, etc. would be able to be elevated, layers removed, added, etc. <b>302</b> would be able to flip and alternate sides changing textures i.e., gel to expanding foam, extra cushioned, etc. dependent on the material it is as <b>304</b> would because it is not the main sole stretching from <b>302</b> heel to mid arch. Some models of Soul SoxS come solely with the 1-3-part system and <b>302</b> not being able to alternate sides. <b>304</b> would be able to alternate sides in this depiction of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref>. shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref>. and change textures, sizes, shapes, materials, etc. by flipping over the opposing side and It would come with the 6-layer support system as shown in this <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref>. and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref>. As shown throughout <b>302</b>-<b>304</b> as all Soul SoxS do come with the 6 Layered Support which comprise of the honeycomb like material that could be made of various textures with mesh odor eating technology, gel beds infused with Essential Oils, CBD, Fragrances, Lotions, etc. and or personalized to user's liking As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref> <b>602</b>-<b>608</b> openings, sleeves, slots, pockets, etc. on heel of sock shown as <b>604</b> to the arch shown as <b>606</b> to front part of the sock shown as <b>608</b>. <b>602</b>-<b>608</b> would be able to accept members of insoles, inserts, footbeds, etc. (refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref> for depiction of insoles, inserts, footbeds, etc.) <b>610</b> depicts the insert within the article of footwear i.e. sock shown as <b>600</b> with the 6 Layered Support and <b>602</b>-<b>608</b> to be of access to any other type of material, textures, shapes, sizes etc. that wish to be attached to the Main Basin insole, insert, footbed, etc. <b>302</b> and <b>304</b> fore foot area and any added layers shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref>. as <b>312</b>-<b>314</b> being able to retain any other type of material, texture, shapes, sizes, etc. as the foremost of the foot and would not necessarily need to be used within a slot, pocket, opening, etc. dependent on the user's wants and needs or whatever is easiest for entry. User could always decide what is best for what part of foot or section of foot to be treated with textures, materials, gels, etc. as mentioned above without diverting from the original invention. Depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref>. shows <b>612</b> as a cushioned no slip top part of high ankle and compression as <b>614</b> with the built-in arch, ankle padding shown as <b>616</b>. <b>618</b> depicts an arch dividing plantar fasciitis support on the sock. This would give the user more support on said area of foot while providing a dividing line for the 1-3-part insert, insole, footbed, etc. to make it easier to stay in place. <b>620</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref>. (not to be confused with the <b>620</b> depicted as an article of footwear i.e. extra compression sock in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>B</figref>.) would be a deeper heel slot, pocket, etc. with gel lining, magnets, adhesive, etc. to hold above mentioned arts Main Basin insole, insert, footbed, etc. <b>610</b> in place. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref> also depicts <b>620</b> as the front end of the sock for extra built-in toe cushioning. <b>620</b> would be a deeper sectioned slot, pocket, opening, etc. as it is in the heel part of the sock to better hold the insert, insole, footbed, etc. in place and both article of footwear i.e. <b>600</b> sock and <b>610</b> shows the insert, insole, footbed, etc. may retain materials, textures, designs, etc. on the outer surface of the sock through magnets, gel, adhesives, e</p>
<heading id="h-0017" level="1">FIG. <b>6</b>D</heading>
<p id="p-0058" num="0056">Depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>D</figref>. is an article of footwear i.e. mid calf cut sock shown as <b>660</b> and shows many slots, pockets, openings, etc. depicted as <b>662</b>-<b>666</b> for the front opening shown as <b>662</b> would be by opening at the top of the sock where users foot would enter, and where the opening, slots, pockets, etc. to retain the footbeds, gel beds, insoles, inserts, etc. such as depicted as <b>302</b>-<b>306</b> In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref>., but not limited to said area if user would like to have The Soul SoxS depicted in this drawing shown as <b>660</b> depict an article of footwear/sock that has received the 6 Layered Support System i.e. inserts, insoles, footbeds, etc. shown as <b>676</b>-<b>678</b> within the article of footwear <b>660</b> and footbeds, insoles, inserts, etc. shown as <b>302</b>-<b>676</b>-<b>678</b> able to be magnetized, adhered, gel, etc. together. It shows the sock <b>660</b> being able to have the main footbed/insert <b>302</b> able to retain 3D printed materials, textures, gels, etc. shown as <b>312</b> and <b>314</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref>. The textures, materials, gels, etc. would be able to be elevated, layers removed, added, etc. <b>302</b> would be able to flip and alternate sides changing textures i.e., gel to expanding foam, extra cushioned, etc. dependent on the material it is as <b>304</b> would because it is not the main sole stretching from <b>302</b> heel to mid arch. Some models of Soul SoxS come solely with the 1-3-part system and <b>302</b> not being able to alternate sides. <b>304</b> would be able to alternate sides in this depiction of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref>. shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>D</figref>. and change textures, sizes, shapes, materials, etc. by flipping over the opposing side and It would come with the 6-layer support system as shown in this <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref>. and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref>. As shown throughout <b>302</b>-<b>304</b> as all Soul SoxS do come with the 6 Layered Support which comprise of the honeycomb like material that could be made of various textures with mesh odor eating technology, gel beds infused with Essential Oils, CBD, Fragrances, Lotions, etc. and or personalized to user's liking As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>D</figref> <b>662</b>-<b>666</b> openings, sleeves, slots, pockets, etc. on heel of sock shown as <b>672</b> to the arch shown as <b>606</b> to front part of the sock shown as <b>676</b>. <b>602</b>-<b>608</b> would be able to accept members of insoles, inserts, footbeds, etc. (refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref> for depiction of insoles, inserts, footbeds, etc.) <b>610</b> depicts the insert within the article of footwear i.e. sock shown as <b>600</b> with the 6 Layered Support and <b>602</b>-<b>608</b> to be of access to any other type of material, textures, shapes, sizes etc. that wish to be attached to the Main Basin insole, insert, footbed, etc. <b>302</b> and <b>304</b> fore foot area and any added layers shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref>. as <b>312</b>-<b>314</b> being able to retain any other type of material, texture, shapes, sizes, etc. as the foremost of the foot and would not necessarily need to be used within a slot, pocket, opening, etc. dependent on the user's wants and needs or whatever is easiest for entry. User could always decide what is best for what part of foot or section of foot to be treated with textures, materials, gels, etc. as mentioned above without diverting from the original invention. Depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref>. shows <b>612</b> as a cushioned no slip top part of high ankle and compression as <b>614</b> with the built-in arch, ankle padding shown as <b>616</b>. <b>618</b> depicts an arch dividing plantar fasciitis support on the sock. This would give the user more support on said area of foot while providing a dividing line for the 1-3-part insert, insole, footbed, etc. to make it easier to stay in place. <b>620</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref>. (not to be confused with the <b>620</b> depicted as an article of footwear i.e. extra compression sock in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>B</figref>.) would be a deeper heel slot, pocket, etc. with gel lining, magnets, adhesive, etc. to hold above mentioned arts Main Basin insole, insert, footbed, etc. <b>610</b> in place. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref> also depicts <b>620</b> as the front end of the sock for extra built-in toe cushioning. <b>620</b> would be a deeper sectioned slot, pocket, opening, etc. as it is in the heel part of the sock to better hold the insert, insole, footbed, etc. in place and both article of footwear i.e. <b>600</b> sock and <b>610</b> shows the insert, insole, footbed, etc. may retain materials, textures, designs, etc. on the outer surface of the sock through magnets, gel, adhesives, etc.</p>
<heading id="h-0018" level="1">FIG. <b>6</b>E</heading>
<p id="p-0059" num="0057">Depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>E</figref>. is an article of footwear i.e. sock shown as <b>680</b> shows many slots, pockets, openings, etc. depicted as <b>682</b>-<b>86</b> for the front opening shown as <b>686</b> would be by opening at the top of the sock where users foot would enter, and where the opening, slots, pockets, etc. to retain the footbeds, gel beds, insoles, inserts, etc. such as <b>688</b>, but not limited to said area if user would like to have The Soul SoxS depicted in this drawing shown as <b>680</b> depict an article of footwear/sock that has received the 6 Layered Support System i.e. inserts, insoles, footbeds, etc. shown as <b>688</b> within the article of footwear <b>680</b> and Inserts shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref>. <b>302</b>-<b>306</b> able to be magnetized, adhered, gel, etc. together. It shows the sock <b>680</b> being able to have the main footbed/insert <b>302</b> able to retain 3D printed materials, textures, gels, etc. shown as <b>312</b> and <b>314</b>. The textures, materials, gels, etc. would be able to be elevated, layers removed, added, etc. <b>302</b> would be able to flip and alternate sides changing textures i.e., gel to expanding foam, extra cushioned, etc. dependent on the material it is as <b>304</b> would because it is not the main sole stretching from <b>302</b> heel to mid arch. Some models of Soul SoxS come solely with the 1-3-part system and <b>302</b> not being able to alternate sides. <b>304</b> would be able to alternate sides in this depiction of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref>. shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref>. and change textures, sizes, shapes, materials, etc. by flipping over the opposing side and It would come with the 6-layer support system as shown in this <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref>. and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref>. As shown throughout <b>302</b>-<b>304</b> as all Soul SoxS do come with the 6 Layered Support which comprises of the honeycomb like material that could be made of various textures with mesh odor eating technology, gel beds infused with Essential Oils, CBD, Fragrances, Lotions, etc. and or personalized to user's liking As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref> <b>682</b>-<b>686</b> openings, sleeves, slots, pockets, etc. on heel of sock shown as <b>684</b> to the arch shown as <b>606</b> to front part of the sock shown as, <b>696</b> <b>608</b>. <b>602</b>-<b>608</b> would be able to accept members of insoles, inserts, footbeds, etc. (refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref> for depiction of insoles, inserts, footbeds, etc.) <b>610</b> depicts the insert within the article of footwear i.e. sock shown as <b>600</b> with the 6 Layered Support and <b>602</b>-<b>608</b> to be of access to any other type of material, textures, shapes, sizes etc. that wish to be attached to the Main Basin insole, insert, footbed, etc. <b>302</b> and <b>304</b> fore foot area and any added layers shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref>. as <b>312</b>-<b>314</b> being able to retain any other type of material, texture, shapes, sizes, etc. as the foremost of the foot and would not necessarily need to be used within a slot, pocket, opening, etc. dependent on the user's wants and needs or whatever is easiest tor entry. User could always decide what is best for what part of foot or section of foot to be treated with textures, materials, gels, etc. as mentioned above without diverting from the original invention. Depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>E</figref>. shows <b>682</b> as a cushioned no slip top part of high ankle and compression shown as <b>694</b> with the built-in arch, ankle padding shown as <b>692</b>. <b>690</b> depicts an arch dividing plantar fasciitis support on the sock. This would give the user more support on said area of foot while providing a dividing line for the 1-3-part insert, insole, footbed, etc. to make it easier to stay in place. <b>620</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref>. (not to be confused with the <b>620</b> depicted as an article of footwear i.e. extra compression sock in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>B</figref>.) would be a deeper heel slot, pocket, within the sock to better retain the inserts, insoles, footbeds, etc. with gel lining, magnets, adhesive, etc. to hold above mentioned arts Main Basin insole, insert, footbed, etc. <b>610</b> in place. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>E</figref> also depicts <b>680</b> as the front end of the sock for extra built-in toe cushioning. <b>696</b> would be a deeper sectioned slot, pocket, opening, etc. as it is in the heel part of the sock to better hold the insert, insole, footbed, etc. in place and both article of footwear i.e. <b>680</b> sock and <b>688</b> shows the insert, insole, footbed, etc. may retain materials, textures, designs, etc. on the outer surface of the sock through magnets, gel, adhesives, etc.</p>
<heading id="h-0019" level="1">FIG. <b>7</b>A. &#x26; <b>7</b>B</heading>
<p id="p-0060" num="0058"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>A</figref>. depicts a version of Soul SoxS that is just one solid insert, footbed, insole, made from gel, rubber, expanded foam, etc. shown as <b>720</b>, depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>A</figref>. shows gel lining, gel beds, etc. comprising of infusions such as CBD, THC(s) (Deltas), essential oils, etc. infused throughout the insole and when stepped on will automatically be infused back to user's touch of foot, sweat glands, calluses, etc. will benefit from the wellness of CBD, essential oils, essential vitamins, etc. and <b>740</b>. The bendable Soul SoxS insert would be able to make entry through anyone of the slots, pockets, sleeves, etc. shown throughout the different drawings and depictions of Soul SoxS with the top opening of sock, heel or arch area being the most reasonable but is completely up to user and what works best for them. The single insert has ribbed and ridged layers of rubber on the upper half of insert shown as <b>722</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>A</figref>. that is made of a bendable rubber that is raised, textured on the ridged and ribbed <b>722</b> area. The middle arch to near bottom heel of of insert shown as <b>724</b> would be made from a gel like material that would also be ridged, raised, ribbed, etc. The intriguing parts about the single insert as opposed to the other version of Soul SoxS shown throughout the drawings and descriptions is the sides depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>A</figref>. as <b>724</b> is that they cup, air pocket, conform, etc. to solid ground when pressure is applied to FIG. <b>7</b>A. They would bend with the consumers foot making like the complete opposite side of a normal insert, insole, footbed, etc. like <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>B</figref>. shown as <b>740</b> is depicted as a normal footbed, insert, insole, etc. is shown with medial, lateral arch support like most inserts and Soul SoxS are made with. The heel gel area depicted as <b>724</b> would be able to cup and conform to the ground, surface, etc. that the user is pressing on. The upper area depicted as <b>722</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>A</figref>. shows ridges, ribbed, gel, but on the opposite side of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>A</figref>. would be flat depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>B</figref> shown as <b>742</b>. As would the medial and lateral arch be raised as a normal insert would be cupping the heel and conforming to foot. The materials, textures, sizes, widths, etc. would all still be customizable. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>B</figref>. would still be able to retain the 6 layers of support if so, chosen by wearer and customized to their liking as mentioned above.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A customizable or personalized article of footwear, comprising:
<claim-text>a sock,</claim-text>
<claim-text>top attachment to the sock,</claim-text>
<claim-text>supports a bottom attachment to sock,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a personalized or customized footbed, insole, insert, etc.,</claim-text>
<claim-text>inserted into sock,</claim-text>
<claim-text>gel lining, magnetic, adhesive lining, etc. within sock,</claim-text>
<claim-text>through slots, pockets, openings,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a personalized or customized footbed, insole, insert, etc.,</claim-text>
<claim-text>may be connected by adhesive, gel lining,</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. A customizable or personalized article of footwear as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, comprising:
<claim-text>a sock</claim-text>
<claim-text>top attachment to the sock,</claim-text>
<claim-text>supports a bottom attachment to sock,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a personalized or customized sock etc.-supports infusions of CBD, Essential Vitamins, Essential Oils, etc.</claim-text>
<claim-text>a personalized or customized footbed, insole, insert, etc.&#x2014;supports infusions of CBD, Essential Vitamins</claim-text>
<claim-text>Fully custom socks made from a variety of customized materials, textures, sizes, shapes, designs, etc. that have multiple openings, slots, pockets, gel lining, magnetic bottom (either within sock or on bottom of sock) and within the sock to retain the multiple pieces of footbed, inserts, insoles, and smaller pieces i.e. added layers, textures, materials to both the outer, inner, bottom, top, etc. of the socks as well as the inserts, insoles, footbeds, etc. which would connect by magnets, gel adhesive, gel lining, etc. to make multiple sections of the insert, insole, footbed, and or as one full insert, insole, footbed, etc. but not limited to certain sizes, The insert, insole, footbeds, etc. being connected by magnets, gel adhesive, gel lining, etc. to be able to bend with user's foot as more comparable to an athletic shoe being a 1-3 part system,</claim-text>
<claim-text>According to user's wants and needs may be infused manually as stated in the arts or be able to reinfuse with said substances above and if so chosen for example(s) listed in the listed arts directly onto the layers, layer by layer, or dependent on textures and materials that rest in a footbed, inserts, insoles, etc., i.e. gel beds that retain Coconut Oils, CBD, Essential Oils, Etc. Just depends on (any of the LISTED SUBSTANCES above could be filled in a plastic, ceramic, recycled materials i.e. baster like syringes with plastic needles that are able to refill, be pre filled depending how much the user needs and wants of MG's for CBD, and that is safe, etc. user would be able to use the syringes, basters, etc., that insert dosages directly into the gel bed replacing any empty gel bed plant based substances, non-plant substances, oils, fragrances, etc. pretty much Anything that can be used and infused as ways listed above and below in the arts to the substances that, etc. and for example the syringe, plastic baster, plastic syringe, ceramic syringe with a metal, plastic, ceramic, needle, or anything similar to a medical syringe, etc. could insert directly into gel retaining footbeds, different retaining layers, 3D printed materials, retaining deep heel cups gel beds, or any sizes or any other part of the insole, insert, footbed, that could accept different substances can retain the (ABOVE LISTED SUBSTANCES) such as THC, CBD oils or any type of infusions of Essential Oils etc. The areas of inserts, insoles, footbeds, etc, that retain the actual layers, textures, materials, etc. would be able to be in variety of all different sizes to retain many different MG's of CBD, THC, Essential oils. Fragrances, plant-based substances, non-plant base substances ETC. for example see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref> as seen <b>102</b> could be a certain number of MG of CBD, as <b>104</b> could be an essential oil(s) as <b>106</b> could be a fragrance, etc. as the user would be able to have gel beds, textures, materials pre filled within retaining footbed , materials, layers, etc. that may roll on straight to textures, i.e. similar to highlighter sized deodorant stick, lip stick sized roller prefilled sticks, where user can manually infuse the layers infuse, how much they infused, and if they want infusions at all., textures, materials that lay and rest within the insole, inserts, footbeds, etc. and that come infused to customer's customization on what oils if any they want chosen listed but not limited to CBD, THC, THC Delta 9, Plant Based Substances, Non Plant Based Substances, Etc. and act similar to a Tide White out pens where user directly infuses the layers by rolling on the pens, etc. could know on certain models without diverting from original invention.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
