<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225486A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225486</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18099433</doc-number>
<date>20230120</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>45</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>45</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>45</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>2003</main-group>
<subgroup>025</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">MULTI-FUNCTIONAL CARRIER BAG</invention-title>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation-in-part>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>29882855</doc-number>
<date>20230119</date>
</document-id>
<parent-status>PENDING</parent-status>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18099433</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation-in-part>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>63301259</doc-number>
<date>20220120</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>New Path Outdoors, LLC</orgname>
<address>
<city>Pengilly</city>
<state>MN</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Gibbs</last-name>
<first-name>Jeff</first-name>
<address>
<city>Pengilly</city>
<state>MN</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="01" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Gibbs</last-name>
<first-name>Kayla Johanna</first-name>
<address>
<city>Pengilly</city>
<state>MN</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="02" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wookey</last-name>
<first-name>Trisha</first-name>
<address>
<city>Bozeman</city>
<state>MT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="03" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Sterry</last-name>
<first-name>Sky</first-name>
<address>
<city>Bozeman</city>
<state>MT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Multi-functional carrying systems, methods, and devices include a multi-functional carrier bag with a central body from which a first stabilizer strap and a second stabilizer strap extend. The multi-functional carrier bag is usable in first carrying position with the central body positioned at a front of a user (e.g., a front torso or lap). The user can grab the second stabilizer strap and pull the multi-functional carrier bag across their body, rotating it until the central body is in a second carrying position at a rear of the user (e.g., on a back, upper torso). With the multi-functional carrier bag in the second carrying position, the second stabilizer strap extends from a side of the central body to attach to a strap connector disposed on the first stabilizer strap to form a three-point connection (e.g., a &#x201c;T&#x201d; connection) on a chest of the user.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="171.45mm" wi="158.75mm" file="US20230225486A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="216.15mm" wi="175.60mm" file="US20230225486A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="205.99mm" wi="173.23mm" file="US20230225486A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="192.02mm" wi="167.89mm" file="US20230225486A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="190.50mm" wi="174.92mm" file="US20230225486A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="195.83mm" wi="133.18mm" file="US20230225486A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="239.95mm" wi="163.75mm" file="US20230225486A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="229.36mm" wi="173.57mm" file="US20230225486A1-20230720-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a continuation-in-part of and claims priority to U.S. Patent Application No. 29/882,855, filed Jan. 19, 2023 and titled &#x201c;Carrying Bag;&#x201d; and this application claims priority to Provisional Patent Application No. 63/301,259, filed Jan. 20, 2022 and titled &#x201c;Multi-Functional Carrier Bag,&#x201d; the entireties of which are incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="tail"?>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Aspects of the present disclosure generally relate to a multi-functional carrier bag and related systems and methods and, more particularly, to a bag that is transitionable between a plurality of carrying states during skiing or other activities.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Many people carry equipment in a backpack or similar bag while engaging in outdoor activities, such as skiing. To maximize freedom of movement during such activities, most bags are positioned on the back of the person. However, skiing often involves taking a lift chair to the top of a mountain, which can be challenging for people wearing such backpacks. More particularly, lift chairs are constantly in motion, with people sitting on the chair as it moves into position and, in some instances, a protective bar is lowered. Accordingly, skiers have to be mindful of the positioning of their bags to accommodate the moving chair and protective bar during a short time period. Many bags are cumbersome and challenging to maneuver, often resulting in problems ranging from an uncomfortable ride to disruption of the lift chair. It is with these observations in mind, among others, that the presently disclosed technology was conceived and developed.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The aforementioned problems can be addressed using the technology disclosed herein. For instance, a multi-functional carrier bag can include a central body at least partially formed of a flexible material and/or a first stabilizer strap. The first stabilizer strap can include a first strap portion extending from a first end of the central body; and/or a second strap portion extending from a second end of the central body, the first strap portion and the second strap portion can form an obtuse angle. The multi-functional carrier bag can also include a second stabilizer strap extending from the central body at a side of the central body between the first end and the second end; and/or a pocket defined into the side of the central body. The pocket can be operable to receive and store the second stabilizer strap when the multi-functional carrier bag is in a first carrying position; and/or provide access to the second stabilizer strap when the multi-functional carrier bag is in a second carrying position.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In some examples, the first end includes a first strap sheath; the second end includes a second strap sheath; and/or the first strap sheath and the second strap sheath are continuous extensions of the flexible material at least partially forming the central body. Additionally, the multi-functional carrier bag can further comprise a zipper disposed on the central body with: a horizontal orientation in the first carrying position; and a non-horizontal orientation in the second carrying position. Moreover, the multi-functional carrier bag can further include a strap connector, disposed on the first stabilizer strap, for receiving a connector of the second stabilizer strap. The connector of the second stabilizer strap can be unattached to the strap connector when the multi-functional carrier bag is in the first carrying position; and/or attached to the strap connector when the multi-functional carrier bag is in the second carrying position. Also, the strap connector disposed on the first stabilizer strap can be a first strap connector; and the multi-functional carrier bag can further include a second strap connector disposed on a front surface of the central body.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In some instances, the connector of the second stabilizer strap couples to the second strap connector disposed on the front surface of the central body when the multi-functional carrier bag is in the first carrying position; and/or the connector strap couples to the first strap connector disposed on the first stabilizer strap when the multi-functional carrier bag is in the second carrying position. Furthermore, the first strap connector can be slidably disposed on the first stabilizer strap; and/or the second strap connector can be fixedly disposed on the front surface of the central body. The central body can include an irregular hexagonal-shaped profile.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In some examples, a multi-functional carrying system can include a central body at least partially formed of a flexible material; and/or a first stabilizer strap including a first strap portion extending from a first end of the central body; and a second strap portion extending from a second end of the central body. The multi-functional carrying system can also include a second stabilizer strap extending from the central body between the first end and the second end; and/or a pocket defined into a side of the central body operable to receive and store the second stabilizer strap when the multi-functional carrying system is in a first carrying position. The pocket can also be operable to provide access to the second stabilizer strap for transitioning the multi-functional carrying system from the first carrying position to a second carrying position. Additionally, the multi-functional carrying system can include a strap connector disposed on the first stabilizer strap for receiving a connector of the second stabilizer strap when the multi-functional carrying system is in the second carrying position.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In some instances, the connector is a magnetic connector, and the strap connector is a magnetic buckle corresponding to the magnetic connector, providing one-handed attachability for the strap connector. The second stabilizer strap can also include a V strap, with a first strap of the V strap coupling to the central body at a first connection point, and a second strap of the V strap coupling to the central body at a second connection point, and/or the pocket can be disposed adjacent to the V strap on the central body. Moreover, the first strap can intersect the second strap with a slidable connector which slides unencumbered along the second strap for automatic adjustments. Additionally or alternatively, the multi-functional carrying system further includes a first pocket configured for cell phone carrying, and a second pocket configured for a hand warmer, the second pocket having an interior foam divider separating the first pocket from the second pocket and preventing heat transfer from the hand warmer to a contents of the second pocket.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In some scenarios, a method of providing a multi-functional carrying system includes carrying a multi-functional carrying bag in a first carrying position. The multi-functional carrying bag can include a central body, a first stabilizer strap, and a second stabilizer strap; and/or the first carrying position can include a connector of the second stabilizer strap coupled to a corresponding strap connector disposed on the first stabilizer strap to form a three-point connection at a front torso of a user. The method can further include transitioning the multi-functional carrying bag from the first carrying position to a second carrying position by rotating the central body of multi-functional carrying bag from a back of a user to the front torso of the user. Additionally or alternatively, the method can include carrying the multi-functional carrying bag in the second carrying position. Moreover, the second carrying position can includes a first strap portion of the first stabilizer strap extending from a first end of the central body; a second strap portion of the first stabilizer strap extending from a second end of the central body; and/or the second stabilizer strap stowed in a pocket or removably coupled to the central body.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In some examples, the second carrying position includes the second stabilizer strap removably coupled to the central body by coupling a first magnetic connector disposed on the second stabilizer strap to a second magnetic connector disposed on an outer surface of the central body. Furthermore, the connector of the second stabilizer strap can couple to the corresponding strap connector using a magnetic connection between the connector and the strap connector. Transitioning the multi-functional carrying bag from the first carrying position to the second carrying position can also include performing a one-handed operation. Additionally, the method can also include accessing a hydration port, while carrying the multi-functional carrying bag in the second carrying position, disposed on a side of the multi-functional carrying bag opposite the pocket for stowing the second stabilizer strap. By way of example, transitioning the multi-functional carrying bag from the first carrying position to the second carrying position can include detaching the connector from the strap connector to disengage the three-point connection at the front torso of the user; and/or rotating the multi-functional carrying bag from a back upper torso of the user to the front torso of the user. Moreover, the method can further include preventing, with a foam liner disposed inside the multi-functional carrying bag, a heat distribution from a first pocket stowing a hand warmer to a second pocket for stowing a mobile device. Implementations described and claimed herein address the forgoing by providing multi-functional carrier bag systems and methods. Other implementations are also described and recited herein. Further, while multiple implementations are disclosed, still other implementations of the presently disclosed technology will become apparent to those skilled in the art from the following detailed description, which shows and describes illustrative implementations of the presently disclosed technology. As will be realized, the presently disclosed technology is capable of modifications in various aspects, all without departing from the spirit and scope of the presently disclosed technology. Accordingly, the drawings and detailed description are to be regarded as illustrative in nature and not limiting.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> illustrates a front side of an example multi-functional carrier bag with one or more carrying positions.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> illustrates a rear side of an example multi-functional carrier bag with one or more carrying positions.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref> illustrates an example multi-functional carrier bag being transitioned between a first carrying position to a second carrying position.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>B</figref> illustrates an example multi-functional carrier bag being transitioned from a first carrying position to a second carrying position by engaging or disengaging a three-point connection.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>C</figref> illustrates an example multi-functional carrier bag in a carrying position with a hydration tube accessible.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>D</figref> illustrates an example multi-functional carrier bag being transitioned between multiple carrying positions.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> illustrates an example method of providing a multi-functional carrying system, which can be performed by the systems and devices disclosed in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>-<b>3</b>D</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">It will be appreciated that for simplicity and clarity of illustration, where appropriate, reference numerals have been repeated among the different figures to indicate corresponding or analogous elements. In addition, numerous specific details are set forth in order to provide a thorough understanding of the examples described herein. However, it will be understood by those of ordinary skill in the art that the examples described herein can be practiced without these specific details. In other instances, methods, procedures and components have not been described in detail so as not to obscure the related relevant feature being described. Also, the description is not to be considered as limiting the scope of the examples described herein. The drawings are not necessarily to scale and the proportions of certain parts may be exaggerated to better illustrate details and features of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The phraseology and terminology employed herein are for the purpose of description and should not be regarded as limiting. For example, the use of a singular term, such as, &#x201c;a&#x201d; is not intended as limiting of the number of items. Further, it should be understood that any one of the features of the presently disclosed technology may be used separately or in combination with any other disclosed features. Other systems, methods, features, and advantages of the presently disclosed technology will be, or become, apparent to one with skill in the art upon examination of the figures and the detailed description. It is intended that all such additional systems, methods, features, and advantages be included within this description, be within the scope of the presently disclosed technology, and be protected by the accompanying claims.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Further, as the presently disclosed technology is susceptible to examples of many different forms, it is intended that the present disclosure be considered as an example of the principles of the presently disclosed technology and not intended to limit the presently disclosed technology to the specific arrangements shown and described. Any one of the features of the presently disclosed technology may be used separately or in combination with any other feature. References to the terms &#x201c;instances,&#x201d; &#x201c;scenarios,&#x201d; &#x201c;examples,&#x201d; and/or the like in the description mean that the feature and/or features being referred to are included in, at least, one aspect of the description. Separate references to these terms and/or the like in the description do not necessarily refer to the same example and are also not mutually exclusive unless so stated and/or except as will be readily apparent to those skilled in the art from the description. For example, a feature, structure, process, step, action, or the like described in one example may also be included in other examples, but is not necessarily included. Thus, the presently disclosed technology may include a variety of combinations and/or integrations of the examples described herein. Additionally, all aspects of the present disclosure, as described herein, are not essential for its practice. Likewise, other systems, methods, features, and advantages of the presently disclosed technology will be, or become, apparent to one with skill in the art upon examination of the figures and the description. It is intended that all such additional systems, methods, features, and advantages be included within this description, be within the scope of the presently disclosed technology, and be encompassed by the claims.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Any term of degree such as, but not limited to, &#x201c;substantially,&#x201d; as used in the description and the appended claims, should be understood to include an exact, or a similar, but not exact configuration. The terms &#x201c;comprising,&#x201d; &#x201c;including&#x201d; and &#x201c;having&#x201d; are used interchangeably in this disclosure. The terms &#x201c;comprising,&#x201d; &#x201c;including&#x201d; and &#x201c;having&#x201d; mean to include, but not necessarily be limited to the things so described.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Lastly, the terms &#x201c;or&#x201d; and &#x201c;and/or,&#x201d; as used herein, are to be interpreted as inclusive or meaning any one or any combination. Therefore, &#x201c;A, B, or C&#x201d; or &#x201c;A, B, and/or C&#x201d; mean any of the following: &#x201c;A,&#x201d; &#x201c;B,&#x201d; or &#x201c;C&#x201d;; &#x201c;A and B&#x201d;; &#x201c;A and C&#x201d;; &#x201c;B and C&#x201d;; &#x201c;A, B and C.&#x201d; An exception to this definition will occur only when a combination of elements, functions, steps or acts are in some way inherently mutually exclusive.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Aspects of the presently disclosed technology relate to a multi-functional carrier bag that can be carried in one or more positions on the body of a person. In one aspect, the multi-functional carrier bag includes various components that make the multi-functional carrier bag transitionable between different carrying positions with a simple one-handed operation of releasing a clasp/buckle and pulling on a strap. As such, the multi-functional carrier bag can be easily adaptable to many situations when the user is either mobile or stationary (e.g., sitting or resting). Various benefits can be realized in a multitude of activities, such as skiing, hiking, mountain climbing, walking, running, bicycling, boating, flying, and so forth, as discussed in greater detail below.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> depicts a front side <b>102</b> of a multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> depicts a rear side <b>104</b> of the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b>. The multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> can be carried in a first carrying position <b>106</b> on the back of a wearer (e.g., as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref>). In the first carrying position <b>106</b>, the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> can establish a first support with a first stabilizer strap <b>108</b> extending from a first end <b>110</b> of a central body <b>112</b> of the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b>, across a front of a user to a second end <b>114</b> of the central body <b>112</b> of the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b>. On the user, the first stabilizer strap <b>108</b> can extend from an upper left shoulder of the user to a bottom right side, or from an upper right shoulder to a bottom left side. A second stabilizer strap <b>116</b> can extend from a side <b>118</b> of the central body <b>112</b> of the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> between the first end <b>110</b> and the second end <b>114</b> to connect to the first stabilizer strap <b>108</b>, for instance, at a strap connector <b>120</b> coupled to the first stabilizer strap <b>108</b>. The strap connector <b>120</b> can include a connector <b>129</b> attached to a fabric or rigid material disposed or looped around a portion of the first stabilizer strap <b>108</b>, somewhat loosely, such that the strap connector <b>120</b> can slide along the first stabilizer strap <b>108</b>, or the strap connector can be fixedly secured in a static position on the first stabilizer strap <b>108</b>. Additionally or alternatively, the strap connector <b>120</b> can include a plastic, metallic, and/or magnetic connector. The second stabilizer strap <b>116</b> can establish a second support around a second side of the user opposite a first side of the first stabilizer strap <b>108</b> by connecting to the first stabilizer strap <b>108</b> at the strap connector <b>120</b> to form a three-point connection at a front position (e.g., a chest position) of a user. Accordingly, the first stabilizer strap <b>108</b> and the second stabilizer strap <b>116</b> can both be used to maintain the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> in the first carrying position <b>106</b> and the second position <b>126</b>. These features can provide multiple points of support, for instance, using the three-point connection or a T-connection <b>122</b> on a front chest of the user, and/or resting pressure from the strap sheaths and stabilizing straps.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In some instance, the first stabilizer strap <b>108</b> can include a first strap portion <b>111</b> extending from the first end <b>110</b> and a second strap portion <b>113</b> extending from the second end <b>114</b>. The first strap portion <b>111</b> and the second strap portion <b>113</b> can extend from the central body <b>112</b> of the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> to form an angle <b>115</b> (e.g., at the central body <b>112</b> or a corner of the central body <b>112</b> adjacent to a side pocket <b>124</b>), which can be an obtuse angle, and/or configures the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> for carrying in the different carrying positions, by matching the contours and anatomical angles of the body of the user.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Additionally, the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> can be transitioned to and carried in a second carrying position <b>126</b> over a front of the wearer (e.g., at the wearer's chest, belly, lap, etc.) For instance, in the second carrying position <b>126</b>, the central body <b>112</b> of the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> can be positioned across a lap or front belly or chest of the wearer with the first stabilizer strap <b>108</b> extending around the back of the wearer. The first stabilizer strap <b>108</b> can extend across one shoulder and diagonally across a back of the wearer. In some instances, the second carrying position <b>126</b> is a sitting carrying position with the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> resting on a lap of the wearer. The second carrying position <b>126</b> can also be a standing position. In the second carrying position <b>126</b>, the second stabilizer strap <b>116</b> can be omitted from providing any support, and only the first stabilizer strap <b>108</b> can support the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> to maintain it in the second carrying position <b>126</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">In some examples, the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> is operable to transition between the first carrying position <b>106</b> and the second carrying position <b>126</b>. For instance, the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> can have a first configuration of components in the first carrying position <b>106</b>, and these components can be reconfigured into a second configuration to transition the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> from the first carrying position <b>106</b> to the second carrying position <b>126</b>. The reconfigurable components can include the second stabilizer strap <b>116</b>. In the first carrying position <b>106</b>, the second stabilizer strap <b>116</b> can be exposed and extending away from the central body <b>112</b> of the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> to attach to the strap connector <b>120</b> on the chest of the wearer. The multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> can be transitioned to the second carrying position <b>126</b> by detaching the second stabilizer strap <b>116</b> from the strap connector <b>120</b>; opening a zipper of the side pocket <b>124</b> or pouch (e.g., adjacent to attachment points of the second stabilizer strap <b>116</b> onto the central body <b>112</b> of the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b>); inserting the second stabilizer strap <b>116</b> into the side pocket <b>124</b> or pouch; securing the second stabilizer strap <b>116</b> in the side pocket <b>124</b> or pouch (e.g., by closing the zipper); and/or sliding the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> around the wearer's body. Conversely, the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> can be transitioned from the second carrying position <b>126</b> to first carrying position <b>106</b> by opening the zipper; extracting the second stabilizer strap <b>116</b> from the pocket or pouch; extending the second stabilizer strap <b>116</b> (e.g., around the waist of the wearer); and/or securing the second stabilizer strap <b>116</b> to the first stabilizer strap <b>108</b> (e.g., forming a three-point connection at the strap connector <b>120</b> on the wearer's chest). Furthermore, the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> can be transitioned between the first carrying position <b>106</b> and the second carrying position <b>126</b> by sliding the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> around the body (e.g., a circular path around a shoulder of the wearer, diagonally across the torso of the wearer, and around a side of the wearer) and/or rotating the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b>. For instance, the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> can be at a different angular rotation/orientation in the second carrying position <b>126</b> relative to the first carrying position <b>106</b>. As such, various zippers, pockets, and other features of the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> can be made more easily accessible in the different carrying positions.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">In some examples, the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> is transitionable between different carrying positions, which can correspond to different activities. For instance, the first carrying position <b>106</b> can correspond to a moving activity such as downhill skiing or cross country skiing. The second carrying position <b>126</b> can correspond to a rest activity such as sitting on a ski lift or standing to access the central body <b>112</b> of the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b>. The components of the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> can be specifically configured for usage during the different activities in the different positions. For instance, one or more pocket and/or zipper orientations and pocket shapes <b>128</b> can be configured with a first access angle in the first carrying position <b>106</b> and/or a second access angle in the second carrying position <b>126</b>. The pocket shape <b>128</b> can have inner seams forming angles and shapes that allow the inner contents to hang (e.g., because of gravity) at a first angle or direction in the first carrying position <b>106</b> and at a second angle or direction in the second carrying position <b>126</b>. In some instances, the pocket shapes <b>128</b> can correspond to a ski lift ticket, a hand warmer, personal items like a phone, wallet, keys, gloves, and the like. Pockets <b>130</b> of the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> can be formed of a mesh material. Additionally, the pockets <b>130</b> can include a hydration bladder (e.g., held in the mesh pocket) with a hydration hose <b>300</b> extending to one or more hydration ports <b>302</b> (e.g., as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>C</figref>). The pocket holding the hydration bladder can be attached to an inside back panel (e.g., an interior side of the rear side <b>104</b>) of the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b>. One or more hydration ports <b>302</b> can be disposed on the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> at the central body <b>112</b>, along the shoulder harness portion (e.g., along a first strap sheath <b>132</b>), and/or along a side harness portion (e.g., along the second strap sheath <b>134</b>). In some instances, the hydration port <b>302</b> is disposed on a side of the central body <b>112</b> opposite the second stabilizer strap <b>116</b> and/or it's storage pocket, such that the hydration port is positioned upright (e.g., at a top of the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b>), when the bag is carried in the front position of the user. A hydration hose <b>300</b> coupling to the hydration bladder can have a magnetic docking clasp, a plastic or metal clip, or the like, removably holding the hydration hose <b>300</b> in place. Additionally, a zipper <b>136</b> on the central body <b>112</b> can provide access to the internal pocket holding the hydration bladder.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Moreover, the pocket materials or other interior or exterior materials may correspond to the multiple carrying positions for multiple activities. The pocket materials, inner material, and/or exterior material may be water resistant, cold/freeze resistant, and/or include zippers or buttons sized and positioned for access with gloves. For instance, the zipper(s) <b>136</b> can include a #8 coil zipper with a storm flap for accessing the main bag pocket in the central body <b>112</b>. One or more #8 urethane zippers can be used for secondary openings <b>138</b> to secondary pockets, such as the phone pocket, the ski pass pocket, and the like. Additionally, the zippers <b>136</b> can extend across the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> at different angles to provide easy access in the different carrying positions. For instance, a ski pass-shaped pocket <b>137</b> (e.g., having a rectangular shape and/or with rounded corners) may be positioned at a bottom left area (e.g., at the second end <b>114</b> of the central body <b>112</b>). An access zipper of the ski pass-shaped pocket <b>137</b> can run along the second strap sheath <b>134</b> at the second strap portion <b>113</b> in a direction generally parallel with an edge of the second strap sheath <b>134</b> and/or the second strap portion <b>113</b> of the first stabilizer strap <b>108</b>. A ski pass pocket <b>137</b> or other pocket can be configured to be upright (e.g., with a zipper <b>136</b> at a side or top of the pocket) in the second carrying position <b>126</b>; and/or non-upright (e.g., with the zipper <b>136</b> facing at least partially downward) in the first carrying position <b>106</b>. In some instances, a mobile device pocket <b>139</b> can have dimensions and/or a material rigidity corresponding to a mobile device shape, such that the pocket is configured to hold a mobile device. The mobile device pocket <b>139</b> can be sewn into the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b>, and can include a divider to keep hand warmers in one portion of the mobile device pocket <b>139</b>, or in other pockets, away from the mobile device (e.g., in another portion of the <b>139</b>). In other words, a pocket such as the mobile device pocket <b>139</b> can include a foam or insulation liner, divider, or other insulator, and/or have a particular zipper access angle, such that the pocket is configured to hold the mobile device. The mobile device pocket <b>139</b> can be approximately <b>6</b> inches deep and <b>7</b> inches wide; and/or can have dimensions that follow contours of the central body <b>112</b>. Additionally or alternatively, the pocket(s) can be configured with a shape, size, and or insulation liner such that the pocket is configured to hold a hand warmer. A bag area <b>140</b> of the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> (e.g., formed into the central body <b>112</b>) can have interior seams to keep contents from migrating to a shoulder harness area and/or the ski pass area formed into one of the ends of the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> (e.g., at harness sheaths extending from the ends of the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b>). An electronics device pocket can include a foam liner with one or more nylon dividers inside the pocket to place a heat pack(s) on one or both sides of the electronic device. Additionally, a mesh pocket inside the central body <b>112</b> can form a large bag portion of the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> with a zippered side <b>142</b> extending along a side of the central body <b>112</b> to provide access to the mesh pocket.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Additionally, the one or more connectors <b>144</b> used for connecting the second stabilizer strap <b>116</b> to the strap connector <b>120</b> (e.g., and/or the two portions of the first stabilizer strap <b>108</b> together) on the first stabilizer strap <b>108</b> can be configured for use in cold, wet, icy, and/or snow conditions. For instance, the connectors <b>144</b> can be magnetic connectors that can be slid and locked in any conditions. The connectors <b>144</b> can include a magnetic buckle such as a magnetic clasp or magnetic Fidlock buckle or a Woojin buckle. Additionally or alternatively, the connectors <b>144</b> can include metal push-snap connectors released by pinching inward a spring-loaded side of the connector <b>144</b>. Use of the magnetic clasp can provide one-handed operations for attaching and detaching the connectors <b>144</b>, with gloves, and/or in snowy/icy conditions. The second stabilizer strap <b>116</b> can include a connector <b>144</b> (e.g., which can be a slidable connector <b>127</b> or a fixed connector). at a first end for attaching the second stabilizer strap <b>116</b> to the strap connector <b>120</b> on the first stabilizer strap <b>108</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">In some examples, a second end of the second stabilizer strap <b>116</b> can split into the V strap <b>117</b> which can be sewn into a zippered storage pocket (e.g., the side pocket <b>124</b>). The &#x201c;V&#x201d; strap <b>117</b> and/or fabric webbing or planar surfaces connecting the second end of the second stabilizer strap <b>116</b> to the central body <b>112</b> can be patterned in a way to keep snow from entering the zippered storage pocket when the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> is in the first carrying position <b>106</b> (e.g., with the zippered storage pocket unzipped and open to release the second stabilizer strap <b>116</b>) as well as the second carrying position <b>126</b> (e.g., with the zippered storage pocket zipped shut).</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Furthermore, the first strap sheath <b>132</b> and/or the second strap sheath <b>134</b> extension member(s) of the central body <b>112</b> can extend non-parallel and/or non-perpendicularly relative to each other, such that the first strap portion <b>111</b> and the second strap portion <b>113</b> of the first stabilizer strap <b>108</b> form the angle <b>115</b>. The first strap portion <b>111</b> and the second strap portion <b>113</b> can attach to (e.g., via a sewing seam), and/or be at least partially enclosed by the first strap sheath <b>132</b> and/or the second strap sheath <b>134</b>. Zippers and pockets can also be formed along the first strap sheath <b>132</b> extending from the first end <b>110</b> of the central body <b>112</b> and the second strap sheath <b>134</b> extending from the second end <b>114</b> of the central body <b>112</b>. The central body <b>112</b>, the first strap sheath <b>132</b>, and/or the second strap sheath <b>134</b> can be formed of a continuous material or fabric extending from the first end <b>110</b> to the second end <b>114</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">In some instances, the hydration ports <b>302</b> can be formed into the first strap sheath <b>132</b> (e.g., accessible via a zipper <b>136</b>), along a side surface of the central body <b>112</b> between the first end <b>110</b> and the second end <b>114</b>, along the second strap sheath <b>134</b>, at one or more junctures between the strap sheath(s) <b>132</b> or <b>134</b> and the central body <b>112</b>, or at any combinations thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">In some examples, a webbing of material can connect the &#x201c;V&#x201d; strap <b>117</b> of the second stabilizer strap <b>116</b> to the central body <b>112</b> (e.g., at a corner formed by the continuous material). Moreover, the connective webbing <b>148</b> for the second stabilizer strap <b>116</b> can have a length corresponding to a zipper <b>136</b> of the pocket for receiving the second stabilizer strap <b>116</b> (e.g., being slightly less than a length of the zipper). The V strap <b>117</b> can have a first strap <b>119</b> coupling to the central body at a first connection point <b>121</b>, and a second strap <b>123</b> coupling to the central body <b>112</b> at a second connection point <b>125</b>. In some examples, the first strap <b>119</b> intersects the second strap <b>123</b> using a slidable connector <b>127</b>, which can slide up and down the second strap <b>123</b> automatically to adjust to a size of a wearer. The slidable connector <b>127</b> can be at or proximate to an end of the first stabilizer strap <b>108</b>, and can slide unencumbered along the second strap <b>123</b> for automatic adjustments to a body shape of a user.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">In some scenarios, the rear side <b>104</b> of the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> can also be formed of water resistant material and/or can be formed of a material for pressing against the wearer, such <b>104</b> as a soft foam, a hard foam, or fabric material. For instance, one or more portions of the rear side can be formed of a thermal molded back panel(s) <b>200</b>. The foam can be a high density polyethylene (HDPE) frame sheet and/or a molded foam such as a 7 mm soft ethylene-vinyl acetate (EVA) foam (e.g., a four-way stretch woven fabric, a porous material, a honeycomb material, etc.) A back side panel <b>202</b> of the shoulder portion <b>204</b> (e.g., a rear of the first strap sheath <b>132</b>) and/or the second strap sheath <b>134</b> at a hip portion <b>206</b> can be formed of a first material, and a central rear panel <b>208</b> of the central body <b>112</b> can be formed of a second material (which can be different, thicker, or softer than the first material). The rear panels behind the first strap sheath <b>132</b> (e.g., the shoulder portion <b>204</b>) and the second strap sheath <b>134</b> (e.g., the hip portion <b>206</b>) can be movably coupled to the central rear panel <b>208</b> of the central body <b>112</b> via one or more hinge points <b>210</b> (e.g., a living hinge and/or flexible portion). For instance, a shoulder panel and a hip panel can be coupled to the central rear panel <b>208</b> with the hinge points <b>210</b>. Additional structure supports (e.g., rigid frames) can be used in some embodiments to maintain a shape of the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b>. The zipper <b>212</b> for the pocket that receives the second stabilizer strap <b>116</b> (e.g., the side pocket <b>124</b>) can run along an edge <b>214</b> of the central rear panel <b>208</b>, traversing into the rear side <b>104</b> of the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b>. In some instances, the central body <b>112</b> can have an exterior profile shape (e.g., with sharp or rounded corners), such as a hexagon or irregular hexagon, a pentagon, a square, a triangle, an irregular parallelogram, and the like (e.g., defined by the central rear panel <b>208</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>3</b>A-<b>3</b>D</figref> depict a wearer using the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> and transitioning the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> between the different carrying positions (e.g., with one or more one-handed operations).</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">For instance, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref> depicts a back of a wearer as the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> is transitioned from the first carrying position <b>106</b> to the second carrying position <b>126</b>. The wearer can grab the first stabilizer strap <b>108</b> with a left hand and pull the first stabilizer strap <b>108</b> in a downward direction to cause the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> to spin or slide around the body of the wearer (e.g., from the back of the wearer to the front of the wearer.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>B</figref> depicts a side and front of a wearer of the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b>. The wearer can disconnect the second stabilizer strap <b>116</b> from the strap connector <b>120</b> and pull the first stabilizer strap <b>108</b> in an upwards direction to cause the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> to slide around the body of the wearer, for instance, from the first carrying position <b>106</b> into the second carrying position <b>126</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>C</figref> depicts a front of a wearer as the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> is transitioned into the second carrying position <b>126</b>. Moreover, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>C</figref> shows the wearer unzipping the access zipper <b>304</b> for the hydration hose <b>300</b>, and attaching the second stabilizer strap <b>116</b> to a strap holding connector <b>306</b> disposed on the central body <b>112</b> of the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> (e.g., for strap storage).</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>D</figref> depicts the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> being transitioned from the second carrying position <b>126</b> to the first carrying position <b>106</b>. For instance, with the central body <b>112</b> at a front of the wearer, the wearer can grab the central body <b>112</b> and/or the first stabilizer strap <b>108</b> with their left hand or right hand and pull the central body <b>112</b> downward to cause the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> to slide around the body of the wearer during a position transition operation <b>308</b>. This can cause the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> to move into a transitional position <b>310</b> at a side of the user while transitioning to the back of the wearer. Upon positioning the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> on their back, the wearer can connect the second stabilizer strap <b>116</b> to the strap connector <b>120</b> disposed on the first stabilizer strap <b>108</b> (e.g., at the chest of the user).</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Additionally or alternatively, the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> can also be transitioned from the first carrying position <b>106</b> to the second carrying position <b>126</b> using a one-handed operation to continue to rotate the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> in the same rotational direction around the body and/or in a reverse rotational direction. Moreover, a zipper <b>136</b> can be in an upright position (e.g., located at a top of the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b>) when the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> is in the second carrying position <b>126</b>. The wearer can unzip the zipper to access inner contents of the central body <b>112</b>. Additionally, with the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b> in the second carrying position <b>126</b>, the wearer can unzip a zipper <b>136</b> and pull the hydration hose <b>300</b> from a hydration hose pocket such that the hydration hose extends out of the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b>. The wearer can remove a cap on the hydration hose, replace the cap, and/or retract the hydration hose back into the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b>. The hydration port <b>302</b> and/or hydration hose <b>300</b> can be stored at and/or extracted from various locations on the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b>, such as from any of the zippers <b>136</b> depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>-<b>3</b>D</figref>, such as on the central body <b>112</b> near the first end <b>110</b> where the first strap sheath <b>132</b> adjoins the central body <b>112</b>, near the second end <b>114</b> where the second strap sheath <b>134</b> adjoins the central body <b>112</b>, at the side opposite the side pocket <b>124</b>, at any corners or sides of a polygonal shape (e.g., a hexagon) forming a profile of the multi-functional carrier bag <b>100</b>, and/or combinations thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> illustrates an example method <b>400</b> for providing the multi-functional carrying bag and systems disclosed herein.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">At operation <b>402</b>, the method <b>400</b> can carry a multi-functional carrying bag in a first carrying position, the multi-functional carrying bag including a central body, a first stabilizer strap, and a second stabilizer strap, and the first carrying position includes: a first strap portion of the first stabilizer strap extending from a first end of the central body; a second strap portion of the first stabilizer strap extending from a second end of the central body; and the second stabilizer strap stowed in a pocket or removably coupled to the central body. At operation <b>404</b>, the method <b>400</b> can transition the multi-functional carrying bag from the first carrying position to a second carrying position by rotating the multi-functional carrying bag from a front torso of a user to a rear upper torso of the user. At operation <b>406</b>, the method <b>400</b> can carry the multi-functional carrying bag in the second carrying position, the second carrying position includes a connector of the second stabilizer strap coupled to a corresponding strap connector disposed on the first stabilizer strap to form a three-point connection at the front torso of the user.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">It is to be understood that the specific order or hierarchy of steps in the method(s) depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> and throughout this disclosure are instances of example approaches and can be rearranged while remaining within the disclosed subject matter. For instance, any of the operations depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> and throughout this disclosure may be omitted, repeated, performed in parallel, performed in a different order, and/or combined with any other of the operations depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> and throughout this disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">While the present disclosure has been described with reference to various implementations, it will be understood that these implementations are illustrative and that the scope of the present disclosure is not limited to them. Many variations, modifications, additions, and improvements are possible. More generally, implementations in accordance with the present disclosure have been described in the context of particular implementations. Functionality may be separated or combined differently in various implementations of the disclosure or described with different terminology. These and other variations, modifications, additions, and improvements may fall within the scope of the disclosure as defined in the claims that follow.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A multi-functional carrier bag comprising:
<claim-text>a central body at least partially formed of a flexible material;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first stabilizer strap including:
<claim-text>a first strap portion extending from a first end of the central body; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second strap portion extending from a second end of the central body, the first strap portion and the second strap portion form an obtuse angle;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second stabilizer strap extending from the central body at a side of the central body between the first end and the second end; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pocket defined into the side of the central body operable to:
<claim-text>receive and store the second stabilizer strap when the multi-functional carrier bag is in a first carrying position; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>provide access to the second stabilizer strap when the multi-functional carrier bag is in a second carrying position.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The multi-functional carrier bag of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the first end includes a first strap sheath;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second end includes a second strap sheath; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first strap sheath and the second strap sheath are continuous extensions of the flexible material at least partially forming the central body.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The multi-functional carrier bag of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a zipper disposed on the central body with:
<claim-text>a horizontal orientation in the first carrying position; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a non-horizontal orientation in the second carrying position.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The multi-functional carrier bag of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a strap connector, disposed on the first stabilizer strap, for receiving a connector of the second stabilizer strap.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The multi-functional carrier bag of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the connector of the second stabilizer strap is:
<claim-text>unattached to the strap connector when the multi-functional carrier bag is in the first carrying position; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>attached to the strap connector when the multi-functional carrier bag is in the second carrying position.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The multi-functional carrier bag of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the strap connector disposed on the first stabilizer strap is a first strap connector; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the multi-functional carrier bag further includes a second strap connector disposed on a front surface of the central body.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The multi-functional carrier bag of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the connector of the second stabilizer strap:
<claim-text>couples to the second strap connector disposed on the front surface of the central body when the multi-functional carrier bag is in the first carrying position; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>couples to the first strap connector disposed on the first stabilizer strap when the multi-functional carrier bag is in the second carrying position.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The multi-functional carrier bag of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the first strap connector is slidably disposed on the first stabilizer strap; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second strap connector is fixedly disposed on the front surface of the central body.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The multi-functional carrier bag of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the central body includes an irregular hexagonal-shaped profile.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. A multi-functional carrying system comprising:
<claim-text>a central body at least partially formed of a flexible material;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first stabilizer strap including:
<claim-text>a first strap portion extending from a first end of the central body; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second strap portion extending from a second end of the central body;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second stabilizer strap extending from the central body between the first end and the second end;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pocket defined into a side of the central body operable to:
<claim-text>receive and store the second stabilizer strap when the multi-functional carrying system is in a first carrying position; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>provide access to the second stabilizer strap for transitioning the multi-functional carrying system from the first carrying position to a second carrying position; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a strap connector disposed on the first stabilizer strap for receiving a connector of the second stabilizer strap when the multi-functional carrying system is in the second carrying position.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The multi-functional carrying system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the connector is a magnetic connector, and the strap connector is a magnetic buckle corresponding to the magnetic connector, providing one-handed attachability for the strap connector.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The multi-functional carrying system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the second stabilizer strap includes a V strap, with a first strap of the V strap coupling to the central body at a first connection point, and a second strap of the V strap coupling to the central body at a second connection point, and the pocket is disposed adjacent to the V strap on the central body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. The multi-functional carrying system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the first strap intersects the second strap with a slidable connector which slides unencumbered along the second strap for automatic adjustments.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The multi-functional carrying system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, further comprising a first pocket configured for cell phone carrying, and a second pocket configured for a hand warmer, the second pocket having an interior foam divider separating the first pocket from the second pocket and preventing heat transfer from the hand warmer to a contents of the second pocket.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. A method of providing a multi-functional carrying system, the method comprising:
<claim-text>carrying a multi-functional carrying bag in a first carrying position, the multi-functional carrying bag includes a central body, a first stabilizer strap, and a second stabilizer strap, and the first carrying position includes a connector of the second stabilizer strap coupled to a corresponding strap connector disposed on the first stabilizer strap to form a three-point connection at a front torso of a user;</claim-text>
<claim-text>transitioning the multi-functional carrying bag from the first carrying position to a second carrying position by rotating the central body of multi-functional carrying bag from a back of a user to the front torso of the user; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>carrying the multi-functional carrying bag in the second carrying position, the second carrying position includes:
<claim-text>a first strap portion of the first stabilizer strap extending from a first end of the central body;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second strap portion of the first stabilizer strap extending from a second end of the central body; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second stabilizer strap stowed in a pocket or removably coupled to the central body.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the second carrying position includes the second stabilizer strap removably coupled to the central body by coupling a first magnetic connector disposed on the second stabilizer strap to a second magnetic connector disposed on an outer surface of the central body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the connector of the second stabilizer strap couples to the corresponding strap connector using a magnetic connection between the connector and the strap connector; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>transitioning the multi-functional carrying bag from the first carrying position to the second carrying position includes performing a one-handed operation.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, further comprising accessing a hydration port, while carrying the multi-functional carrying bag in the second carrying position, disposed on a side of the multi-functional carrying bag opposite the pocket for stowing the second stabilizer strap.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein transitioning the multi-functional carrying bag from the first carrying position to the second carrying position includes:
<claim-text>detaching the connector from the strap connector to disengage the three-point connection at the front torso of the user; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>rotating the multi-functional carrying bag from a back upper torso of the user to the front torso of the user.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, further comprising preventing, with a foam liner disposed inside the multi-functional carrying bag, a heat distribution from a first pocket stowing a hand warmer to a second pocket for stowing a mobile device.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
