<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225425A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225425</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17577320</doc-number>
<date>20220117</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>17</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Clothing Apparatus</invention-title>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Warren</last-name>
<first-name>Joan Grace</first-name>
<address>
<city>Stockton</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="01" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kellum</last-name>
<first-name>Cory Deon</first-name>
<address>
<city>Stockton</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Warren</last-name>
<first-name>Joan Grace</first-name>
<address>
<city>Stockton</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="01" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kellum</last-name>
<first-name>Cory Deon</first-name>
<address>
<city>Stockton</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A clothing apparatus includes a body portion, a hood, and a front panel fastening mechanism. The body portion comprises a first front panel, a second front panel, and a rear panel. The first front panel and the second front panel are coupled to the rear panel to form a neck aperture. The first front panel comprises a first free edge and a first lower corner. The second front penal comprises a second free edge and a second lower corner. The first lower corner and the second lower corner are chamfered corners. The front panel fastening mechanism attaches the first free edge to the second free edge. The rear panel comprises an upper torso section and a lower blanket section. The lower blanket section is attachable to the first front panel and the second front panel.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="195.24mm" wi="152.74mm" file="US20230225425A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="233.51mm" wi="154.77mm" file="US20230225425A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="202.61mm" wi="158.83mm" file="US20230225425A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="192.02mm" wi="146.30mm" file="US20230225425A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="199.98mm" wi="145.29mm" file="US20230225425A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention relates generally to garments. More specifically, the present invention is a multi-functional garment that incorporates regular garments and blankets. The present invention is specifically designed for children, such as newborns, babies, infants, or toddlers. However, the present invention is not limited to this option, and it may further be adapted for different purposes. For example, the present invention can also be used by immobilized persons.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">One of the greatest frustrations of parenting a young child is attending to their clothing, for both warmth and cleanliness and health, while carrying out the other tasks of ordinary life that require bringing them along to various locations away from a home. The primary obstacle is managing to bring along all of the items necessary to attend to those needs while balancing performance of the tasks while carrying the child.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">A typical assortment of items that are on a child include: a diaper, clothes actually being worn (shirt, pants, socks, hat), and a coat or other wrap or swaddling, if not additionally a blanket. Beyond the demands of bringing along sheer quantity of so many items, there is also the problem of shuffling the various items in order to clothe and clean of the child. Eliminating some objects, in order to manage carrying, may find a parent empty handed to perform such a task. For example, leaving behind a blanket may mean that a child may have to be changed on a surface with no separation between the child's sensitive skin and the cold or rough or hot surface. Swaddling the child and foregoing additional clothes may make carrying the child easier and foster sleeping while out of the house, but if the child becomes restless, then the child can only be cooled by being only in a diaper, with skin exposed to the world, as well as the swaddling cloth becoming another object to be carried, defeating the advantage of not having to carry additional clothing. If a thick coat is put onto the child, then a blanket might reasonably be considered superfluous and left behind. However, when a change is necessary, the coat doesn't provide room to cover the child's bottom, or must be removed from the child, in order to serve as a changing blanket, adding a step, requiring another garment to be handled, and leaves the upper body of the child more exposed while performing the change.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Therefore, it is an objective of the present invention to provide a clothing apparatus that incorporates a coat and a blanket.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The present invention discloses a clothing apparatus that comprises a body portion, a hood, and a front panel fastening mechanism. The body portion comprises a first front panel, a second front panel, and a rear panel. The first front panel and the second front panel are coupled to the rear panel to form a neck aperture. The hood is attached to the body portion around the neck aperture. The first front panel comprises a first free edge and a first lower corner. The second front penal comprises a second free edge and a second lower corner. The first lower corner and the second lower corner are chamfered corners. The front panel fastening mechanism attaches the first free edge to the second free edge. The rear panel comprises an upper torso section and a lower blanket section. The upper torso section, the first front panel, and the second front panel cover a torso of a wearer. The lower blanket section is attachable to the first front panel and the second front panel.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">One or more of the following features may be included. The clothing apparatus may further comprise a first sleeve and a second sleeve. The first sleeve may extend from a first side of the body portion, and the second sleeve may extend from a second side of the body portion. The first side of the body portion may comprise a first opening below the first sleeve, and the second side of the body portion may comprise a second opening below the second sleeve. The first sleeve and the second sleeve may be detachable from the body portion. The first front panel may further comprise a pocket. The upper torso section may comprise a first slit at lower center of the upper torso section, and the first slit may be a horizontal slit. The upper torso section may comprise a plurality of first slits that are arranged one above another. The lower blanket section may comprise a second slit at lower center of the lower blanket section, and the second slit may be a horizontal slit. The lower blanket section may be detachable from the upper torso section. The clothing apparatus may further comprise a pacifier attached to the body portion.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The accompanying drawings, which are included to provide a further understanding of the invention are incorporated in and constitute a part of this specification, illustrate an embodiment of the invention and together with the description serve to explain the principles of the invention. They are meant to be exemplary illustrations provided to enable persons skilled in the art to practice the disclosure and are not intended to limit the scope of the present invention. That is, the dimensions of the components of the present invention, independently and in relation to each other can be different. It should be noted that the drawings are schematic and not necessarily drawn to scale. Some drawings are enlarged or reduced to improve drawing legibility.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> depicts a front view of an embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> depicts a front view of an embodiment of the present invention, wherein a lower blanket section folds up onto front panels.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> depicts a back view of an embodiment of the present invention, wherein the lower blanket section folds up onto the front panels.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> depicts a front view of an embodiment of the present invention, wherein a cap is detached from a body portion.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAIL DESCRIPTIONS OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">As a preliminary matter, it will readily be understood by one having ordinary skill in the relevant art that the present disclosure has broad utility and application. As should be understood, any embodiment may incorporate only one or a plurality of the above-disclosed aspects of the disclosure and may further incorporate only one or a plurality of the above-disclosed features. Furthermore, any embodiment discussed and identified as being &#x201c;preferred&#x201d; is considered to be part of a best mode contemplated for carrying out the embodiments of the present disclosure. Other embodiments also may be discussed for additional illustrative purposes in providing a full and enabling disclosure. Moreover, many embodiments, such as adaptations, variations, modifications, and equivalent arrangements, will be implicitly disclosed by the embodiments described herein and fall within the scope of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Accordingly, while embodiments are described herein in detail in relation to one or more embodiments, it is to be understood that this disclosure is illustrative and exemplary of the present disclosure and is made merely for the purposes of providing a full and enabling disclosure. The detailed disclosure herein of one or more embodiments is not intended, nor is to be construed, to limit the scope of patent protection afforded in any claim of a patent issuing here from, which scope is to be defined by the claims and the equivalents thereof. It is not intended that the scope of patent protection be defined by reading into any claim a limitation found herein that does not explicitly appear in the claim itself. Accordingly, it is intended that the scope of patent protection is to be defined by the issued claim(s) rather than the description set forth herein.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Additionally, it is important to note that each term used herein refers to that which an ordinary artisan would understand such term to mean based on the contextual use of such term herein. When not explicitly defined herein, to the extent that the meaning of a term used herein&#x2014;as understood by the ordinary artisan based on the contextual use of such term&#x2014;differs in any way from any particular dictionary definition of such term, it is intended that the meaning of the term as understood by the ordinary artisan should prevail.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Furthermore, it is important to note that, as used herein, &#x201c;a&#x201d; and &#x201c;an&#x201d; each generally denotes &#x201c;at least one,&#x201d; but does not exclude a plurality unless the contextual use dictates otherwise. When used herein to join a list of items, &#x201c;or&#x201d; denotes &#x201c;at least one of the items,&#x201d; but does not exclude a plurality of items of the list. Finally, when used herein to join a list of items, &#x201c;and&#x201d; denotes &#x201c;all of the items of the list.&#x201d;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The following detailed description refers to the accompanying drawings. Wherever possible, the same reference numbers are used in the drawings and the following description to refer to the same or similar elements. While many embodiments of the disclosure may be described, modifications, adaptations, and other implementations are possible. For example, substitutions, additions, or modifications may be made to the elements illustrated in the drawings, and the methods described herein may be modified by substituting, reordering, or adding stages to the disclosed methods. Accordingly, the following detailed description does not limit the disclosure. Instead, the proper scope of the disclosure is defined by the appended claims. The present disclosure contains headers. It should be understood that these headers are used as references and are not to be construed as limiting upon the subject matter disclosed under the header.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Other technical advantages may become readily apparent to one of ordinary skill in the art after review of the following figures and description. It should be understood at the outset that, although exemplary embodiments are illustrated in the figures and described below, the principles of the present disclosure may be implemented using any number of techniques, whether currently known or not. The present disclosure should in no way be limited to the exemplary implementations and techniques illustrated in the drawings and described below.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Unless otherwise indicated, the drawings are intended to be read together with the specification and are to be considered a portion of the entire written description of this invention. As used in the following description, the terms &#x201c;horizontal&#x201d;, &#x201c;vertical&#x201d;, &#x201c;left&#x201d;, &#x201c;right&#x201d;, &#x201c;up&#x201d;, &#x201c;down&#x201d; and the like, as well as adjectival and adverbial derivatives thereof (e.g., &#x201c;horizontally&#x201d;, &#x201c;rightwardly&#x201d;, &#x201c;upwardly&#x201d;, &#x201c;radially&#x201d;, etc.), simply refer to the orientation of the illustrated structure as the particular drawing figure faces the reader. Similarly, the terms &#x201c;inwardly,&#x201d; &#x201c;outwardly&#x201d; and &#x201c;radially&#x201d; generally refer to the orientation of a surface relative to its axis of elongation, or axis of rotation, as appropriate. As used herein, the term &#x201c;proximate&#x201d; refers to positions that are situated close/near in relationship to a structure. As used in the following description, the term &#x201c;distal&#x201d; refers to positions that are situated away from positions.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The present disclosure includes many aspects and features. Moreover, while many aspects and features relate to, and are described in the context of clothing apparatuses, embodiments of the present disclosure are not limited to use only in this context.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The present invention is a clothing apparatus. It is an aim of the present invention to provide a clothing apparatus that incorporates a coat and a blanket. It is another aim of the present invention to allow a child to be seated comfortably in a car set.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Referring now to the figures of the present disclosure. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a front view illustrating the components of the present invention. The clothing apparatus of the present invention comprises a body portion <b>10</b>, a first sleeve <b>20</b>, a second sleeve <b>30</b>, and a hood <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>-<b>4</b></figref>, the body portion <b>10</b> is configured to at least partially cover a wearer's torso. It should be noted that the body portion <b>10</b> can be of any shape, size, material, features, type or kind, orientation, location, quantity, components, and arrangements of components that would allow the present invention to fulfill the objectives and intents of the present invention. In one embodiment, the body portion <b>10</b> of the clothing apparatus of the present invention comprises two front panels, i.e., a first front panel <b>100</b> and a second front panel <b>110</b>, and a rear panel <b>120</b>. The first front panel <b>100</b> and the second front panel <b>110</b> may be coupled to the rear panel <b>120</b> by any suitable means known in the art, such as stitching. It is also contemplated that the first front panel <b>100</b>, the second front panel <b>110</b>, and the rear panel <b>120</b> can each be made of one or more panels or portions, for example, stitched together.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The body portion <b>10</b> of the clothing apparatus of the present invention comprises a neck aperture <b>140</b> for receiving the wearer's neck therethrough or encircling the wearer's neck. The neck aperture <b>140</b> may be formed by the first front panel <b>100</b>, the second front panel <b>110</b>, and the rear panel <b>120</b> coupled together.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The first front panel <b>100</b> and the second front panel <b>110</b> are preferably symmetrically shaped as mirror images of one another thereby covering the front of the torso. The first front panel <b>100</b> comprises a first free edge <b>102</b> and a first lower corner <b>104</b>, while the second front panel <b>110</b> comprises a second free edge <b>112</b> and a second lower corner <b>114</b>. In one embodiment, a front panel fastening mechanism <b>130</b> is used to attach the first front panel <b>100</b> to the second front panel <b>110</b>. Specifically, the front panel fastening mechanism <b>130</b> may be arranged on the first free edge <b>102</b> of the first front panel <b>100</b> and the second free edge <b>112</b> of the second front panel <b>110</b> such that the first free edge <b>102</b> may be attached to the second free edge <b>112</b> to join the first front panel <b>100</b> and the second front panel <b>110</b> together. Moreover, the front panel fastening mechanism <b>130</b> allows easy separation of the first front panel <b>100</b> and the second front panel <b>110</b>. The front panel fastening mechanism <b>130</b> may be any suitable fastening means, including but not limited to button and buttonholes, snaps, clamps, clasps, hook and loop fasteners, zippers, drawstrings, stickpins, clamping pins, magnets, etc. Preferably, the first front panel <b>100</b> and/or the second front panel <b>110</b> comprises a pocket <b>106</b> to allow users to store diapers, wipes, or other small items therein. In a preferred embodiment, the pocket <b>106</b> may be closed by any suitable fasteners.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The first lower coiner <b>104</b> of the first front panel <b>100</b> is preferably a chamfered corner. Similarly, the second lower corner <b>114</b> of the second front panel <b>110</b> is also preferably a chamfered corner. In this way, a triangular cut-out section <b>118</b> is formed at the bottom of the first front panel <b>100</b> and the second front panel <b>110</b> when the first front panel <b>100</b> and the second front panel <b>110</b> are joined together, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>, <b>4</b>, and <b>5</b></figref>. This triangular cut-out section <b>118</b> allows a seat belt to easily travel through while alleviating discomfort of the wearer.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">In reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>-<b>4</b></figref>, the rear panel comprises an upper torso section <b>122</b> and a lower blanket section <b>124</b>. The upper torso section <b>122</b>, together with the first front panel <b>100</b> and the second front panel <b>110</b>, covers the torso of the wearer. The lower blanket section <b>124</b> may be folded up and attached to the first front panel <b>100</b> and the second front panel <b>110</b> such that the wearer's lower body may be covered by the blanket, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>. In the illustrated embodiments, the upper torso section <b>122</b> and the lower blanket section <b>124</b> are formed in one piece. However, in other embodiments, the lower blanket section <b>124</b> may be detachable from the upper torso section <b>122</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">A blanket fastening mechanism may be used to attach the lower blanket section <b>124</b> to the first front panel <b>100</b> and the second front panel <b>110</b>. For example, the blanket fastening mechanism may comprise three pairs of fasteners, i.e., a first pair of corner fasteners <b>132</b>, a second pair of corner fasteners <b>134</b>, and a pair of center fasteners <b>136</b>. The first pair of corner fasteners <b>132</b> and the second pair of corner fasteners <b>134</b> are employed to attach the two lower corners of the lower blanket section <b>124</b> to the first front panel <b>100</b> and the second front panel <b>110</b>, while the pair of center fasteners <b>136</b> is used to hold the bottom edge <b>125</b> of the lower blanket section <b>124</b> to the first front panel <b>100</b> and or the second front panel <b>110</b>. The blanket fastening mechanism allows the lower blanket section <b>124</b> to be folded up and held to the first front panel <b>100</b> and the second front panel <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The upper torso section <b>122</b> may comprise a first slit <b>126</b> that is configured to allow the seat belt to travel through. The first slit <b>126</b> is preferably a horizontal slit located at the lower center portion of the upper torso section <b>122</b>. In a preferred embodiment, the upper torso section <b>122</b> comprises a plurality of first slits <b>126</b> that are arranged one above another such that the user can adjust the position of the seat belt, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>. The first slit <b>126</b> may be provided with a first cover <b>127</b> to conceal the first slit <b>126</b>. Moreover, the triangular cut-out section <b>118</b> formed by the first front panel <b>100</b> and the second front panel <b>110</b> preferably exposes the first slit <b>126</b> when the first front panel <b>100</b> and the second front panel <b>110</b> are joined together.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The lower blanket section <b>124</b> may comprise a second slit <b>128</b> that allows the seat belt to travel through when the lower blanket section <b>124</b> is folded up onto the first front panel <b>100</b> and or the second front panel <b>110</b>. In a preferred embodiment, the second slit <b>128</b> comprises a second cover <b>129</b> to conceal the second slit <b>128</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The first sleeve <b>20</b> extends from a first side <b>150</b> of the body portion <b>10</b>, while the second sleeve <b>30</b> extends from a second side <b>160</b> of the body portion <b>10</b>. It should be noted that the first sleeve <b>20</b> and the second sleeve <b>30</b> can be of any shape, size, material, features, type or kind, orientation, location, quantity, components, and arrangements of components that would allow the present invention to fulfill the objectives and intents of the present invention. In a preferred embodiment, the first sleeve <b>20</b> and/or the second sleeve <b>30</b> are detachable from the body portion <b>10</b>. In one embodiment, the first side <b>150</b> of the body portion <b>10</b> comprises a first opening <b>152</b> below the first sleeve <b>20</b> to allow tubes or wire to pass through; similarly, the second side <b>160</b> of the body portion <b>10</b> comprises a second opening <b>162</b> below the second sleeve <b>30</b> to allow tubes or wire to pass through.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The hood <b>40</b> of the clothing apparatus of the present invention may he attached around the neck aperture <b>140</b> of the body portion <b>10</b> such that the hood <b>40</b> may be raised above the head of the wearer to protect the head from weather or cold. In a preferred embodiment, the hood <b>40</b> is attached to the body portion <b>10</b> via snap buttons. However, other fasteners are also contemplated. In a preferred embodiment, the clothing apparatus of the present invention further comprises a pacifier <b>50</b> attached to the body portion. In one embodiment, the body portion may further comprise a pair of detachable epaulets, and the pacifier <b>50</b> may be attached to the epaulets, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Although the disclosure has been explained in relation to its preferred embodiment, it is to he understood that many other possible modifications and variations can be made without departing from the spirit and scope of the disclosure.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A clothing apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a body portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first sleeve:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second sleeve;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a hood;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a front panel fastening mechanism;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the body portion comprising a first front panel, a second front panel, and a rear panel;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first sleeve extending from a first side of the body portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second sleeve extending from a second side of the body portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first side of the body portion comprising a first opening below the first sleeve;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second side of the body portion comprises a second opening below the second sleeve;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first front panel and the second front panel being coupled to the rear panel to form a neck aperture;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the hood being attached to the body portion around the neck aperture;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first front panel comprising a first free edge and a first lower corner;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second front panel comprising a second free edge and a second lower corner;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first lower corner and the second lower corner being chamfered corners to form a triangular cut-out section when the first front panel and the second front panel are joined together;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the front panel fastening mechanism attaching the first free edge to the second free edge;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the rear panel comprising an upper torso section and a lower blanket section;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the upper torso section, the first front panel, and the second front panel covering a torso of a wearer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the upper torso section comprising a plurality of first slits at lower center of the upper torso section;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the plurality of first slits being horizontal slits;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the plurality of first slits being exposed via the triangular cut-out section when the first front panel and the second front panel are joined together; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the lower blanket section being attachable to the first front panel and the second front panel.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. (canceled)</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. (canceled)</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. (canceled)</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The clothing apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first front panel further comprises a pocket.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. (canceled)</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. (canceled)</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The clothing apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the lower blanket section comprises a second slit at lower center of the lower blanket section, and the second slit is a horizontal slit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. (canceled)</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The clothing apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a pacifier attached to the body portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. (canceled)</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. (canceled)</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. (canceled)</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. (canceled)</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. (canceled)</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. (canceled)</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. (canceled)</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. (canceled)</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. (canceled)</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. (canceled)</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
