<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225528A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225528</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17579304</doc-number>
<date>20220119</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>17</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>9</main-group>
<subgroup>10</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>20</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>9</main-group>
<subgroup>1045</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>9</main-group>
<subgroup>1036</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>20</main-group>
<subgroup>025</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>9</main-group>
<subgroup>109</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">BODY PILLOW</invention-title>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>FRIDABABY, LLC</orgname>
<address>
<city>Miami</city>
<state>FL</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>LEE</last-name>
<first-name>Stella</first-name>
<address>
<city>Los Angeles</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>FRIDABABY, LLC</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Miami</city>
<state>FL</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A body pillow has an elongate body formed around an axis. An outer cover of the pillow includes a stretchy circumferential band of material disposed around the axis and to be spaced from either end of the pillow. Ends of first and second inner pillows are disposed near or under the circumferential band. The user may helically twist the body of the pillow around the axis at the circumferential band. Doing so separates the inner pillows and increases their firmness. An inner side of the outer cover may be made of a stretchy fabric that conforms to the body of the user, while outer side may be composed mostly of nonstretch material to retain the pillows' shape. The twisted and nontwisted configurations of the pillow make it an effective sleeping aid for expecting mothers during different stages of their pregnancies.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="36.58mm" wi="158.75mm" file="US20230225528A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="183.39mm" wi="109.56mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225528A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="167.05mm" wi="72.98mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225528A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="176.70mm" wi="160.02mm" file="US20230225528A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="208.62mm" wi="128.27mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225528A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="208.03mm" wi="127.17mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225528A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="157.06mm" wi="117.01mm" file="US20230225528A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="148.59mm" wi="143.59mm" file="US20230225528A1-20230720-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="154.18mm" wi="158.50mm" file="US20230225528A1-20230720-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="229.28mm" wi="120.40mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225528A1-20230720-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="224.79mm" wi="124.54mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225528A1-20230720-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="153.92mm" wi="84.16mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225528A1-20230720-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00012" num="00012">
<img id="EMI-D00012" he="177.72mm" wi="116.08mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225528A1-20230720-D00012.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">A body pillow is meant to lay alongside a sleeper's body rather than just be underneath his or her head. A typical mattress presents a flat plane as its upper surface and will cushion only a part of a sleeper's body, such as his or her front, back or one side. A body pillow lends additional lateral support.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Body pillows have been provided for use by pregnant women who otherwise may experience discomfort while attempting to sleep. One form of these body or pregnancy pillows has a length much greater than its thickness. However, pregnancy pillows currently on the market have drawbacks. They often take up too much room in the bed, do not stay in place, do not permit the use of a conventional head pillow, are itchy, have exposed and irritating zippers, have shapes or firmnesses that cannot be easily altered, and/or are stuffed with a fill that gets lumpy and poorly distributed over time. Optimally, a pregnancy pillow should be long enough to support the belly and knees/legs at the same time, should be easy for the user to position both herself and the pillow, should be able to be easily altered in shape as the user's body changes shape, should have a firmness that can be changed for different parts of the body, and should permit the user to use her own head pillow. The body pillow described herein provides these advantages.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">According to one aspect of the invention, a body pillow is provided that has a pillow body defined by an elongate outer cover. The outer cover has a circumferential band that is formed around a long axis of the pillow body, and so as to be spaced from both first and second opposed ends of the outer cover. This circumferential band is composed of a stretch fabric. The body further includes first and second inner pillows that are disposed inside of the outer cover. A first end of the first inner pillow is disposed near the first end of the outer cover. A second end of the first inner pillow is disposed to be near the circumferential band. A first end of the second inner pillow is disposed to be near the circumferential band. A second end of the second inner pillow is disposed to be near the second end of the outer cover.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The body pillow is capable of assuming each of a nontwisted configuration and a twisted configuration. In the twisted configuration, the outer cover is helically twisted around the axis at the circumferential band. This pushes apart the second end of the first inner pillow from the first end of the second inner pillow. It also increases the firmness of the first and second inner pillows. In the nontwisted configuration, the outer cover is not helically twisted about its axis. In one embodiment, the body pillow may be helically twisted by varying amounts to suit the user. One of these amounts can be 360 degrees.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">According to another aspect of the invention, a body pillow has an elongate outer cover defining a pillow body, the pillow body being formed around along a longitudinal axis. The outer cover has an inner side that in use faces a torso of the user and an opposed outer side for facing away from the torso of the user. The inner side extends from a first side margin of the outer cover to a second side margin of the outer cover. A first, stretch fabric makes up at least a majority of the inner side. An outer side also extends from the first side margin to the second side margin. A second, nonstretch fabric makes up at least a majority of the outer side.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In one embodiment, the outer cover has a first end disposed on the axis and a second end disposed on the axis to be remote from the first end. The outer cover has a circumferential band of stretch fabric that is disposed around the axis so as to be between the first end and the second ends. Substantially all of the inner side of the outer cover is composed of stretch fabric. Substantially all of the outer side, with the exception of the circumferential band, is composed of nonstretch fabric.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In one embodiment, the pillow is capable of being helically twisted about its longitudinal axis by about 360 degrees, so that in the twisted configuration only stretchy fabric will face the torso of the user.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In either of the above aspects of the invention, a width of the circumferential band, when the body pillow is in the nontwisted configuration and as measured in a direction parallel to the axis, is less than about a tenth of an overall length of the body pillow, as measured between the first and second ends thereof in parallel to the axis.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In either of the above aspects of the invention, the outer cover is composed of a plurality of fabric panels. These fabric panels include the circumferential band and at least one panel made out of nonstretch fabric. In one embodiment, the outer cover has at least two such panels made out of nonstretch fabric.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In either of the above aspects of the invention, the circumferential band may be positioned closer to the first end of the outer cover than to the second end of the outer cover. In these embodiments, an axial length of the first inner pillow will be shorter than an axial length of the second inner pillow. Alternatively, the circumferential band may be positioned approximately equidistantly between the first end and the second end of the outer cover, and in this case the axial lengths of the inner pillows will be about the same.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In either of the above aspects of the invention, the body pillow is tapered from the second end of the outer cover to the first end of the outer cover. In one embodiment, the tapering occurs in a horizontal plane, but not in a vertical plane. Said another way, a thickness of the body pillow from a midline on the inner side to a midline on the outer side tapers as one proceeds from the second end of the outer cover to the first end of the outer cover, but the thickness from a top margin or seam to a bottom margin or seam remains substantially constant along most of the length of the outer cover. In one embodiment, the outer cover has a further, end panel, disposed at the second end, which is made of nonstretch fabric.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In either of the above aspects of the invention, first and second inner pillows are disposed inside of the outer cover, and may be filled with expanded polystyrene (EPS) microbeads.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The body pillow enables the use of a method for enhancing the comfort of a pregnant woman, during both a first time during her pregnancy and a second time during her pregnancy that is spaced from the first time. At the first time, the body pillow may be used in an untwisted configuration. At the second time, the user helically twists the body pillow, about its axis and at the outer cover's circumferential band of stretchy material, by a desired amount. In the twisted configuration, the spacing between the first and second inner pillows is increased, and/or the firmness of each of the first and second inner pillows is increased. The user then sleeps with the body pillow in the twisted configuration. In one embodiment, the user helically twists the pillow a full 360-degrees about the axis, so that stretchy material continues to face her torso.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The pillow of the present invention enhances the support of the user's knees or legs, and increases the ability of the user to adjust and customize pillow firmness. Because of the pillow's technical advantages, the user gets a better night's sleep, especially during pregnancy when the shape and weight of her body changes.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Further aspects of the invention and their advantages can be discerned in the following detailed description as read in conjunction with the drawings of exemplary embodiments, in which like characters denote like parts and in which:</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a perspective view, from a viewpoint near an outer side and a first end, of a first embodiment of a pillow according to the invention;;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a perspective view, from a viewpoint near an inner side and a second end, of the pillow shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is an inner side view of the pillow shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is an outer side view of the pillow shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is a top view of the pillow shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is a top view of the pillow shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, but shown in a twisted configuration;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> is an axial sectional view taken along Line <b>7</b>-<b>7</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> is an axial sectional view of the pillow after the user has separated the first inner pillow from the second inner pillow;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref> is an axial sectional view of the pillow shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, but shown in a twisted configuration;</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref> is a perspective view, taken from near a second end thereof, of a first inner pillow for use in the embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b></figref> is a side view of a first inner pillow for use in the embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>12</b></figref> is a top view of the first inner pillow shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>13</b></figref> is a perspective view, taken from near a second end thereof, of a second inner pillow for use in the embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>14</b></figref> is a side view of the second inner pillow shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>13</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>15</b></figref> is a top view of the second inner pillow shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>13</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>16</b>A-<b>16</b>D</figref> show different possible positions of the body pillow used during sleep, a user being shown in phantom;</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>17</b></figref> is a top view of a body pillow according to a second embodiment of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>18</b></figref> is a top view of a first inner pillow for use in the embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>17</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>19</b></figref> is a top view of a second inner pillow for use in the embodiment shown in</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>17</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>20</b></figref> is a perspective view of the pillow shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>17</b></figref>, but in a twisted configuration; and</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>21</b></figref> is a block diagram illustrating steps in a method of use according to the invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">As seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, a body pillow <b>100</b> according to a first embodiment of the invention is formed around a longitudinal axis X. An outer cover <b>102</b> of pillow <b>100</b> defines the limits of a body <b>104</b> thereof, and extends from a first end <b>106</b> to a second end <b>108</b> remote from the first end <b>106</b>. Ends <b>106</b>, <b>108</b> are positioned on axis X. In overall dimensions, the body pillow is much longer than it is either wide or tall. For example, a length of body pillow <b>100</b>, from end <b>106</b> to end <b>108</b> measured in parallel to axis X, can be about 54 inches. A height, as measured in a vertical plane when the pillow is put in use, can be about_inches along most of the pillow's length. However, and as seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, the pillow <b>100</b> is tapered, in a horizontal direction between an outer side <b>110</b> to an inner side <b>112</b>, as one proceeds from the second end <b>108</b> to the first end <b>106</b>. A greatest diameter of the second end <b>108</b>, in a plane orthogonal to axis X, may be about 10 inches. [?] Herein, I use &#x201c;inner side&#x201d; to mean the side that in use faces the torso of the mother, and &#x201c;outer side&#x201d; to mean the opposed side that in use faces away from the torso of the mother. But as seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>3</b> and <b>4</b></figref>, in a vertical plane, the pillow <b>100</b> is not tapered throughout most of its length, but just rounded on the ends.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Stated another way, and referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>3</b>-<b>5</b></figref>, the inner side <b>112</b> has an imaginary midline <b>116</b> that extends between ends <b>106</b>, <b>108</b> and bisects inner side <b>112</b>. The outer side <b>110</b> likewise has an imaginary midline <b>118</b> that likewise extends between ends <b>106</b> and <b>108</b>, and bisects outer side <b>110</b>. The inner side <b>112</b> is joined to the outer side <b>110</b>, as by stitching, at a top seam or margin <b>120</b>, and also at an opposed, bottom seam or margin <b>122</b>. As one proceeds along the pillow body <b>104</b> from second end <b>108</b> to first end <b>106</b>, the distance between outer midline <b>118</b> and inner midline <b>116</b> decreases, but the distance between top margin <b>120</b> and bottom margin <b>122</b> does not, except near either end <b>106</b>, <b>108</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">A circumferential band <b>114</b> of material is disposed around axis X, at a location between ends <b>106</b> and <b>108</b>. In the embodiment seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>-<b>16</b>D</figref>, this location is closer to the first end <b>106</b> than it is to the second end <b>108</b>. For example, one edge of band <b>114</b> may be disposed at about 16 &#xbd; inches from end <b>106</b>. The width of band <b>114</b>, as measured in a direction parallel to axis X, can be less than a tenth of the overall length of pillow <b>100</b>, and in this illustrated embodiment is about three inches. The width of band <b>114</b> is selected to be the minimum necessary to allow at least a 360 degree helical twisting of the pillow <b>100</b> around axis X at the band <b>114</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">To accommodate this degree of helical twisting, the circumferential band <b>114</b> is made of a stretchy material. In one embodiment, this can be a stretchy material with a soft pile, such as a nylon/Spandex jersey. The rest of outer side <b>110</b> preferably is composed of a smooth, soft but nonstretch material, such as a TENCEL&#xae; weave. TENCEL&#xae; is a trademark for a rayon fabric made of lyocell and modal fibers. In one embodiment, the remaining panels of stretchy fabric described herein are made of nylon/Spandex jersey, and the remaining panels of nonstretch fabric described herein are made of TENCEL&#xae;.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">In the illustrated embodiment, a first panel <b>124</b> of nonstretch material extends from band <b>114</b> to end <b>106</b>, and extends between seams <b>120</b> and <b>122</b>. A second panel <b>126</b> of nonstretch material extends from band <b>114</b> to end <b>108</b>, and between seams <b>120</b> and <b>122</b>. As more clearly seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b> and <b>3</b></figref>, a second panel <b>128</b> of stretch material extends between band <b>114</b> and end <b>106</b>, and between seams <b>120</b> and <b>122</b>. A third panel <b>130</b> of stretch material extends between band <b>114</b> and end <b>108</b> and between seams <b>120</b> and <b>122</b>. The result is that, in the illustrated embodiment, all of inner side <b>112</b> is a soft stretch material, while most of the outer side <b>110</b> is composed of nonstretch material. As constructed of the preferred materials, the inner side <b>112</b> conforms to the user's body and particularly her belly, will be inherently cool to the touch, and is highly breathable and comfortable. The outer side <b>110</b> will be smooth, will absorb moisture better than cotton, and regulates heat. The outer side <b>110</b> keeps the pillow <b>100</b>'s support and shape.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The outer cover <b>102</b> is completed by an end panel <b>200</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>), which can be made of a nonstretch material and which can take the shape of an oval or disk. It is preferred that all panels recited herein be joined together by stitching at hidden (interior facing) seams. A zipper <b>202</b> may be placed along the seam or margin <b>120</b> to permit the user to insert and extract the inner pillows, described below. The zipper <b>202</b> should be provided with a covering flap (not shown).</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">In one embodiment, the panels of the outer cover <b>102</b> are color-coded. For example, the color of the circumferential band <b>114</b> can be made to be in a color different from the rest of the panels of the cover. This is to provide the user a visual clue as to where to twist the pillow. In another embodiment, stretch panels <b>114</b>, <b>128</b> and <b>130</b> may be provided in a first color, while nonstretch panels <b>124</b>, <b>126</b> and <b>200</b> may be provided in another color. In a third embodiment, the color of circumferential band <b>114</b> may be chosen to be different from the color of nonstretch panels <b>124</b>, <b>126</b> and <b>200</b>, and also to be different in color from the rest of the stretch panels <b>128</b> and <b>130</b>. In a fourth embodiment, the color of all panels is the same.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">In the embodiment of the invention where circumferential band <b>114</b> is closer to end <b>106</b> than it is to end <b>108</b>, two inner pillows <b>1000</b>, <b>1300</b> are provided to be of different lengths. A first, smaller, inner pillow <b>1000</b> is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>10</b>-<b>12</b></figref>. Pillow <b>1000</b> has a first end <b>1002</b> that, in use, will be adjacent to outer cover end <b>106</b>. A second end <b>1004</b> is remote from first end <b>1002</b> and, in use, will be disposed near or under circumferential band <b>114</b>. Inner pillow <b>1000</b> can be tapered from second end <b>1004</b> to first end <b>1002</b>. Preferably, the taper is selected such that it conforms to the degree and type of taper of the outer cover <b>102</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">In the illustrated embodiment, a cover <b>1006</b> of the first inner pillow <b>1000</b> is made from an inner panel <b>1008</b> that extends from end <b>1002</b> to end <b>1004</b> and from a bottom seam <b>1010</b> to a top seam <b>1012</b>; an outer panel <b>1014</b> that also extends from end <b>1002</b> to end <b>1004</b> and from top seam <b>1012</b> to bottom seam <b>1010</b>; and a preferably elliptical end panel <b>1016</b>, the margins of which are stitched to inner panel <b>1008</b> and outer panel <b>1014</b>. Panels <b>1008</b>, <b>1014</b> and <b>1016</b> can be made of nonstretch fabric. A zipper <b>1018</b> is located on seam <b>1010</b> (alternatively but not shown, on seam <b>1012</b>) to permit access to the interior of first inner pillow <b>1000</b>. The zipper may have its pull removed and covered by a flap of fabric (not shown) to reduce irritation to the user. First inner pillow <b>1000</b> may be about eighteen inches long. Its end panel <b>1016</b> may take the form of an ellipse in which a major axis is disposed vertically in use and which may be about nine inches. A minor axis of end panel <b>1016</b> is disposed horizontally in use and may be about five inches. In conformance with the nature of the taper of outer cover <b>102</b>, first inner pillow <b>1000</b> is tapered in a horizontal plane but not in a vertical plane, as is evident in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>11</b> and <b>12</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The second inner pillow <b>1300</b> is illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>13</b>-<b>15</b></figref>. The second inner pillow <b>1300</b> extends from a first end <b>1302</b>, which in use is disposed near or under the circumferential band <b>114</b> of outer cover <b>102</b>, to a second end <b>1304</b>, which in use is disposed to be adjacent the second end <b>108</b> of outer cover <b>102</b>. In this illustrated embodiment, a cover <b>1306</b> of second inner pillow <b>1300</b> is made up of four fabric panels: an inner panel <b>1308</b>, an outer panel <b>1310</b>, a first end panel <b>1312</b> and a second end panel <b>1314</b>. The inner panel <b>1308</b> extends from first end <b>1302</b> to second end <b>1304</b> and from a top seam <b>1316</b> to a bottom seam <b>1318</b>. The outer panel <b>1310</b> likewise extends from first end <b>1302</b> to second end <b>1304</b> and from top seam <b>1316</b> to bottom seam <b>1318</b>. First end panel <b>1312</b> is disposed at first end <b>1302</b> and may take the form of an ellipse, such as one having a major axis of about nine inches and a minor axis of about five inches. Second end panel <b>1314</b> is disposed at second end <b>1304</b> and may take the form of a disc with a diameter of about nine inches. An axial length of second inner pillow may be about 36 inches, in the embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>-<b>16</b>D</figref> (in which the lengths of the first and second inner pillows are different from each other and in which circumferential band <b>114</b> is positioned closer to first end <b>106</b> than to second end <b>108</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">The second inner pillow <b>1300</b> may be tapered from second end <b>1304</b> to first end <b>1302</b>. The degree of taper preferably conforms to that of outer cover <b>102</b>. Also to this end, the second inner pillow is tapered in a horizontal plane, as seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>15</b></figref>, but not in a vertical plane, as seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>14</b></figref>, except near ends <b>1302</b>, <b>1304</b>. Panels <b>1308</b>, <b>1310</b>, <b>1312</b> and <b>1314</b> may be made of a nonstretch fabric. A zipper <b>1320</b> may be positioned along seam <b>1316</b> (alternatively, along seam <b>1318</b>) to afford access to the interior of second inner pillow <b>1300</b>. Ideally the zipper <b>1320</b> should have its pull removed and should be covered by a fabric flap (not shown), so as to not be a source of irritation to the user.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">First and second inner pillows <b>1000</b>, <b>1300</b> may be filled with a fill <b>700</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>7</b>-<b>9</b></figref>) such as expanded polystyrene (EPS) microbeads. The micro EPS beads may have an average diameter of about 1 mm. A micro EPS bead fill is easily adjustable and adaptable, is breathable, does not get hot, is lightweight and easy to maneuver, and feels plush and soft to the user.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>7</b>-<b>9</b></figref> show pillow <b>100</b> in a nontwisted configuration (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref>), a twisted configuration (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref>) and a transitional state between these configurations (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref>). In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref>, the second end <b>1004</b> of first inner pillow <b>1000</b> is adjacent or even touching first end <b>1302</b> of second inner pillow <b>1300</b>, at a location underneath circumferential band <b>114</b>. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref>, the user has pushed the fill <b>700</b> in first inner pillow <b>1000</b> away from the fill <b>700</b> in second inner pillow <b>1300</b>, leaving a region <b>800</b> through which the outer cover is not supported by fill <b>700</b> at all. This region <b>800</b> should include circumferential band <b>114</b>. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref>, the user has helically twisted outer cover <b>102</b> about axis X at circumferential band <b>114</b>. The outer cover <b>102</b> may, for example, be twisted by a full 360 degrees, such that stretch panels <b>128</b> and <b>130</b> of the inner side <b>112</b> again face the torso of the user. This twisting will increase the separation of first inner pillow end <b>1004</b> from second pillow end <b>1302</b>. The twisting also has the effect of increasing the firmness of fill <b>700</b> in pillows <b>1000</b>, <b>1300</b>. Helically twisting pillow <b>100</b> about its axis X keeps the inner pillows <b>1000</b>, <b>1300</b> separated when the pillow <b>100</b> is in use.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>16</b>A-<b>16</b>D</figref> depict use of the pillow <b>100</b> in various configurations. Note that while the pillow <b>100</b>, and its inner pillows <b>1000</b>, <b>1300</b>, are formed along a straight, longitudinal axis X, in use they don't stay that way. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>16</b>A</figref>, the pillow <b>100</b> is being used in an untwisted configuration. The first, smaller end <b>106</b> is positioned near the upper chest of mom M. The pillow <b>100</b> has been curved to conform to the torso of mom M's body, and the lower end <b>108</b> may be positioned between her legs. The utility of this configuration is enhanced because the pillow <b>100</b> is wider where it is inserted between the mom's legs, and is not as wide at that portion facing mom M's belly. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>16</b>B</figref>, mom M is using pillow <b>100</b> in a similar way, but only after she has twisted pillow <b>100</b> at circumferential band <b>114</b>. Since mom M has twisted the pillow through 360&#xb0;, both of the stretchy inner panels <b>128</b>, <b>130</b> remain proximate to her body. This increases the firmness and level of support contributed by inner pillows <b>1000</b>, <b>1300</b>. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>16</b>C</figref>, the pillow <b>100</b> has been helically twisted at circumferential band <b>114</b> so as to increase the firmness of inner pillows <b>1000</b>, <b>1300</b>. As so configured, pillow <b>100</b> is used to support mom M's back. Finally, in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>16</b>D</figref>, pillow <b>100</b> is used in an untwisted configuration, but mom M is laying partially on top of it, with the lower end <b>108</b> padding mom M's knees and legs.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>17</b>-<b>19</b></figref> illustrate an alternative embodiment, in which a circumferential band <b>1700</b> is located approximately equidistantly between a first end <b>1702</b> of the outer cover <b>1704</b>, and a second end <b>1706</b> thereof. A first inner pillow <b>1800</b> is longer than the first inner pillow <b>1000</b> of the first embodiment, and a second inner pillow <b>1900</b> is commensurately shorter than the second inner pillow <b>1300</b>. The materials from which alternative body pillow <b>1708</b> and its inner pillows <b>1800</b>, <b>1900</b> are made otherwise can be the same, as can the overall degree and type of taper and the composition of the inner and outer sides <b>1710</b>, <b>1712</b> of the outer cover <b>1704</b>. First pillow <b>1800</b> has enough volume and length for arm support and belly support. Second inner pillow <b>1900</b> still has enough volume and length for knee and leg support. The degree of taper from second end <b>1706</b> to first end <b>1702</b> remains the same as that of the first illustrated embodiment, so that the user's belly can have low profile support but wider support for the user's knees and legs. The pillow <b>1708</b> remains helically twistable from a nontwisted configuration to a twisted configuration (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>20</b></figref>) and back, at circumferential band <b>1700</b>, so that the user may adjust the firmness and/or placement of inner pillows <b>1800</b> and <b>1900</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>21</b></figref> depicts steps in a method of using either pillow <b>100</b> or pillow <b>1708</b>. The pillow may presently be in ether an untwisted configuration <b>2100</b>, as seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref>, or a twisted configuration <b>2102</b>, seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref>. If the pillow is presently in the untwisted configuration, the user only has to use it at step <b>2104</b>. But the user may want to increase the firmness in the inner pillows. To do this, and at step <b>2106</b>, she separates the inner pillows, and more particularly the fill <b>700</b> in those inner pillows, as seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref>. Then, at step <b>2108</b>, she helically twists the outer cover <b>102</b>, <b>1704</b>, possibly through about 360 degrees so that the stretchy material is again presented for conformance to her body. Doing this places the pillow in a twisted configuration at <b>2102</b>, and the user may choose to use the pillow in this configuration at step <b>2110</b>. To return the pillow to an untwisted configuration, the user simply untwists it at step <b>2112</b>. The ability to so easily reconfigure the pillow makes it ideal as a sleeping aid for different stages or times during pregnancy.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">In summary, a body pillow has been shown and described that is particularly suited as a sleeping aid during pregnancy. The user may helically twist the pillow at a stretchy circumferential band to increase the firmness of inner pillows disposed inside of the outer cover, or use the pillow in an untwisted configuration. The pillow is thus adaptable for use during different times during pregnancy.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">While illustrated embodiments of the present invention have been described and illustrated in the appended drawings, the present invention is not limited thereto but only by the scope and spirit of the appended claims.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>We claim:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A body pillow comprising:
<claim-text>an elongate outer cover defining a pillow body, the pillow body formed along a longitudinal axis, the outer cover having a first end disposed on the axis and a second end disposed on the axis to be remote from the first end;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the outer cover having a circumferential band formed around the axis, the circumferential band spaced from the first end of the outer cover and from the second end of the outer cover and composed of a stretch fabric;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first inner pillow disposed inside of the outer cover, a first end of the first inner pillow disposed to be near the first end of the outer cover, a second end of the first inner pillow remote from the first end of the first inner pillow disposed to be near the circumferential band;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second inner pillow disposed inside of the outer cover, a first end of the second inner pillow disposed to be near the circumferential band, a second end of the second inner pillow remote from the first end of the second inner pillow disposed to be near the second end of the outer cover; wherein</claim-text>
<claim-text>the body pillow is capable of assuming each of a nontwisted configuration and a twisted configuration, wherein in the nontwisted configuration the outer cover is not helically twisted about the axis, and the second end of the first inner pillow is at a first distance from the first end of the second inner pillow; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein, in the twisted configuration, the outer cover is helically twisted about the axis at the circumferential band, and the second end of the first inner pillow is at a second distance from the first end of the second inner pillow, the second distance being greater than the first distance.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The body pillow of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein a width of the circumferential band, in the nontwisted configuration and as measured in a direction parallel to the axis, is less than a tenth of an overall length of the outer cover, in the nontwisted configuration and measured in a direction parallel to the axis.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The body pillow of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein a width of the circumferential band, in the nontwisted configuration and as measured in a direction parallel to the axis, is about three inches.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The body pillow of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the body pillow is capable of being twisted at least about 360 degrees to assume the twisted configuration.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The body pillow of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the outer cover is composed of a plurality of fabric panels including a panel making up the circumferential band, at least one fabric panel of the outer cover joined to the circumferential band being made of a nonstretch fabric.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The body pillow of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein at least two fabric panels of the outer cover joined to the circumferential band are made of nonstretch fabric.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The body pillow of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the circumferential band is disposed around the axis to be closer to the first end than to the second end.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The body pillow of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein an axial length of the first inner pillow is shorter than an axial length of the second inner pillow.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The body pillow of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the outer cover is tapered from the second end of the outer cover to the first end of the outer cover.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The body pillow of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the outer cover has a length in the untwisted condition, and wherein an inner side of the outer cover, in use, faces the user and an outer side of the outer cover is remote from the user, the inner side extending from a first side margin of the outer cover to a second side margin of the outer cover, the outer side extending from the first side margin to the second side margin, the inner side having an axially oriented inner midline bisecting a surface of the inner side between the first side margin and the second side margin, the outer side having an axially oriented outer midline bisecting a surface of the outer side between the first side margin and the second side margin, a thickness of the body pillow in the untwisted condition between the first side margin and the second side margin remaining substantially constant throughout most of the length of the outer cover, a thickness of the body pillow in the untwisted condition between the inner midline and the outer midline tapering from the second end of the outer cover to the first end of the outer cover.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The body pillow of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the circumferential band is disposed around the axis at point approximately equidistant from the first end of the outer cover to the second end of the outer cover.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. A body pillow comprising:
<claim-text>an elongate outer cover defining a pillow body, the pillow body formed along a longitudinal axis;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the outer cover having an inner side for facing the user and an outer side for positioning remote from the user, the inner side extending from a first side margin of the outer cover to a second side margin of the outer cover opposed to the first side margin, a first fabric making up at least a majority of the inner side, the first fabric being a stretch fabric;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the outer side extending from the first side margin to the second side margin, a second fabric making up at least a majority of the outer side, the second fabric being a nonstretch fabric.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. The body pillow of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the outer cover has a first end disposed on the axis and a second end disposed on the axis to be remote from the first end, a circumferential band of stretch fabric disposed around the axis and to be between the first end and the second end, substantially all of the inner side of the outer cover being composed of stretch fabric, substantially all of the outer side of the outer cover being composed of nonstretch fabric with the exception of the circumferential band.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The body pillow of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the circumferential band is located at a position closer to the first end than the second end.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. The body pillow of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the circumferential band is located approximately equidistantly from the first end and the second end.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. The body pillow of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the inner side comprises a first inner side panel extending from the first end to the circumferential band and a second inner side panel extending from the second end to the circumferential band, the first and second inner side panels being made of a stretch fabric.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. The body pillow of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the outer side comprises a first outer side panel extending from the first end to the circumferential band and a second outer side panel extending from the second end to the circumferential band, the first and second outer side panels being made of a nonstretch fabric.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. The body pillow of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the outer cover has a first end disposed on the axis and a second end disposed on the axis to be remote from the first end, the outer cover tapering from the second end to the first end.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. The body pillow of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein the outer cover has a length in the untwisted condition, an inner side of the outer cover, in use, facing the user and an outer side of the outer cover being remote from the user, the inner side extending from a first side margin of the outer cover to a second side margin of the outer cover, the outer side extending from the first side margin to the second side margin, the inner side having an axially oriented inner midline bisecting a surface of the inner side between the first side margin and the second side margin, the outer side having an axially oriented outer midline bisecting a surface of the outer side between the first side margin and the second side margin, a thickness of the body pillow in the untwisted condition between the first side margin and the second side margin remaining substantially constant throughout most of the length of the outer cover, a thickness of the body pillow in the untwisted condition between the inner midline and the outer midline tapering from the second end of the outer cover to the first end of the outer cover.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. The body pillow of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein first and second inner pillows are disposed inside of the outer cover, the first inner pillow extending from the first end toward the circumferential band, the second inner pillow extending from the second end toward the circumferential band.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text><b>21</b>. The body pillow of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00020">claim 20</claim-ref>, wherein the first inner pillow has a first end disposed adjacent the first end of the outer cover and a second end disposed near the circumferential band, the first inner pillow tapering in thickness from the second end of the first inner pillow to the first end of the first inner pillow.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text><b>22</b>. The body pillow of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00020">claim 20</claim-ref>, wherein the second inner pillow has a first end disposed near the circumferential band and a second end disposed adjacent the second end of the outer cover, the second inner pillow tapering in thickness from the second end of the second inner pillow to the first end of the second inner pillow.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text><b>23</b>. The body pillow of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein first and second inner pillows are disposed inside of the outer cover, each of the first and second inner pillows being filled with expanded polystyrene microbeads.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024" num="00024">
<claim-text><b>24</b>. The body pillow of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein a cover of the first inner pillow and a cover of the second inner pillow are composed of a nonstretch fabric.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025" num="00025">
<claim-text><b>25</b>. The body pillow of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the outer cover has a first end disposed on the axis and a second end disposed on the axis to be remote from the first end, an end panel disposed at the second end to join the inner side to the outer side at the second end, the end panel formed of nonstretch fabric.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026" num="00026">
<claim-text><b>26</b>. The body pillow of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the nonstretch fabric is composed of modal and lyocell fibers.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027" num="00027">
<claim-text><b>27</b>. The body pillow of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the stretch fabric is nylon/spandex.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028" num="00028">
<claim-text><b>28</b>. A method of using a body pillow to enhance the comfort of a pregnant woman during a first time and during a second time spaced from the first time, the method including the steps of:
<claim-text>providing an elongate body pillow to have a first end on an axis, a second end on the axis to be remote from the first end, and a circumferential band disposed around the axis and being made of a stretch fabric, the circumferential band spaced from the first end and the second end, the circumferential band being part of an outer cover of the body pillow, the body pillow further having a first inner pillow disposed inside the outer cover between the first end and the circumferential band and a second inner pillow disposed inside of the outer cover between the second end and the circumferential band;</claim-text>
<claim-text>at the first time, using the body pillow in an untwisted configuration;</claim-text>
<claim-text>at the second time, helically twisting the pillow at the circumferential band to a twisted configuration, thereby increasing the spacing between the first and second inner pillows and/or increasing a firmness of the first and second inner pillows; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>at the second time, using the body pillow in the twisted configuration.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029" num="00029">
<claim-text><b>29</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00028">claim 28</claim-ref>, wherein the body pillow has an inner side, a majority of which is composed of a stretch fabric, and an outer side, a majority of which is composed of a nonstretch fabric, said step of helically twisting comprising twisting the body pillow about 360 degrees around the axis.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
