<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225588A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225588</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18155371</doc-number>
<date>20230302</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>10-2022-0006185</doc-number>
<date>20220114</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>005</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>00105</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>0057</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e61">DETACHABLE ENDOSCOPE FOR THE DUODENUM</invention-title>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>TAEWOONG MEDICAL CO., LTD.</orgname>
<address>
<city>Gimpo-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>PARK</last-name>
<first-name>Sung Hwan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Seoul</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="01" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>JI</last-name>
<first-name>Hyun Soo</first-name>
<address>
<city>Seoul</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A detachable endoscope for a duodenum including an insertion unit whose one end is intended to be inserted into a body, and which is provided with a force applying module pivotably disposed on the one end; an operation unit coupled to another end of the insertion unit, and operating the one end of the insertion unit to perform a bending motion with use of an operation module; and a detachment unit including a first detachment module disposed within the operation unit, and a second detachment module disposed within the insertion unit and detachably coupled to the first detachment module.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="68.66mm" wi="147.15mm" file="US20230225588A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="83.23mm" wi="149.18mm" file="US20230225588A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="189.57mm" wi="144.27mm" file="US20230225588A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="202.61mm" wi="157.31mm" file="US20230225588A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="158.33mm" wi="159.00mm" file="US20230225588A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="93.13mm" wi="154.09mm" file="US20230225588A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="215.82mm" wi="157.73mm" file="US20230225588A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="91.44mm" wi="158.67mm" file="US20230225588A1-20230720-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="114.81mm" wi="154.77mm" file="US20230225588A1-20230720-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present application claims priority to Korean Patent Application No. 10-2022-0006185, filed Jan. 14, 2022, the entire contents of which is incorporated herein for all purposes by this reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">Field of the Invention</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates to a device, and more particularly to a detachable endoscope for the duodenum.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">Background Art</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">In general, a medical procedure using an endoscope is to insert an endoscope equipped with a camera and a medical procedure tool through a small hole without making a large incision in the body of a patient, and then proceed with the procedure while observing the affected part of the patient through the image taken by the endoscope in the body. In particular, the endoscopic procedure starting from laparoscopic surgery has advantages in that the incision region is smaller than that of laparotomy, so the scar region is also small, and there is little bleeding, which leads to the quick patient recovery after the procedure.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The conventional endoscopes are integrally constituted with an insertion part intended to be inserted into the human body and an operation part that operates the insertion part, and a plurality of channels and guides are embedded through the inside of each part. In particular, an image sensing device such as an expensive CCD is provided at the front end of the insertion part inserted into the body. Therefore, it is difficult to separate only the insertion part from the operation part and replace it with a new one. To overcome this problem, in line with the trend of strengthening the sanitary function of medical endoscopes, various types of detachable endoscopes are being used in which an insertion part intended to be inserted into the body and an operation part for operating the insertion part are connected to each other when being used, or separated from each other when being stored.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">However, in the conventional detachable endoscope having a structure in which the operation part and the insertion part are detachably coupled by the medium of the connection part, in order to separate the insertion part and the operation part from each other by releasing the engagement in the connection part after the endoscopic procedure, a pressing member such as a button must be provided in the connection part, and the engagement connection in the connection part must be released using this pressing member. Therefore, the structure of the connection part that detachably connects the operation part and the insertion part to each other becomes very complicated, and the manufacturing cost of the endoscope increases.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Further, the overall number of components provided in the connection part of the endoscope increases due to the engagement release button and accessory structures associated therewith additionally provided in the connection part. In the case of a mechanical malfunction of the engagement release button, the endoscope for a medical procedure cannot be used, while the cost required to maintain/repair the connection part increases.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">A technical problem to be addressed by the present disclosure is to provide a detachable endoscope that prevents internal contamination of the endoscope and allows easy replacement and cleaning of a part intended to be inserted into the human body by configuring the detachable endoscope such that the part is detachable.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Technical drawbacks, which the present disclosure is to address, are limited to the aforementioned ones, and unmentioned or other technical drawbacks may be clearly appreciated from the following detailed description by a person having ordinary skill in the art to which the present disclosure belongs.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">To accomplish the above-described technical objects, a detachable endoscope for a duodenum according to an example of this disclosure may include an insertion unit whose one end is intended to be inserted into a body, and which is provided with a force applying module pivotably disposed on the one end; an operation unit coupled to another end of the insertion unit, and operating the one end of the insertion unit to perform a bending motion with use of an operation module; and a detachment unit including a first detachment module disposed within the operation unit, and a second detachment module disposed within the insertion unit and detachably coupled to the first detachment module.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">According to an example of this disclosure, the first detachment module may include a first module body, and a first intermediate connection part and a second intermediate connection part disposed within the first module body and receiving a force from the operation module, and the second detachment module may include a second module body, and a first insertion end connection part and a second insertion end connection part disposed within the second module body, detachably connected to the first intermediate connection part, and respectively connected to a first operation wire and a second operation wire transferring a force applied by the operation module to one end of the insertion module or the force applying module.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">According to an example of this disclosure, the first intermediate connection part may be provided in two pairs, which are spaced apart from each other along the inner circumference of the first module body, and the second intermediate connection part may extend through the center of the two pairs of the first intermediate connection parts, and the first insertion end connection part may be provided in two pairs corresponding to the first intermediate connection parts, and the two pairs of the first insertion end connection parts may be spaced apart from each other along the inner circumference of the second module body, and the second insertion end connection part may extend through the center of the two pairs of the first insertion end connection parts.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">According to an example of this disclosure, each of the first intermediate connection part and the second intermediate connection part may be provided with an insertion groove formed concavely inward in a longitudinal direction at its one end, and each of the first insertion end connection part and the second insertion end connection part may be provided with an engaging member formed protrudingly outward in a longitudinal direction from its one end and detachably inserted into and coupled to the insertion groove.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">According to an example of this disclosure, the engaging member may be formed protrudingly in a length shorter than the concave depth of the insertion groove.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">According to an example of this disclosure, the second insertion end connection part may be connected to the force applying module by a medium of the operation wire, and when the first detachment module and the second detachment module are coupled to each other, the force applying module may be operated to rotate about a rotational axle perpendicular to the longitudinal direction of the insertion unit with use of the operation module.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">According to an example of this disclosure, the second insertion end connection part may be provided with a curved connection member extending toward the force applying module and at least partially curved with respect to the longitudinal direction of the second insertion end connection part.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In the detachable endoscope according to the embodiments of the present disclosure, the insertion unit intended to be inserted into the human body is configured to be detachable from the operation unit, so that the internal contamination of the endoscope can be prevented and parts can be easily replaced and cleaned. Additionally, in the course of coupling, without the use of a separate engaging or locking structure, it is possible to realize simple and easy assembly and disassembly of the insertion unit.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The effects of the present disclosure are not limited to the aforementioned effects, but should be understood as including all effects that can be inferred from the configuration provided by the description or claims of the present application.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a perspective view showing a detachable endoscope according to an embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a front view showing one end of an operation unit provided in a detachable endoscope according to an embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a perspective view showing a state before the coupling of a first detachment module and a second detachment module provided in a detachment unit according to an embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is a perspective view showing a state in which a first detachment module and a second detachment module provided in a detachment unit according to an embodiment of the present disclosure are coupled to each other.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is a perspective view showing the inside of the first detachment module and the second detachment module in a state before they are coupled in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is a perspective view showing the inside of the first detachment module and the second detachment module in a coupled state of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>A</figref> is a perspective view showing a state before the intermediate connection part and the insertion end connection part provided in the detachable endoscope according to an embodiment of the present disclosure are coupled to each other. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>7</b>B and <b>7</b>C</figref> are perspective views showing states before the coupling of the intermediate connection part and the insertion end connection part is completed. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>D</figref> is a perspective view showing a state in which the intermediate connection part and the insertion end connection part are coupled.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> is a plan view showing an insertion unit according to an embodiment of the present disclosure. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> includes an enlarged perspective view showing the insertion end of the insertion unit.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Hereinafter, embodiments of the present disclosure will be described with reference to the accompanying drawings. However, the disclosure can be embodied in various different forms, and the scope of the disclosure should not be construed as being limited to the embodiments described herein. In the drawings, in order to describe clearly the disclosure, parts not related to the description are omitted, and like reference signs will be given to like constitutional elements throughout the specification.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">As used herein, &#x201c;connecting(or combining)&#x201d; a part with another part (or &#x201c;bring&#x201d; a part into contact or touch with another part) may refer to a case where they are &#x201c;indirectly connected&#x201d; to each other with other element intervening therebetween, as well as a case where they are &#x201c;directly connected&#x201d;. Further, when a part &#x201c;includes(or comprises)&#x201d; a component, it means not that the part excludes other component, but instead that the part may further include other component unless expressly stated to the contrary.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The terms used herein are used to merely describe specific embodiments, but are not intended to limit the disclosure. Singular expressions may include the meaning of plural expressions unless the context clearly indicates otherwise. The terms such as &#x201c;include (or comprise)&#x201d;, &#x201c;have (or be provided with)&#x201d;, and the like are intended to indicate that features, numbers, steps, operations, components, parts, or combinations thereof written in the following description exist, and thus should not be understood as that the possibility of existence or addition of one or more different features, numbers, steps, operations, components, parts, or combinations thereof is excluded in advance.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Hereinafter, embodiments of this disclosure will be described in detail with reference to the accompanying drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a perspective view showing a detachable endoscope according to an embodiment of the present disclosure. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a front view showing one end of an operation unit provided in a detachable endoscope according to an embodiment of the present disclosure. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a perspective view showing a state before the coupling of a first detachment module and a second detachment module provided in a detachment unit according to an embodiment of the present disclosure. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is a perspective view showing a state in which a first detachment module and a second detachment module provided in a detachment unit according to an embodiment of the present disclosure are coupled to each other.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> to <b>4</b></figref>, a detachable endoscope <b>10</b> may be a device for inspecting and performing medical procedures on organs inside a body. Here, the target part for the inspection and medical procedure may be, for example, the duodenum.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The detachable endoscope <b>10</b> may include an operation unit <b>100</b>, an insertion unit <b>200</b>, and a detachment unit <b>300</b>. In addition, the detachable endoscope <b>10</b> may further include a joint unit (not shown) electrically connected to an endoscope control and management system (not shown).</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The operation unit <b>100</b> is a part that the user manipulates to control the operation of the insertion unit <b>200</b>, and may include an operation module H. In this case, the operation module H may include a first operation part H<b>10</b>, a second operation part H<b>20</b>, and a third operation part H<b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">To one end (hereinafter, a first coupling end) of the operation unit <b>100</b>, the detachable insertion unit <b>200</b> can be selectively connected. In the state in which the insertion unit <b>200</b> is coupled to the operation unit <b>100</b>, the user can rotate the first operation part H<b>10</b> in left and right directions, so that the front end (hereinafter, referred to as an insertion end) of the insertion unit <b>200</b> can be caused to perform a bending motion in up and down directions, or can rotate the second operation part H<b>20</b> in left and right directions, so that the aforementioned front end can be caused to perform a bending motion in left and right directions. Additionally, the user can control the pivoting of a force applying module <b>400</b> to be described later by rotating the third operation part H<b>30</b> in one direction.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The first operation part H<b>10</b> may be provided with a lower sprocket (not shown) and a lower chain (not shown) meshed therewith, and the second operation part H<b>20</b> may be provided with an upper sprocket (not shown) and an upper chain (not shown) meshed therewith. In this case, when the first operation part H<b>10</b> and/or the second operation part H<b>20</b> are/is rotated by the user's manipulation, the lower sprocket and/or the upper sprocket rotate(s), and this rotational motion can be converted into reciprocating rectilinear motion by the lower chain and/or the upper chain.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The lower chain and the upper chain may be connected to the inside of the insertion unit <b>200</b> by the medium of a first, second, third and fourth connection wires <b>101</b>, <b>102</b>, <b>103</b> and <b>104</b> and a first, second, third and fourth operation wires <b>201</b>, <b>202</b>, <b>203</b> and <b>204</b>, which will be described later. In this case, by the reciprocating rectilinear motion of the upper chain and/or the lower chain, the first, second, third, and fourth connection wires <b>101</b>, <b>102</b>, <b>103</b>, <b>104</b> and the first, second, third, and fourth operation wires <b>201</b>, <b>202</b>, <b>203</b>, <b>204</b> are selectively linearly moved, so that the insertion end of the insertion unit <b>200</b> connected to the first, second, third, and fourth operation wires <b>201</b>, <b>202</b>, <b>203</b>, <b>204</b> can be bent in the up and down directions or in the left and right directions. At this time, the user can adjust the bending amount of the insertion end by appropriately changing the rotation angle of the first operation part H<b>10</b> and/or the second operation part H<b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">In this case, the rotation of the lower sprocket and the upper sprocket may be made by the manual rotational manipulation of the user who holds the first operation parts H<b>10</b> and the second operation part H<b>20</b> provided in the operation module H. However, the present disclosure is not limited to this, but it may also be constituted by connecting a rotational axle connected to each of the lower sprocket and the upper sprocket with a driving means such as an electric motor, and using a separate remote control means for controlling the driving means.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The third operation part H<b>30</b> may be connected to a lifting unit (not shown) disposed inside the operation unit <b>100</b>. In this case, the lifting unit may be operated, as an embodiment, in a hydraulic manner. In this case, the lifting unit may include a hydraulic pressure supply part (not shown) and a linear movement shaft (not shown). In this case, the hydraulic pressure supply part may supply hydraulic pressure to the linear movement shaft connected to an intermediate connection member <b>105</b> to be described later based on the manipulation of the third operation part H<b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">At this time, when the third operation part H<b>30</b> is rotated in one of the left and right directions (hereinafter, referred to as the operation direction) by the user in a state in which the insertion unit <b>200</b> is coupled to the operation unit <b>100</b>, the linear movement shaft can move backward (&#x2212;Y axis direction) due to the hydraulic pressure supplied by the hydraulic pressure supply part.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Accordingly, the intermediate connection member <b>105</b> and the second intermediate connection body <b>315</b>, and the second insertion end connection body <b>345</b> coupled thereto and the fifth operation wire <b>205</b> move in the direction of being pulled toward the operation unit <b>100</b> (hereinafter, referred to as the force applying direction) (e.g., &#x2212;Y axis direction), so that force can be applied to the force applying module <b>400</b> connected to the fifth operation wire <b>205</b> in the force applying direction (&#x2212;Y axis direction). Accordingly, the force applying module <b>400</b> can pivot in the first rotation direction R<b>1</b> toward the operation unit <b>100</b> around the pivot axis C.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Meanwhile, the present disclosure is not limited to the above-described embodiment, but the lifting unit may also rotate the force applying module <b>400</b> by being operated in a manner other than the hydraulic manner. However, for the convenience of description, hereinafter, an embodiment in which the lifting unit operates in a hydraulic manner will be mainly described.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Meanwhile, the third operation part H<b>30</b> may be provided with an elastic part (not shown). This elastic part may be compressed and deformed as the third operation part H<b>30</b> is rotated in the operation direction by the user. Thereafter, by generating an elastic restoring force in the opposite direction to the operation direction and returning the third operation part H<b>30</b> to its original position when the force applied to the third operation unit H<b>30</b> is removed, the hydraulic pressure applied to the linear movement shaft is removed, so that the second intermediate connection part, the second insertion end connection part, and the fifth operation wire <b>205</b> can move back in an opposite direction (Y axis direction) to the force applying direction. Accordingly, the force applying module <b>400</b> can rotate in the second rotation direction R<b>2</b> opposite to the first rotation direction R<b>1</b>, and can return to the original position.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">A part (i.e., the insertion end) of the insertion unit <b>200</b> may be inserted into the body during an endoscopic procedure. In this case, the insertion end of the insertion unit <b>200</b> may be an end among both ends of the insertion unit <b>200</b>, which is opposite to the end coupled to the operation unit <b>100</b> (hereinafter, referred to as a second coupling end). At the insertion end, an illuminating and photographing unit may be provided which has a light source for illuminating the inside of the body, and an image sensor for photographing the inside of the body.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The aforementioned force applying module <b>400</b> may be disposed at the insertion end of the insertion unit <b>200</b>. Specifically, the force applying module <b>400</b> may be disposed in the opening provided at the aforementioned insertion end. In this case, the force applying module <b>400</b> may be installed to be pivotable around a connection axis C perpendicular to the longitudinal direction (Y axis direction) of the insertion unit <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">During an endoscopic procedure, a separate procedure equipment may be inserted into the insertion unit <b>200</b> through an insertion structure for connection provided in the detachable endoscope <b>10</b>. This procedure equipment may pass through the inner passage (not shown) of the insertion unit <b>200</b>, and moves to the outside of the insertion end through the above-mentioned opening to perform a medical procedure on the duodenum or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">In this case, the force applying module <b>400</b> may apply force to the procedure equipment, which has been moved to the outside of the insertion end through the opening, to bend the procedure equipment toward a position where the medical procedure is required.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">For example, during an endoscopic procedure, by rotating the force applying module <b>400</b> in the first rotation direction R<b>1</b> using the third operation unit H<b>30</b>, the procedure equipment can be bent in a direction corresponding to the first rotation direction R<b>1</b>. In the case where the endoscopic procedure is completed or the procedure equipment needs to be replaced, by removing the force applied to the third operation part H<b>30</b> and returning the force applying module <b>400</b> to its original position, it is possible to remove the force applied to the procedure equipment and return it to the state before the bending.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">In an example, the insertion unit <b>200</b> may have an elongate cylindrical shape with a hollow formed therein. At least this portion of the insertion unit <b>200</b> may be formed with a flexible material, so that the bending direction can be adjusted by the operation unit <b>100</b> as described above. For example, a cover forming the outer surface of the insertion unit <b>200</b> may be formed with a flexible tube material such as a resin composition.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Meanwhile, the operation unit <b>100</b> may include a manipulation switch and a manipulation button for injecting or discharging liquid and gas used during an endoscopic procedure. A part (e.g., the second coupling end or its periphery) of the insertion unit <b>200</b> detachably coupled with the first coupling end of the operation unit <b>100</b> via the detachment unit <b>300</b> may be provided with an entrance through which a medical procedure tool such as an endoscopic procedure tool having a clip is protruded from or retracted into the insertion unit <b>200</b>, and with a cap for opening and closing the entrance.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">As exemplarily shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b> to <b>4</b></figref>, a first support cover K<b>10</b> may be provided at the first coupling end of the operation unit <b>100</b>. In this case, an air supply channel C<b>30</b> for supplying air, a water supply channel C<b>20</b> for supplying water, and a terminal C<b>40</b> electrically connected to an illuminating and photographing part provided at the above-described insertion end may be formed to pass through the first support cover K<b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The detachment unit <b>300</b> may detachably connect the operation unit <b>100</b> and the insertion unit <b>200</b>. In this case, the detachment unit <b>300</b> may include a first detachment module <b>300</b><i>a </i>and a second detachment module <b>300</b><i>b </i>that are detachably coupled to each other. The operation unit <b>100</b> and the insertion unit <b>200</b> may be connected or separated by the coupling or decoupling of the first detachment module <b>300</b><i>a </i>and the second detachment module <b>300</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">The first detachment module <b>300</b><i>a </i>may be arranged to be inserted into the operation unit <b>100</b>, and may include a first module body <b>310</b>, a first intermediate connection part and a second intermediate connection part. And the second detachment module <b>300</b><i>b </i>may be arranged to be inserted into the insertion unit <b>200</b>, and may be provided with a second module body <b>330</b>, a first insertion end connection part, and a second insertion end connection part.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">In this case, although reference numerals are not indicated in the drawings, for the convenience of description, hereinafter, the first intermediate connection part will be denoted by reference number <b>320</b>, and the second intermediate connection part will be denoted by reference number <b>320</b>&#x2032;. Additionally, the first insertion end connection part will be denoted by reference number <b>340</b>, and the second insertion end connection part will be denoted by reference number <b>340</b>&#x2032;.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">The first module body <b>310</b> may be a housing in which a first middle hollow and a second middle hollow are formed penetrating both ends along the longitudinal direction (Y axis direction). These first and second middle hollows may be arranged on the same line to be communicated with each other, along the through holes for connection <b>111</b>, <b>112</b>, <b>113</b>, <b>114</b>, and <b>115</b> (in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>) provided in the first support cover K<b>10</b> and the longitudinal direction (Y axis direction).</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">The first intermediate connection part <b>320</b> may connect the operation module H and the first insertion end connection part <b>340</b> to be described later by the medium of the first, second, third, and fourth connection wires <b>101</b>, <b>102</b>, <b>103</b>, and <b>104</b>. At this time, the first intermediate connection part <b>320</b> may be provided with two pairs of first intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b>, and first connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b> respectively provided thereto.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">In an example, the first intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b> may be bars having an elongate cylindrical shape. The first intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b> may be inserted penetrating the first middle hollow of the first module body <b>310</b>. At this time, both ends of the first intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b> may be disposed at least partially outside the first module body <b>310</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">The first connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b> may be detachably connected to first engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, and <b>334</b> to be described later. The first connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b> may be disposed at one ends of the first intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b>, and these one ends of the first intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b> may be ends facing the insertion unit <b>200</b>. The other ends of the first intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b> may be connected to one ends of the first, second, third, and fourth connection wires <b>101</b>, <b>102</b>, <b>103</b>, and <b>104</b>, and at this time, the other ends of the first, second, third, and fourth connection wires <b>101</b>, <b>102</b>, <b>103</b>, and <b>104</b> may be connected to the lower chain or the upper chain provided in the first operation part H<b>10</b> or the second operation part H<b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">In this case, as the user manipulates the first operation part H<b>10</b> or the second operation part H<b>20</b>, the rotational motion of the lower sprocket or the upper sprocket can be converted into reciprocating rectilinear motion by the lower chain or upper chain, and subsequently, the first, second, third, and fourth connection wires <b>101</b>, <b>102</b>, <b>103</b>, and <b>104</b> connected to the lower chain or the upper chain can perform reciprocating rectilinear motion. Accordingly, the first intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b> connected to the first, second, third and fourth connection wires <b>101</b>, <b>102</b>, <b>103</b>, and <b>104</b>, and the first connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b> can perform reciprocating rectilinear motion along a direction parallel to the longitudinal direction (Y axis direction).</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">The first connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b> may be formed with a larger outer diameter than the outer diameter of the first intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b>. At this time, elastic members, which the intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b> are inserted penetrating, may be disposed between the first connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b> and the first, second, third, and fourth connection wires <b>101</b>, <b>102</b>, <b>103</b>, and <b>104</b>. As the first intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b> are pressed by the first insertion end connection part <b>340</b> during the coupling process, these elastic members are compressed and deformed, and can generate an elastic restoring force for returning the first intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b> to their original positions. The elastic member may be constituted with, for example, a coil spring.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">The first coupling ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b> may be provided with first insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, and <b>324</b> into which the first engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, and <b>334</b> are inserted when the insertion unit <b>200</b> and the operation unit <b>100</b> are coupled to each other, and first guide projections T<b>1</b>, T<b>2</b>, T<b>3</b>, and T<b>4</b> for guiding rotation of the first intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">The first insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, and <b>324</b> may be formed concavely in the longitudinal direction (e.g., &#x2212;Y axis direction) inward from the first connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b>. The first insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, and <b>324</b> may be provided with penetration parts N formed to penetrate through the first connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b> in a direction (X axis direction) perpendicular to the longitudinal direction (Y axis direction). The first insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, and <b>324</b> may be partially communicated with the outside through the penetration parts N. Additionally, the first engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, and <b>334</b> can be in an engaged state and secured in the first insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, and <b>324</b> by the penetration parts N.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">The first guide projections T<b>1</b>, T<b>2</b>, T<b>3</b>, and T<b>4</b> can guide the rotational motion of the first intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b>. The first guide projections T<b>1</b>, T<b>2</b>, T<b>3</b>, and T<b>4</b> may be formed to protrude toward the outside in the radial direction from the first connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b> of the first intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">In the case where after the insertion of the first engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, and <b>334</b> into the first insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, and <b>324</b>, the first insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b> press the first connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b>, or the second insertion end connection part <b>340</b>&#x2032; is pulled and moved backward (&#x2212;Y axis direction) by the manipulation of the operation module H, the first guide projections T<b>1</b>, T<b>2</b>, T<b>3</b>, and T<b>4</b> can move along the first guide slits G<b>1</b>, G<b>2</b>, G<b>3</b>, and G<b>4</b> formed in the first module body <b>310</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">The first guide slits G<b>1</b>, G<b>2</b>, G<b>3</b>, and G<b>4</b> may include a curved line part that is curved and extended from one side of the first module body <b>310</b> to the other side thereof, and a straight line part connected to this curved line part and extending backward (&#x2212;Y axis direction) parallel to the longitudinal direction of the first intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">In the case where the first insertion end connection part <b>340</b> moves backward (&#x2212;Y axis direction), the first guide projections T<b>1</b>, T<b>2</b>, T<b>3</b>, and T<b>4</b> first rotate along the curved line part, and thereby the first intermediate connection body <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b> can be rotated and simultaneously guided to move backward (&#x2212;Y axis direction) by the first guide projection T<b>1</b>, T<b>2</b>, T<b>3</b>, and T<b>4</b>. Thereafter, as the first insertion end connection part <b>340</b> moves further backward (&#x2212;Y axis direction), the guide projections T<b>1</b>, T<b>2</b>, T<b>3</b>, and T<b>4</b> passing through the curved line part move linearly along the straight line part, and accordingly, the first engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, and <b>334</b> are engaged inside the first insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, and <b>324</b>, and thereby the first intermediate connection part <b>320</b> and the second insertion end connection part <b>340</b>&#x2032; are coupled so that they are not separated during the endoscopic procedure, and can operate integrally by manipulating the operation module H.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">The second intermediate connection part <b>320</b>&#x2032; may connect the operation module H and the force applying module <b>400</b> disposed at the insertion end by the medium of the intermediate connection member <b>105</b>. In this case, the second intermediate connection part <b>320</b>&#x2032; may be provided with one second intermediate connection body <b>315</b> and a second connection end E<b>5</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">The second intermediate connection body <b>315</b> may be inserted penetrating the second middle hollow spaced apart from the first middle hollow. At this time, both ends of the second intermediate connection body <b>315</b> may be disposed at least partially outside the first module body <b>310</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">The second connection end E<b>5</b> may be detachably connected to the second engaging member <b>335</b> to be described later. The second connection end E<b>5</b> may be disposed at one end of the second intermediate connection body <b>315</b>, and the intermediate connection member <b>105</b> may be provided at the other end of the second intermediate connection body <b>315</b>. In this case, the intermediate connection member <b>105</b> may be connected to the third operation part H<b>30</b> by the medium of the lifting unit.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">As exemplarily shown in the drawings, the intermediate connection member <b>105</b> may be formed to protrude from the second intermediate connection body <b>315</b> toward the rear (&#x2212;Y axis direction) in parallel with the longitudinal direction (Y axis direction). In this case, the rear end of the intermediate connection member <b>105</b> may be provided with a protrusion for engagement to engage with the linear movement shaft of the lifting unit. In this case, after the intermediate connection member <b>105</b> is inserted into an engagement groove (not shown) provided at the front end of the linear movement shaft, the engagement protrusion can be engaged and secured in the engagement groove. By this, the intermediate connection member <b>105</b> and the second intermediate connection body <b>315</b> can be coupled to the lifting unit. Meanwhile, the present disclosure is not limited to this, but as another embodiment, the intermediate connection member <b>105</b> may be connected to the linear movement shaft by the medium of a connection wire (not shown).</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">In this case, as the user manipulates the third operation part H<b>30</b> in the operation direction, the linear movement shaft and the intermediate connection member <b>105</b> connected thereto can perform a rectilinear motion in the force applying direction (&#x2212;Y axis direction) by the hydraulic pressure supplied from the hydraulic pressure supply part. At the same time, the second intermediate connection body <b>315</b> and the second connection end E<b>5</b> may perform a rectilinear motion in the force applying direction (&#x2212;Y axis direction).</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">A second insertion groove <b>325</b> and a second guide projection T<b>5</b> may be formed at the second connection end E<b>5</b>, and the second guide projection T<b>5</b> may move along the second guide slit G<b>5</b> provided in the first module body <b>310</b> and may guide the movement of the second intermediate connection body <b>315</b>. Other specific features of the second intermediate connection part <b>320</b>&#x2032; and the coupling method with the second insertion end connection part <b>340</b>&#x2032; are the same as or similar to those of the above-described first intermediate connection part <b>320</b>, so redundant descriptions thereof will be omitted.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">As described above, the first intermediate connection part <b>320</b> may include two pairs of first intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b>. In this case, for the convenience of description, the two pairs of first intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b> will be referred to as the first-first intermediate connection body <b>311</b>, the first-second intermediate connection body <b>312</b>, the first-third intermediate connection body <b>313</b>, and the first-fourth intermediate connection body <b>314</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">In this case, two pairs of first middle hollows may be formed in the first module body <b>310</b>, and the first-first, first-second, first-third, and first-fourth intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b> may be inserted penetrating them, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">The first-first, first-second, first-third, and first-fourth intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b> may be arranged symmetrically with each other, within the first module body <b>310</b>, in the width direction (X axis direction) and/or in the height direction (Z axis direction). Specifically, the first-first intermediate connection body <b>311</b> may be arranged symmetrically with the first-second intermediate connection body <b>312</b> in the width direction (X axis direction). At this time, the first-first intermediate connection body <b>311</b> may be arranged symmetrically with the first-third intermediate connection body <b>313</b> in the height direction (Z axis direction), and the first-third intermediate connection body <b>313</b> may be arranged symmetrically with the first-fourth intermediate connection body <b>314</b> in the width direction (X axis direction). Accordingly, the first-first intermediate connection body <b>311</b> and the first-second intermediate connection body <b>312</b> can be arranged side by side in a pair on the upper side inside the first module body <b>310</b>, and the first-third intermediate connection body <b>313</b> and the first-fourth intermediate connection body <b>314</b> can be arranged side by side in a pair on the lower side inside the first module body <b>310</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">In this case, the second middle hollow may extend beyond the inner region of the first module body <b>310</b>, defined by the first-first, first-second, first-third, and first-fourth intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b>, and as a result, the second intermediate connection part <b>320</b>&#x2032; may be surrounded by the first-first, first-second, first-third, and first-four intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b> to be located in the center.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">The connection ends of the first and second intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, <b>314</b>, and <b>315</b>, that is, the first-first connection end E<b>1</b>, the first-second connection end E<b>2</b>, and the first-third connection end E<b>3</b>, the first-fourth connection end E<b>4</b>, and the second connection end E<b>5</b> may be arranged to protrude outward from the first module body <b>310</b> toward the insertion unit <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">Additionally, the first connection wire <b>101</b>, the second connection wire <b>102</b>, the third connection wire <b>103</b>, and the fourth connection wire <b>104</b> may be connected to the other ends of the first intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b>, respectively, which are opposite to the first connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b>. And the above-described intermediate connection member <b>105</b> may be provided at the other end of the second intermediate connection body <b>315</b> opposite to the second connection end E<b>5</b>, so that the other ends can be connected to the lifting unit. In this case, each of the first intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, and <b>314</b> may be disposed in the first module body <b>310</b> in a state of being inserted penetrating the elastic member in the form of a coil spring.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">As described above, the second detachment module <b>300</b><i>b </i>may be provided with the second module body <b>330</b>, the first insertion end connection part <b>340</b>, and the second insertion end connection part <b>340</b>&#x2032;.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">The second module body <b>330</b> may be a housing in which a first insertion end hollow and a second insertion end hollow penetrating both ends along a longitudinal direction (Y axis direction) are formed.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">The first insertion end connection part <b>340</b> can transfer the force applied by the user's manipulation of the operation module H to the insertion end by the medium of the first, second, third, and fourth operation wires <b>201</b>, <b>202</b>, <b>203</b>, and <b>204</b>, so that the insertion end of the insertion unit <b>200</b> can perform a bending motion. In this case, the first insertion end connection part <b>340</b> may include two pairs of first insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b>, which are provided with the first engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, and <b>334</b>, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">The first insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b> may be bars having an elongate cylindrical shape in an example. The first insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b> may be inserted penetrating the first insertion end hollow of the second module body <b>330</b>. In this case, both ends of the first insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b> may be arranged protruding at least partially to the outside of the second module body <b>330</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">Each of the first insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b> may have a rack gear part L on its one surface. Each of the rack gear parts L may be disposed on a surface among surfaces of the first insertion end connection body <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, or <b>344</b>, which faces the center of the second module body <b>330</b>. And, the rack gear parts L may extend along the longitudinal direction (Y axis direction) of the first insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">The first engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, and <b>334</b> can be inserted into the aforementioned first insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, and <b>324</b> of the first connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, and E<b>4</b>, and can be detachably coupled thereto.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">The first engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, and <b>334</b> may be disposed at one ends of the first insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b>, and the one ends of the first insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b> may be ends facing the operation unit <b>100</b>. In this case, one ends of the first, second, third, and fourth operation wires <b>201</b>, <b>202</b>, <b>203</b>, and <b>204</b> can be connected to the other ends of the first insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b>, and the other ends of the first, second, third, and fourth operation wires <b>201</b>, <b>202</b>, <b>203</b>, and <b>204</b> can be connected to the inside of the insertion ends.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">At this time, the first engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, and <b>334</b> may be formed in a protruding length similar to the depth of the concaves inward in the longitudinal direction of the first insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, and <b>324</b>, preferably in a shorter protruding length. Accordingly, when the first engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, and <b>334</b> are inserted into the first insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, and <b>324</b>, a predetermined clearance may exist between the first engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, and <b>334</b> and the first insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, and <b>324</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">The second insertion end connection part <b>340</b>&#x2032; can transfer the force applied by the user manipulating the third operation part H<b>30</b> by the medium of the fifth operation wire <b>205</b> to the force applying module <b>400</b>, so that the force applying module <b>400</b> can rotate. In this case, the second insertion end connection part <b>340</b>&#x2032; may include one second insertion end connection body <b>345</b>, a curved connection member <b>346</b>, and a second engaging member <b>335</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">The second insertion end connection body <b>345</b> may be inserted penetrating the second insertion end hollow spaced apart from the first insertion end hollow. In this case, both ends of the second insertion end connection body <b>345</b> may be disposed at least partially outside the second module body <b>330</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">The curved connection member <b>346</b> may be disposed between the second insertion end connection body <b>345</b> and the force applying module <b>400</b>, and may have a hollow formed therein for accommodating the operation wire <b>205</b>. The operation wire <b>205</b> may be disposed in the inner hollow of the curved connection member <b>346</b>, and extend toward the force applying module <b>400</b> from the second insertion end connection body <b>345</b>. In this case, one end of the operation wire <b>205</b> can be connected to the second insertion end connection body <b>345</b>, and the other end of the operation wire <b>205</b> can be connected to the force applying module <b>400</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">The curved connection member <b>346</b> may have a curved part curved with respect to the longitudinal direction (Y axis direction) of the second insertion end connection part <b>340</b>&#x2032;. Through this curved part, the disposal state such as the bending direction, bending degree, and the like of the operation wire <b>205</b> disposed inside the inner hollow of the curved connection member <b>346</b> can be adjusted.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">Specifically, the second operation wire <b>205</b> may have one end connected to the second insertion end connection body <b>345</b> and the other end extending toward the insertion end. In this case, a part between the aforementioned one end and the other end of the second operation wire <b>205</b> can be bent and extended along the curved connection member <b>346</b>. Accordingly, among the entire length of the second operation wire <b>205</b>, the length extending past the curved connection member <b>346</b> may be disposed extending toward the insertion end inside the insertion unit <b>200</b> in the longitudinal direction (Y axis direction) to pass through the center of the insertion unit <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">Additionally, the second insertion end connection part <b>340</b>&#x2032; can be placed without affecting the second insertion end connection part <b>340</b>&#x2032; disposed in a straight line within the limited space inside the second module body <b>330</b> through the curved connection member <b>346</b>, so that the space utilization can be improved.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">The second engaging member <b>335</b> may be inserted into the second insertion groove <b>325</b> of the second connection end E<b>5</b> and detachably coupled thereto. The second engaging member <b>335</b> may be formed protruding outward in the longitudinal direction (&#x2212;Y axis direction) at the opposite end of the curved connection member <b>346</b> among both ends of the second insertion end connection body <b>345</b>. In this case, one end of the operation wire <b>205</b> can be connected to the other end of the second insertion end connection body <b>345</b>, and the other end of the fifth operation wire <b>205</b> can be connected to the force applying module <b>400</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">In this case, as the user manipulates the third operation part H<b>30</b> in the operation direction, the linear movement shaft and the intermediate connection member <b>105</b> connected thereto and the second intermediate connection body <b>315</b> can perform a rectilinear motion in the force applying direction (&#x2212;Y axis direction) by the hydraulic pressure supplied from the hydraulic pressure supply part.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">In this case, a second insertion groove <b>325</b> and a second guide projection T<b>5</b> can be formed at the second connection end E<b>5</b>, and the second guide projection T<b>5</b> can move along the second guide slit G<b>5</b> provided in the second module body <b>330</b>, and can guide the movement of the second intermediate connection body <b>315</b>. Other specific features of the second intermediate connection part <b>320</b>&#x2032; and the coupling method with the second insertion end connection part <b>340</b>&#x2032; and the operation manner after the coupling are the same as or similar to those of the above-described first intermediate connection part <b>320</b>, so redundant descriptions thereof will be omitted.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">As described above, the first insertion end connection part <b>340</b> may include two pairs of first insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b>. In this case, for the convenience of description, the two pairs of first insertion end connection bodies will be referred to as the first-first insertion end connection body <b>341</b>, the first-second insertion end connection body <b>342</b>, the first-third insertion end connection body <b>343</b>, and the first-fourth insertion end connection body <b>344</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">In this case, two pairs of first insertion end hollows may be formed in the second module body <b>330</b>, and the first-first, first-second, first-third, and first-fourth insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b> may be inserted penetrating these two pairs of first insertion end hollows, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">The first-first, first-second, first-third, and first-fourth insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b> may be arranged symmetrically with each other in the width direction (X axis direction) and/or the height direction (Z axis direction) in the second module body <b>330</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0098">Specifically, the first-first insertion end connection body <b>341</b> may be arranged symmetrically with the first-second insertion end connection body <b>342</b> in the width direction (X axis direction). Accordingly, the rack gear part L of the first-first insertion end connection body <b>341</b> and the rack gear part L of the first-second insertion end connection body <b>342</b> can be arranged to face each other.</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0099">Additionally, the first-first insertion end connection body <b>341</b> may be arranged symmetrically with the first-third insertion end connection body <b>343</b> in the height direction (Z axis direction), and the first-third insertion end connection body <b>343</b> may be arranged symmetrically with the first-fourth insertion end connection body <b>344</b> in the width direction (X axis direction). Accordingly, the third rack gear part L of the first-third insertion end connection body <b>343</b> and the fourth rack gear part L of the first-fourth insertion end connection body <b>344</b> may be arranged to face each other.</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0100">Accordingly, the first-first insertion end connection body <b>341</b> and the first-second insertion end connection body <b>342</b> can be arranged side by side in a pair on the upper side inside the second module body <b>330</b>, and the first-third insertion end connection body <b>343</b> and the first-fourth insertion end connection body <b>344</b> can be arranged side by side in a pair on the lower side inside the second module body <b>330</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0101">In this case, as described above, the second insertion end connection part <b>340</b>&#x2032; may be disposed in a region defined by being surrounded by the first-first, first-second, first-third, and first-fourth insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b> in the second module body <b>330</b>. In this case, the second insertion end connection body <b>345</b>, in one embodiment, can extend through the middle of the first-first, first-second, first-third, and first-fourth insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0102">In the above case, the second module body <b>330</b> may be provided with a pinion gear unit P. In this case, the pinion gear unit P may include a first pinion gear P<b>10</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>5</b> and <b>6</b></figref>), and a second pinion gear P<b>20</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>5</b> and <b>6</b></figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0103">The first pinion gear P<b>10</b> may be disposed between the first-first insertion end connection body <b>341</b> and the first-second insertion end connection body <b>342</b>, so that it can be meshed with the first rack gear part L of the first-first insertion end connection body <b>341</b> and the second rack gear part L of the first-second insertion end connection body <b>342</b> at the same time. In this meshed state, the first pinion gear P<b>10</b> may rotate around the first central axle part perpendicular to the longitudinal direction (Y axis direction) according to the user's manipulation of the operation module H.</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0104">The second pinion gear P<b>20</b> may be disposed between the first-third insertion end connection body <b>343</b> and the first-fourth insertion end connection body <b>344</b>, so that it can be meshed with the third rack gear part L of the first-third insertion end connection body <b>343</b> and the fourth rack gear part L of the first-fourth insertion end connection body <b>344</b> at the same time. In this meshed state, the second pinion gear P<b>20</b> may rotate around the second central axle part perpendicular to the longitudinal direction (Y axis direction) according to the user's manipulation of the operation module H.</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0105">The second central axle part may be disposed on the same line as the first central axle part, but may be configured to be separated from each other and independently rotatable. Accordingly, while the first pinion gear P<b>10</b> and the second pinion gear P<b>20</b> rotate around the first central axle part or the second central axle part, they can avoid interfering (or hindering) each other's rotational movements.</p>
<p id="p-0107" num="0106">The second module body <b>330</b> may be provided with a guide hole (not shown) which is formed penetrating in the longitudinal direction (Y axis direction) while passing past the center of a region surrounded by the first-first, first-second, first-third, and first-fourth insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b>. In this regard, the guide hole may be disposed between the first pinion gear and the second pinion gear so as not to interfere with rotation of the pinion gears. In this case, the second insertion end connection body <b>345</b> can be disposed inside the above-described guide hole, and can perform reciprocating rectilinear motion in parallel with the longitudinal direction (Y axis) inside the guide hole.</p>
<p id="p-0108" num="0107">The second module body <b>330</b> may be provided with straight line guide slits G extending along the longitudinal direction (Y axis direction) on its upper and lower surfaces. The straight line guide slits G may include a pair of &#x2018;upper surface straight line guide slits&#x2019; provided on the upper surface of the second module body <b>330</b> to face the first-first insertion end connection body <b>341</b> and the first-second insertion end connection body <b>342</b>, respectively, and a pair of &#x2018;lower surface straight line guide slits&#x2019; provided on the lower surface of the second module body <b>330</b> to face the first-third insertion end connection body <b>343</b> and the first-fourth insertion end connection body <b>344</b>, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0109" num="0108">In this case, the first-first insertion end connection body <b>341</b> and the first-second insertion end connection body <b>342</b> may each be provided with &#x2018;upper surface guide protruding members I&#x2019; extending upward and inserted into the supper surface straight line guide slits G. And the first-third insertion end connection body <b>343</b> and the first-fourth insertion end connection body <b>344</b> may each be provided with &#x2018;lower surface guide protruding members I&#x2019; extending downward and inserted into the lower surface straight line guide slits G. In this case, respective guide protruding members I can guide the reciprocating rectilinear motion of the first insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b> by moving along the corresponding linear guide slits G.</p>
<p id="p-0110" num="0109">At one end of each of the first-first, first-second, first-third, and first-fourth insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b>, the first-first engaging member <b>331</b>, the first-second engaging member <b>332</b>, the first-third engaging member <b>333</b>, or the first-fourth engaging member <b>334</b> may be provided. And, to the other end of each of the first-first, first-second, first-third, and first-fourth insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, and <b>344</b>, the first operation wire <b>201</b>, the second operation wire <b>202</b>, the third operation wire <b>203</b>, or the fourth operation wire <b>204</b> may be connected.</p>
<p id="p-0111" num="0110"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is a perspective view showing the inside of the first detachment module and the second detachment module in a state before they are coupled in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is a perspective view showing the inside of the first detachment module and the second detachment module in a coupled state of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0112" num="0111">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>5</b> and <b>6</b></figref>, a method in which the operation unit <b>100</b> and the insertion unit <b>200</b> are coupled to each other may be as follows.</p>
<p id="p-0113" num="0112">First, the first coupling end of the operation unit <b>100</b> and the second coupling end of the insertion unit <b>200</b> may be disposed to face each other. At this time, before coupling, the first coupling end of the operation unit <b>100</b> may be in a &#x2018;parallel-aligned state&#x2019; with the second coupling end of the insertion unit <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0114" num="0113">Here, when viewing the detachable endoscope <b>10</b> from above based on the Z axis of the drawing, the &#x2018;parallel-aligned state&#x2019; may mean a state in which the virtual first reference line connecting the first-first connection end E<b>1</b> and the first-second connection end E<b>2</b> [and connecting the first-third connection end E<b>3</b> and the first-fourth connection end E<b>4</b>] provided in the operation unit <b>100</b> is parallel to the virtual second reference line connecting one end of the first-first insertion end connection body <b>341</b> and one end of the first-second insertion end connection body <b>342</b> [and connecting one end of the first-third insertion end connection body <b>343</b> and one end of the first-fourth insertion end connection body <b>344</b>] provided in the insertion unit <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0115" num="0114">Next, the operation unit <b>100</b> and the insertion unit <b>200</b> can move in a direction parallel to the longitudinal direction (Y axis direction) and approaching each other (hereinafter, referred to as a coupling direction). Accordingly, the first-first engaging member <b>331</b>, the first-second engaging member <b>332</b>, the first-third engaging member <b>333</b>, and the first-fourth engaging member <b>334</b> of the insertion unit <b>200</b> can be inserted into the first-first insertion groove <b>321</b> of the first-first connection end E<b>1</b>, the first-second insertion groove <b>322</b> of the first-second connection end E<b>2</b>, the first-third insertion groove <b>323</b> of the first-third connection end E<b>3</b>, and the first-fourth insertion groove <b>324</b> of the first-fourth connection end E<b>4</b>. At this time, the second engaging member <b>335</b> of the second insertion end connection part <b>340</b>&#x2032; can be inserted into the second insertion groove <b>325</b> provided in the second connection end E<b>5</b> of the second intermediate connection part <b>320</b>&#x2032;.</p>
<p id="p-0116" num="0115">Next, when the first and second intermediate connection part <b>320</b> and <b>320</b>&#x2032; move backward (&#x2212;Y axis direction) by the user's manipulation of the operation module H, the first and second connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, E<b>4</b>, and E<b>5</b> and the first and second intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, <b>314</b>, and <b>315</b> may move backward (&#x2212;Y axis direction) while being rotated by the first and second guide projections T<b>1</b>, T<b>2</b>, T<b>3</b>, T<b>4</b>, and T<b>5</b> and the first and second guide slits G<b>1</b>, G<b>2</b>, G<b>3</b>, G<b>4</b>, and G<b>5</b>. With this, the first and second engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, <b>334</b>, and <b>335</b> may be secured to one ends of the first and second insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, <b>324</b>, and <b>325</b> in the engaged state, so that the insertion unit <b>200</b> and the operation unit <b>100</b> can be coupled with each other. In this regard, the specific combination method will be described in detail below.</p>
<p id="p-0117" num="0116"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>A</figref> is a perspective view showing a state before the intermediate connection part and the insertion end connection part provided in the detachable endoscope according to an embodiment of the present disclosure are coupled to each other. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>7</b>B and <b>7</b>C</figref> are perspective views showing states before the coupling of the intermediate connection part and the insertion end connection part is completed. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>D</figref> is a perspective view showing a state in which the intermediate connection part and the insertion end connection part are coupled.</p>
<p id="p-0118" num="0117">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>7</b>A to <b>7</b>D</figref>, a method for coupling the first intermediate connection part <b>320</b> or the second intermediate connection part <b>320</b>&#x2032; provided in the operation unit <b>100</b> with the first insertion end connection part <b>340</b> or the second insertion end connection part <b>340</b>&#x2032; provided in the insertion unit <b>200</b> may be as follows.</p>
<p id="p-0119" num="0118">First, as described above, when the operation unit <b>100</b> and the insertion unit <b>200</b> in a state before coupling are disposed facing each other, the first and second intermediate connection parts <b>320</b> and <b>320</b>&#x2032; and the first and second insertion end connection parts <b>340</b> and <b>340</b>&#x2032; may be disposed facing each other. At this time, in a state where the first and second connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, E<b>4</b>, and E<b>5</b> face the first and second engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, <b>334</b>, and <b>335</b> each other, the first and second intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, <b>314</b>, and <b>315</b> may be arranged on the same line as the first and second insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, <b>344</b>, and <b>345</b> in the longitudinal direction (Y axis direction) (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>A</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0120" num="0119">Next, the operation unit <b>100</b> and the insertion unit <b>200</b> may be moved so as to come closer along the coupling direction by the user. In this case, the first and second engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, <b>334</b>, and <b>345</b> can be inserted into the first and second insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, <b>324</b>, and <b>325</b> provided at the first and second connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, E<b>4</b>, and E<b>5</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0121" num="0120">At this time, the first and second engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, <b>334</b>, and <b>335</b> may be provided with an &#x2018;engaging projection&#x2019; protrudingly formed toward the outer side of the radial direction of the first and second engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, <b>334</b>, and <b>335</b> at their front ends. When the first and second engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, <b>334</b>, and <b>335</b> are inserted into the first and second insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, <b>324</b>, and <b>325</b>, the engaging projections may be accommodated in the first and second insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, <b>324</b>, and <b>325</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>B</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0122" num="0121">Next, as the operation unit <b>100</b> and the insertion unit <b>200</b> move further along the coupling direction (Y axis direction), the front ends of the first and second insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, <b>344</b>, and <b>345</b> may come into contact with the first and second connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, E<b>4</b>, and E<b>5</b>. At this time, the first and second engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, <b>334</b>, and <b>335</b> are formed in a length shorter than or equal to the depth of the first and second insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, <b>324</b>, and <b>325</b>, so the first and second engaging members can avoid interference in contact between the first and second insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, <b>344</b>, and <b>345</b>, and the first and second connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, E<b>4</b>, and E<b>5</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0123" num="0122">Next, the user may operate a locking part <b>200</b><i>a </i>provided at the second coupling end of the insertion unit <b>200</b> to couple and secure the insertion unit <b>200</b> to the operation unit <b>100</b>. As an example, the locking part <b>200</b><i>a </i>may be rotatably installed at the second coupling end, and the first coupling end of the operation unit <b>100</b> may be inserted into this locking unit <b>200</b><i>a. </i>In this case, as the user rotates the locking part <b>200</b><i>a </i>in one direction, the locking part <b>200</b><i>a </i>and the first coupling end may be coupled in a screw connection method and secured together.</p>
<p id="p-0124" num="0123">In this regard, when the locking part <b>200</b><i>a </i>is rotated, the first and second insertion end connection bodies <b>341</b>, <b>342</b>, <b>343</b>, <b>344</b>, and <b>345</b> are further moved in the coupling direction (&#x2212;Y axis direction) in a state of being in contact with the first and second connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, E<b>4</b>, and E<b>5</b>, so that they can press the first and second connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, E<b>4</b>, and E<b>5</b> and the first and second intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, <b>314</b>, and <b>315</b> backward (&#x2212;Y axis direction). With this, the first and second guide projections T<b>1</b>, T<b>2</b>, T<b>3</b>, T<b>4</b>, and T<b>5</b> move backward (&#x2212;Y axis direction) while rotating along the &#x2018;curved line parts&#x2019; of the first and second guide slits G<b>1</b>, G<b>2</b>, G<b>3</b>, G<b>4</b>, and G<b>5</b>, and as a result, the first and second connection ends E<b>1</b>, E<b>2</b>, E<b>3</b>, E<b>4</b>, and E<b>5</b> and the first and second intermediate connection bodies <b>311</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>313</b>, <b>314</b>, and <b>315</b> can be rotated around the longitudinal direction (Y axis direction).</p>
<p id="p-0125" num="0124">By this rotation, in a state where the first and second engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, <b>334</b>, and <b>335</b> are accommodated in the first and second insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, <b>324</b>, and <b>325</b>, the engaging projections can protrude to the outside of the first and second insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, <b>324</b>, and <b>325</b> through the penetration part N to be in a non-separable state (primary coupled state) (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>C</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0126" num="0125">Next, in the primary coupled state, by the user's manipulation of the operation module H, the first and second intermediate connection part <b>320</b> and <b>320</b>&#x2032; can be pulled backward (&#x2212;Y axis direction). In this case, the first and second guide projections T<b>1</b>, T<b>2</b>, T<b>3</b>, T<b>4</b>, and T<b>5</b> pass through the &#x2018;curved line parts&#x2019; of the first and second guide slits G<b>1</b>, G<b>2</b>, G<b>3</b>, G<b>4</b>, and G<b>5</b> and move backward (&#x2212;Y axis direction) along the &#x2018;straight line parts,&#x2019; and accordingly, the engaging projections of the first and second engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, <b>334</b>, and <b>335</b> protruding outward through the penetration part N can be in the engaged state at the inner ends of the first and second insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, <b>324</b>, and <b>325</b>. As a result, the first and second intermediate connection parts <b>320</b> and <b>320</b>&#x2032; and the first and second insertion end connection parts <b>340</b> and <b>340</b>&#x2032; may be coupled to become a non-separable state (secondary coupled state) (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>D</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0127" num="0126">Thereafter, in the &#x2018;secondary coupled state&#x2019;, by the user's manipulation of the operation module H, the first intermediate connection part <b>320</b> and the first insertion end connection part <b>340</b> can operate to perform reciprocating rectilinear motion integrally, and the second intermediate connection part <b>320</b>&#x2032; and the second insertion end connection part <b>340</b>&#x2032; can operate to perform reciprocating rectilinear motion integrally.</p>
<p id="p-0128" num="0127">Meanwhile, when removal or replacement of the insertion unit <b>200</b> is required, the insertion unit <b>200</b> may be separated from the operation unit <b>100</b> by a process as follows.</p>
<p id="p-0129" num="0128">First, reference points (not shown) provided respectively on the first operation part H<b>10</b>, the second operation part H<b>20</b>, and the third operation part H<b>30</b> may be aligned in a line. In this way, when the first, second, and third operation parts H<b>10</b>, H<b>20</b>, and H<b>30</b> are aligned along the reference points, the operation unit <b>100</b> and the insertion unit <b>200</b> can again be in a &#x2018;parallel-aligned state&#x2019; as described above.</p>
<p id="p-0130" num="0129">Next, the locking state may be released by rotating the locking part <b>200</b><i>a </i>of the insertion unit <b>200</b> in a direction opposite to the locking direction. After the unlocking of the locking part <b>200</b><i>a </i>is completed, the user may separate the insertion unit <b>200</b> by moving it away from the operation unit <b>100</b> in a direction opposite to the coupling direction. Thereafter, the replacement of the insertion unit <b>200</b> may be completed by coupling another insertion unit as a replacement to the operation unit <b>100</b> through the same or similar method as described above.</p>
<p id="p-0131" num="0130">Regarding the operation method of the detachable endoscope <b>10</b> according to the above-described present disclosure, in the case where the insertion unit <b>200</b> and the operation unit <b>100</b> are assembled in the &#x2018;second coupled state&#x2019;, by the user's manipulation of the first operation part H<b>10</b> or the second operation part H<b>20</b>, the first intermediate connection part <b>320</b> performs reciprocating rectilinear motion through the lower sprocket and the upper sprocket, and the lower chain and upper chain respectively connected thereto, and at this time, the first insertion end connection part <b>340</b> can perform reciprocating rectilinear motion integrally with the first intermediate connection part <b>320</b> while being coupled with it through the first engaging members <b>331</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>333</b>, and <b>334</b> and the first insertion grooves <b>321</b>, <b>322</b>, <b>323</b>, and <b>324</b>, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0132" num="0131">Additionally, in the &#x2018;second coupled state&#x2019;, the hydraulic pressure supply part supplies hydraulic pressure to the linear movement shaft or removes the supplied hydraulic pressure by the user's manipulation of the third operation part H<b>30</b>, and thus the second intermediate connection part <b>320</b>&#x2032; and the second insertion end connection part <b>340</b>&#x2032; which are coupled through the second engaging member <b>335</b> and the second insertion groove <b>325</b> can perform reciprocating rectilinear motion integrally.</p>
<p id="p-0133" num="0132">In this case, the first detachment module <b>300</b><i>a </i>may be connected to the operation module H by the medium of the lower sprocket and the upper sprocket rotated in forward/backward directions by the first and second operation parts H<b>10</b> and H<b>20</b>, the lower chain and the upper chain connected thereto to be wound around them, and the first, second, third and fourth connection wires <b>101</b>, <b>102</b>, <b>103</b> and <b>104</b> connected to both ends of the chains. Additionally, the first detachment module <b>300</b><i>a </i>may be connected to the operation module H by the medium of a hydraulic pressure supply part and a linear movement shaft that perform reciprocating rectilinear motion forward/rearward by the third operation part H<b>30</b>, and the intermediate connection member <b>105</b> coupled to them.</p>
<p id="p-0134" num="0133">The first and second connection wires <b>101</b> and <b>102</b> connected to both ends of the upper chain connected to the upper sprocket operate in linkage with the first and second operation wires <b>201</b> and <b>202</b> disposed side by side in a pair on the upper side of the inside of the insertion unit <b>200</b> based on the drawing, so that the first and second connection wires can bend the insertion end of the insertion unit <b>200</b> in the left and right directions.</p>
<p id="p-0135" num="0134">Contrarily, the third and fourth connection wires <b>103</b> and <b>104</b> connected to both ends of the lower chain connected to the lower sprocket operate in linkage with the third and fourth operation wires <b>203</b> and <b>204</b> disposed side by side in a pair on the lower side of the inside of the insertion unit <b>200</b> based on the drawing, so that the third and fourth connection wires can bend the insertion end of the insertion unit <b>200</b> in the up and down directions. However, the present disclosure is not limited to this, and bending manipulations in the up and down directions and the left and right directions may be reversed depending on the design of the endoscope <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0136" num="0135">The intermediate connection member <b>105</b> connected to the hydraulic pressure supply part and the linear movement shaft is surrounded by the first, second, third and fourth connection wires <b>101</b>, <b>102</b>, <b>103</b> and <b>104</b> and is disposed within a defined space, so that it can operate in linkage with the fifth operation wire <b>205</b> to cause the force applying module <b>400</b> to pivot. In this case, the fifth operation wire <b>205</b> may be disposed in a space surrounded by the first, second, third, and fourth operation wires <b>201</b>, <b>202</b>, <b>203</b>, and <b>204</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0137" num="0136">In the detachable endoscope <b>10</b> according to the embodiments of the present disclosure, the insertion unit <b>200</b> intended to be inserted into the human body is configured to be detachable from the operation unit <b>100</b>, so that the internal contamination of the endoscope <b>10</b> can be prevented and parts can be easily replaced and cleaned. Additionally, in the course of coupling, without the use of a separate engaging or locking structure, it is possible to realize simple and easy assembly and disassembly of the insertion unit <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0138" num="0137">The afore-mentioned description of the disclosure is just an example, and a person having ordinary skill in the art may understand that it can be easily modified into other specific configuration without changing the technical spirit or essential features of the disclosure. Thus, the embodiments described above should be construed as being illustrative in every respect and not restrictive. For example, the respective components described as a singular form may be implemented in a distributed form, and likewise the respective components described as a distributed form may be implemented in a combined form.</p>
<p id="p-0139" num="0138">The scope of the present disclosure is represented by the following claims, and all modifications and changes derived from the meaning and scope of the claims and equivalent concepts thereof should be interpreted as being included in the scope of the present disclosure.</p>
<heading id="h-0008" level="1">REFERENCE SIGN LIST</heading>
<p id="p-0140" num="0139"><b>10</b>: Detachable endoscope</p>
<p id="p-0141" num="0140"><b>100</b>: Operation unit</p>
<p id="p-0142" num="0141"><b>200</b>: Insertion unit</p>
<p id="p-0143" num="0142"><b>300</b>: Detachment unit</p>
<p id="p-0144" num="0143"><b>400</b>: Force applying module</p>
<p id="p-0145" num="0144">H: Operation module</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A detachable endoscope for a duodenum comprising:
<claim-text>an insertion unit whose one end is intended to be inserted into a body, and which is provided with a force applying module pivotably disposed on the one end;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an operation unit coupled to another end of the insertion unit, and operating the one end of the insertion unit to perform a bending motion with use of an operation module; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a detachment unit including a first detachment module disposed within the operation unit, and a second detachment module disposed within the insertion unit and detachably coupled to the first detachment module.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The detachable endoscope for a duodenum of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first detachment module includes a first module body, and a first intermediate connection part and a second intermediate connection part disposed within the first module body and receiving a force from the operation module, and
<claim-text>wherein the second detachment module includes a second module body, and a first insertion end connection part and a second insertion end connection part disposed within the second module body, detachably connected to the first intermediate connection part, and respectively connected to a first operation wire and a second operation wire transferring a force applied by the operation module to one end of the insertion module or the force applying module.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The detachable endoscope for a duodenum of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the first intermediate connection part is provided in two pairs, which are spaced apart from each other along the inner circumference of the first module body, and the second intermediate connection part extends through the center of the two pairs of the first intermediate connection parts, and
<claim-text>wherein the first insertion end connection part is provided in two pairs corresponding to the first intermediate connection parts, and the two pairs of the first insertion end connection parts are spaced apart from each other along the inner circumference of the second module body, and the second insertion end connection part extends through the center of the two pairs of the first insertion end connection parts.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The detachable endoscope for a duodenum of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein each of the first intermediate connection part and the second intermediate connection part is provided with an insertion groove formed concavely inward in a longitudinal direction at its one end, and
<claim-text>wherein each of the first insertion end connection part and the second insertion end connection part is provided with an engaging member formed protrudingly outward in a longitudinal direction from its one end and detachably inserted into and coupled to the insertion groove.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The detachable endoscope for a duodenum of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the engaging member is formed protrudingly in a length shorter than the concave depth of the insertion groove.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The detachable endoscope for a duodenum of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the second insertion end connection part is connected to the force applying module by a medium of the operation wire, and
<claim-text>wherein when the first detachment module and the second detachment module are coupled to each other, the force applying module is operated to rotate about a rotational axle perpendicular to the longitudinal direction of the insertion unit with use of the operation module.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The detachable endoscope for a duodenum of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the second insertion end connection part is provided with a curved connection member extending toward the force applying module and at least partially curved with respect to the longitudinal direction of the second insertion end connection part.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
