<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225240A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225240</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17576506</doc-number>
<date>20220114</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>17</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>06</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>068</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">MODULAR WHEEL ASSEMBLY</invention-title>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="obligated-assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>SCHAFFERT MANUFACTURING COMPANY, INC.</orgname>
<address>
<city>Indianola</city>
<state>NE</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Schaffert</last-name>
<first-name>Paul E.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Indianola</city>
<state>NE</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="01" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Schaffert</last-name>
<first-name>Kris</first-name>
<address>
<city>Indianola</city>
<state>NE</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A press wheel includes a hub configured to rotate about an axis. The press wheel may further include a mounting portion removably attachable to the hub and having a center plane substantially perpendicular to the axis upon removable attachment with the hub. The press wheel may further include a plurality of tread portions connected to the mounting portion and configured to define a circumferential portion of the press wheel. The plurality of tread portions may have voids between adjacent tread portions. Each tread portion of the plurality of tread portions may include a tine extending away from the center plane.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="84.33mm" wi="158.75mm" file="US20230225240A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="208.87mm" wi="136.31mm" file="US20230225240A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="229.28mm" wi="134.03mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225240A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="224.28mm" wi="151.64mm" file="US20230225240A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="233.26mm" wi="154.01mm" file="US20230225240A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="221.66mm" wi="134.70mm" file="US20230225240A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="180.93mm" wi="148.08mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225240A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="207.77mm" wi="151.47mm" file="US20230225240A1-20230720-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="216.32mm" wi="135.30mm" file="US20230225240A1-20230720-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="200.07mm" wi="127.68mm" file="US20230225240A1-20230720-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="95.25mm" wi="118.62mm" file="US20230225240A1-20230720-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The described examples relate generally to press wheels for furrow closing assemblies, and methods of use thereof.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Multi-row planters may be used for agricultural seed planting. A planter may include multiple row units configured for opening a seed furrow, depositing seeds within the furrow, and closing the seed furrow around the seeds. In some cases, each row unit of the planter may also open a fertilizer furrow adjacent to each seed furrow, deposit liquid fertilizer in each fertilizer furrow, and close each fertilizer furrow. Further, a press wheel or firmer wheel may often be used for compacting the soil in the seeded furrows after the soil has been planted and, in some instances, after a closing wheel has deposited loose soil overtop of the seed.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Conventional press wheels may include a hub having a fixed diameter from a central rotational axis of the press wheel. Conventional press wheels may, in some cases, have one or more tines that extend from the hub at a fixed length or other dimension. The dimensions of the press wheel, such as the dimensions of the hub and/or the tine, may impact the performance of the press wheel in the field. As one example, the size of the tine may impact the amount of soil placed over the seed. Different end users may require different amounts of soil be placed over the seed based on a variety of field and seed conditions. Accordingly, conventional techniques may limit the ability of a user to adapt to field conditions and change the performance of the press wheel, absent completely replacing a press for another. As such, there is a need for systems and techniques to improve the adaptability of press wheels for a variety of field conditions and user preferences.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Examples of the present invention are directed to modular wheel assemblies and methods of use thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In one example, a modular press wheel is disclosed. The modular press wheel includes a hub configured to rotate about an axis. The modular press wheel further includes a first rim feature. The first rim feature includes a first mounting portion removably attachable to the hub. The first rim feature further includes a first set of tread portions connected to the first mounting portion and configured to define a first circumferential portion of the modular press wheel. The modular press wheel further includes a second rim feature. The second rim feature includes a second mounting portion removably attachable to the hub. The second rim feature further includes a second set of tread portions connected to the second mounting portion and configured to define a second circumferential portion of the modular press wheel.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In another example, for at least the first set of tread portions, each tread portion of the first set of tread portions may include a tine extending away from a center plane of the first mounting portion. The center plane may be substantially perpendicular to the axis upon removable attachment of the first rim feature with the hub. The tine define may define a chord relative to a radial surface of the first mounting portion.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In another example, at least the first mounting portion may include a first mounting plate having an inner curved edge, and an outer curved edge opposite the inner curved edge. The first set of tread portions may be connected to the first mounting plate along the outer curved edge. The hub may include a rim feature engagement surface. Further, the first mounting plate may include a hub engagement surface extending from the inner curved edge to the outer curved edge. In some cases, the hub and the first mounting portion may be removably attachable to one another via a lap joint defined along a portion of the rim feature engagement surface and a portion of the hub engagement surface.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In another example, the hub may include a series of hub holes circumferentially spaced about the axis. The first mounting plate may include a series of first mounting plate holes circumferentially spaced about the axis. The first mounting plate holes may be alignable with the series of hub holes, upon removable attachment of the first mounting plate with the hub. In some cases, the modular press wheel may further include a fastener configured to removably attach the hub and the first mounting plate and advanceable through an aligned pair of a hub hole of the series of hub holes and a first mounting plate hole of the series of first mounting plate holes.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In another example, upon removable attachment of the hub and the first mounting portion, the outer curved edge extends beyond an outermost circumferential edge of the hub. The first and second circumferential portions may be adjacent circumferential portions of the modular press wheel.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In another example, a modular press wheel is disclosed. The modular press wheel includes a hub configured to rotate about an axis. The modular press wheel includes a mounting portion removably attachable to the hub and having a center plane substantially perpendicular to the axis upon removable attachment with the hub. The modular press wheel includes a plurality of tread portions connected to the mounting portion and configured to define a circumferential portion of the modular press wheel. The plurality of tread portions includes voids between adjacent tread portions, wherein each tread portion of the plurality of tread portions comprises a tine extending away from the center plane.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In one example, the mounting portion may be one of a set of mounting portions. Each mounting portion of the set of mounting portions may be removably attachable with the hub and connected with a corresponding plurality of tines that cooperate to define a complete circumferential portion of the modular press wheel. In some cases, the set of mounting portions includes four mounting portions. Each mounting portion of the four mounting portions may have a common arcuate shape that is configured to establish the four mounting portions in a substantially circular shape when the four mounting portions are arranged end to end with one another.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In another example, each mounting portion of the set of mounting portions may contact one or more adjacent mounting portions upon removable attachment of the mounting portion with the hub. Further, a shape or a size of the tine of the respective tread portion may vary along the circumferential portion.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In another example, the mounting portion may include a mounting plate defining a series of slots along an outermost circumferential edge of the mounting portion. The plurality of tread portions may be connected to the mounting portion via welds formed between a slot of the series of slot the tine of the respective tread portion.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In another example, the mounting portion may be a first mounting portion have a first size. The plurality of tread portions may be a first plurality of tread portions. In this regard, the modular press wheel may further include a second mounting portion having a second size and that is removably attachable to the hub and connected with a second plurality of tread portions. In a first configuration, the first mounting portion may be removably attached to the hub at a predetermined mounting location with the first plurality of tread portions spaced apart from the axis based on the first size of the first mounting portion. In a second configuration, the second mounting is removably attached to the hub at the predetermined mounting location with the second plurality of tread portions spaced apart from the axis based on the second size of the second mounting portion, the second size larger than the first size.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In another example, a method for modifying a modular press wheel is disclosed. The method includes uncoupling a first mounting portion from a predetermined mounting location of a hub of the modular press wheel. The first mounting portion may have a first size and may be connected to a first plurality of tread portions. The first plurality of tread portions may define a circumferential portion of the modular press wheel. The method may further include coupling a second mounting portion to the predetermined mounting location of the hub. The second mounting portion may have a second size and may be connected to a second plurality of tread portions. The second plurality of tread portions may define the circumferential portion upon the coupling of the second mounting portion of the predetermined mounting location.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In another example, the second size may be larger than the first size such that the coupling of the second mounting portion to the predetermined mounting location increases a radius of the modular press wheel.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In another example, the second plurality of tread portions may have a different size, shape or arrangement than the first plurality of tread portions. In this regard, the coupling of the second mounting portion to the predetermined mounting location may change the size, shape, or arrangement of tread portions along the circumferential portion of the modular press wheel.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In another example, the uncoupling of the first mounting portion may further include loosening a fastener and removing the fastener from an aligned pair of a hub hole of the hub and a first mounting portion hole of the first mounting portion. Further, the coupling of the second mounting portion may further include extending the fastener through an aligned pair of the hub hole and a second mounting portion hole of the second mounting portion.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In addition to the exemplary aspects and examples described above, further aspects and examples will become apparent by reference to the drawings and by study of the following description.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The disclosure will be readily understood by the following detailed description in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, wherein like reference numerals designate like structural elements, and in which:</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> depicts a side view of an agricultural tractor and an agricultural planter;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> depicts a top-rear perspective view of the agricultural tractor and agricultural planter of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, with a press wheel;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> depicts a rear view of the agricultural planter and the press wheel of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>A</figref> depicts an example modular press wheel;</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>B</figref> depicts an exploded view of the modular press wheel of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>A</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>C</figref> depicts a cross-sectional view of the modular press wheel of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>A</figref>, taken along line <b>4</b>C-<b>4</b>C of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>A</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b>A</figref> depicts another example modular press wheel;</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b>B</figref> depicts an exploded view of the modular press wheel of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b>A</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref> depicts another example modular press wheel in a first configuration;</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>B</figref> depicts an exploded view of the modular press wheel of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>C</figref> depicts the modular press wheel of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref> in a second configuration;</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>A</figref> depicts a top view of an example rim feature;</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>B</figref> depicts a top view of another example rim feature;</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>C</figref> depicts a top view of another example rim feature;</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>D</figref> depicts a top view of another example rim feature;</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>E</figref> depicts a top view of another example rim feature;</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>F</figref> depicts a top view of another example rim feature;</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>G</figref> depicts a side view of another example rim feature;</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> depicts a top view of another example rim feature;</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref> depicts another example hub;</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref> depicts an example metal sheet including a template for mounting portions of the present disclosure; and</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b></figref> depicts a flow diagram of a method of modifying a modular press wheel.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The description that follows includes sample systems, methods, and apparatuses that embody various elements of the present disclosure. However, it should be understood that the described disclosure may be practiced in a variety of forms in addition to those described herein.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The following disclosure relates generally to modular press wheels and associated systems and methods of use thereof. Broadly, a press wheel may be substantially any type of wheel or firming device that is configured for compacting the soil in the seeded furrows after the soil has been planted. For example, the press wheel may be configured to generally compact the soil in order to promote seed germination by minimizing air pockets. This can improve the capillary action of the moisture in the soil as well as reducing wind erosion of the soil over the seed.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">To facilitate the foregoing, a press wheel may generally include a hub that is configured to rotate about an axis. The hub may include or otherwise be connected with a plurality of tread portions arranged along a circumferential portion of the hub. In one example, the tread portions may include tines and/or other structures that extend from the hub for engagement with the soil. The tine or tread portions may have voids between adjacent tines such that a circumferential edge of the hub or press wheel and one or both adjacent tines may contact the ground together to promote firming. The diameter of the hub as well as the size and shape of the tread portions or tines may impact the performance of the press wheel in the field. As one example, larger tines may encourage more soil placement over a seed as compared with smaller tines. However, conventional press wheels often include a fixed diameter wheel and/or a fixed size and shape tread portion or tine. The conventional arrangement may therefore limit the ability of a farmer to adapt the press wheel to different field conditions and farmer preferences.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The modular press wheel of the present disclosure may mitigate such hindrances by providing a reconfigurable and adaptable press wheel. For example, the modular press wheel of the present disclosure may include one or more universal components that is removably coupleable with one or more modular components. The one or more modular components may have a different size, shape, configuration, material, and/or other property. Accordingly, the one or more universal components and the one or more modular components may cooperate with one another in order to change the characteristics of the press wheel, such as changing one or more of a diameter of the hub and/or a size and/or shape of one or more of the tread portions. In this regard, the one or more universal components and the one or more modular components may cooperate with one another in order to change the performance of the press wheel, including changing the press wheel in order to cause the press wheel to move more or less soil over the seed, as may be desired.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">In one example, the modular press wheel includes a hub and one or more rim features. The hub may be a universal component of the modular press wheel. For example, the hub may generally be a circular or wheel-type or plate-type component that is configured to rotate about an axis. For example, the hub may include a central mounting feature that is configured for mounting on or otherwise coupling to an axle component of a furrow closing assembly or other assembly. The rim features may be modular components of the modular press wheel. For example, the rim features may be removably coupleable with the hub in order to define or form the modular press wheel and establish the modular press wheel as having one or more specified characteristics, such as having a predetermined diameter and/or a predetermined size and/or shape of the tread portions.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">By way of illustration, one or more of the rim features may include a mounting portion and a set of tread portions. The mounting portion may be formed form a plate or metal sheet and may be generally removably attachable with the hub. For example, the mounting portion may be arranged adjacent the hub in order to define a lap joint therebetween, which may be secured by one or more fasteners. The set of tread portions may be connected to the mounting portion and define a circumferential portion of the rim feature. For example, the set of tread portions may include a plurality of tines that are connected to and circumferentially spaced along an outer arcuate surface or edge of the mounting portion, as one example. The rim feature may be removably coupled to the hub in order to define the set of tread portions of the rim feature as a circumferential portion of the modular press wheel. In this regard, upon removably attachment, the modular press wheel may exhibit, at the given circumferential portion, a diameter and have a tread portion size and shape as defined by the tread portions of the rim feature.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">The rim features may therefore facilitate the adaptability and reconfigurability of the modular press wheel by allowing the modular press to have different diameters and shape and sizes of the tread portions, as needed. For example, the rim feature may generally form a lap joint with the hub and extend beyond an outermost edge of the hub. As such, the rim feature, when removably attached to hub, may define or establish the diameter of the hub. This may allow a first rim feature to have a first size that establishes the modular press wheel as having a first diameter. In turn, a second rim feature may have a second size that establishes the modular press wheel as having a second diameter that is different than the first diameter. A farmer or other user may change out the first rim feature for the second feature in order to change a size of the modular press wheel. Continuing the non-limiting example, the first rim feature may include a first set of tread portions having a first size or type, and the second rim feature may include a second set of tread portions having a second size or type. As such, a farmer or other user may also change out the first rim feature for the second feature in order to change a size or type of tread portions.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Multiple rim features may be arranged together with one another to define a complete or continuous circumferential periphery of the modular press wheel. For example, and as shown herein, four rim features, each of a generally common size may each be removably attached to the hub in order to define the continuous circumferential periphery of the modular press wheel. Each of the four rim features may have a common arcuate shape such that when the four rim features are arranged end to end, the four rim features define a substantially circular shape of the modular press wheel. In other cases, more or fewer modular rim features may be used to established the circular shape.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">Turning to the Drawings, the modular press wheel of the present disclosure may be used with an agriculture planter <b>70</b> having one or more trailing arm assemblies <b>100</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>. Each trailing arm assembly <b>100</b> may include a fertilizer furrow opener assembly <b>150</b>. The fertilizer furrow opener assembly <b>150</b> may be configured to open the soil, such as with an opener disc, and optionally supply fertilizer and/or seed to an open furrow. Each trailing arm assembly <b>100</b> may also include a trailing furrow closer assembly <b>200</b>. The trailing furrow closer assembly <b>200</b> may be configured to close the soil, such as with a closing wheel. As described and shown herein, one or more press wheels, such as the modular press wheels of the present disclosure may be connected to end of the trailing arm assemblies <b>110</b>. This may allow the press wheel to firm the soil after closing.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">The modular press wheels of the present disclosure may be used with a variety of different planters and trailing arm assemblies. For purposes of illustration, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> and <b>2</b></figref> show the planter <b>70</b> as including a tongue or hitch <b>60</b> for hitching the planter <b>70</b> to a hitch <b>55</b> of a tractor <b>50</b>. The tractor <b>50</b> tows the planter <b>70</b> in the direction of arrow F and provides power to the planter <b>70</b> (e.g., via a power take off (&#x201c;PTO&#x201d;)) for powering the operations of the planter <b>70</b>. As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the planter <b>70</b> may include a frame <b>75</b> from which the hitch <b>60</b> extends and the various planter components are supported. The various components of the planter <b>70</b> may include the plurality of trailing arm assemblies <b>100</b>. The trailing arm assemblies <b>100</b> may function as row units for planting seeds and distributing liquid fertilizer, for example, from a common liquid fertilizer tube <b>170</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">While many configurations are possible, each row unit shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> may include a frame <b>154</b> for supporting various components of the planter <b>70</b>. The row units in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> are shown as including a furrow opener disc <b>158</b>, a gage wheel <b>162</b>, and a seed hopper <b>166</b>. Broadly, the seed furrow opener disc <b>158</b> may be configured to create a furrow in which the planter <b>70</b> deposits seed. The gage wheel <b>162</b> may be configured to determine or control a depth at which the planter <b>70</b> deposits the seed. The planter <b>70</b> may further include a series of the trailing arm assemblies <b>200</b>, each of which may include a trailing furrow closer wheel <b>208</b> followed by a press wheel <b>250</b> and associated subassemblies. This configuration allows for treating the soil after the furrow has been closed by the closing wheel <b>208</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">In one example, the closing wheels <b>208</b> may contact the soil and close an open furrow. This operation may form a closed furrow seam <b>292</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>. The press wheel <b>250</b> may follow behind respective closing wheels <b>208</b> and be connected to the closing assembly <b>200</b> via a mounting fork <b>280</b>. The press wheel <b>250</b> may be configured to rotate about an axle <b>284</b> that is rotatably connected to the mounting assembly or fork <b>280</b>. The press wheel <b>250</b> may include tread portions <b>258</b>. In this regard, the press wheel <b>250</b> may follow the closing wheels <b>208</b> and condition the closed furrow seam <b>292</b> using the tread portions <b>258</b>. For example, the press wheel <b>250</b> may apply a downward pressure on the closed furrow <b>292</b>. The pressure against the soil may come from tread portions <b>258</b> and/or a rim. The pressure may be applied without applying pressure from webbing or other material linking the tread portions <b>258</b> at any point other than that proximal to a center plane. In one example, the tread portions <b>258</b> may extend from each side of a center plane.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, the press wheel <b>250</b> may be approximately centered on the closed furrow seam <b>292</b>. This position may be independent of the location of either the opener disc <b>158</b> or the closing wheels <b>208</b>. In some cases, the closing wheels <b>208</b> may be positioned on the sides of the open furrow in order to close the furrow. As such, additionally or alternatively the press wheel <b>250</b> may be centered between the closing wheels and/or positioned in any of a variety of other arrangements as may be appropriate for a given application.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">As the press wheel <b>250</b> creates a downward pressure, the press wheel <b>250</b> and the tread portions <b>258</b> may imprint a tread pattern <b>288</b> on the ground. The tread pattern <b>288</b> may resemble a chicken track. The imprint pattern may be formed because the volume between tread patterns may not contact the soil, limiting contact to either or both of the rim and the tread portion <b>258</b>. In one example, two lines may extend from and at an angle to a line passing at or close to the closed furrow seam <b>292</b>. The two lines may be angled in the same direction. The lines may be symmetric, having a common point meeting proximal to the center plane and pointing away from the direction of travel of the tractor <b>50</b> and/or arranged in any of a variety of other directions as may be appropriate for a given application.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>A and <b>4</b>B</figref>, a modular press wheel <b>400</b> is shown. The modular press wheel <b>400</b> may be used with the planter <b>70</b> and trailing assemblies <b>100</b> discussed generally above with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>-<b>3</b></figref>. For example, substantially analogous to the press wheel <b>250</b>, the modular press wheel <b>400</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>A</figref> an <b>4</b>B may be used to condition a closed furrow seam and generally firm the soil, as needed. It will therefore be appreciated that the modular press wheel <b>400</b> described in relation to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>A-<b>4</b>B</figref> may function in a manner similar manner to the press wheel <b>250</b> show in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>-<b>3</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">The modular press wheel <b>400</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>A and <b>4</b>B</figref> includes a hub <b>402</b>. The hub <b>402</b> may be a universal component of the modular press wheel <b>400</b>. For example, the hub <b>402</b> may have a universal or common size. This may allow modular components of various different sizes and configurations to be removably attached to the hub <b>402</b> in order to establish the modular press wheel <b>400</b> as having predetermined characteristics or performance qualities. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>B</figref>, the hub <b>402</b> may be formed from a plate or sheet or metal material. For example, the hub <b>402</b> may be a generally flat component having a first surface <b>405</b> and a second surface <b>407</b> opposite the first surface <b>405</b>. The hub <b>402</b> may have a generally circular shape in order to form a wheel-type component. For example, the hub <b>402</b> may have an outer circumferential edge <b>408</b>. The outer circumferential edge <b>408</b> may be an arcuate or circular perimeter of the hub <b>402</b>. The hub <b>402</b> may be configured to rotate about an axis <b>404</b>. In this regard, the hub <b>402</b> may include or define an axial hole <b>409</b>. The axial hole <b>409</b> may be arranged on a center axis of the hub <b>402</b> and be configured to receive an axle component of a trailing assembly, such as an axial component of the trailing assemblies shown above in relation to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>-<b>3</b></figref>. The hub <b>402</b> may be configured to removably attach with one or more modular components of the modular press wheel <b>400</b>, as described herein. In this regard, the hub <b>402</b> is shown as including or defining a plurality of hub holes <b>410</b>, such as hub hole <b>410</b><i>a. </i>The plurality of hub holes <b>410</b> may be circumferentially spaced holes that are arranged generally along the outer circumferential edge <b>408</b>. The plurality of hub holes <b>410</b> may each be configured to receive a fastener to support removably attachment of modular components of the hub <b>402</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">The modular press wheel <b>400</b> further include a plurality of rim features. The plurality of rim features may be removably attachable with the hub <b>402</b> in order to form the press wheel <b>400</b>. With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>A and <b>4</b>B</figref>, the press wheel <b>400</b> is shown as including a first rim feature <b>430</b>, a second rim feature <b>450</b>, a third rim feature <b>470</b>, and a fourth rim feature <b>480</b>. The rim features <b>430</b>, <b>450</b>, <b>470</b>, <b>480</b> may each be removably attachable with the hub <b>402</b> in order to form the modular press wheel <b>400</b>. For example, the first rim feature <b>430</b> may be removably connected to the hub <b>402</b> in order to form a first circumferential portion <b>406</b><i>a </i>of the modular press wheel <b>400</b>, the second rim feature <b>450</b> may be removably connected to the hub <b>402</b> in order to form a second circumferential portion <b>406</b><i>b </i>of the modular press wheel <b>400</b>, the third rim feature <b>470</b> may be removably connected to the hub <b>402</b> in order to form a third circumferential portion <b>406</b><i>c </i>of the modular press wheel <b>400</b>, and the fourth rim feature <b>480</b> may be removably connected to the hub <b>402</b> in order to form a fourth circumferential portion <b>406</b><i>d </i>of the modular press wheel <b>400</b>. The rim features <b>430</b>, <b>450</b>, <b>470</b>, <b>480</b> may therefore cooperate to define a complete circumference of the modular press wheel <b>400</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>A</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">For purposes of illustration, the first rim feature <b>430</b> is described in turn below. It will be appreciated that each of the rim features <b>430</b>, <b>450</b>, <b>470</b>, <b>480</b> may be substantially similar or identical to one another, and therefore, the discussion and depiction of the components of the first rim feature <b>430</b> may apply equally to each of the rim features <b>430</b>, <b>450</b>, <b>470</b>, <b>480</b> and/or any of the other rim features described herein. The first rim feature <b>430</b> may generally include a mounting portion <b>432</b> and a set of tread portions <b>440</b>. The mounting portion <b>432</b> may be formed from a plate or sheet of metal material. For example, the mounting portion <b>432</b> may have a generally flat shape with a first mounting portion surface <b>433</b> and a second mounting portion surface <b>435</b> opposite the first mounting portion surface <b>433</b>. In other cases, as described herein, the mounting portion <b>432</b> may have a curved or contoured profile, as may be appropriate for a given application. The mounting portion <b>432</b> may be used to facilitate connection of the first rim feature <b>430</b> with the hub <b>402</b>. In the example of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>A and <b>4</b>B</figref>, the mounting portion <b>432</b> is defined by a generally arcuate shape with an inner curved surface <b>437</b> and an outer curved surface <b>434</b>. The inner curved surface <b>437</b> and the outer curved surface <b>434</b> may generally have a similar curvature and run generally parallel one another. For example, the mounting portion <b>432</b> is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>B</figref> as having a first end <b>439</b><i>a </i>and a second end <b>439</b><i>b, </i>and the inner curved surface <b>437</b> and the outer curved surface <b>434</b> may run generally parallel one another from the first end <b>439</b><i>a </i>and to the second end <b>439</b><i>b. </i>The mounting portion <b>434</b> is further shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>A and <b>4</b>B</figref> as having a plurality of slots <b>436</b> spaced along the outer curved surface <b>434</b>. Each of the slots <b>436</b> may be configured to receive a tread portion, such as a tine, as explained herein below. Further, the mounting portion <b>432</b> is shown as include a plurality of mounting portion holes <b>438</b>, such as a mounting portion hole <b>438</b><i>a. </i>The holes of the plurality of mounting portion holes <b>438</b> may be configured to receive fastener of the modular press wheel <b>400</b> in order to facilitate the removable attachment of the first rim feature <b>430</b> to the hub <b>402</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">The first rim feature <b>430</b> is also shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>B</figref> as including the set of tread portions <b>440</b>. The set of tread portions <b>440</b> may include individual tread portions that are connected to the mounting portion <b>432</b> along the outer curved surface <b>434</b>. The set of tread of tread portions <b>440</b> may be configured to engage soil to facilitate the firming operations described herein. For example, the set of tread portions may include tines <b>442</b>. A given tine <b>442</b> may be defined by a cylindrical metal component, such as rod, that is bent or configured in a manner to define the tread portion of tracks of the modular press wheel <b>400</b>. In the example of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>A and <b>4</b>B</figref>, the tines <b>442</b> may be configured to define a V-shape with a first tine portion <b>443</b><i>a </i>and a second tine portion <b>443</b><i>b </i>extend from a tine center <b>444</b>. The tine <b>442</b> may be connected to the outer curved surface <b>434</b> at the tine center <b>444</b>. For example, the tine center <b>444</b> may be seated in a respective one of the slots <b>436</b> and welded or otherwise connected to the mounting portion <b>432</b> at the slot <b>436</b>. Each of the tine portions <b>434</b><i>a, </i><b>434</b><i>b </i>may extend from the tine center <b>442</b> and generally away from a center axis or center plane of the mounting portion <b>432</b> (e.g., a plane that may be defined by one or both of the surfaces <b>433</b>, <b>435</b>). For example, the tine portions <b>434</b><i>a, </i><b>434</b><i>b </i>may extend away from the center plane in one or more of a radial direction, an axial direction, or tangential direction such that one or both of the tine portions <b>434</b><i>a, </i><b>434</b><i>b </i>define a chord relative to a radial surface (e.g., surface <b>433</b>, <b>435</b>) of the modular press wheel <b>400</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">In the example of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>A and <b>4</b>B</figref>, the mounting portion <b>432</b> is shown connected with three tines <b>442</b>, each separated by a void <b>445</b>. This arrangement, in combination with the directional configuration of the tine portions <b>434</b><i>a, </i><b>434</b><i>b, </i>may allow the modular press wheel <b>400</b> to have multiple points of contact with soil during rotation. As one example, terminal ends of the tine portions <b>434</b><i>a, </i><b>434</b><i>b </i>may contact the soil at a substantially common point with a tine center of an adjacent tine. In this regard, at least some portion of adjacent tines, or adjacent tread portions more generally, may contact the ground at a common time during rotation of the modular press wheel <b>400</b>. In other cases, other shape and orientations of the tines and tread portions are possible, as shown and described below with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>7</b>A-<b>8</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">With continued reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>B</figref>, the second rim feature <b>450</b> is shown including a second mounting portion <b>452</b>, including ends <b>453</b><i>a, </i><b>453</b><i>b, </i>and a second set of tread portions <b>460</b>, which may be substantially analogous to the mounting portion <b>432</b> and the tread portions <b>440</b>. Further, the third rim feature <b>470</b> is shown including a third mounting portion <b>472</b>, including ends <b>473</b><i>a, </i><b>473</b><i>b, </i>and a third set of tread portions <b>776</b>, which may be substantially analogous to the mounting portion <b>432</b> and the tread portions <b>440</b>. Further, the fourth rim feature <b>480</b> is shown including a fourth mounting portion <b>482</b>, including ends <b>483</b><i>a, </i><b>483</b><i>b, </i>and a fourth set of tread portion <b>486</b>, which may be substantially analogous to the mounting portion <b>432</b> and the tread portions <b>440</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">In the exploded view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>B</figref>, a fastener <b>420</b> is also shown. The fastener <b>420</b> may be configured to facilitate the removably coupling of one or more of the rim features with the hub <b>402</b>. In this regard, the fastener <b>420</b> is shown as including a bolt <b>421</b> and nut <b>422</b>. The bolt <b>422</b> may be an elongated bolt with a threaded end. The nut <b>422</b> may be configured for threadable engagement with the bolt <b>421</b> at the treaded end.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">The modular press wheel <b>400</b> may be coupled with the rim features <b>430</b>, <b>450</b>, <b>470</b>, <b>480</b> removably attached to the hub <b>402</b>. With continued reference to the first rim feature <b>430</b>, the first rim feature <b>430</b> may be arranged such that the mounting portion <b>432</b> defines a lap joint or overlap with a portion of the hub <b>402</b>, as shown in the cross-sectional view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>C</figref>. For example, one or both of the surfaces <b>405</b>, <b>407</b> of the hub <b>402</b> may define a rim feature engagement surface. Further, one or both of the surfaces <b>433</b>, <b>435</b> of the mounting portion <b>432</b> may define a hub engagement surface. The first rim feature <b>430</b> and the hub <b>402</b> may be arranged overlapped and contacting along the rim feature engagement surface and the hub engagement surface. The first rim feature <b>430</b> and the hub <b>402</b> may be arranged in order to align the plurality of hub holes <b>410</b> with the plurality of mounting portion holes <b>438</b>. The fastener <b>420</b> may then be advanced through an aligned pair of the holes (e.g., holes <b>410</b><i>a, </i><b>438</b><i>a</i>) in order to removably secure the first rim feature <b>430</b> to the hub <b>402</b>. Additional fasteners may be used to secure the first rim feature <b>430</b> to the hub <b>402</b> at each of aligned pairs of holes. With the first rim feature <b>430</b> removably attached to the hub <b>402</b>, the tread portions <b>440</b> may define the circumferential portion <b>406</b><i>a </i>of the modular press wheel <b>400</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>A</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">The second rim feature <b>450</b> may be removably coupled to the hub <b>402</b> in a similar manner such that the second set of tread portions <b>460</b> defines the circumferential portion <b>406</b><i>b </i>of the modular press wheel <b>400</b>. The third rim feature <b>470</b> may be removably coupled to the hub <b>402</b> in a similar manner such that the third set of tread portions <b>476</b> defines the circumferential portion <b>406</b><i>c </i>of the modular press wheel <b>400</b>. The fourth rim feature <b>480</b> may be removably coupled to the hub <b>402</b> in a similar manner such that the fourth set of tread portions <b>486</b> defines the circumferential portion <b>406</b><i>d </i>of the modular press wheel.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">The rim features <b>430</b>, <b>450</b>, <b>470</b>, <b>480</b> may be arranged end to end to define a complete circumference of the modular press wheel <b>400</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>A</figref>. For example, the first and second rim features <b>430</b>, <b>450</b> may be removably coupled to the hub <b>402</b> with ends <b>439</b><i>b, </i><b>453</b><i>a </i>adjacent one another to define the circumferential portions <b>406</b><i>a, </i><b>406</b><i>b </i>as adjacent circumferential portions. Further, the second and third rim feature <b>450</b>, <b>470</b> may be removably coupled to the hub <b>402</b> with ends <b>453</b><i>b, </i><b>473</b><i>a </i>adjacent one another to define the circumferential portions <b>406</b><i>b, </i><b>406</b><i>c </i>as adjacent circumferential portions. Further, the third and fourth rim features <b>470</b>, <b>480</b> may be removably coupled to the hub <b>402</b> with ends <b>473</b><i>b, </i><b>483</b><i>a </i>adjacent one another to define the circumferential portions <b>406</b><i>c, </i><b>406</b><i>d </i>as adjacent circumferential portions. Further, the fourth and the first rim features <b>480</b>, <b>430</b> may be removably coupled with the hub <b>402</b> with ends <b>483</b><i>b, </i><b>439</b><i>a </i>adjacent one another to define the circumferential portions <b>406</b><i>d, </i><b>406</b><i>a </i>as adjacent circumferential portions.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>A</figref>, each of the rim features <b>430</b>, <b>450</b>, <b>470</b>, <b>480</b> may overlap and extend beyond the edge <b>408</b> of the hub <b>402</b>. In this regard, the diameter of the modular press wheel <b>400</b> may be defined by the size of the rim features <b>430</b>, <b>450</b>, <b>470</b>, <b>480</b>. Further, size and shape of the tread portion of the modular press wheel <b>400</b> may be defined by size and shape of respective tread portions of the rim features <b>430</b>, <b>450</b>, <b>470</b>, <b>480</b> described herein. The modular press wheels described herein may be configured such that a diameter of the press wheel and/or a size or shape of respective tread portions may be changed. For example, differently size and/or shaped modular rim features may be swapped out with any one of the rim features <b>430</b>, <b>450</b>, <b>470</b>, <b>480</b> described above in order to form a modular press wheel having a different diameter and/or a different size or shape of tread portions.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">For example, and with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>5</b>A and <b>5</b>B</figref>, a press wheel <b>500</b> is shown. The press wheel <b>500</b> may be substantially analogous to the press wheel <b>400</b> and include a hub <b>502</b> and rim features <b>530</b>, <b>550</b>, <b>570</b>, <b>580</b>. The hub <b>502</b> may be a universal hub and may have size and shape that is substantially the same as the hub <b>402</b> described in relation to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>A and <b>4</b>B</figref>. In this regard, the hub <b>502</b> may include a first surface <b>505</b>, a second surface <b>507</b>, an outer circumferential edge <b>508</b>, an axial hole <b>509</b>, a plurality of hubs holes <b>510</b>, such as a hub hole <b>510</b><i>a; </i>redundant explanation of which is omitted here for clarity. Further, the first rim feature <b>530</b> may be a modular component similar to the first rim feature <b>430</b> described in relation to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>A and <b>4</b>B</figref>. In this regard, the first rim feature <b>530</b> may include a mounting portion <b>532</b>, a set of tread portions <b>540</b>, a first surface <b>533</b>, a second surface <b>535</b>, an inner curved surface <b>537</b>, an outer curved surface <b>534</b>, ends <b>539</b><i>a, </i><b>539</b><i>b, </i>slots <b>536</b>, an plurality of mounting holes <b>538</b>, including hole <b>538</b><i>a, </i>tines <b>542</b>, tine centers <b>544</b>, first tine portion <b>534</b><i>a, </i>second tine portion <b>534</b><i>b</i>, and voids <b>545</b>; redundant explanation of which is omitted here for clarity.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">The second rim feature <b>550</b> may be substantially analogous to the first rim feature <b>530</b> and include a mounting portion <b>552</b>, a tread portion <b>560</b>, and ends <b>553</b><i>a, </i><b>553</b><i>b. </i>The third rim feature <b>570</b> may be substantially analogous to the first rim feature <b>530</b> and include a mounting portion <b>572</b>, a set of tread portions <b>576</b>, and ends <b>573</b><i>a, </i><b>573</b><i>b. </i>The fourth rim feature <b>580</b> may be substantially analogous to the first rim feature <b>580</b> and include a mounting portion <b>582</b>, a set of tread portion <b>586</b>, and ends <b>583</b><i>a, </i><b>583</b><i>b. </i>The tread portion <b>540</b> of the first rim feature <b>530</b> may define a first circumferential portion <b>506</b><i>a </i>of the modular press wheel <b>500</b> when removably attached to the hub <b>502</b>. The tread portion <b>560</b> of the second rim feature <b>560</b> may define a second circumferential portion <b>506</b><i>b </i>of the modular press wheel <b>500</b> when removably attached to the hub <b>502</b>. The tread portion <b>576</b> of the third rim feature <b>570</b> may define a third circumferential portion <b>506</b><i>c </i>of the modular press wheel <b>500</b> when removably attached to the hub <b>502</b>. The tread portion <b>586</b> of the fourth rim feature <b>580</b> may define a fourth circumferential portion <b>506</b><i>d </i>of the modular press wheel <b>500</b> when removably attached to the hub <b>502</b>. The rim features <b>530</b>, <b>550</b>, <b>570</b>, <b>580</b> may be removably attached using fasteners <b>520</b>, including a threaded bolt <b>521</b> and nut <b>522</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">Notwithstanding the foregoing similarities, the rim features <b>530</b>, <b>550</b>, <b>570</b>, <b>580</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>5</b>A and <b>5</b>B</figref> may be larger than the rim features <b>430</b>, <b>450</b>, <b>470</b>, <b>480</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>A and <b>4</b>B</figref>. For example, the mounting portion <b>532</b> of the first rim feature <b>530</b> may have a larger radial dimension such that the inner curved surface <b>537</b> the outer curved surface <b>534</b> are further away from one another. As such, upon removably attachment of the first rim feature <b>530</b> to the hub <b>502</b> (which may be the same as the hub <b>402</b>), the mounting portion <b>532</b> extends beyond the circumferential edge <b>508</b> of the hub <b>502</b> by a greater amount, thereby increasing the diameter of the modular press wheel <b>500</b>, as compared to the modular press wheel <b>400</b>. The rim features <b>550</b>, <b>570</b>, <b>580</b> may have a similar size as the rim feature <b>530</b> so that the rim features <b>530</b>, <b>570</b>, <b>580</b>, collectively, form the larger diameter of the modular press wheel <b>500</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">The rim features <b>530</b>, <b>550</b>, <b>570</b>, <b>580</b> are shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>5</b>A and <b>5</b>B</figref> as having tread portions of generally similar size and shape as compared to the tread portions of the corresponding rim features of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>A and <b>4</b>B</figref>. It will be appreciated, however, that the rim features may have any appropriate tread pattern, size, and/or shape, as may be required for a particular application. For example, a rim feature may have tread portions that are smaller or larger than the tread portions shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>A-<b>5</b>B</figref>. Further, a rim feature may have tread portions that are more or less densely arranged as compared to the tread portions shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>A-<b>5</b>B</figref>. Further, a rim feature may have tread portions that are differently shaped as compared to the tread portions shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>A-<b>5</b>B</figref>. In other cases, other variations of the tread portions are possible. This may allow a farmer or other user to change one modular rim feature for another in order to change the size or type of tread portions without replacing the entire press wheel.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">In another example, the modular press wheel of the present disclosure may be configured to define a press wheel having a first diameter in a first configuration and a second diameter in a second configuration. The first and second diameters may be defined using the same set of a hub and accompanying rim features. For example, and with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b>A-<b>6</b>C</figref>, a press wheel <b>600</b> is shown. With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref>, the press wheel <b>600</b> is shown in a first configuration in which the press wheel <b>600</b> has a first diameter. The press wheel <b>600</b> may be adaptable or modifiable to define a second diameter in a second configuration, as shown with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>C</figref>, using the same or same-sized components as that shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">Initially, the press wheel <b>600</b> may be substantially analogous to the press wheel <b>400</b> and include a hub <b>602</b> and rim features <b>630</b>, <b>650</b>, <b>670</b>, <b>680</b>. The hub <b>602</b> may be a universal hub and may have size and shape that is substantially the same as the hub <b>402</b> described in relation to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>A and <b>4</b>B</figref>. In this regard, the hub <b>602</b> may include a first surface <b>605</b>, a second surface <b>607</b>, an outer circumferential edge <b>608</b>, an axial hole <b>609</b>, a plurality of hubs holes <b>610</b>, such as a hub holes <b>610</b><i>a; </i>redundant explanation of which is omitted here for clarity. Further, the first rim feature <b>630</b> may be a modular component similar to the first rim feature <b>630</b> described in relation to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>A and <b>4</b>B</figref>. In this regard, the first rim feature <b>630</b> may include a mounting portion <b>632</b>, a set of tread portions <b>640</b>, a first surface <b>633</b>, a second surface <b>635</b>, an inner curved surface <b>637</b>, an outer curved surface <b>634</b>, ends <b>639</b><i>a, </i><b>639</b><i>b, </i>slots <b>636</b>, an plurality of mounting holes <b>638</b>, including hole <b>638</b><i>a, </i>tines <b>642</b>, tine centers <b>644</b>, first tine portion <b>634</b><i>a, </i>second tine portion <b>634</b><i>b</i>, and voids <b>645</b>; redundant explanation of which is omitted here for clarity.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">The second rim feature <b>650</b> may be substantially analogous to the first rim feature <b>630</b> and include a mounting portion <b>652</b>, a tread portion <b>660</b>, and ends <b>653</b><i>a, </i><b>653</b><i>b. </i>The third rim feature <b>670</b> may be substantially analogous to the first rim feature <b>630</b> and include a mounting portion <b>672</b>, a set of tread portions <b>676</b>, and ends <b>673</b><i>a, </i><b>673</b><i>b. </i>The fourth rim feature <b>680</b> may be substantially analogous to the first rim feature <b>680</b> and include a mounting portion <b>682</b>, a set of tread portion <b>686</b>, and ends <b>683</b><i>a, </i><b>683</b><i>b. </i>The tread portion <b>640</b> of the first rim feature <b>630</b> may define a first circumferential portion <b>606</b><i>a </i>of the modular press wheel <b>600</b> when removably attached to the hub <b>602</b>. The tread portion <b>660</b> of the second rim feature <b>660</b> may define a second circumferential portion <b>606</b><i>b </i>of the modular press wheel <b>600</b> when removably attached to the hub <b>602</b>. The tread portion <b>676</b> of the third rim feature <b>670</b> may define a third circumferential portion <b>606</b><i>c </i>of the modular press wheel <b>600</b> when removably attached to the hub <b>602</b>. The tread portion <b>686</b> of the fourth rim feature <b>680</b> may define a fourth circumferential portion <b>606</b><i>d </i>of the modular press wheel <b>600</b> when removably attached to the hub <b>602</b>. The rim features <b>630</b>, <b>650</b>, <b>670</b>, <b>680</b> may be removably attached using fasteners <b>620</b>, including a threaded bolt <b>621</b> and nut <b>622</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">Notwithstanding the foregoing similarities, the press wheel <b>600</b> may be configured to transition between the first configuration of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref> (in which the press wheel <b>600</b> has a first, smaller diameter), to the second configuration of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>C</figref> (in which the press wheel <b>600</b> has a second, larger diameter). The press wheel <b>600</b> may be configured to transition between the first and second diameters using the same or similarly-sized components in each configuration. In order to facilitate the foregoing, the hub <b>602</b> may include at least two generally concentric rings of hub holes. For example, the plurality of hub holes <b>610</b><i>a </i>may be a first plurality of hub holes that define a first ring of hub holes about a rotational axis of the hub <b>602</b>. Further, a second plurality of hub holes <b>610</b><i>b </i>may define a second ring of hub holes about the rotational axis of the hub <b>602</b>. The second plurality of hub holes <b>610</b><i>b </i>may define the ring of hub holes generally around the first plurality of hub holes <b>610</b><i>a. </i>For example, the ring defined by the second plurality of hub holes <b>610</b><i>b </i>may generally have a diameter that is larger than a diameter of the ring that is defined by the first plurality of hub holes <b>610</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">In order to define the first configuration having the first diameter of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref>, the rim features <b>630</b>, <b>650</b>, <b>670</b>, <b>680</b> may be coupled to the hub <b>602</b> at respective holes of the plurality of hub holes <b>610</b><i>a. </i>For example, the diameter of the press wheel <b>600</b> may be based on the position of the rim features <b>630</b>, <b>650</b>, <b>670</b>, <b>680</b> as defined relative to the hub <b>602</b>. In this regard, the rim features <b>630</b>, <b>650</b>, <b>670</b>, <b>680</b> may define a first diameter of the press wheel based on the relatively smaller diameter defined by the first plurality of hub holes <b>610</b><i>a. </i>Further, in order to define the second configuration having the second diameter of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>C</figref>, the rim features <b>630</b>, <b>650</b>, <b>670</b>, <b>680</b> may be coupled to the hub <b>602</b> at respective holes of the plurality of hub holes <b>610</b><i>b. </i>As described above, the diameter of the press wheel <b>600</b> may be based on the position of the rim features <b>630</b>, <b>650</b>, <b>670</b>, <b>680</b> as defined relative to the hub <b>602</b>. In this regard, the rim features <b>630</b>, <b>650</b>, <b>670</b>, <b>680</b> may define a second diameter of the press wheel based on the relatively larger diameter defined by the second plurality of hub holes <b>610</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">In some cases, gaps may be defined between adjacent rim features <b>630</b>, <b>650</b>, <b>670</b>, <b>680</b> along the circumference of the modular wheel in the second configuration of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>C</figref>. In this regard, plates, inserts, and/other features, such as those attached by a welds, bolts and/or other fastening techniques may be connected to the hub <b>602</b> at the gaps. Accordingly, the inserts may operate to fill in a portion of a given gap, which may add strength and rigidity to the modular wheel <b>600</b>. For example, the inserts may be connected to the hub <b>602</b> and extend therefrom to the outer circumference of the modular wheel <b>600</b> that is defined by the rim features <b>630</b>, <b>650</b>, <b>670</b>, <b>680</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>7</b>A-<b>7</b>G</figref> different variations of tread portions are shown. It will be appreciated that any of the tread portions shown with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>7</b>A-<b>7</b>G</figref> may be used in the modular press wheels shown above in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>A-<b>6</b>C</figref>. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>A</figref>, a rim feature <b>700</b><i>a </i>is shown having a mounting portion <b>704</b><i>a </i>and a tread portion <b>708</b><i>a. </i>The tread portion <b>708</b><i>a </i>may be defined by a series of V-shaped tines <b>712</b><i>a. </i>The tines <b>712</b><i>a </i>may have any appropriate length and spacing, as may be required for a given application. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>B</figref>, a rim feature <b>700</b><i>b </i>is shown having a mounting portion <b>704</b><i>b </i>and a tread portion <b>708</b><i>b. </i>The tread portion <b>708</b><i>b </i>may be defined by a series of one-sided tines <b>712</b><i>b </i>that extend from a right-hand side of the mounting portion <b>704</b><i>b. </i>The tines <b>712</b><i>b </i>may have any appropriate length and spacing, as may be required for a given application. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>C</figref>, a rim feature <b>700</b><i>c </i>is shown having a mounting portion <b>704</b><i>c </i>and a tread portion <b>708</b><i>c. </i>The tread portion <b>708</b><i>c </i>may be defined by a series of one-sided tines <b>712</b><i>c </i>that extend from a left-hand side of the mounting portion <b>704</b><i>c. </i>The tines <b>712</b><i>c </i>may have any appropriate length and spacing, as may be required for a given application. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>D</figref>, a rim feature <b>700</b><i>d </i>is shown having a mounting portion <b>704</b><i>d </i>and a tread portion <b>708</b><i>d. </i>The tread portion <b>708</b><i>d </i>may be defined by series of alternating short V-shaped tines <b>712</b><i>d </i>and long V-shaped tines <b>712</b><i>d</i>&#x2032;. The tines <b>712</b><i>d, </i><b>712</b><i>d</i>&#x2032; may have any appropriate length and spacing, as may be required for a given application.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>E</figref>, a rim feature <b>700</b><i>e </i>is shown having a mounting portion <b>704</b><i>e </i>and a tread portion <b>708</b><i>e. </i>The tread portion <b>708</b><i>e </i>may be defined by a series of tines <b>712</b><i>e </i>that are alternatingly disposed along either side of the mounting portion <b>704</b><i>e. </i>For example, a first tine <b>714</b><i>a </i>of the series of tines <b>712</b><i>e </i>may be disposed to extend from a first side <b>702</b><i>e </i>of the mounting portion <b>704</b><i>e, </i>a second tine <b>716</b><i>e </i>of the series of tines <b>712</b><i>e </i>may be disposed to extend from a second side <b>701</b><i>e </i>of the mounting portion <b>704</b><i>e, </i>a third tine <b>718</b><i>e </i>of the series of tines <b>712</b><i>e </i>may be disposed to extend from the first side <b>702</b><i>e </i>of the mounting portion <b>704</b><i>e, </i>and so on, as may be appropriate for a given configuration of the modular assembly. Further, the series of tines <b>712</b><i>e </i>may be staggered along the mounting portion <b>704</b><i>e, </i>such that each tine is offset from an adjacent tine. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>E</figref>, the first tine <b>714</b><i>e </i>may be separated from the second tine <b>716</b><i>e </i>by an offset <b>703</b><i>e. </i>Further, at a circumferential position of the first tine <b>714</b><i>e </i>on the mounting portion <b>704</b><i>e, </i>there may be no tine extending from the second side <b>701</b><i>e. </i>Further, at a circumferential position of the second tine <b>716</b><i>e </i>on the mounting portion <b>704</b><i>e, </i>there may no tine extending from the first side <b>702</b><i>e. </i>Further, at the circumferential position of the third tine <b>718</b><i>e </i>on the mounting portion <b>704</b><i>e, </i>there may be no tine extending from the second side <b>701</b><i>e, </i>and so along the circumference of the mounting portion <b>704</b><i>e. </i>In this regard, the series of tines <b>712</b><i>e </i>may cooperate to form a staggered tine pattern with adjacent tines of the series extending from opposing sides of the mounting portion <b>704</b><i>e, </i>as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>E</figref>. The tines <b>712</b><i>e </i>may have any appropriate length and spacing, as may be required for a given application.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>F</figref>, a rim feature <b>700</b><i>f </i>is shown having a mounting portion <b>704</b><i>f </i>and a tread portion <b>708</b><i>f. </i>The tread portion <b>708</b><i>f </i>may be defined by a series of V-shaped tines <b>712</b><i>f. </i>The tines <b>712</b><i>f </i>may have any appropriate length and spacing, as may be required for a given application. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>F</figref>, the mounting portion <b>704</b><i>f </i>may define a first side <b>701</b><i>f </i>and a second side <b>702</b><i>f </i>that is generally opposite the first side <b>701</b><i>f. </i>The mounting portion <b>704</b><i>f </i>may further define a series of cupped or scalloped features <b>716</b><i>f. </i>The scalloped features <b>716</b> may be generally concave indents or grooves formed into the mounting portion <b>704</b><i>f </i>at the first side <b>701</b><i>f. </i>In the example of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>F</figref>, a single scalloped feature <b>716</b><i>f </i>is shown defined between adjacent times <b>712</b><i>f, </i>all of which are at the first side <b>701</b><i>f. </i>In this regard, the second side <b>702</b><i>f </i>may have a flat or generally smooth contour. In other examples, scalloped features <b>716</b> may additionally or alternatively be defined in at the second side <b>702</b><i>f, </i>including variations in which multiple scalloped features <b>716</b><i>f </i>are defined between adjacent tines <b>716</b><i>f. </i>In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>G</figref>, a rim feature <b>700</b><i>g </i>is shown having a mounting portion <b>704</b><i>g </i>and a tread portion <b>708</b><i>g. </i>The tread portion <b>708</b><i>g </i>may be defined by a series of V-shaped tines <b>712</b><i>g. </i>The tines <b>712</b><i>g </i>may have any appropriate length and spacing, as may be required for a given application. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>G</figref>, the mounting portion <b>704</b><i>g </i>may include an outer periphery <b>706</b><i>g. </i>The outer periphery <b>706</b><i>g </i>may define a scalloped features <b>716</b><i>g </i>that extend into a body of the mounting portion <b>704</b><i>g. </i>For example, the scalloped feature <b>716</b><i>g </i>may be concave grooved or indented feature that are cut or scalloped into the mounting portion <b>704</b><i>g </i>at the outer periphery <b>706</b><i>g. </i>In the example of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>G</figref>, a single scalloped portion <b>716</b> is shown extend between adjacent tines <b>712</b><i>g. </i>In other cases more or fewer scalloped features and/or scalloped features may be defined by the outer periphery <b>706</b><i>g </i>as may be appropriate for a given application. In other examples, other configuration and arrangement of the tines are possible and contemplated herein.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">In other examples a shape of the mounting portion may be modified. For example, rather than a substantially flat plate, the mounting portion may be a complex, wavy, and/or irregular shape, which may by formed from a casting process. For example, and as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref>, a rim feature <b>800</b> may include a mounting portion <b>804</b> connected to a set of tread portion <b>808</b> that are defined by V-shaped tines <b>812</b>. The mounting portion <b>804</b> may have a wavy shape or other curvature.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">The hub <b>402</b> and the hub <b>502</b> are shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>A-<b>6</b></figref><i>c </i>above as being substantially the same component of similar size and shape. The modular press wheel of the present disclosure may include various other hubs based on a given application. For example, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref> shows a hub <b>900</b>. The hub <b>900</b> may be formed from a sheet of metal <b>901</b> and have an outer circumferential surface <b>902</b> and an axial hole <b>904</b>. A plurality of hub holes <b>906</b> may be formed through the sheet <b>901</b> and be configured for removably coupling modular components of a given modular press wheel. Notwithstanding the foregoing, the hub <b>900</b> is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref> as including cutouts <b>908</b>. The cutouts <b>908</b> may be formed through a complete thickness of the sheet <b>901</b>. In some cases, the cutouts <b>908</b> may be configured to reduce an overall weight of the hub <b>900</b> and associated press wheel. In other examples, other configurations of the hub <b>902</b> are possible.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">One or more components of the modular press wheels described herein may be manufactured from a single sheet of material. For example, and with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref>, a single sheet of metal material <b>1000</b> is shown. In the present example, the single sheet <b>1000</b> may be used to form multiple mounting portions of a modular press wheel. For example, the single sheet <b>1000</b> is show as including an outline for (shown in dash line), a first mounting portion <b>1002</b><i>a, </i>a second mounting portion <b>1002</b><i>b, </i>a third mounting portion <b>1002</b><i>c, </i>a fourth mounting portion <b>1002</b><i>d, </i>a fifth mounting portion <b>1002</b><i>e, </i>a sixth mounting portion <b>1002</b><i>f, </i>a seventh mounting portion <b>1002</b><i>g, </i>an eighth mounting portion <b>1002</b><i>h, </i>a ninth mounting portion <b>1002</b><i>i, </i>a tenth mounting portion <b>1002</b><i>j, </i>an eleventh mounting portion <b>1002</b><i>k, </i>and a twelfth mounting portion <b>1002</b><i>l</i>. In this regard, the single sheet of material <b>1000</b> may be used to produce twelve mounting portions, which may reduce material reduce and manufacturing costs.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">To facilitate the reader's understanding of the various functionalities of the examples discussed herein, reference is now made to the flow diagram in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b></figref>, which illustrates process <b>1100</b>. While specific steps (and orders of steps) of the methods presented herein have been illustrated and will be discussed, other methods (including more, fewer, or different steps than those illustrated) consistent with the teachings presented herein are also envisioned and encompassed with the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">At operation <b>1104</b>, a first mounting portion is uncoupled from a predetermined mounting location of a hub of modular press wheel. The first mounting portion may have a first size and connected to a first plurality of tread portions. The first plurality of tread portions may define a circumferential portion of the press wheel. For example, and with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>A</figref>, the mounting portion <b>432</b> may be uncoupled from the hub <b>402</b>. The mounting portion <b>432</b> may have a first, smaller size, and have the set of tread portions <b>440</b> that define the circumferential portion <b>406</b><i>a. </i>The mounting portion <b>432</b> may be uncoupled from the hub <b>402</b> may loosening the faster <b>420</b> such that the mounting portion <b>432</b> may be separated from the hub <b>402</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">At operation <b>1108</b>, a second mounting portion is coupled to the predetermined mounting location of the hub. The second mounting portion may have a second size and connected to a second plurality of tread portions. The second plurality of tread portions may define the circumferential portion upon the coupling of the second mounting portion of the predetermined mounting location. For example, and with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>A-<b>5</b>B</figref>, the mounting portion <b>530</b> may be coupled to the hub <b>402</b>. The mounting portion <b>530</b> may have a second, larger size, and have the set of tread portions <b>540</b>. Accordingly, upon coupling the mounting portion <b>530</b> to the hub <b>402</b>, the modular press wheel may exhibit the second size, with the tread portions <b>540</b> defining the circumferential portion <b>506</b><i>a. </i>The mounting portion <b>530</b> may be coupled to the hub <b>402</b> may extending the fastener through an aligned pair of holes of the mounting portion <b>530</b> and holes of the hub <b>402</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">Other examples and implementations are within the scope and spirit of the disclosure and appended claims. For example, features implementing functions may also be physically located at various positions, including being distributed such that portions of functions are implemented at different physical locations. Thus, the foregoing descriptions of the specific examples described herein are presented for purposes of illustration and description. They are not targeted to be exhaustive or to limit the examples to the precise forms disclosed. It will be apparent to one of ordinary skill in the art that many modifications and variations are possible in view of the above teachings.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A modular press wheel comprising
<claim-text>a hub configured to rotate about an axis;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first rim feature comprising
<claim-text>a first mounting portion removably attachable to the hub, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first set of tread portions connected to the first mounting portion and configured</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>to define a first circumferential portion of the modular press wheel; and
<claim-text>a second rim feature comprising
<claim-text>a second mounting portion removably attachable to the hub, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second set of tread portions connected to the second mounting portion and configured to define a second circumferential portion of the modular press wheel.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The modular press wheel of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein, for at least the first set of tread portions, each tread portion of the first set of tread portions comprises a tine extending away from a center plane of the first mounting portion, wherein the center plane is substantially perpendicular to the axis upon removable attachment of the first rim feature with the hub.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The modular press wheel of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the tine defines a chord relative to a radial surface of the first mounting portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The modular press wheel of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>at least the first mounting portion comprises a first mounting plate having an inner curved edge, and an outer curved edge opposite the inner curved edge, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first set of tread portions are connected to the first mounting plate along the outer curved edge.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The modular press wheel of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the hub comprises a rim feature engagement surface,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first mounting plate comprises hub engagement surface extending from the inner curved edge to the outer curved edge, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the hub and the first mounting portion are removably attachable to one another via a lap joint defined along a portion of the rim feature engagement surface and a portion of the hub engagement surface.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The modular press wheel of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the hub comprises a series of hub holes circumferentially spaced about the axis, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first mounting plate comprises a series of first mounting plate holes circumferentially spaced about the axis and alignable with the series of hub holes, upon removable attachment of the first mounting plate with the hub.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The modular press wheel of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, further comprising a fastener configured to removably attach the hub and the first mounting plate and advanceable through an aligned pair of a hub hole of the series of hub holes and a first mounting plate hole of the series of first mounting plate holes.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The modular press wheel of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein, upon removable attachment of the hub and the first mounting portion, the outer curved edge extends beyond an outermost circumferential edge of the hub.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The modular press wheel of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first and second circumferential portions are adjacent circumferential portions of the modular press wheel.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. A modular press wheel comprising
<claim-text>a hub configured to rotate about an axis;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mounting portion removably attachable to the hub and having a center plane substantially perpendicular to the axis upon removable attachment with the hub; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of tread portions connected to the mounting portion and configured to define a circumferential portion of the modular press wheel, the plurality of tread portions having voids between adjacent tread portions, wherein each tread portion of the plurality of tread portions comprises a tine extending away from the center plane.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The modular press wheel of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the mounting portion is one of a set of mounting portions, each mounting portion of the set of mounting portions removably attachable with the hub and connected with a corresponding plurality of tines that cooperate to define a complete circumferential portion of the modular press wheel.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The modular press wheel of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the set of mounting portions comprises four mounting portions, each mounting portion of the four mounting portions having a common arcuate shape that is configured to establish the four mounting portions in a substantially circular shape when the four mounting portions are arranged end to end with one another.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. The modular press wheel of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein each mounting portion of the set of mounting portions contacts one or more adjacent mounting portions upon removable attachment of the mounting portion with the hub.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The modular press wheel of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein a shape or a size of the tine of the respective tread portion varies along the circumferential portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. The modular press wheel of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the mounting portion comprises a mounting plate defining a series of slots along an outermost circumferential edge of the mounting portion, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the plurality of tread portions are connected to the mounting portion via welds formed between a slot of the series of slot the tine of the respective tread portion.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. The modular press wheel of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the mounting portion is a first mounting portion have a first size,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the plurality of tread portions is a first plurality of tread portions,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the modular press wheel further comprises
<claim-text>a second mounting portion having a second size and removably attachable to the hub and connected with a second plurality of tread portions,</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>in a first configuration, the first mounting portion is removably attached to the hub at a predetermined mounting location with the first plurality of tread portions spaced apart from the axis based on the first size of the first mounting portion, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>in a second configuration, the second mounting is removably attached to the hub at the predetermined mounting location with the second plurality of tread portions spaced apart from the axis based on the second size of the second mounting portion, the second size larger than the first size.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. A method for modifying a modular press wheel, the method comprising
<claim-text>uncoupling a first mounting portion from a predetermined mounting location of a hub of the modular press wheel, the first mounting portion have a first size and connected to a first plurality of tread portions, the first plurality of tread portions defining a circumferential portion of the modular press wheel; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>coupling a second mounting portion to the predetermined mounting location of the hub, the second mounting portion having a second size and connected to a second plurality of tread portions, the second plurality of tread portions defining the circumferential portion upon the coupling of the second mounting portion of the predetermined mounting location.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein the second size is larger than the first size such that the coupling of the second mounting portion to the predetermined mounting location increases a radius of the modular press wheel.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein the second plurality of tread portions has a different size, shape or arrangement than the first plurality of tread portions such that the coupling of the second mounting portion to the predetermined mounting location changes the size, shape, or arrangement of tread portions along the circumferential portion of the modular press wheel.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>uncoupling the first mounting portion further comprises loosening a fastener and removing the fastener from an aligned pair of a hub hole of the hub and a first mounting portion hole of the first mounting portion, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>coupling the second mounting portion further comprises extending the fastener through an aligned pair of the hub hole and a second mounting portion hole of the second mounting portion.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
