<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225488A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225488</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17825418</doc-number>
<date>20220526</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>17</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>45</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>45</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>021</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>45</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>2200</main-group>
<subgroup>0575</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>B</section>
<class>25</class>
<subclass>H</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>006</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Hammer Holder</invention-title>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>63300962</doc-number>
<date>20220119</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Gioia</last-name>
<first-name>Constantine Michael</first-name>
<address>
<city>West Columbia</city>
<state>SC</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="01" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Gioia</last-name>
<first-name>Valeska N.</first-name>
<address>
<city>West Columbia</city>
<state>SC</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Gioia</last-name>
<first-name>Constantine Michael</first-name>
<address>
<city>West Columbia</city>
<state>SC</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="01" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Gioia</last-name>
<first-name>Valeska N.</first-name>
<address>
<city>West Columbia</city>
<state>SC</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The hammer holder is a device used to secure a hammer to a user when not in use. The hammer holder comprises a rigid conduit attached to a mounting panel. The rigid conduit further comprises an expanded aperture, an elongated slot, and a constricted aperture. The expanded aperture and the constricted aperture are oppositely and terminally positioned on the rigid conduit, connected by the elongated slot. The placement and dimensions of the components of the rigid conduit allow a hammer bell and neck to be inserted at the expanded aperture, slid through the elongated slot, and held at the constricted aperture.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="161.63mm" wi="115.99mm" file="US20230225488A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="193.89mm" wi="118.03mm" file="US20230225488A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="196.43mm" wi="134.45mm" file="US20230225488A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="172.89mm" wi="137.16mm" file="US20230225488A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="201.68mm" wi="131.74mm" file="US20230225488A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="185.25mm" wi="93.13mm" file="US20230225488A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="156.29mm" wi="129.54mm" file="US20230225488A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="192.28mm" wi="89.49mm" file="US20230225488A1-20230720-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="197.95mm" wi="69.68mm" file="US20230225488A1-20230720-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="150.11mm" wi="155.96mm" file="US20230225488A1-20230720-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention relates generally to a hammer holder. More specifically, the holder provides a cylindrical-shaped holder that can be mounted on a tool belt using an attachment plate.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Hammers have many uses, building construction, general carpentry, assembling furniture to name a few. Hammer holders are designed to secure the hammer to one's person, on a tool belt or apron and allow hands to be free till hammer is needed. Further, the hammer holder can be used while working in a location where there is no place to set the hammer down, such as on a ladder, lift, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">An objective of the present invention is to make the process of securing and or deploying a hammer as quick, simple, and easy as possible. Another objective of the present invention is to provide a hammer holder that can be mounted on the tool belt. The hammer holder provides a cylindrical-shaped holder that the user can secure the hammer. Utilizing the present invention, the hammer can be available anywhere and can be carried around without having the user hold the hammer. Additional features and benefits are further discussed in the sections below.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a top front isometric view of the hammer holder of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a rear bottom isometric view of the hammer holder of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a top front exploded perspective view of the hammer holder of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is a top front perspective view of an alternative embodiment of the hammer holder the present invention wherein the invention is configured for a left-handed use.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is a right-side elevation view of the hammer holder of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is a perspective view of the hammer holder of the present invention, showing an exemplary hammer entering the rigid conduit.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> is a perspective view of the hammer holder of the present invention, showing an exemplary hammer resting in the constricted aperture and the blocking assembly gate engaged with the rigid conduit.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> is a perspective view of the hammer holder of the present invention, showing an exemplary hammer resting in the constricted aperture and the blocking assembly gate engaged with the rigid conduit.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref> is a side elevation view of an exemplary hammer used with the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAIL DESCRIPTIONS OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">All illustrations of the drawings are for the purpose of describing selected versions of the present invention and are not intended to limit the scope of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The present invention provides a hammer holder. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>-<b>8</b></figref>, a user can secure a hammer <b>5</b> onto the present invention. The present invention allows the user to carry the hammer <b>5</b> anywhere and have it ready to use. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref>, traditional hammers <b>5</b> have many parts such as the face, bell <b>51</b>, neck <b>52</b>, cheek, claw, and handle. Unlike a conventional hammer holder, the present invention does not work with the hammer handle but with the bell <b>51</b>, face, and neck <b>52</b>. Utilizing the present invention, the hammer <b>5</b> can be secured or deployed quickly using all-natural hand movements. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, in a preferred embodiment, the present invention comprises a rigid conduit <b>1</b>, a mounting panel <b>2</b>, and at least one releasable fastener <b>4</b>. The rigid conduit <b>1</b> accommodates the hammer <b>5</b>. The holder is assembled with the mounting panel <b>2</b> using the at least one releasable fastener <b>4</b> and the assembly can be mounted on a work belt. In the other embodiments, the holder can be mounted on a tool apron or other garment.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The rigid conduit <b>1</b> provides a hollow cylindrical structure. The front of the rigid conduit <b>1</b> includes an expanded aperture <b>11</b>, while the rear of the rigid conduit <b>1</b> includes a constricted aperture <b>13</b>. The rigid conduit <b>1</b> comprises an elongated slot <b>12</b> that uniformly runs on top of the rigid conduit <b>1</b> from the expanded aperture <b>11</b> at the front to the constricted aperture <b>13</b> at the rear of the rigid conduit <b>1</b>. The constricted aperture <b>13</b> is slightly rounded. The elongated slot <b>12</b> runs down the rear, connecting to the rounded constricted aperture <b>13</b>. The constricted aperture <b>13</b> is where the hammer's neck <b>52</b> rests when the hammer is secured. Further, the rigid conduit <b>1</b> comprises a plurality of attachment holes on the middle portion of the left and right surfaces of the rigid conduit <b>1</b>. The plurality of attachment holes allows the rigid conduit <b>1</b> to be assembled with the mounting panel <b>2</b> on the desired side based on the user's preferences. In the preferred embodiment, all surfaces on the rigid conduit <b>1</b> are smooth, all edges are rounded. The holder can be adjusted for right- or left-handed users. As seen in FIG. , the holder is positioned for a left-handed user. The rigid conduit <b>1</b> may be made of, but is not limited to, PVC or Polypropylene material. In the preferred embodiment, the holder can hold the hammers from <b>12</b>oz to <b>28</b>oz. For larger hammers, a larger elongated slot <b>12</b> and expanded aperture <b>11</b> is required and the reverse for smaller hammers.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In order to correctly accommodate the hammer <b>5</b> in the rigid conduit <b>1</b>, the dimensions of the components of the rigid conduit <b>1</b> are specifically tailored to match the dimensions of the components of the hammer <b>5</b> being used. Specifically, the expanded aperture <b>11</b> has an expanded aperture diameter <b>14</b> and the constricted aperture <b>13</b> has a constricted aperture diameter <b>15</b>. The constricted aperture diameter <b>15</b> is generally the same length as the width of the elongated slot <b>12</b> and is smaller than the expanded aperture diameter <b>14</b>. The hammer <b>5</b> has a bell <b>51</b> with a bell diameter <b>53</b> and a neck <b>52</b> with a neck diameter <b>54</b>. In order for the hammer <b>5</b> to correctly engage with the rigid conduit <b>1</b>, the bell diameter <b>53</b> must be less than the expanded aperture diameter <b>14</b> and greater than the constricted aperture diameter <b>15</b>, while the neck diameter <b>54</b> must be less than the constricted aperture diameter <b>54</b>. This dimensional relationship between the hammer <b>5</b> and the rigid conduit <b>1</b> allows the hammer <b>5</b> to slide into the rigid conduit <b>1</b> without sliding out the back end of the rigid conduit <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">As can be seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, the mounting panel <b>2</b> provides a flat rectangular structure, although any desired shape and structure may be used. In the preferred embodiment, the mounting panel <b>2</b> comprises a plurality of attachment apertures. The plurality of attachment apertures is located on the lower portion of the mounting panel <b>2</b>. The plurality of attachment holes and the plurality of attachment apertures allow the mounting panel <b>2</b> to be assembled with the rigid conduit <b>1</b> using the at least one releasable fastener <b>4</b>. In the preferred embodiment, the mounting panel <b>2</b> is made of, but not limited to, plastic, leather, canvas, or other durable material. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, a belt clasp <b>21</b> may be attached to the mounting panel <b>2</b> opposite the rigid conduit <b>1</b>. In the preferred embodiment, the belt clasp <b>21</b> is a simple clip configured to slide over a belt or other article of clothing, securing the hammer holder to the user. In other embodiments, the belt clasp <b>21</b> may be a slot configured for a belt to slide through or any other means of attaching the invention to a user.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">As can be seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>-<b>4</b></figref>, the at least one releasable fastener <b>4</b> secures the assembly of the holder and the attachment plate. In the preferred embodiment, the at least one releasable fastener <b>4</b> is, but not limited to, Chicago fasteners. The at least one releasable fastener <b>4</b> is preferably easily removable to allow adjustment of the holder between a left-handed and right-handed orientation. The at least one releasable fastener <b>4</b> provides a flat cylindrical structure, although any desired structure may be used.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In one embodiment of the present invention shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, the rigid conduit <b>1</b> connects to the mounting panel <b>2</b> with the at least one releasable fastener <b>4</b> as follows. The at least one releasable fastener <b>4</b> comprises a first fastener <b>41</b> and a second fastener <b>42</b>. The plurality of attachment holes on the rigid conduit <b>1</b> comprises a first hole <b>45</b> and a second hole <b>46</b> and the plurality of attachment apertures on the mounting panel <b>2</b> comprises a first aperture <b>43</b> and a second aperture <b>44</b>. In this system of two fasteners, the first fastener <b>41</b> is positioned into the first hole <b>45</b>, the second fastener <b>42</b> is positioned into the second hole <b>46</b>, the first fastener <b>41</b> is further positioned into the first aperture <b>43</b>, and the second fastener <b>42</b> is further positioned into the second aperture <b>44</b>. The first hole <b>45</b> and the second hole <b>46</b> may be positioned on either side of the rigid conduit <b>1</b> or may be positioned through both sides of the rigid conduit <b>1</b>, allowing the rigid conduit <b>1</b> to be attached to the mounting panel <b>2</b> in a left-handed or right-handed orientation. In some embodiments, a plurality of reinforcement tabs <b>47</b> may be placed between the rigid conduit <b>1</b> and the mounting panel <b>2</b>, further secured by the at least one releasable fastener <b>4</b>, to provide structural stability to the connection.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">In some embodiments of the present invention, the hammer holder includes a blocking assembly <b>3</b>. The purpose of the blocking assembly is to ensure that the hammer <b>5</b> cannot accidentally fall out of the rigid conduit <b>1</b>. The blocking assembly <b>3</b> comprises a gate <b>31</b> and a lanyard <b>32</b>. The gate <b>31</b> is secured to the hammer holder by the lanyard <b>32</b>, with the lanyard connecting at one end to the gate <b>31</b>, and at the opposite end to a fixed component of the hammer holder. This fixed component of the hammer holder may be the plurality of reinforcement tabs <b>47</b>, the mounting panel <b>2</b>, the belt clasp <b>21</b>, the rigid conduit <b>1</b>, or any other component of the present invention. The gate <b>31</b> connects with the rigid conduit <b>1</b> to block the interior channel of the rigid conduit <b>1</b>, keeping the hammer from being able to be removed from the rigid conduit <b>1</b> while the gate <b>31</b> is in place. To better accommodate the blocking assembly, the rigid conduit <b>1</b> may further comprise a first locking formation <b>33</b> and a second locking formation <b>34</b>. In the preferred embodiment, the first locking formation <b>33</b> is a narrow slot at the bottom of the rigid conduit <b>1</b> and the second locking formation <b>34</b> is a pair of slits opposite each other on the elongated slot <b>12</b>. In this embodiment, the gate <b>31</b> is wider at the top than the bottom, allowing the bottom of the gate <b>31</b> to be inserted into the first locking formation <b>33</b>, while the top of the gate does not pass through the second locking formation <b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The procedure for securing the hammer <b>5</b> utilizing the present invention is as follows. Secure the holder to the user's preferred side of the waist and hold the hammer <b>5</b> by grasping the hammer's handle. Both the holder and the hammer are oriented in a horizontal position. The hand holding the hammer is used to locate the elongated slot <b>12</b> and expanded aperture <b>11</b> of the rigid conduit <b>1</b>. As can be seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>, the hammer's neck <b>52</b>, bell <b>51</b>, and face are inserted into the elongated slot <b>12</b> and expanded aperture <b>11</b> of the rigid conduit <b>1</b>. The hammer's neck <b>52</b> is the only part of the hammer <b>5</b> that fits the elongated slot <b>12</b>. The hammer <b>5</b> is moved backward until the hammer's bell <b>51</b> contacts the rear end at the constricted aperture <b>13</b>. Once the hammer <b>5</b> is situated in the rigid conduit <b>1</b>, the blocking assembly <b>3</b> may be engaged with the rigid conduit <b>1</b>. Since the bell <b>51</b> of the hammer <b>5</b> is larger than the elongated slot <b>12</b> and constricted aperture <b>13</b> of the rigid conduit <b>1</b>, the hammer <b>5</b> stays in the rigid conduit <b>1</b> and pivots down to a vertical position when not held by the user. As can be seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>-<b>8</b></figref>, the neck <b>52</b> of the hammer <b>5</b> rests securely on the constricted aperture <b>13</b> of the rigid conduit <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The procedure for deploying the hammer <b>5</b> utilizing the present invention is as follows. If the blocking assembly <b>3</b> is in place, the blocking assembly <b>3</b> is disconnected from the rigid conduit <b>1</b>. The hammer <b>5</b> is grabbed by the handle and tilted so that the neck <b>52</b> of the hammer <b>5</b> moves from the constricted aperture <b>13</b> to the elongated slot <b>12</b>. The hammer is then moved forward, sliding the neck <b>52</b> through the elongated slot <b>12</b> from the constricted aperture <b>13</b> to the expanded aperture <b>11</b>, releasing the hammer from the rigid conduit <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Although the invention has been explained in relation to its preferred embodiment, it is to be understood that many other possible modifications and variations can be made without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A hammer retention apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a rigid conduit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mounting panel;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the rigid conduit further comprising an expanded aperture, an elongated slot, and a constricted aperture;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the expanded aperture being terminally positioned onto the rigid conduit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the constricted aperture being terminally positioned onto the rigid conduit, opposite the expanded aperture; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the elongated slot connecting between the expanded aperture and the constricted aperture.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The hammer retention apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> comprising:
<claim-text>at least one releasable fastener; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the at least one releasable fastener being mounted between the rigid conduit and the mounting panel.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The hammer retention apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref> comprising:
<claim-text>the at least one releasable fastener being a first fastener and a second fastener;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the mounting panel comprising a first aperture and a second aperture;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the rigid conduit comprising a first hole and a second hole;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first fastener being positioned into the first hole;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second fastener being positioned into the second hole;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first fastener being positioned into the first aperture; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second fastener being positioned into the second aperture.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The hammer retention apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> comprising:
<claim-text>a blocking assembly; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the blocking assembly being removably positioned into the rigid conduit across the elongated slot.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The hammer retention apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref> comprising:
<claim-text>the blocking assembly comprising a gate, a lanyard, a first locking formation, and a second locking formation;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the lanyard being connected between the gate and the mounting panel;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first locking formation being positioned adjacent to the elongated slot;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second locking formation being positioned offset from the elongated slot about the rigid conduit; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the gate being slidably mounted into the first locking formation and the second locking formation.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The hammer retention apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> comprising:
<claim-text>a belt clasp; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the belt clasp being positioned onto the mounting panel, opposite to the rigid conduit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The hammer retention apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> comprising:
<claim-text>a plurality of reinforcement tabs;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the plurality of reinforcement tabs being distributed between the rigid conduit and the mounting panel; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the at least one releasable fastener being positioned through one of the plurality of reinforcement tabs.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. A hammer retention apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a rigid conduit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mounting panel;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a belt clasp;</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one releasable fastener;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the at least one releasable fastener being mounted between the rigid conduit and the mounting panel; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the belt clasp being positioned onto the mounting panel, opposite to the rigid conduit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The hammer retention apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> comprising:
<claim-text>the rigid conduit further comprising an expanded aperture, an elongated slot, and a constricted aperture;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the expanded aperture being terminally positioned onto the rigid conduit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the constricted aperture being terminally positioned onto the rigid conduit, opposite the expanded aperture and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the elongated slot connecting between the expanded aperture and the constricted aperture.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The hammer retention apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> comprising:
<claim-text>a blocking assembly;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the blocking assembly being removably positioned into the rigid conduit across the elongated slot;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the blocking assembly comprising a gate, a lanyard, a first locking formation, and a second locking formation;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the lanyard being connected between the gate and the mounting panel;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first locking formation being positioned adjacent to the elongated slot;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second locking formation being positioned offset from the elongated slot about the rigid conduit; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the gate being slidably mounted into the first locking formation and the second locking formation.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The hammer retention apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> comprising:
<claim-text>the at least one releasable fastener being a first fastener and a second fastener;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the mounting panel comprising a first aperture and a second aperture;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the rigid conduit comprising a first hole and a second hole;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first fastener being positioned into the first hole;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second fastener being positioned into the second hole;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first fastener being positioned into the first aperture; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second fastener being positioned into the second aperture.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The hammer retention apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> comprising:
<claim-text>a plurality of reinforcement tabs;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the plurality of reinforcement tabs being distributed between the rigid conduit and the mounting panel; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the at least one releasable fastener being positioned through one of the plurality of reinforcement tabs.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. A hammer retention apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a rigid conduit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mounting panel;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a belt clasp;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a blocking assembly;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the rigid conduit further comprising an expanded aperture, an elongated slot, and a constricted aperture;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the expanded aperture being terminally positioned onto the rigid conduit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the constricted aperture being terminally positioned onto the rigid conduit, opposite the expanded aperture;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the elongated slot connecting between the expanded aperture and the constricted aperture;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the belt clasp being positioned onto the mounting panel, opposite to the rigid conduit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the blocking assembly being removably positioned into the rigid conduit across the elongated slot;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the blocking assembly comprising a gate, a lanyard, a first locking formation, and a second locking formation;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the lanyard being connected between the gate and the mounting panel;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first locking formation being positioned adjacent to the elongated slot;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second locking formation being positioned offset from the elongated slot about the rigid conduit; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the gate being slidably mounted into the first locking formation and the second locking formation.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The hammer retention apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> comprising:
<claim-text>at least one releasable fastener;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the at least one releasable fastener being mounted between the rigid conduit and the mounting panel;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the at least one releasable fastener being a first fastener and a second fastener;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the mounting panel comprising a first aperture and a second aperture;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the rigid conduit comprising a first hole and a second hole;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first fastener being positioned into the first hole;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second fastener being positioned into the second hole;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first fastener being positioned into the first aperture; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second fastener being positioned into the second aperture.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. The hammer retention apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> comprising:
<claim-text>a plurality of reinforcement tabs;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the plurality of reinforcement tabs being distributed between the rigid conduit and the mounting panel; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the at least one releasable fastener being positioned through one of the plurality of reinforcement tabs.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
