<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225478A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225478</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18097453</doc-number>
<date>20230116</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>45</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>24</main-group>
<subgroup>36</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>45</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>24</main-group>
<subgroup>36</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">HAIRCUT FADE GUIDE</invention-title>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>63299946</doc-number>
<date>20220115</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Harris</last-name>
<first-name>Glenn</first-name>
<address>
<city>Pflugerville</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Harris</last-name>
<first-name>Glenn</first-name>
<address>
<city>Pflugerville</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A guide for encircling a head of a person to guide cutting of hair of the person includes an elastomeric band having an inside surface, an outside surface, a substantially straight top edge, and a bottom edge that includes at least one curved portion and a back template. In use, with the elastomeric band around the person's head and positioned for cutting of the person's hair, the person's hair may be cut utilizing the top edge or the bottom edge as a guide. In some embodiments, the top edge of the elastomeric band includes an outwardly-projecting upper rim that has a substantially flat top surface, and the bottom edge of the elastomeric band includes an outwardly-projecting lower rim. Preferably a set of the guides are included, each guide in the set having a unique curvature or diameter with respect to the other guides of the set.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="164.85mm" wi="152.91mm" file="US20230225478A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="176.78mm" wi="154.94mm" file="US20230225478A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="127.42mm" wi="162.64mm" file="US20230225478A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="166.62mm" wi="157.31mm" file="US20230225478A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="158.58mm" wi="168.99mm" file="US20230225478A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="183.39mm" wi="145.54mm" file="US20230225478A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="205.49mm" wi="139.87mm" file="US20230225478A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims the benefit of U.S. Provisional Patent Application 63/299,946, filed on Jan. 21, 2022, and is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="tail"?>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">STATEMENT REGARDING FEDERALLY SPONSORED RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Not Applicable.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">This invention relates to hair styling, and more particularly to an elastomeric guide for fading and cutting hair.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">When cutting a person's hair to produce a taper, a fade, or a straight cut, it is helpful to have a guiding tool for ensuring symmetry and evenness. Prior art devices, such as that taught in U.S. Pat. No. 5,865,192 to Sealy on Feb. 2, 1999, call for a rigid band encircling the person's head and one or more tracts used to guide a trimmer. U.S. Pat. No. 1,569,452 to Bradley on Jan. 12, 1926 teaches a rigid device for encircling the person's head and clamping the device thereto with a spring-biased clamping mechanism. The device of US Patent Publication 2017/0027297 to Cover on Feb. 2, 2017 teaches a guide that is adhered to the person's head. All of these prior art solutions are cumbersome to use and are not securely attachable or reusable. The guides themselves are limited and only accommodate a minimal number of cutting styles.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Therefore, there is a need for a device that is easily selected and affixed to the person's head in a secure manner. Such a needed invention would provide for a plurality of different guides having different curvatures or neck line guides for accommodating a wide variety of desired hair styles and cutting techniques. Such a needed device or set of devices would be relatively inexpensive and intuitive to use. The present invention accomplishes these objectives.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The present device is a guide for encircling a head of a person to guide cutting of hair of the person. An elastomeric band has an inside surface, an outside surface, a substantially straight top edge, and a bottom edge that includes at least one curved portion and a back template. Preferably the elastomeric band is made from a silicone rubber material, but could be made from other materials.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In use, with the elastomeric band around the person's head and positioned for cutting of the person's hair, the person's hair may be cut utilizing the top edge or the bottom edge as a guide. A guide with the desired curved portion or back template is selected and fitted around the person's head and aligned so that either the top edge or the bottom edge guides the cutting of the person's hair.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In some embodiments, the top edge of the elastomeric band includes an outwardly-projecting upper rim that has a substantially flat top surface. In the same or other embodiments without the upper rim, the bottom edge of the elastomeric band includes an outwardly-projecting lower rim. The upper rim and the lower rim strengthen the elastomeric band and provide a larger surface for guiding the cutting of the hair, either with scissors, an electric razor, or the like. The back template is used to guide cutting the hair around a neckline of the person. The curved portion may be configured for guiding the cutting of the hair around the person's ears, for example. The curved portion may be configured for guiding the cutting of the hair into a blend, a fade, a taper, or other styles as desired. The elastomeric band is repositioned frequently, such as after cutting one band of the hair, to expose an adjacent band of the hair that is cut next with the repositioned guide.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Preferably a set of the guides are included, each guide in the set having a unique curvature with respect to the other guides of the set. In this way the curvature desired by the person may be selected and used. In some embodiments each guide of the set has a unique color, and/or a unique diameter for fitting around heads of varying sizes.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The present invention is a device that is easily selected and affixed to the person's head in a secure manner. The guides of the present invention provide for a plurality of different curvatures and neck line guides or back templates for accommodating a wide variety of desired hair styles and cutting techniques. The present invention is relatively inexpensive and intuitive to use. Other features and advantages of the present invention will become apparent from the following more detailed description, taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, which illustrate, by way of example, the principles of the invention.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a top perspective view of the invention, illustrating a guide as in use on the head of a person;</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a bottom perspective view of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a front elevational view of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is a rear elevational view of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is a left-side elevational view of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is a left-side elevational view of an alternate embodiment of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> is a left-side elevational view of a set of the guides having differing bottom curvatures;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> is a left-side elevational view of a set of the guides having differing colors; and</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref> is a top plan view of a set of the guides having differing diameters.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Illustrative embodiments of the invention are described below. The following explanation provides specific details for a thorough understanding of and enabling description for these embodiments. One skilled in the art will understand that the invention may be practiced without such details. In other instances, well-known structures and functions have not been shown or described in detail to avoid unnecessarily obscuring the description of the embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Unless the context clearly requires otherwise, throughout the description and the claims, the words &#x201c;comprise,&#x201d; &#x201c;comprising,&#x201d; and the like are to be construed in an inclusive sense as opposed to an exclusive or exhaustive sense; that is to say, in the sense of &#x201c;including, but not limited to.&#x201d; Words using the singular or plural number also include the plural or singular number respectively. Additionally, the words &#x201c;herein,&#x201d; &#x201c;above,&#x201d; &#x201c;below&#x201d; and words of similar import, when used in this application, shall refer to this application as a whole and not to any particular portions of this application. When the claims use the word &#x201c;or&#x201d; in reference to a list of two or more items, that word covers all of the following interpretations of the word: any of the items in the list, all of the items in the list and any combination of the items in the list. When the word &#x201c;each&#x201d; is used to refer to an element that was previously introduced as being at least one in number, the word &#x201c;each&#x201d; does not necessarily imply a plurality of the elements, but can also mean a singular element.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>-<b>4</b></figref> illustrate a guide <b>10</b> for encircling a head <b>25</b> of a person <b>20</b> to guide cutting of hair <b>26</b> of the person <b>20</b>. An elastomeric band <b>30</b> has an inside surface <b>34</b>, an outside surface <b>36</b>, a substantially straight top edge <b>38</b>, and a bottom edge <b>32</b> that includes at least one curved portion <b>40</b> and a back template <b>50</b>. Preferably the elastomeric band <b>30</b> is made from a silicone rubber material, but could be made from other elastomeric materials.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In use, with the elastomeric band <b>30</b> around the person's head <b>20</b> and positioned for cutting of the person's hair <b>26</b>, the person's hair <b>26</b> may be cut utilizing the top edge <b>38</b> or the bottom edge <b>32</b> as a guide. A guide <b>10</b> with the desired curved portion <b>40</b> or back template <b>50</b> is selected and fitted around the person's head <b>25</b> and aligned so that either the top edge <b>38</b> or the bottom edge <b>32</b> guides the cutting of the person's hair <b>26</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">In some embodiments, the top edge <b>38</b> of the elastomeric band <b>30</b> includes an outwardly-projecting upper rim <b>60</b> that has a substantially flat top surface (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>-<b>5</b></figref>). In the same or other embodiments without the upper rim <b>60</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b>-<b>8</b></figref>), the bottom edge <b>32</b> of the elastomeric band <b>30</b> includes an outwardly-projecting lower rim <b>70</b>. The upper rim <b>60</b> and the lower rim <b>70</b> strengthen the elastomeric band <b>30</b> and provide a larger surface for guiding the cutting of the hair <b>26</b>, either with scissors, an electric razor, or the like. The back template <b>50</b> is used to guide cutting the hair <b>26</b> around a neckline <b>28</b> of the person <b>20</b>. The curved portion <b>40</b> may be configured for guiding the cutting of the hair <b>26</b> around the person's ears <b>27</b>, for example. The curved portion <b>40</b> may be configured for guiding the cutting of the hair <b>26</b> into a blend, a fade, a taper, or other styles as desired. The elastomeric band <b>30</b> is repositioned frequently, such as after cutting one band of the hair <b>26</b>, to expose an adjacent band of the hair <b>26</b> that is cut next with the repositioned guide <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Preferably a set <b>11</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref>) of the guides <b>10</b> are included, each guide <b>10</b> in the set <b>11</b> having a unique curvature <b>80</b> with respect to the other guides <b>10</b> of the set <b>11</b>. In this way the curvature <b>80</b> desired by the person <b>20</b> may be selected and used. In some embodiments each guide <b>10</b> of the set <b>11</b> has a unique color <b>90</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref>), and/or a unique diameter D<sub>x </sub>(<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref>) for fitting around heads <b>25</b> of varying sizes.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The elastomeric band <b>30</b> may include a rigid or non-stretchable portion (not shown), two opposing ends of which are connected with an elastic strap (not shown) to provide a similar function.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">While a particular form of the invention has been illustrated and described, it will be apparent that various modifications can be made without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention. Accordingly, it is not intended that the invention be limited, except as by the appended claims.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Particular terminology used when describing certain features or aspects of the invention should not be taken to imply that the terminology is being redefined herein to be restricted to any specific characteristics, features, or aspects of the invention with which that terminology is associated. In general, the terms used in the following claims should not be construed to limit the invention to the specific embodiments disclosed in the specification, unless the above Detailed Description section explicitly defines such terms. Accordingly, the actual scope of the invention encompasses not only the disclosed embodiments, but also all equivalent ways of practicing or implementing the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The above detailed description of the embodiments of the invention is not intended to be exhaustive or to limit the invention to the precise form disclosed above or to the particular field of usage mentioned in this disclosure. While specific embodiments of, and examples for, the invention are described above for illustrative purposes, various equivalent modifications are possible within the scope of the invention, as those skilled in the relevant art will recognize. Also, the teachings of the invention provided herein can be applied to other systems, not necessarily the system described above. The elements and acts of the various embodiments described above can be combined to provide further embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">All of the above patents and applications and other references, including any that may be listed in accompanying filing papers, are incorporated herein by reference. Aspects of the invention can be modified, if necessary, to employ the systems, functions, and concepts of the various references described above to provide yet further embodiments of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Changes can be made to the invention in light of the above &#x201c;Detailed Description.&#x201d; While the above description details certain embodiments of the invention and describes the best mode contemplated, no matter how detailed the above appears in text, the invention can be practiced in many ways. Therefore, implementation details may vary considerably while still being encompassed by the invention disclosed herein. As noted above, particular terminology used when describing certain features or aspects of the invention should not be taken to imply that the terminology is being redefined herein to be restricted to any specific characteristics, features, or aspects of the invention with which that terminology is associated.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">While certain aspects of the invention are presented below in certain claim forms, the inventor contemplates the various aspects of the invention in any number of claim forms. Accordingly, the inventor reserves the right to add additional claims after filing the application to pursue such additional claim forms for other aspects of the invention.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A guide for encircling a head of a person to guide cutting of hair of the person, the guide comprising:
<claim-text>an elastomeric band having an inside surface, an outside surface, a substantially straight top edge, and a bottom edge including at least one curved portion and a back template;</claim-text>
<claim-text>whereby with the elastomeric band around the person's head and positioned for cutting of the person's hair, the person's hair may be cut utilizing the top edge or the bottom edge as a guide.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The guide of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the top edge of the elastomeric band includes an outwardly-projecting upper rim having a substantially flat top surface.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The guide of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the bottom edge of the elastomeric band includes an outwardly-projecting lower rim.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The guide of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref> wherein the bottom edge of the elastomeric band includes an outwardly-projecting lower rim.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The guide of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref> wherein the elastomeric band is made with a silicone rubber material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. A set of the guides of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref> wherein the bottom edges of each of the guides have a unique curvature with respect to the other guides of the set of guides.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The set of the guides of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref> wherein each of the guides is made with a unique color of silicone rubber with respect to the other guides of the set of guides.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. A set of the guides of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref> wherein each of the guides has a unique diameter configured for fitting around heads of varying sizes.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. A plurality of the sets of the guides of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref> wherein each set of the guides has a unique diameter, with respect to the diameters of the other sets, configured for fitting around heads of varying sizes.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. A plurality of the sets of the guides of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref> wherein each set of the guides has a unique diameter, with respect to the diameters of the other sets, configured for fitting around heads of varying sizes, and wherein the guides of each set are made with a common color that is unique among the other sets of the guides.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. A plurality of the sets of the guides of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref> wherein each set of the guides has a unique diameter, with respect to the diameters of the other sets, configured for fitting around heads of varying sizes.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
