<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225292A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225292</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18067658</doc-number>
<date>20221216</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>27</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>27</main-group>
<subgroup>005</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>27</main-group>
<subgroup>003</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">SYSTEM, METHOD, AND DEVICE FOR SECURING A LEASH TO AN OBJECT</invention-title>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>63290515</doc-number>
<date>20211216</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Markham</last-name>
<first-name>William</first-name>
<address>
<city>Alpine</city>
<state>UT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Markham</last-name>
<first-name>William</first-name>
<address>
<city>Alpine</city>
<state>UT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Systems, methods, and devices for securing an object using a connection device. The systems, methods, and devices for securing an object using a connection device, for example to hang a decoration from a ceiling rafter, attach a strap to a trailer, or any other situation in which a connection device is needed, including for an owner to restrain pets using a leash without actually holding on to the leash. A device and system may include a loop constructed of a flexible material, wherein the material comprises a hole disposed therethrough and a connector including a frame. A portion of the frame is disposed through the hole of the loop such that the connector is releasably coupled to the loop and the connector is configured to receive a line.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="100.67mm" wi="158.75mm" file="US20230225292A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="220.73mm" wi="180.00mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225292A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="216.41mm" wi="170.01mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225292A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="224.79mm" wi="175.18mm" file="US20230225292A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="232.75mm" wi="147.15mm" file="US20230225292A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="228.77mm" wi="153.42mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225292A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="231.14mm" wi="173.23mm" file="US20230225292A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="231.14mm" wi="154.35mm" file="US20230225292A1-20230720-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="231.14mm" wi="139.02mm" file="US20230225292A1-20230720-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="227.92mm" wi="159.60mm" file="US20230225292A1-20230720-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="227.92mm" wi="160.36mm" file="US20230225292A1-20230720-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="227.92mm" wi="160.36mm" file="US20230225292A1-20230720-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00012" num="00012">
<img id="EMI-D00012" he="227.92mm" wi="160.36mm" file="US20230225292A1-20230720-D00012.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The disclosure relates to systems, methods, and devices for releasably securing a line to an object, and specifically to releasing securing a leash to a post with a gated connector.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Pet owners often take their pets for walks. In many places, when walking a pet, laws require the pet remain on a leash. Even in places where leashes are not required by law, a pet owner may be liable for damage or injury caused by a pet not on a leash. For these reasons, it is wise to keep pets restrained when the pets are in public areas. Pet owners may use a variety of different leashes including traditional leashes and retractable leashes. Retractable leashes allow the owner to give the pet more or less room to roam depending on the circumstances. Retractable leashes typically include a leash handle in which a retractable cord is contained.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">In many instances, however, it may become necessary (or it may be convenient) for the owner to leave the pet on a leash for a short time. Examples include, the pet owner needing to use a restroom, wanting to get a drink, or going into a store or other location where pets might not be allowed. Other examples include times that a pet owner may desire to leash a pet to a fixed object within sight of the owner while the owner engages in a recreational activity such as enjoying a picnic, participating in a sports activity, or swimming/sunbathing at the beach, or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">When an owner wants to restrain a leashed pet, they are faced with the problem of how to attach the leash to a fixed object without removing the leash from the pet's collar. Whether the leash is a standard leash, or a retractable leash they are not configured to be attached to other objects. While owners can tie or otherwise attach a leash to an object, this shortens the leash and restricts the movement of the pet. In many cases, after tying or otherwise attaching the leash to an object, the leash is too short to comfortably restrain the pet. Furthermore, leashes are not made to be tied to objects and the leash material could be abraded or otherwise damaged when the pet is tied to a fixed object.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In light of the foregoing, disclosed herein are systems, methods, and devices for attaching leashes to fixed objects without damaging the leash and without causing the leash to be too short for the pet to be comfortable while restrained.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Non-limiting and non-exhaustive implementations of the disclosure are described with reference to the following figures, wherein like reference numerals refer to like or similar parts throughout the various views unless otherwise specified. Advantages of the disclosure will become better understood with regard to the following description and accompanying drawings where:</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a front view of an exemplary device for securing a leash to an object;</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a side view of a fully expanded exemplary device for securing a leash to an object;</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a front view of an exemplary device for securing a leash to an object attached to an extendable leash;</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is a front view of an exemplary device for securing a leash to an object in use (e.g., the device attaches an extendable leash to a rail of a fence or other object);</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is a front view of an exemplary device for securing a leash to an object that is attached to an optional buckle and strap, which are then attached to a post or other object;</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is a front view of an exemplary device for securing a leash to an object, wherein the device is attached to the handle of an extendable leash and to a leash cord to thereby secure the leash and leash cord around an object;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> is a close-up view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> is a front view of another exemplary device for securing a leash to an object, wherein the device is attached to a leash and to a bar;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref> is a schematic flow chart diagram of a method for using a device to secure a leash to an object;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref> is a schematic flow chart diagram of a method for using a device to secure a leash to an object;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b></figref> is a schematic flow chart diagram of a method for using a device to secure a leash to an object: and</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>12</b></figref> is a schematic flow chart diagram of a method for releasably securing a leash to a post.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Disclosed herein are systems, methods, and devices for releasably securing a line to an object. The systems, methods, and devices described herein may specifically implemented for releasably securing a leash to a post to restrain a pet without holding the leash. The devices described herein may be used in connection with regular or extendable leashes when an owner of a pet desires to attach the leash to an object.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">One method of securing a pet to an object in a public area includes tying the pet's leash to the object. This method is problematic because the leash cord is not intended to be tied into a knot. Furthermore, the pet owner may not adequately secure the knot to the object, thus, allowing the pet to free itself, and get lost and/or cause damage and/or injury to itself or others. If the pet owner does tie a very secure knot, the pet pulling on the leash might cause the knot to tighten and be very difficult to untie. Finally, tying a very secure knot by unskilled person might require a substantial amount of the leash cord, leaving the pet little or no leash to move around and/or get comfortable.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Another method of securing a pet to an object includes removing the leash from the pet, wrapping the leash around an object, threading the leash through the leash handle (or loop), and then reattaching the leash to the pet. This method can also be problematic because the pet is not on the leash while the owner is securing it to an object. If there are two or more people, one person could hold the pet while the other wraps the leash around the object, but with only one person, the pet could get away. Furthermore, depending on the size of the object used, there could be very little leash left for the animal to use to move around or get comfortable.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In light of the foregoing, disclosed herein are embodiments of attachment devices configured to attach leashes to a variety of fixed or other objects. The embodiments described herein enable numerous benefits to pet owners who desire or need to attach the pet's leash to an object to restrain their pet or pets while the owner engages in another activity.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Before the methods, systems, and devices for allowing an owner to restrain pets with leashes without actually holding on to the leash are disclosed and described, it is to be understood that this disclosure is not limited to the configurations, process steps, and materials disclosed herein as such configurations, process steps, and materials may vary somewhat. It is also to be understood that the terminology employed herein, is used for describing implementations only and is not intended to be limiting since the scope of the disclosure will be limited only by the appended claims and equivalents thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">In describing and claiming the disclosure, the following terminology will be used in accordance with the definitions set out below.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">It must be noted that, as used in this specification and the appended claims, the singular forms &#x201c;a,&#x201d; &#x201c;an,&#x201d; and &#x201c;the&#x201d; include plural referents unless the context clearly dictates otherwise.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">As used herein, the term &#x201c;about&#x201d; used in reference to a given parameter is inclusive of the stated value and has the meaning dictated by the context (e.g., it includes the degree of error associated with measurement of the given parameter).</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">As used herein, the terms &#x201c;comprising,&#x201d; &#x201c;including,&#x201d; &#x201c;containing,&#x201d; &#x201c;characterized by,&#x201d; and grammatical equivalents thereof are inclusive or open-ended terms that do not exclude additional, unrecited elements or method steps.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">As used herein, the term &#x201c;ring formation&#x201d; is inclusive of all geometries and is not limited to circular or elliptical geometries. The ring formations described herein form a closed loop, and in some cases, the closed loop may be opened with a gate or other means.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">A detailed description of systems, methods, and devices consistent with embodiments of the disclosure is provided below. While several embodiments are described, it should be understood that this disclosure is not limited to any one embodiment, but instead encompasses numerous alternatives, modifications, and equivalents. In addition, while numerous specific details are set forth in the following description in order to provide a thorough understanding of the embodiments disclosed herein, some embodiments may be practiced without some or all of these details. Moreover, for clarity, certain technical material that is known in the related art has not been described in detail to avoid unnecessarily obscuring the disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Referring now to the figures, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a view of a device <b>100</b> for releasably securing a line to an object. The device <b>100</b> may specifically be used for securing a leash to a post or similar object to restrain an animal without actively holding the leash. The device <b>100</b> includes a connector portion <b>102</b> and a loop portion <b>104</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The connector portion <b>102</b> may be implemented with several different embodiments as described herein. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, the connector portion <b>102</b> includes a double gate connector <b>106</b> that comprises a first gate <b>108</b> and a second gate <b>110</b>. The double gate connector <b>106</b> comprises a rigid frame <b>112</b> that forms two encircled ring formations (as described herein the &#x201c;ring formations&#x201d; defined by the double gate connector <b>106</b> need not have a circular geometry). The geometry of the frame <b>112</b> specifically defines a first ring formation <b>109</b> and a second ring formation <b>111</b>. The first gate <b>108</b> serves as a component of the first ring formation <b>109</b>, and the first gate <b>108</b> may be depressed to create an opening into the first ring formation <b>109</b>. The second gate <b>110</b> serves as a component of the second ring formation <b>111</b>, and the second gate <b>110</b> may be depressed to create an opening into the second ring formation <b>111</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The double gate connector <b>106</b> may be implemented with different features. In some implementations, one or more of the first gate <b>108</b> or the second gate <b>110</b> comprises a spring such that the gate <b>108</b>, <b>110</b> automatically springs back to reform the ring formation <b>109</b>, <b>111</b> when the gate <b>108</b>, <b>110</b> is not actively being depressed by a user or another object. When each of the first gate <b>108</b> and the second gate <b>110</b> are implemented with a spring, the double gate connector <b>106</b> may be referred to as a double spring gate connector. In other implementations, only one of the first gate <b>108</b> or the second gate <b>110</b> may be implemented with a spring.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">In other implementations, one or more of the first gate <b>108</b> or the second gate <b>110</b> is implemented with a locking sleeve, such as a locking sleeve implemented with a locking carabiner. In this implementation, the gate <b>108</b>, <b>110</b> may include a rivet pin enabling the gate <b>108</b>, <b>110</b> to pivot inward toward the center of the ring formation <b>109</b>, <b>111</b>. When the gate <b>108</b>, <b>110</b> is released and no longer pressed inward, the gate <b>108</b>, <b>110</b> may be locked to a nose formation of the frame and then locked in place with a locking sleeve.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The connector portion <b>102</b> may include a dual carabiner as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, and may alternatively include another connection means that defines a first ring formation <b>109</b> and a second ring formation <b>111</b>. The two ring formations <b>109</b>, <b>111</b> defined by the connector portion <b>102</b> allow the connector portion <b>102</b> to be releasably coupled to the loop portion <b>104</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The connector portion <b>102</b> may be formed as a component of a retractable leash or a standard leash. The connector portion <b>102</b> may be releasably attached to a retractable leash or a standard leash. Thus, the connector portion <b>102</b> provides convenience and adaptability for a user to interface with different leash devices.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The loop portion <b>104</b> of the device <b>100</b> includes a length of flexible material <b>114</b>. The flexible material <b>114</b> is releasably or permanently disposed in a loop formation to define a loop <b>116</b>. The flexible material <b>114</b> includes a hole <b>118</b> disposed therethrough, and the hole <b>118</b> may include a reinforcement grommet as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>. The loop portion <b>104</b> may additionally include a tab <b>120</b> wherein the flexible material <b>114</b> is not disposed in a loop formation, but rather forms a flat tab that may be easily gripped by a user.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is an exploded view of the device <b>100</b>, wherein the flexible material <b>114</b> is opened and not formed into the loop <b>116</b> formation shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>. The flexible material <b>114</b> includes a first releasably attachable end <b>120</b> and a second releasably attachable end <b>122</b>. The releasably attachable ends <b>120</b>, <b>122</b> enable a user to create and break the loop <b>116</b> formation, and further to adjust the size of the loop <b>116</b> formation.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The first releasably attachable end <b>120</b> and the second releasably attachable end <b>122</b> include a means for attaching a first end of the flexible material <b>114</b> to a second end of the flexible material <b>114</b>. The example illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the releasably attachable ends <b>120</b>, <b>122</b> are configured to attach to one another with a hook and loop material. The releasably attachable ends <b>120</b>, <b>122</b> may be connected by other means, including, for example, snaps, buckles, click buckles, hooks, zippers, buttons, clasps, hook and eye closure, and so forth.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">In an exemplary embodiment, the overall length of device <b>100</b> is about 135 mm. When the second releasably attachable end <b>122</b> is folded over and attached to first releasably attachable end <b>120</b>, the overall length of the device <b>100</b> may be about 107 mm. It will be appreciated that these dimensions may vary somewhat depending upon the type of leash, post, or another object to which the device <b>100</b> may be attached.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> illustrates a side view of the device attached to a retractable leash <b>324</b>. The first releasably attachable end <b>120</b> is joined to the second releasably attachable end <b>122</b> via hook and loop material such that the flexible material <b>114</b> forms a closed loop <b>116</b> around a handle of the retractable leash <b>324</b>. It should be appreciated that it would then be easy to wrap a leash cord around an object and clip the leash cord to the connector portion <b>102</b>. This creates an easy way to attach a pet leash to an object without having to remove the leash from the pet, tie the leash into a knot, or thread the leash through a hole.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is a perspective view of the device <b>100</b> being used to releasably secure a leash cord <b>426</b> around an object <b>428</b>. The loop portion <b>104</b> of the device <b>100</b> is releasably attached to a handle of retractable leash <b>324</b>. The device <b>100</b> and retractable leash <b>324</b> are then wrapped around an object <b>428</b>, such as a rail or other part of the object (e.g., fence), with the connector portion <b>102</b> clipped onto leash cord <b>426</b>. Similar to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, the flexible material <b>114</b> forms a closed loop <b>116</b> with the joining of first releasably attachable end <b>120</b> and second releasably attachable end <b>122</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">It will be appreciated that the attachment devices disclosed herein have universal implementation with respect to their ability to attach to and be removed from various leashes. The device disclosed comprises a universal component that may be attached to and removed from one leash to then attached to and removed from another leash. For example, the attachment devices disclosed may be attached to and removed from a retractable leash and then has the ability to attach to a second, standard web leash or rope leash.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The device <b>100</b> allows for great flexibility in attaching a leash to another object. Use of the device <b>100</b> may be as follows. First, the flexible material <b>114</b> may be wrapped around a loop of a leash, the handle of a retractable leash or a standard leash, or wrapped around a post, a tree, or another object. Second, first releasably attachable end <b>120</b> is attached to second releasably attachable end <b>122</b> to create a closed loop <b>116</b>. Third, the leash is attached to the connector portion <b>102</b> attaching the leash to an object.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The device <b>100</b> thus facilitates the connection of the leash cord <b>426</b> to an object. Using the device <b>100</b> for releasably securing a leash cord <b>426</b> to an object means that it is not necessary to tie the leash cord <b>426</b> to an object or thread the leash cord <b>426</b> through anything. In particular, it is not necessary to disconnect the leash cord <b>426</b> from the pet. Furthermore, because the flexible material is small and compact, it could easily stay affixed to the retractable or standard leash until use of the device is required, or it could be stored in a pocket, or even on the collar of the pet, while walking the pet.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">It will be appreciated that a typical leash is about six feet long, but the length of the leash may be any length a user desires to permit a pet to move freely while attached to the leash. When using a leash, for example a typical six-foot leash, to wrap around an object it will appreciated that each object has a varying circumference. While using a typical six-foot leash the object's circumference can range from a minimum circumference of about one inch to a maximum circumference that is less than or equal to about five-and-a-half feet, such that the leash is able to wrap around and be attached to the object while still providing some slack in the leash to allow movement for the pet. This concept is referred to as an &#x201c;infinity length.&#x201d; Thus, the &#x201c;infinity length&#x201d; is the circumference of the object to which the leash may be attached and is proportional to the length of the leash, where the leash length is longer than the circumference of the object to which the leash is attached. For example, an &#x201c;infinity length&#x201d; for a leash that is six feet long ranges from about one-inch up to about five-and-a-half feet.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> illustrates an embodiment in which device <b>100</b> is attached to a buckle <b>530</b> on a strap or on a standard leash, which is wrapped around an object <b>428</b>, such as a table leg or railing, and then attached to the connector portion <b>102</b>. Similar to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>3</b> and <b>4</b></figref>, the flexible material <b>114</b> of the loop portion <b>104</b> forms a closed loop with the joining of the first releasably attachable end <b>120</b> and the second releasably attachable end <b>122</b>. In addition to attaching to a standard leash or a retractable leash, the device <b>100</b> could also be attached to any strap or belt to facilitate the attachment of the strap or belt to an object.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">It should be appreciated that the flexibility of the device <b>100</b> extends beyond use in pet leashes. The device <b>100</b> could be used in any application where a strap, belt, or cord needs to be attached to an object. The device <b>100</b> could be used to hang a decoration from a ceiling rafter, attach a strap to a trailer, or any other situation in which a connection device is needed.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b> and <b>7</b></figref> illustrate perspective views of a device <b>600</b> for releasably securing a line to an object. The device <b>600</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is similar to the device <b>100</b> discussed in connection with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>-<b>5</b></figref>, with the exception that the loop portion <b>604</b> is permanently affixed to an object, rather than releasably affixed like the loop portion <b>104</b> described in connection with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>-<b>5</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">The device <b>600</b> includes the loop portion <b>604</b> wrapped around and attached to the handle of a retractable leash <b>324</b>. The connector portion <b>102</b> is coupled to each of the loop portion <b>104</b> and a leash cord <b>426</b>. In the embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>, the loop portion <b>604</b> is permanently affixed to the handle of the retractable leash <b>324</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">It should be appreciated that the device <b>600</b> is small enough and simple enough that it never needs to be removed from the handle of the retractable leash <b>324</b>. In this embodiment, the device <b>600</b> may be permanently attached (e.g., sewn) onto the handle of the retractable leash <b>324</b>, thus making it available any time there is a need to attach the retractable leash <b>324</b> to another object. This is a small and simple device that will greatly increase the utility of leashes for pet owners and make it much easier and more convenient to attach leashes to other objects.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> illustrates a device <b>800</b> for releasably securing a leash cord <b>426</b> to an object. The device <b>800</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> is like the devices <b>100</b>, <b>600</b> discussed herein, with the exception that the connector portion <b>802</b> comprises a single gate <b>810</b> rather than two gates. The connector portion <b>802</b> defines a first ring formation <b>809</b> and a second ring formation <b>811</b>, but only the second ring formation <b>811</b> can be opened by way of a gate <b>810</b>. In the implementation illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref>, the first ring formation <b>809</b> is releasably attached to the loop portion <b>804</b> because the loop portion is looped through the permanently affixed first ring formation <b>809</b> as shown. In the implementation illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref>, the loop portion <b>804</b> includes a cord in a loop formation, such that the cord may be looped around the permanently affixed first ring formation <b>809</b> and may further be releasably attached to the leash cord <b>426</b> as shown.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref> is a schematic flow chart diagram of a method <b>900</b> for using a device to secure a leash to an object. The method <b>900</b> includes at <b>902</b> forming a closed loop around a handle of a retractable leash, or around a loop of a leash, by joining the first and second releasably attachable ends of the device to form a loop. The method <b>900</b> continues at <b>904</b> and the leash cord is wrapped around an object. The method <b>900</b> continues at <b>906</b> and the leash cord is attached to the device by hooking it into a connector, such as a carabiner or other connecting device, attached to the device.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref> is a schematic flow chart diagram of a method <b>1000</b> for using a device for securing a leash to an object. The method <b>1000</b> includes at <b>1002</b> attaching a loop of flexible material around the loop or handle of a leash and permanently joining the ends of the flexible material such that there is a tab or length of flexible material extending from the joined loop. The method <b>1000</b> continues at <b>1004</b> and a hole is formed into the tab and a connector, such as a carabiner or other connecting device, is attached to the hole in the tab. The method <b>1000</b> continues at <b>1006</b> and a leash cord is wrapped around an object and then clipped into the connector, thus attaching the leash to the object.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b></figref> is a schematic flow chart diagram of a method <b>1100</b> for using a device to secure a leash to an object. The method <b>1100</b> includes at <b>1102</b> attaching a looped flexible material to an object. The method <b>1100</b> continues at <b>1104</b> and the looped flexible material is attached to a connector, such as a carabiner or other connecting device. The method <b>1100</b> continues at <b>1106</b> and a leash cord is attached to the connector, thus attaching the leash to another object.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>12</b></figref> is a schematic flow chart diagram of a method <b>1200</b> for releasably securing a leash to a post. The method <b>1200</b> includes releasably coupling at <b>1202</b> a loop <b>116</b> to a first ring formation of a double gate connector <b>106</b>. The loop <b>116</b> is constructed of a flexible material <b>114</b>, and the flexible material <b>114</b> includes a hole <b>118</b> disposed therethrough. The hole <b>118</b> disposed through the flexible material is sized for receiving a first gate <b>108</b> and/or a frame <b>112</b> of the double gate connector <b>106</b>. The method <b>1200</b> continues with looping at <b>1204</b> a leash cord <b>426</b> around a post. The method <b>1200</b> continues with releasably hooking at <b>1206</b> a second ring formation <b>111</b> of the double gate connector around the leash cord <b>426</b> to releasably secure the leash cord <b>426</b> to the post. The second ring formation <b>111</b> of the double gate connector <b>106</b> is releasably hooked at <b>1206</b> by opening a second gate <b>110</b> of the double gate connector <b>106</b>.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">EXAMPLES</heading>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The following examples pertain to further embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Example 1 is a device for securing a leash to an object.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">Example 2 is a device as in Example 1, wherein the device comprises a flexible material and at least one connector comprising a double gate, wherein the at least one connector is attached to the flexible material.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">Example 3 is a device as in any of Examples 1-2, wherein the device comprises a releasably joined loop of flexible material that includes a grommet, a first releasably attachable end, and a second releasably attachable end.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">Example 4 is an apparatus as in any of Examples 1-3, wherein the flexible material further comprises at least one material selected from the group consisting of: rubber, silicone, and elastic.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">Example 5 is an apparatus as in any of Examples 1-4, wherein the flexible material further comprises at least one zip tie.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">Example 6 is an apparatus as in any of Examples 1-5, wherein the flexible material further comprises at least one of the group consisting of: paracord, string, and rope.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">Example 7 is an apparatus as in any of Examples 1-6, wherein the first releasably attachable end and the second releasably attachable end are joined with an apparatus selected from the group consisting of: one or more hooks, one or more snaps, one or more buttons, one or more zippers, one or more buckles, one or more click buckles, one or more pins, and one or more clasps.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">Example 8 is an apparatus as in any of Examples 1-7, wherein the flexible material further comprises a chain.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">Example 9 is an apparatus as in any of Examples 1-8, wherein the flexible material further comprises webbing.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">Example 10 is an apparatus as in any of Examples 1-9, wherein the flexible material further comprises tape.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">Example 11 is an apparatus as in any of Examples 1-10, wherein the flexible material further comprises a wire or braided cable.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">Example 12 is an apparatus as in any of Examples 1-11, wherein the at least one connector of the device is attached to the grommet.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">Example 13 is an apparatus as in any of Examples 1-12, wherein the at least one connector of the device comprises at least one carabiner.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">Example 14 is an apparatus as in any of Examples 1-13, wherein the at least one connector of the device comprises at least one click buckle.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">Example 15 is an apparatus as in any of Examples 1-14, wherein the flexible material is between 10 and 30 mm wide, and the overall length of the flexible material from the grommet to the first releasably attachable end is between 100 mm and 150 mm.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">Example 16 is an apparatus as in any of Examples 1-15, wherein the flexible material is about 20 mm wide.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">Example 17 is an apparatus as in any of Examples 1-16, wherein the first releasably attachable end and the second releasably attachable end are joined with a hook and loop material.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">Example 18 is an apparatus as in any of Examples 1-17, wherein the first releasably attachable end is covered with about 20 mm of hook and loop material.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">Example 19 is an apparatus as in any of Examples 1-18, wherein the second releasably attachable end is covered with about 120 mm of hook and loop material.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">Example 20 is an apparatus as in any of Examples 1-20, wherein the flexible material further comprises a reflective material.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">Example 21 is a device for securing a leash to an object: wherein the device comprises a flexible material having two ends permanently joined together such that the flexible material creates a loop around a leash handle, the flexible material loop further comprising a flattened out tab portion, wherein the tab portion further comprises a hole; wherein the device further comprises at least one connector comprising a double gate, wherein the at least one connector is attached to the flexible material.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">Example 22 is an apparatus as in as in Example 21, wherein the flexible material further comprises at least one material selected from the group consisting of: rubber, silicone, and elastic.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">Example 23 is an apparatus as in any of Examples 21-22, wherein the flexible material further comprises at least one zip tie.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">Example 24 is an apparatus as in any of Examples 21-23, wherein the flexible material further comprises at least one of the group consisting of: paracord, string, and rope.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">Example 25 is an apparatus as in any of Examples 21-24, wherein the flexible material further comprises a chain.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">Example 26 is an apparatus as in any of Examples 21-25, wherein the flexible material further comprises webbing.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">Example 27 is an apparatus as in any of Examples 21-26, wherein the flexible material further comprises tape.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">Example 28 is an apparatus as in any of Examples 21-27, wherein the flexible material further comprises a wire.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">Example 29 is an apparatus as in any of Examples 21-28, wherein the device further comprises a grommet in the hole in the tab portion of the device.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">Example 30 is an apparatus as in any of Examples 21-29, wherein the grommet is a quarter inch (6.35 mm) grommet.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">Example 31 is an apparatus as in any of Examples 21-30, wherein the at least one connector is attached to the grommet.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">Example 32 is an apparatus as in any of Examples 21-31, wherein the device further comprises at least one connector attached to the grommet, wherein the connector is one or more carabiners.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">Example 33 is an apparatus as in any of Examples 21-32, wherein the device further comprises at least one connector attached to the grommet, wherein the connector is at least one click buckle.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">Example 34 is an apparatus as in any of Examples 21-33, wherein the flexible material is between 10 and 50 mm wide.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">Example 35 is an apparatus as in any of Examples 21-34, wherein the flexible material further comprises a reflective material.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">Example 36 is a system for securing a pet on a leash to an object. The system includes a device that comprises a releasably joined loop of flexible material that includes a grommet, a first releasably attachable end, and a second releasably attachable end. The device includes any of the features described in connection with the apparatus of Examples 1-20.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">Example 37 is a method of securing a pet on a leash to an object. The method includes forming a loop around a handle of a retractable leash or around a loop of a leash by joining the first and second releasably attachable ends of the device. The method continues and a leash cord is wrapped around an object. The method continues and the leash cord is attached to the device by hooking it into a connector attached to the device. The method includes any of the features described in connection with the device of Examples 1-20.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">Example 38 is a method of securing a pet on a leash to an object. The method includes attaching a loop of flexible material around the loop or handle of a leash and permanently joining the ends of the flexible material such that there is a tab or length of flexible material extending from the joined loop. The method continues and a hole is formed into the tab and a connector is attached to the hole in the tab. The method continues and a leash cord is wrapped around an object and then clipped into the connector, thus attaching the leash to the object. The method includes any of the features described in connection with the device of Examples 21-35.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">Example 39 is a method of securing a pet on a leash to an object. The method includes attaching a looped flexible material to an object. The method continues and the looped flexible material is attached to a connector. The method continues and a leash cord is attached to the connector, thus attaching the leash to another object. The method includes any of the features described in connection with the device of Examples 1-20.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">Example 40 is a device, system, or method as in any of Examples 1-39, wherein the attachment device is a universal component that may be attached to and removed from one leash to then attached to and removed from another leash.</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">Example 41 is a device. The device includes a loop constructed of a flexible material, wherein the flexible material comprises a hole disposed therethrough. The device includes a connector comprising a frame defining a first ring formation and a second ring formation, wherein the first ring formation is opened by way of a first gate, and wherein the second ring formation is opened by way of a second gate. The device is such that a portion of the frame defining the first ring formation is disposed through the hole of the loop such that the connector is releasably coupled to the loop. The device is such that the second ring formation of the connector is configured to receive a line.</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0098">Example 42 is a device as in Example 41, wherein the connector is a double gate connector and further comprises a swivel disposed between the first gate and the second gate, wherein the swivel enables the first gate to rotate relative to the second gate.</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0099">Example 43 is a device as in any of Examples 41-42, wherein the hole disposed through the flexible material further comprises a grommet, and wherein an interior diameter defined by the grommet is optimized to receive the frame of the connector and the first gate.</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0100">Example 44 is a device as in any of Examples 41-43, wherein the line comprises a leash cord, and wherein the second gate is configured to open to enable the second ring formation to receive the leash cord; and wherein the second gate is configured to close such that the leash cord is disposed within the second ring formation.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0101">Example 45 is a device as in any of Examples 41-43, wherein the connector comprises a double gate carabiner comprising: a first carabiner comprising the first ring formation and the first gate; and a second carabiner comprising the second ring formation and the second gate.</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0102">Example 46 is a device as in any of Examples 41-45, wherein at least one of the first gate or the second gate comprises a spring configured to automatically spring into a closed position when not being depressed, and wherein the closed position is defined by at least one of the first ring formation or the second ring formation forming a closed loop.</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0103">Example 47 is a device as in any of Examples 41-46, wherein the loop is formed of a length of the flexible material comprising a first releasably attachable portion and a second releasably attachable portion, and wherein the first releasably attachable portion is attached to the second releasably attachable portion to form the loop.</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0104">Example 48 is a device as in any of Examples 41-47, wherein the first releasably attachable portion is joined to the second releasably attachable portion by way of one or more of a hook, snap, button, zipper, buckle, clasp, or hook and eye closure.</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0105">Example 49 is a device as in any of Examples 41-48, wherein the length of the flexible material further comprises a tab, and wherein the hole disposed through the flexible material is located at the tab, and wherein the tab is disposed between the first releasably attachable portion and the second releasably attachable portion.</p>
<p id="p-0107" num="0106">Example 50 is a device as in any of Examples 41-49, wherein at least one of the first gate or the second gate comprises a locking sleeve such that the at least one of the first gate or the second gate can be locked in a closed position, wherein the closed position is defined by at least one of the first ring formation or the second ring formation forming a closed loop.</p>
<p id="p-0108" num="0107">Example 51 is a system. The system includes a leash cord. The system includes a loop constructed of a flexible material, wherein the flexible material comprises a hole disposed therethrough. The system includes a connector comprising a frame defining a first ring formation and a second ring formation, wherein the first ring formation is opened by way of a first gate, and wherein the second ring formation is opened by way of a second gate. The system is such that at least a portion of the frame defining the first ring formation is disposed through the hole of the loop such that the connector is releasably coupled to the loop. The system is such that the second ring formation of the connector is configured to receive the leash cord to releasably secure the leash cord around an object.</p>
<p id="p-0109" num="0108">Example 52 is a system as in Example 51, wherein the connector is a double gate connector and further comprises a swivel disposed between the first gate and the second gate, wherein the swivel enables the first gate to rotate relative to the second gate.</p>
<p id="p-0110" num="0109">Example 53 is a system as in any of Examples 51-52, wherein the hole disposed through the flexible material further comprises a grommet, and wherein an interior diameter defined by the grommet is optimized to receive the frame of the connector and the first gate.</p>
<p id="p-0111" num="0110">Example 54 is a system as in any of Examples 51-53, wherein the second gate is configured to open to enable the second ring formation to receive the leash cord; and wherein the second gate is configured to close such that the leash cord is disposed within the second ring formation.</p>
<p id="p-0112" num="0111">Example 55 is a system as in any of Examples 51-54, wherein the connector comprises a double gate carabiner comprising: a first carabiner comprising the first ring formation and the first gate; and a second carabiner comprising the second ring formation and the second gate.</p>
<p id="p-0113" num="0112">Example 56 is a system as in any of Examples 51-55, wherein at least one of the first gate or the second gate comprises a spring configured to automatically spring into a closed position when not being depressed, and wherein the closed position is defined by at least one of the first ring formation or the second ring formation forming a closed loop.</p>
<p id="p-0114" num="0113">Example 57 is a system as in any of Examples 51-56, wherein the loop is formed of a length of the flexible material comprising a first releasably attachable portion and a second releasably attachable portion, and wherein the first releasably attachable portion is attached to the second releasably attachable portion to form the loop.</p>
<p id="p-0115" num="0114">Example 58 is a system as in any of Examples 51-57, wherein the first releasably attachable portion is joined to the second releasably attachable portion by way of one or more of a hook, snap, button, zipper, buckle, clasp, or hook and eye closure.</p>
<p id="p-0116" num="0115">Example 59 is a system as in any of Examples 51-58, wherein the length of the flexible material further comprises a tab, and wherein the hole disposed through the flexible material is located at the tab, and wherein the tab is disposed between the first releasably attachable portion and the second releasably attachable portion.</p>
<p id="p-0117" num="0116">Example 60 is a method of releasably securing a leash cord to an object. The method includes releasably coupling a loop to a first ring formation defined by a frame of a double gate connector, wherein the loop is constructed of a flexible material, and wherein the flexible material comprises a hole disposed therethrough for receiving the frame of the double gate connector. The method includes looping the leash cord around the object. The method includes releasably hooking a second ring formation defined by the frame of the double gate connector around the leash cord to releasably secure the leash cord to the post.</p>
<p id="p-0118" num="0117">Reference throughout this specification to &#x201c;an example&#x201d; means that a particular feature, structure, or characteristic described in connection with the example is included in at least one embodiment of the disclosure. Thus, appearances of the phrase &#x201c;in an example&#x201d; in various places throughout this specification are not necessarily all referring to the same embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0119" num="0118">As used herein, a plurality of items, structural elements, compositional elements, and/or materials may be presented in a common list for convenience. However, these lists should be construed as though each member of the list is individually identified as a separate and unique member. Thus, no individual member of such list should be construed as a de facto equivalent of any other member of the same list solely based on its presentation in a common group without indications to the contrary. In addition, various embodiments and examples of the disclosure may be referred to herein along with alternatives for the various components thereof. It is understood that such embodiments, examples, and alternatives are not to be construed as de facto equivalents of one another but are to be considered as separate and autonomous representations of the disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0120" num="0119">Although the foregoing has been described in some detail for purposes of clarity, it will be apparent that certain changes and modifications may be made without departing from the principles thereof. It should be noted that there are many alternative ways of implementing both the processes and apparatuses described herein. Accordingly, the present embodiments are to be considered illustrative and not restrictive.</p>
<p id="p-0121" num="0120">Those having skill in the art will appreciate that many changes may be made to the details of the above-described embodiments without departing from the underlying principles of the disclosure.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A device comprising:
<claim-text>a loop constructed of a flexible material, wherein the flexible material comprises a hole disposed therethrough; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a connector comprising a frame defining a first ring formation and a second ring formation, wherein the first ring formation is opened by way of a first gate, and wherein the second ring formation is opened by way of a second gate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a portion of the frame defining the first ring formation is disposed through the hole of the loop such that the connector is releasably coupled to the loop; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second ring formation of the connector is configured to receive a line.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the connector is a double gate connector and further comprises a swivel disposed between the first gate and the second gate, wherein the swivel enables the first gate to rotate relative to the second gate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the hole disposed through the flexible material further comprises a grommet, and wherein an interior diameter defined by the grommet is optimized to receive the frame of the connector and the first gate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the line comprises a leash cord, and wherein the second gate is configured to open to enable the second ring formation to receive the leash cord; and
<claim-text>wherein the second gate is configured to close such that the leash cord is disposed within the second ring formation.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the connector comprises a double gate carabiner comprising:
<claim-text>a first carabiner comprising the first ring formation and the first gate; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second carabiner comprising the second ring formation and the second gate.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein at least one of the first gate or the second gate comprises a spring configured to automatically spring into a closed position when not being depressed, and wherein the closed position is defined by at least one of the first ring formation or the second ring formation forming a closed loop.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the loop is formed of a length of the flexible material comprising a first releasably attachable portion and a second releasably attachable portion, and wherein the first releasably attachable portion is attached to the second releasably attachable portion to form the loop.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the first releasably attachable portion is joined to the second releasably attachable portion by way of one or more of a hook, snap, button, zipper, buckle, clasp, or hook and eye closure.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the length of the flexible material further comprises a tab, and wherein the hole disposed through the flexible material is located at the tab, and wherein the tab is disposed between the first releasably attachable portion and the second releasably attachable portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein at least one of the first gate or the second gate comprises a locking sleeve such that the at least one of the first gate or the second gate can be locked in a closed position, wherein the closed position is defined by at least one of the first ring formation or the second ring formation forming a closed loop.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. A system comprising:
<claim-text>a leash cord;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a loop constructed of a flexible material, wherein the flexible material comprises a hole disposed therethrough;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a connector comprising a frame defining a first ring formation and a second ring formation, wherein the first ring formation is opened by way of a first gate, and wherein the second ring formation is opened by way of a second gate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a portion of the frame defining the first ring formation is disposed through the hole of the loop such that the connector is releasably coupled to the loop; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second ring formation of the connector is configured to receive the leash cord to releasably secure the leash cord around an object.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the connector is a double gate connector and further comprises a swivel disposed between the first gate and the second gate, wherein the swivel enables the first gate to rotate relative to the second gate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the hole disposed through the flexible material further comprises a grommet, and wherein an interior diameter defined by the grommet is optimized to receive the frame of the connector and the first gate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the second gate is configured to open to enable the second ring formation to receive the leash cord; and
<claim-text>wherein the second gate is configured to close such that the leash cord is disposed within the second ring formation.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the connector comprises a double gate carabiner comprising:
<claim-text>a first carabiner comprising the first ring formation and the first gate; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second carabiner comprising the second ring formation and the second gate.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein at least one of the first gate or the second gate comprises a spring configured to automatically spring into a closed position when not being depressed, and wherein the closed position is defined by at least one of the first ring formation or the second ring formation forming a closed loop.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the loop is formed of a length of the flexible material comprising a first releasably attachable portion and a second releasably attachable portion, and wherein the first releasably attachable portion is attached to the second releasably attachable portion to form the loop.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein the first releasably attachable portion is joined to the second releasably attachable portion by way of one or more of a hook, snap, button, zipper, buckle, clasp, or hook and eye closure.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein the length of the flexible material further comprises a tab, and wherein the hole disposed through the flexible material is located at the tab, and wherein the tab is disposed between the first releasably attachable portion and the second releasably attachable portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. A method of releasably securing a leash cord to an object, the method comprising:
<claim-text>releasably coupling a loop to a first ring formation defined by a frame of a double gate connector, wherein the loop is constructed of a flexible material, and wherein the flexible material comprises a hole disposed therethrough for receiving the frame of the double gate connector;</claim-text>
<claim-text>looping the leash cord around the object; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>releasably hooking a second ring formation defined by the frame of the double gate connector around the leash cord to releasably secure the leash cord to the post.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
