<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225579A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225579</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18190740</doc-number>
<date>20230327</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>11</main-group>
<subgroup>30</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>11</main-group>
<subgroup>40</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>11</main-group>
<subgroup>30</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>11</main-group>
<subgroup>4019</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>11</main-group>
<subgroup>4083</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">FLOOR CLEANER</invention-title>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17237930</doc-number>
<date>20210422</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11612293</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18190740</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>63015075</doc-number>
<date>20200424</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Techtronic Floor Care Technology Limited</orgname>
<address>
<city>Tortola</city>
<country>VG</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>VG</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Rukavina</last-name>
<first-name>Douglas M.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Concord</city>
<state>NC</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A floor cleaner that includes a recovery tank having a top side, a bottom wall opposite the top side, and a sidewall that extends from the bottom wall and defines a perimeter of the recovery tank, the bottom wall and the sidewall at least partially define a storage volume of the recovery tank. The recover tank further includes an inlet aperture, the inlet aperture adjacent the storage volume and the top side and configured to direct fluid into the storage volume. A baffle wall is connected to the sidewall and the baffle wall faces toward the inlet aperture. An inlet aperture axis extending centrally through the inlet aperture and the inlet aperture axis extends through the baffle wall.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="122.00mm" wi="122.00mm" file="US20230225579A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="237.74mm" wi="113.11mm" file="US20230225579A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="192.96mm" wi="157.14mm" file="US20230225579A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="226.99mm" wi="146.05mm" file="US20230225579A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="177.63mm" wi="138.51mm" file="US20230225579A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="129.54mm" wi="124.04mm" file="US20230225579A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="241.55mm" wi="116.16mm" file="US20230225579A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="187.11mm" wi="146.30mm" file="US20230225579A1-20230720-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="212.09mm" wi="142.49mm" file="US20230225579A1-20230720-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="130.22mm" wi="125.73mm" file="US20230225579A1-20230720-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a continuation of U.S. patent application Ser. No. 17/237,930, filed Apr. 22, 2021, which issued as U.S. Pat. No. 11,612,293 on Mar. 28, 2023, which claims priority to U.S. Provisional Patent Application No. 63/015,075, filed Apr. 24, 2020, the entire contents all of which are hereby incorporated by reference herein.</p>
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="tail"?>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates to floor cleaners and more particularly to floor cleaners that dispense a fluid onto a surface and recovery and store the fluid in a recovery tank.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">In one embodiment a floor cleaner includes a supply tank configured to store a fluid, a fluid distributor in fluid communication with the supply tank, the fluid distributor operable to dispense the fluid onto a surface being cleaned. The floor cleaner further includes a suction inlet and a suction source in fluid communication with the suction inlet, the suction source operable to generate a suction airflow that is configured to draw the fluid from the surface through the suction inlet. The floor cleaner further includes a recovery tank in fluid communication with the suction inlet and the suction source, the recovery tank configured to receive the fluid and the suction airflow from the suction inlet and separate the suction airflow from the suction inlet. The recover tank includes a top side, a bottom wall opposite the top side, and a sidewall that extends from the bottom wall and defines a perimeter of the recovery tank, the bottom wall and the sidewall at least partially define a storage volume of the recovery tank. An inlet duct is adjacent the top side of the recovery tank. The recovery tank further includes an inlet aperture that faces the bottom wall, the inlet aperture adjacent the storage volume and the top side and configured to direct the fluid from the inlet duct into the storage volume. The inlet aperture is adjacent the sidewall of the recovery tank and the inlet aperture is a longitudinal shaped aperture having an aperture width and an aperture depth, the aperture width being greater than the aperture depth, and the aperture width extends along the sidewall and the aperture depth extends along an inlet duct axis.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Other aspects of the invention will become apparent by consideration of the detailed description and accompanying drawings.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a perspective view of a floor cleaner according to one embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a perspective view of a recovery tank of the floor cleaner of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a perspective view of the recovery tank of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> with a lid in an open position.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is a cross-sectional view of the recovery tank of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is an alternative cross-sectional view of the recovery tank of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is an enlarged view of a portion of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> is a perspective view of the lid of the recovery tank of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> is a bottom side view of the lid of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref> is a top side view of the lid of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref> is a cross-sectional view through a recovery tank according to an alternative embodiment.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Before any embodiments of the invention are explained in detail, it is to be understood that the invention is not limited in its application to the details of construction and the arrangement of components set forth in the following description or illustrated in the following drawings. The invention is capable of other embodiments and of being practiced or of being carried out in various ways.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> illustrates a floor cleaner <b>10</b>. The floor cleaner <b>10</b> includes a supply tank <b>12</b> and a fluid distributor <b>14</b>. The supply tank <b>12</b> stores a fluid, for example, a cleaning fluid that includes water, detergent, or a mixture of water and detergent. The fluid distributor <b>14</b> is in fluid communication with the supply tank <b>12</b> and is operable to dispense the fluid from the supply tank <b>12</b> onto a surface being cleaned. The floor cleaner <b>10</b> further includes a suction inlet <b>16</b> and a suction source <b>18</b>. The suction source <b>18</b> is in fluid communication with the suction inlet <b>16</b>. The suction source <b>18</b> includes a motor and a fan in one embodiment that are operable to generate a suction airflow through the suction inlet <b>16</b>. The suction airflow draws the fluid from the surface being cleaned through the suction inlet <b>16</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The floor cleaner <b>10</b> further includes a recovery tank <b>20</b>. The recovery tank <b>20</b> is in fluid communication with the suction source <b>18</b> and the suction inlet <b>16</b>. The recovery tank <b>20</b> receives the fluid and the suction airflow from the suction inlet <b>16</b> and the recovery tank <b>20</b> separates the fluid from the suction airflow. The fluid is stored in the recovery tank <b>20</b> and the suction airflow exits the recovery tank and travels to the suction source <b>18</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the recovery tank <b>20</b> includes a top side <b>22</b>, a bottom side or wall <b>24</b>, opposite the top side <b>22</b>, and a sidewall <b>26</b> that extends up from the bottom wall <b>24</b>. The sidewall <b>26</b> defines a perimeter of the recovery tank <b>20</b> and together the sidewall <b>26</b> and the bottom wall <b>24</b> define a storage volume of the recovery tank <b>20</b> for the fluid. A lid <b>28</b> is removably coupled to the sidewall <b>26</b> and the lid <b>28</b> defines the top side <b>22</b> of the recovery tank <b>20</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, the lid <b>28</b> movable relative to the sidewall <b>26</b> between a closed position (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>) and an open position (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>) for emptying the storage volume.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>3</b> and <b>4</b></figref>, the recovery tank <b>20</b> further includes a recovery tank inlet <b>30</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>) and a recovery tank outlet <b>32</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>). A mixture of the fluid and the suction airflow enters the recovery tank <b>20</b> through the inlet <b>30</b>. The fluid is substantially separated from the airflow and retained in the storage volume of the recovery tank <b>20</b> while the airflow moves through the outlet <b>32</b> and travels to the suction source <b>18</b>. The recovery tank <b>20</b> includes a float <b>34</b>. The float <b>34</b> closes an outlet aperture <b>36</b> of the storage volume when the fluid reaches a maximum fill level <b>38</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">With continued reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, the recovery tank <b>20</b> includes an inlet duct <b>40</b> that directs the fluid and the suction airflow from the recover tank inlet <b>30</b> into the storage volume of the recovery tank <b>20</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, the inlet duct <b>40</b> includes a first portion <b>42</b> and a second portion <b>44</b>. The first portion <b>42</b> extends upwardly from the inlet <b>30</b> to the lid <b>28</b> and to the second portion <b>44</b>. The second portion <b>44</b> of the inlet duct <b>40</b> is part of the lid <b>28</b> and directs the fluid and the suction airflow into the storage volume of the recovery tank <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The second portion <b>44</b> of the inlet duct <b>40</b> includes a first end <b>46</b> and a second end <b>48</b>. A top wall <b>50</b> and a bottom wall <b>52</b> of the duct portion <b>44</b> both extend between the first end <b>46</b> and the second end <b>48</b>. The bottom wall <b>52</b> faces the bottom wall <b>24</b> of the recovery tank <b>20</b>. An inlet aperture <b>54</b> to the storage volume extends through the bottom wall <b>52</b> adjacent the second end <b>48</b> of the duct portion <b>44</b>. The illustrated bottom wall <b>52</b> is angled relative to the bottom wall <b>24</b> of the recovery tank <b>20</b>. In some embodiments, the bottom wall <b>52</b> is angled about 1 to 8 degrees relative to the bottom wall <b>24</b> of the recovery tank <b>20</b> so that the second end <b>48</b> of the duct <b>44</b> is closer to the bottom wall <b>24</b> of the recovery tank <b>20</b> than the first end <b>46</b> of the duct <b>44</b>. The angle facilities the flow of fluid toward the inlet aperture <b>54</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>5</b> and <b>6</b></figref>, the inlet aperture <b>54</b> is adjacent the top side <b>22</b> of the recovery tank <b>20</b> and the inlet aperture <b>54</b> faces the bottom wall <b>24</b> of the recovery tank <b>20</b>. The inlet aperture <b>24</b> is also adjacent the storage volume of the recovery tank <b>20</b> such that the fluid and the airflow exit the inlet duct <b>40</b> into the storage volume directed by the inlet aperture <b>54</b>. The inlet aperture <b>54</b> is adjacent the sidewall <b>26</b> of the recovery tank <b>20</b>. The inlet aperture <b>54</b> is spaced a distance <b>58</b> from the sidewall <b>26</b> measured generally parallel to the bottom wall <b>24</b> of the recovery tank <b>20</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>. In one embodiment, the distance <b>58</b> is in a range from 0 to 20 millimeters (mm). In another embodiment, the distance <b>58</b> is in a range from 0 to 10 mm. In yet another embodiment, the distance <b>58</b> is in a range from 0 to 6 mm. The adjacent and close relationship between the inlet aperture <b>54</b> and the sidewall <b>26</b> enables the fluid entering the storage volume of the recovery tank <b>20</b> to flow through the inlet aperture <b>54</b> onto the sidewall <b>26</b> to facilitate separation of the fluid from the airflow and inhibit formation of foam from cleaning agents in the fluid. Increasing the distance <b>58</b> (e.g., between about 4 mm and 20 mm) tends to increase the impact of the fluid against the sidewall <b>26</b> absorbing energy of the incoming flow that facilitates separation of the fluid from the airflow. It has been found that the distance <b>58</b> may be selected to provide desired fluid and airflow separation while inhibiting or minimizing the formation of foam. An inlet aperture axis <b>60</b> extends centrally through the inlet aperture <b>54</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>. In some embodiments, the inlet aperture axis <b>60</b> is perpendicular to the bottom wall <b>24</b> of the recovery tank <b>20</b> plus or minus 20 degrees.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The duct portion <b>44</b> is adjacent the top side <b>22</b> of the recovery tank <b>20</b> and extends in a direction from a first or front side <b>62</b> of the sidewall <b>26</b> to a second or back side <b>64</b> of the sidewall <b>26</b> opposite the front side <b>62</b>. The top wall <b>50</b> of the duct portion <b>44</b> is transparent or semitransparent such that the duct portion <b>44</b> is visible to a user during operation of the floor cleaner and the user can see the fluid traveling through the duct portion <b>44</b> and through the inlet aperture <b>54</b> into the storage volume of the recovery tank <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">An inlet duct axis <b>68</b> extends centrally through the duct portion <b>44</b> along a length of the duct portion <b>44</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, the axis <b>68</b> is angled relative to the bottom wall <b>24</b> of the recovery tank <b>20</b> due to the angle of the bottom wall <b>52</b> of the duct portion <b>44</b> discussed above. The inlet duct axis <b>68</b> is at an angle <b>70</b> with the respect to the inlet aperture axis <b>60</b>. In some embodiments, the angle <b>70</b> is in a range from 85 degrees to 135 degrees. In other embodiments, the angle <b>70</b> is in a range from 90 degrees to 110 degrees. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref>, a width <b>72</b> of the duct portion <b>44</b> is measured perpendicular to the axis <b>68</b>. The width <b>72</b> increase in a direction toward the inlet aperture <b>54</b> along the axis <b>68</b>. The width <b>72</b> widens from a first width <b>72</b><i>a </i>at the first end <b>46</b> to a second width <b>72</b><i>b </i>near the inlet aperture <b>54</b> and the second end <b>48</b>. The inlet aperture <b>54</b> is a longitudinal shaped aperture having a width <b>74</b> and a depth <b>75</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref>), where the width <b>74</b> extends along the sidewall <b>26</b> and the depth <b>75</b> extends along the inlet duct axis <b>68</b>. The width <b>74</b> of the inlet aperture <b>54</b> generally corresponds to the second width <b>72</b><i>b. </i>In one embodiment, the width <b>74</b> of the inlet aperture <b>54</b> is equal to the width <b>72</b><i>b. </i>In some embodiments, width <b>72</b><i>b </i>is between 1.25 and 3 times width <b>72</b><i>a, </i>and may be between 1.5 and 2.5 times wider than the width <b>72</b><i>a </i>in such embodiments. Increased width <b>74</b> of the inlet aperture <b>54</b> provides a wider flow surface along the sidewall <b>26</b> facilitating separation of the fluid and the airflow and inhibiting formation of foam. In one embodiment, at least a portion of the width <b>74</b> extends along the sidewall <b>26</b> for a distance greater than the depth <b>75</b>. In one embodiment, at least a portion of the width <b>74</b> extends along the sidewall <b>26</b> for a distance from 1.1 to 12 times the depth <b>75</b>, and may be from 1.5 to 12 times the depth <b>75</b>. In one embodiment, at least a portion of the width <b>74</b> extends along the sidewall <b>26</b> for a distance from 2 to 6 times the depth <b>75</b>, and may be from 3 to 5 times the depth <b>75</b>. In one embodiment, the inlet aperture <b>54</b> is a longitudinal shaped aperture having at least a portion of the width <b>74</b> extending along the sidewall <b>26</b> a constant distance from the sidewall <b>26</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref>, a height <b>100</b> of the duct portion <b>44</b> is measured perpendicular to the axis <b>68</b>. The height <b>100</b> increases in a direction toward the inlet aperture <b>54</b> along the axis <b>68</b>. The height <b>100</b> increases from a first height <b>100</b><i>a </i>at the first end <b>46</b> to a second height <b>100</b><i>b </i>near the inlet aperture <b>54</b> and the second end <b>48</b>. In one embodiment, the height <b>100</b> gradually increases from the first height <b>100</b><i>a </i>to the second height <b>100</b><i>b </i>between the first end <b>46</b> and the second end <b>48</b>. In another embodiment, the height <b>100</b> increases from the first height <b>100</b><i>a </i>to the second height <b>100</b><i>b </i>via one or more steps. In the embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref>, the height increases by both a step <b>98</b> and a gradual increase downstream of the step. In one embodiment, the height <b>100</b><i>b </i>is between 1.03 and 2 times the height <b>100</b><i>a. </i>In another embodiment, the height <b>100</b><i>b </i>is between 1.3 and 1.8 times higher than the height <b>100</b><i>a. </i>In yet another embodiment, the height <b>100</b><i>b </i>is between 1.03 and 1.3 times higher than the height <b>100</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Because of the increasing width <b>72</b> and height <b>100</b> along the axis <b>68</b>, the cross-sectional area of the duct portion <b>44</b> also increases in the same direction toward the inlet aperture <b>54</b> along the axis <b>68</b>. The increasing cross-sectional area reduces the flow velocity of the fluid and the suction airflow in the duct portion <b>44</b>. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref>, the duct portion <b>44</b> has a first cross-sectional area <b>76</b> at the first end <b>46</b> of the duct portion <b>44</b> and a second cross-sectional area <b>78</b> at the second end <b>48</b> of the duct portion <b>44</b> that is greater than the cross-sectional area <b>76</b>. The second cross-sectional area <b>78</b> is directly adjacent the inlet aperture <b>54</b>. In one embodiment, the area of the inlet aperture <b>54</b> is equal to the second cross-sectional area <b>78</b>. In some embodiments the second cross-sectional area <b>78</b> is between 1.25 and 4 times the first cross-sectional area <b>76</b>, and may be between 2 and 3 times the first cross-sectional area <b>76</b> in such embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>, the duct portion <b>44</b> includes a deflecting surface <b>80</b>. The deflecting surface <b>80</b> is adjacent the inlet aperture <b>54</b> and facilitates a change in direction of the flow of fluid and the airflow from along the duct axis <b>68</b> to along the inlet aperture axis <b>60</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, the deflecting surface <b>80</b> is curved and generally tangent to the top wall <b>50</b> of the duct portion <b>44</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>5</b> and <b>7</b></figref>, a ducted channel <b>82</b> surrounds the inlet aperture <b>54</b> inside the recovery tank <b>20</b>. The ducted channel <b>82</b> facilitates downward flow of the fluid and the airflow and inhibits flow in lateral or horizontal directions. The ducted channel <b>82</b> extends toward the bottom wall <b>24</b> of the recovery tank <b>20</b> and has a length <b>84</b>. In some embodiments, the length <b>84</b> is at least 5 mm. In such embodiments, the length <b>84</b> may be greater than 15 mm and in yet other embodiments greater than 25 mm. The illustrated ducted channel <b>82</b> is formed by a portion <b>86</b> of the sidewall <b>26</b> and a portion <b>88</b> of the lid <b>28</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, the recovery tank <b>20</b> further includes a baffle wall <b>90</b>. The baffle wall <b>90</b> faces toward the inlet aperture <b>54</b> and the inlet aperture axis <b>60</b> extends through the baffle wall <b>90</b>. In some embodiments, the axis <b>60</b> is generally perpendicular to the baffle wall <b>90</b>. In some embodiments, the baffle wall <b>90</b> is angled or slanted relative to the bottom wall <b>24</b> of the recovery tank <b>20</b>. For example, the baffle wall <b>90</b> may be angled 1 to 15 degrees, including 2 to 10 degrees, relative to the bottom wall <b>24</b> to promote fluid drainage off of the baffle wall <b>90</b> toward the bottom wall <b>24</b>, which may also inhibit the formation of foam in the recovery tank <b>20</b>. The baffle wall <b>90</b> is spaced a baffle height <b>92</b> measured from the bottom wall <b>24</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>. The baffle wall <b>90</b> is positioned to be greater than a predetermined fluid level in the tank, such that when fluid level is lower than the predetermined level, the fluid entering the tank through the inlet aperture <b>54</b> engages the baffle wall <b>90</b> before engaging the surface of the fluid, inhibiting formation of foam in the recovery tank <b>20</b>. In one embodiment, the baffle height <b>92</b> is selected to be greater than the fluid height at 50% of the maximum fill level <b>38</b>. In a preferred embodiment, the baffle height <b>92</b> is greater than the maximum fill level <b>38</b> of the recovery tank <b>20</b>. In some embodiments, the baffle height <b>92</b> is about 2 mm to about 30 mm greater than the maximum fill level <b>38</b>, and between about 5 mm to about 15 mm greater than the maximum fill level <b>38</b> in some embodiments. In the illustrated embodiment, the baffle wall <b>90</b> is formed by a recess <b>94</b> in the sidewall <b>26</b>. The recess <b>94</b> forms a lifting handle <b>55</b> for the recovery tank <b>20</b> that can be used in combination with a handle <b>96</b> of the lid <b>28</b>. In one embodiment, the handle <b>55</b> includes a grip portion <b>57</b> disposed adjacent the recess <b>94</b> for a user's fingers to engage when using the handle <b>55</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Although the invention has been described in detail with reference to certain preferred embodiments, variations and modifications exist within the scope and spirit of one or more independent aspects of the invention as described.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A floor cleaner comprising:
<claim-text>a supply tank configured to store a fluid;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fluid distributor in fluid communication with the supply tank, the fluid distributor operable to dispense the fluid onto a surface being cleaned;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a suction inlet;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a suction source in fluid communication with the suction inlet, the suction source operable to generate a suction airflow that is configured to draw the fluid from the surface through the suction inlet; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a recovery tank in fluid communication with the suction inlet and the suction source, the recovery tank configured to receive the fluid and the suction airflow from the suction inlet and separate the suction airflow from the fluid, the recover tank including:
<claim-text>a top side,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a bottom wall opposite the top side,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a sidewall that extends from the bottom wall and defines a perimeter of the recovery tank, the bottom wall and the sidewall at least partially define a storage volume of the recovery tank,</claim-text>
<claim-text>an inlet duct having an inlet aperture configured to direct the fluid from the inlet duct into the storage volume,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a baffle wall connected to the sidewall and the baffle wall facing toward the inlet aperture, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an inlet aperture axis extending centrally through the inlet aperture,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the inlet aperture axis extends through the baffle wall.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The floor cleaner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the inlet aperture is adjacent the sidewall of the recovery tank and the inlet aperture is a longitudinal shaped aperture having an aperture width and an aperture depth, the aperture width being greater than the aperture depth, wherein the aperture width extends along the sidewall and the aperture depth extends along an inlet duct axis.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The floor cleaner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein at least a portion of the aperture width extends along the sidewall a constant distance from the sidewall.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The floor cleaner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the aperture width is transverse to the inlet duct axis.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The floor cleaner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the aperture width corresponds to the inlet duct adjacent the inlet aperture.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The floor cleaner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the aperture width is from 1 to 12 times the aperture depth.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The floor cleaner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the inlet duct is adjacent the top side of the recovery tank configured to direct a flow velocity of the fluid and the suction airflow along the sidewall downstream of the inlet duct.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The floor cleaner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the inlet aperture faces the bottom wall.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The floor cleaner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the inlet aperture is disposed above the baffle wall in a direction from the bottom wall to the top side.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The floor cleaner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the inlet aperture is spaced from the sidewall a distance measured parallel to the bottom wall, the distance in a range from 0 millimeters to 20 millimeters.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The floor cleaner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the inlet aperture forms an outlet of the inlet duct.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The floor cleaner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a ducted channel that surrounds the inlet aperture inside of the recovery tank and the ducted channel extends toward the bottom wall, wherein the ducted channel has a length measured from the inlet aperture toward the bottom wall, and wherein the length is at least 5 millimeters.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. The floor cleaner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the recovery tank includes a lid removably coupled to the sidewall, and wherein the lid includes the inlet duct.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The floor cleaner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the inlet duct includes a first portion that extends from the bottom wall and a second portion formed in the lid.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. The floor cleaner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the inlet duct has a cross-sectional area that increases in a direction toward the inlet aperture configured to reduce a flow velocity of the fluid and the suction airflow in the inlet duct.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. The floor cleaner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the inlet duct forms an axis that extends centrally through the inlet duct along a length of the inlet duct, wherein the inlet duct has a width measured perpendicular to the inlet duct axis, and wherein the width increases in a direction toward the inlet aperture along the inlet duct axis.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. The floor cleaner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the inlet duct has a height that increases in a direction toward the inlet aperture.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. The floor cleaner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the sidewall has a first side and a second side opposite the first side, wherein the inlet duct extends in a direction from the first side toward the side.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. The floor cleaner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the baffle wall is spaced a baffle height measured from the bottom wall, the baffle height is greater than 50% of a maximum fill level of the storage volume measured from the bottom wall.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. The floor cleaner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the baffle height is greater than the maximum fill level in a range from 2 millimeters to 30 millimeters.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
