<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225251A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225251</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18124005</doc-number>
<date>20230321</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>202210281390.9</doc-number>
<date>20220321</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>46</main-group>
<subgroup>26</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>16</class>
<subclass>H</subclass>
<main-group>37</main-group>
<subgroup>12</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>46</main-group>
<subgroup>264</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>F</section>
<class>16</class>
<subclass>H</subclass>
<main-group>37</main-group>
<subgroup>122</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e61">DOUBLE-SWING-ROD MECHANISM AND FRUIT PICKING MACHINE USING SAME</invention-title>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>DongGuan Koham IndustriaI Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<address>
<city>Dongguan</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ma</last-name>
<first-name>Xianpeng</first-name>
<address>
<city>Dongguan</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>DongGuan Koham IndustriaI Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Dongguan</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The present disclosure relates to the technical field of olive picking machines, in particular, to a double-swing-rod mechanism and a fruit picking machine using same. The double-swing-rod mechanism includes a supporting main body used for rigidly supporting a fruit picking machine, a rotating shaft component connected to the supporting main body, two conical gears that axially rotate around the rotating shaft component, two swing rods movably connected to the two conical gears respectively to achieve a swing effect, and a drive gear movably connected to the supporting main body.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="102.87mm" wi="158.75mm" file="US20230225251A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="114.55mm" wi="158.50mm" file="US20230225251A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="94.23mm" wi="163.07mm" file="US20230225251A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="199.81mm" wi="155.87mm" file="US20230225251A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="128.44mm" wi="157.65mm" file="US20230225251A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="124.38mm" wi="164.76mm" file="US20230225251A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="113.20mm" wi="161.46mm" file="US20230225251A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="129.62mm" wi="156.38mm" file="US20230225251A1-20230720-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present disclosure relates to the technical field of olive picking machines, in particular, to a double-swing-rod mechanism and a fruit picking machine using same.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">In order to improve the efficiency of picking olives and other similar products, according to a height problem in picking and a size characteristic of a picked product, a picking tool with a power striking structure, namely, an olive picking machine, is invented, which is used to strike branches of fruit trees to make the branches shake, so as to cause fruits to fall off. The olive picking machine in the prior art mainly includes a striking device using a lever structure, a power main body that drives the striking device to swing, and a supporting rod that carries the power main body and the striking device to a certain height. Specifically, the existing striking device includes a plurality of long and narrow rod-shaped or strip-shaped striking components, and also includes a swing arm that carries the striking components and drives the components to complete a striking action. Generally, there are at least two swing arm components to complete actions with mutual opposite acting forces, which can maintain a balance of force. A main consideration is that a horizontal bar action has poor control over a striking force on fruits. For example, the fruits cannot be struck down or are directly broken, and a high counter-acting force is generated on an operator, resulting in difficulty in operation. The action of the swing arm component is realized by the power main body. The power main body includes a drive motor rigidly supported to the supporting rod and a double-swing-rod mechanism that is in power connection to the drive motor. The drive motor drives the double-swing-rod mechanism to produce an action of a certain trajectory to drive the swing arm component to move, causing the striking components to complete a striking action.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">At present, a structural design for the double-swing-rod mechanism at home and abroad mainly uses a crank rocker mechanism to drive the swing arm components to complete a swing action. Since the crank rocker mechanism needs to drive two swing arm components at the same time, a secondary feed structure needs to be hinged between the crank rocker mechanism and each swing arm component to achieve a four-rod hinge manner, for example, equipment for picking olives and similar products described in the domestic patent No. CN201280029788, an operating component of a harvester for picking olives and similar products described in the domestic patent No. CN201821289188, and a device for picking olives and similar products described in the foreign patent No. EP2384614A1. In a structural design, the two secondary feed structures need to be designed to occupy a certain space to ensure that there is no collision. The secondary feed structure will decompose force transmission and reduce a swing amplitude of a swing arm component. In addition, an axial line corresponding to a rocker of a crank rocker mechanism and an axial line corresponding to a motor are arranged in parallel with each other, which can make full use of a length of an olive picking machine, mainly through 45&#xb0;-engagement of two gears. Although the design of the above structure is conducive to improving the overall length of the olive picking machine, compactness of the structural design will be greatly reduced after the length of the double-swing-rod mechanism is increase. In addition, the 45&#xb0;-engagement of the two gears will generate a higher counter-reacting force on a housing during running, which will have to rely on more machined parts or reinforcement structures to assist in supporting, and will also lead to an increase in mechanical wear during the running. The prior art also provides a device for picking olives as described in the foreign patent No. EP2862434A1. A crank rocker mechanism and each swing arm component are connected by a universal wheel structure. However, the universal structure is complex and has a high requirement for precision, resulting in an increase in the overall production cost.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In order to overcome the above deficiencies, the present disclosure aims to provide a technical solution capable of solving the above problems.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">A double-swing-rod mechanism includes a supporting main body used for rigidly supporting a fruit picking machine, a rotating shaft component connected to the supporting main body, two conical gears that axially rotate around the rotating shaft component, two swing rods movably connected to the two conical gears respectively to achieve a swing effect, and a drive gear movably connected to the supporting main body, wherein eccentric wheels that rotates around the rotating shaft component are arranged on the conical gears; the swing rods rotate around the eccentric wheels; the two conical gears are oppositely disposed; and the drive gear is engaged between the two conical gears.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Preferably, the supporting main body includes a backplane and supporting plates arranged in front of the backplane; a space for accommodating a gear is formed between the backplane and the two supporting plates; the rotating shaft component is fixedly connected between the two supporting plates; the conical gears are restrained between the two supporting plates through the rotating shaft component; and the drive gear is movably connected to the backplane.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Preferably, a barrier structure corresponding to the drive gear is arranged in a middle portion of the rotating shaft component; and the two conical gears are separated by the barrier structure.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Preferably, the conical gears are bevel gears, and the conical gears are engaged with the drive gear by helical tooth structures.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Preferably, the eccentric wheels are formed on the conical gears; rotating shaft holes penetrating through the eccentric wheels are formed in the axial lines of the conical gears; first bearings are arranged in the rotating shaft holes; and the conical gears and the eccentric wheels rotate around the rotating shaft component through the first bearings.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Preferably, connection sleeves surrounding the rotating shaft component are also arranged on the eccentric wheels; peripheries of the connection sleeves are sleeved with flat washers and second bearings; the flat washers are located between the first bearings and the second bearings; and the connection sleeves are movably connected with the supporting plates through the second bearings.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Preferably, third bearings are arranged at peripheries of the eccentric wheels; and one ends of the swing rods are provided with annular portions sleeving the third bearings.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">A fruit picking machine using a double-swing-rod mechanism includes the foregoing double-swing-rod mechanism, and further includes a supporting rod, a power drive main body and two striking members, wherein the power drive main body includes a housing and a drive motor; the double-swing-rod mechanism is arranged inside the housing; the drive motor is arranged at a back portion of a supporting main body; the drive motor is in power connection with the drive gear; rotating shaft sleeve holes and power sleeve holes are formed in the two striking members; the two striking members are both rotatably connected to a front end of the housing through the rotating shaft sleeve holes; the two striking members are both hinged and cooperate with the two swing rods through the power sleeve holes; and a rear portion of the housing is fixed on the supporting rod.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Preferably, the housing includes an upper shell and a lower shell that are in longitudinal symmetry; the upper shell and the lower shell fixedly cover each other through a bolt; mounting openings are formed in front ends of the upper shell and the lower shell; two ends of the mounting openings are respectively provided with rotating shaft structures connected to the upper shell and the lower shell; and the rotating shaft structures are rotatably connected with the rotating shaft sleeve holes.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Preferably, the rotating shaft structures include bolt rod pieces, fourth bearings and fifth bearings; the front ends of the upper shell and the lower shell are tightened by using the bolt rod pieces; the fourth bearings and the fifth bearings sleeve the bolt rod pieces; first conical sleeves are also arranged on the bolt rod pieces and located between the fourth bearings and the fifth bearings; second conical sleeves are respectively arranged at positions, located between the fourth bearings and the upper shell, on the bolt rod pieces and positions, located between the fifth bearings and the lower shell, on the bolt rod pieces; the rotating shaft sleeve holes are rotatably connected with the fourth bearings and the fifth bearings; and positioning rings limited between the fourth bearings and the fifth bearings are arranged on inner sides of the rotating shaft sleeve holes.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Preferably, shielding structures located in middle portions of the mounting openings are further respectively formed at the front ends of the upper shell and the lower shell; the two shielding structures are fixedly abutted through bolts; and positions, hinged to the swing rods, of the power sleeve holes are shielded by the shielding structures.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Preferably, fixing bolts connected to the rotating shaft component are respectively arranged on the upper shell and the lower shell; and two ends of the rotating shaft component are respectively in threaded connection with the two fixing bolts.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Preferably, arc surfaces used for wrapping the supporting rod are respectively arranged at rear portions of the upper shell and the lower shell; a clearance capable of being flexibly pressed is reserved between the arc surfaces of the upper shell and the lower shell; and bolt holes for pressing the clearance are respectively formed in the arc surfaces of the upper shell and the lower shell.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Preferably, the striking members include a plurality of long and narrow rod-like or strip-shaped striking components; the striking members further include swing arm components for carrying the striking components and driving the striking components to complete striking actions; the rotating shaft sleeve holes and the power sleeve holes are both arranged on the swing arm components; and the two swing arm components are located on a same plane.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Preferably, the swing arm components include vertical platy structures and ringlike structures surrounding edges of the platy structures; the swing arm components form structures with &#x201c;I&#x201d;-shaped cross sections by using the platy structures and the ringlike structures; a plurality of threaded connection cylinders for connecting the plurality of striking components are formed on the swing arm components; openings of the threaded connection cylinders are upward; the threaded connection cylinders are longitudinally combined with the platy structures; the threaded connection cylinders are transversely combined with the ringlike structures; the threaded connection cylinders are in threaded connection with connectors; the connectors are combined to the striking components by means of injection molding; and the rotating shaft sleeve holes and the power sleeve holes are both formed in the swing arm components.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Compared with the prior art, the present disclosure has the following beneficial effects.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In terms of gear fitting, a top and a bottom of the drive gear are respectively engaged with the conical gears, so that an engagement area of the drive gear is greatly enlarged. Compared with the traditional structure in which the drive gear is only engaged with one conical gear, the present disclosure can improve engagement between the gears, so that mechanical wear during running is reduced, and running between the gears is more stable.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In terms of force balance, an opposite acting force generated by the engagement between the gears on the housing is reduced by using clockwise and anticlockwise rotations of the two conical gears. With reference to the structural design of the eccentric wheel, the two swing rods can move reversely during running, and can achieve an effect of maintaining a force balance like a traditional secondary feed structure.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In terms of force transmission, gear transmission is used to replace the traditional secondary feed structure, which changes a force transmission manner, implements that the two swing rods are simultaneously driven in a three-rod hinge manner, reduces decomposition of a force caused by parts in a fitting process, and increases a swing amplitude of the striking members.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">In terms of space design, the engagement between the drive gear and the conical gears makes full use of a three-dimensional space design, so that the compactness of the overall structure is improved by simplifying an overall length by using a thickness, and all the parts cooperate each other more compactly.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The additional aspects and advantages of the prevent disclosure will be provided in the following descriptions, part of which will become apparent from the following descriptions or be learned through the practice of the prevent disclosure.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">To describe the embodiments of the present disclosure or the technical solutions in the existing art more clearly, drawings required to be used in the embodiments or the illustration of the existing art will be briefly introduced below. Obviously, the drawings in the illustration below are only some embodiments of the present disclosure. Those ordinarily skilled in the art also can acquire other drawings according to the provided drawings without doing creative work.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a schematic structural diagram of a double-swing-rod mechanism in the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a schematic sectional structural diagram of a double-swing-rod mechanism in the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is an exploded structural diagram of a double-swing-rod mechanism in the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is a schematic structural diagram of a fruit picking machine in the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is a schematic structural diagram of a fruit picking machine without a supporting rod in the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is a schematic structural diagram after a housing in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is disassembled in the present disclosure; and</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> is an enlarged diagram of a circle A in the present disclosure after sectioning along a rotating shaft structure.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Reference numerals and names in the drawings are as follows:</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">supporting body <b>10</b>, rotating shaft component <b>20</b>, conical gear <b>30</b>, swing rod <b>40</b>, drive gear <b>50</b>, supporting rod <b>60</b>, striking member <b>70</b>, power drive main body <b>80</b>, rotating shaft structure <b>90</b>, backplane <b>11</b>, supporting plate <b>12</b>, barrier structure <b>21</b>, fixing bolt <b>22</b>, eccentric wheel <b>31</b>, first bearing <b>32</b>, connection sleeve <b>33</b>, flat washer <b>34</b>, second bearing <b>35</b>, third bearing <b>36</b>, annular portion <b>41</b>, rotating shaft sleeve hole <b>71</b>, power sleeve hole <b>72</b>, striking component <b>73</b>, swing arm component <b>74</b>, platy structure <b>75</b>, ringlike structure <b>76</b>, threaded connection cylinder <b>77</b>, connector <b>78</b>, positioning ring <b>79</b>, housing <b>81</b>, drive motor <b>82</b>, upper shell <b>83</b>, lower shell <b>84</b>, arc surface <b>85</b>, bolt hole <b>86</b>, mounting opening <b>87</b>, shielding structure <b>88</b>, bolt rod piece <b>91</b>, fourth bearing <b>92</b>, fifth bearing <b>93</b>, first conical sleeve <b>94</b>, and second conical sleeve <b>95</b>.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The technical solutions in the embodiments of the present disclosure will be clearly and completely described below. Apparently, the described embodiments are only a part of the embodiments of the present disclosure, rather than all the embodiments. All other embodiments obtained by those of ordinary skill in the art based on the embodiments in the present disclosure without creative work shall fall within the protection scope of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref>, in this embodiment of the present disclosure, a double-swing-rod mechanism includes a supporting main body <b>10</b> used for rigidly supporting a fruit picking machine, a rotating shaft component <b>20</b> connected to the supporting main body <b>10</b>, two conical gears <b>30</b> that axially rotate around the rotating shaft component <b>20</b>, two swing rods <b>40</b> movably connected to the two conical gears <b>30</b> respectively to achieve a swing effect, and a drive gear <b>50</b> movably connected to the supporting main body <b>10</b>. Eccentric wheels <b>31</b> that rotates around the rotating shaft component <b>20</b> are arranged on the conical gears <b>30</b>. The swing rods <b>40</b> rotate around the eccentric wheels <b>31</b>. The two conical gears are oppositely disposed. The drive gear <b>50</b> is engaged between the two conical gears <b>30</b>. A fruit picking machine using the foregoing double-swing-rod mechanism is provided, which further includes a supporting rod <b>60</b>, a power drive main body <b>80</b> and two striking members <b>70</b>. The power drive main body <b>80</b> includes a housing <b>81</b> and a drive motor <b>82</b>. The double-swing-rod mechanism is arranged inside the housing <b>81</b>. The drive motor <b>82</b> is arranged at a back portion of a supporting main body <b>10</b>. The drive motor <b>82</b> is in power connection with the drive gear <b>50</b>. Rotating shaft sleeve holes <b>71</b> and power sleeve holes <b>72</b> are formed in the two striking members <b>70</b>. The two striking members <b>70</b> are both rotatably connected to a front end of the housing <b>81</b> through the rotating shaft sleeve holes <b>71</b>. The two striking members <b>70</b> are both hinged and cooperate with the two swing rods <b>40</b> through the power sleeve holes <b>72</b>. A rear portion of the housing <b>81</b> is fixed on the supporting rod <b>60</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">In the above technical solution, a manner of coaxially clockwise and anticlockwise rotations of the gears is ingeniously used. The eccentric wheels <b>31</b> drive the two swing rods <b>40</b> to swing, so that the double-swing-rod mechanism is arranged inside the housing <b>81</b> of the power drive main body <b>80</b>. The drive gear <b>50</b> is in power connection with the drive motor <b>82</b>. The striking members <b>70</b> of the fruit picking machine is arranged on the housing <b>81</b> of the drive main body <b>80</b>. The double-swing-rod mechanism and the striking members <b>70</b> are then hinged to complete overall power connection. By means of this technical means, in terms of gear fitting, a top and a bottom of the drive gear <b>50</b> are respectively engaged with the conical gears <b>30</b>, so that an engagement area of the drive gear <b>50</b> is greatly enlarged. Compared with the traditional structure in which the drive gear <b>50</b> is only engaged with one conical gear <b>30</b>, the present disclosure can improve engagement between the gears, so that mechanical wear during running is reduced, and running between the gears is more stable.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">In terms of force balance, an opposite acting force generated by the engagement between the gears on the housing <b>81</b> is reduced by using clockwise and anticlockwise rotations of the two conical gears <b>30</b>. With reference to the structural design of the eccentric wheels <b>31</b>, the two swing rods <b>40</b> can move reversely during running, and can achieve an effect of maintaining a force balance like a traditional secondary feed structure.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">In terms of force transmission, gear transmission is used to replace the traditional secondary feed structure, which changes a force transmission manner, implements that the two swing rods <b>40</b> are simultaneously driven in a three-rod hinge manner, reduces decomposition of a force caused by parts in a fitting process, and increases a swing amplitude of the striking members <b>70</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">In terms of space design, the engagement between the drive gear <b>50</b> and the conical gears <b>30</b> makes full use of a three-dimensional space design, so that the compactness of the overall structure is improved by simplifying an overall length by using a thickness, and all the parts cooperate each other more compactly.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">In order to more clearly and completely describe the technical means taken by the above technical solutions to solve the technical problems, the following will implement specific technical features on the double-swing-rod mechanism and the fruit picking machine:</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The technical features for the double-swing-rod mechanism are as follows:</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">Further as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, the supporting main body <b>10</b> is designed to include a backplane <b>11</b> and supporting plates <b>12</b> arranged in front of the backplane <b>11</b>. A space for accommodating a gear is formed between the backplane <b>11</b> and the two supporting plates <b>12</b>. The rotating shaft component <b>20</b> is fixedly connected between the two supporting plates <b>12</b>. The conical gears <b>30</b> are restrained between the two supporting plates <b>12</b> through the rotating shaft component <b>20</b>. The drive gear <b>50</b> is movably connected to the backplane <b>11</b>. A rear portion of the supporting main body <b>10</b> is provided with the drive motor <b>82</b>, and a front portion of the supporting main body <b>10</b> is connected with the striking members <b>70</b>. For cooperation between the two conical gears <b>30</b> and the drive gear <b>50</b> as well as the rotating shaft component <b>20</b>, preferably, a barrier structure <b>21</b> corresponding to the drive gear <b>50</b> is arranged in a middle portion of the rotating shaft component <b>20</b>. The two conical gears <b>30</b> are separated by the barrier structure <b>21</b>. In addition, the conical gears <b>30</b> are bevel gears, and the conical gears <b>30</b> are engaged with the drive gear <b>50</b> by helical tooth structures. The eccentric wheels <b>31</b> and the conial gears <b>30</b> are of an integrated structure. That is, the eccentric wheels <b>31</b> are formed on the conical gears <b>30</b>. Rotating shaft holes penetrating through the eccentric wheels <b>31</b> are formed in the axial lines of the conical gears <b>30</b>. First bearings <b>32</b> are arranged in the rotating shaft holes. The conical gears <b>30</b> and the eccentric wheels <b>31</b> rotate around the rotating shaft component <b>20</b> through the first bearings <b>32</b>, thereby achieving reliable connection between the eccentric wheels <b>31</b>, the conical gears <b>30</b> and the rotating shaft component <b>20</b>. In this structural design, connection sleeves <b>33</b> surrounding the rotating shaft component <b>20</b> are also arranged on the eccentric wheels <b>31</b>. Peripheries of the connection sleeves <b>33</b> are sleeved with flat washers <b>34</b> and second bearings <b>35</b>. The flat washers <b>34</b> are located between the first bearings <b>32</b> and the second bearings <b>35</b>. The connection sleeves <b>33</b> are movably connected with the supporting plates <b>12</b> through the second bearings <b>35</b>, so that cooperation between the conical gears <b>30</b> and the supporting main body <b>10</b> is more reliable. For cooperation between the eccentric wheels <b>31</b> and the swing rods <b>40</b>, third bearings <b>36</b> are arranged at peripheries of the eccentric wheels <b>31</b>. One ends of the swing rods <b>40</b> are provided with annular portions <b>41</b> sleeving the third bearings <b>36</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The technical features for the fruit picking machine are as follows:</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Further as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref>, the striking members <b>70</b> mainly structurally include a plurality of long and narrow rod-like or strip-shaped striking components <b>73</b>, and swing arm components <b>74</b> for carrying the striking components <b>73</b> and driving the striking components to complete striking actions. The rotating shaft sleeve holes <b>71</b> and the power sleeve holes <b>72</b> are both arranged on the swing arm components <b>74</b>. During use, the supporting rod is held with a hand to drive the power drive main body <b>80</b>, and the swing arm components <b>74</b> will swing, thereby driving the striking components <b>73</b> to strike fruits or branches, so that the fruits shake and fall off. For the structural design, to improve strength of the striking members <b>70</b> and facilitate removal and replacement of the striking components <b>73</b> on the striking members <b>70</b>, the swing arm components <b>74</b> include vertical platy structures <b>75</b> and ringlike structures <b>76</b> surrounding edges of the platy structures <b>75</b>. The swing arm components <b>74</b> form structures with &#x201c;I&#x201d;-shaped cross sections by using the platy structures <b>75</b> and the ringlike structures <b>76</b>. A plurality of threaded connection cylinders <b>77</b> for connecting the plurality of striking components <b>73</b> are formed on the swing arm components <b>74</b>. Openings of the threaded connection cylinders <b>77</b> are upward. The threaded connection cylinders <b>77</b> are longitudinally combined with the platy structures <b>75</b>. The threaded connection cylinders <b>77</b> are transversely combined with the ringlike structures <b>76</b>. The threaded connection cylinders <b>77</b> are in threaded connection with connectors <b>78</b>. The connectors <b>78</b> are combined to the striking components <b>73</b> by means of injection molding. The rotating shaft sleeve holes <b>71</b> and the power sleeve holes <b>72</b> are both formed in the swing arm components <b>74</b>. Since the swing arm components <b>74</b> are configured to be of the structures with the &#x201c;I&#x201d;-shaped cross sections, and the threaded connection cylinders <b>77</b> are formed on the structures, which fully uses a triangular supporting structure, so that this structural design is hard to bend or break, and materials for producing the swing arm components <b>74</b> can be saved. The striking components <b>73</b> and the swing arm components <b>74</b> are then connected by using the connectors <b>78</b>, so that the striking components <b>73</b> are in threaded connection with the swing arm components <b>74</b> through the connectors <b>78</b>, and it is convenient to remove and replace the striking components <b>73</b>. In addition, the two swing arm components <b>74</b> are located on a same plane. The two swing arm components <b>74</b> are designed to be on the same plane to maintain a force balance in the plane and a space when the two swing arm components <b>74</b> swing each other. A certain rotational force will be generated in the swing process if the two swing arm components <b>74</b> are not located on the same plane.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">For a structural design of the housing <b>81</b>, the housing <b>81</b> includes an upper shell <b>83</b> and a lower shell <b>84</b> that are in longitudinal symmetry. The upper shell <b>83</b> and the lower shell <b>84</b> fixedly cover each other through a bolt. Mounting openings <b>87</b> are formed in front ends of the upper shell <b>83</b> and the lower shell <b>84</b>. The mounting openings <b>87</b> are used for being connected to the two striking members <b>70</b>. Two ends of the mounting openings <b>87</b> are respectively provided with rotating shaft structures <b>90</b> connected to the upper shell <b>83</b> and the lower shell <b>84</b>. The rotating shaft structures <b>90</b> are rotatably connected with the rotating shaft sleeve holes <b>71</b>. Specifically, the rotating shaft structures <b>90</b> include bolt rod pieces <b>91</b>, fourth bearings <b>92</b> and fifth bearings <b>93</b>. The front ends of the upper shell <b>83</b> and the lower shell <b>84</b> are tightened by using the bolt rod pieces <b>91</b>. The fourth bearings <b>92</b> and the fifth bearings <b>93</b> sleeve the bolt rod pieces <b>91</b>. First conical sleeves <b>94</b> are also arranged on the bolt rod pieces <b>91</b> and located between the fourth bearings <b>92</b> and the fifth bearings <b>93</b>. Second conical sleeves <b>95</b> are respectively arranged at positions, located between the fourth bearings <b>92</b> and the upper shell <b>83</b>, on the bolt rod pieces <b>91</b> and positions, located between the fifth bearings <b>93</b> and the lower shell <b>84</b>, on the bolt rod pieces. The rotating shaft sleeve holes <b>71</b> are rotatably connected with the fourth bearings <b>92</b> and the fifth bearings <b>93</b>. Positioning rings <b>79</b> limited between the fourth bearings <b>92</b> and the fifth bearings <b>93</b> are arranged on inner sides of the rotating shaft sleeve holes <b>71</b>. By this design, the running fit between the housing <b>81</b> and the swing arm components is stable and reliable. In addition, shielding structures <b>88</b> located in middle portions of the mounting openings <b>87</b> are further respectively formed at the front ends of the upper shell <b>83</b> and the lower shell <b>84</b>. The two shielding structures <b>88</b> are fixedly abutted through bolts. Positions, hinged to the swing rods, of the power sleeve holes are shielded by the shielding structures <b>88</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">To improve fitting firmness between the rotating shaft component <b>20</b> and the housing <b>81</b>, fixing bolts <b>22</b> connected to the rotating shaft component <b>20</b> are respectively arranged on the upper shell <b>83</b> and the lower shell <b>84</b>. Two ends of the rotating shaft component <b>20</b> are respectively in threaded connection with the two fixing bolts <b>22</b>. For a connection manner of the housing <b>81</b> and the supporting rod <b>60</b>, arc surfaces <b>85</b> used for wrapping the supporting rod <b>60</b> are respectively arranged at rear portions of the upper shell <b>83</b> and the lower shell <b>84</b>. A clearance capable of being flexibly pressed is reserved between the arc surfaces <b>85</b> of the upper shell <b>83</b> and the lower shell <b>84</b>. Bolt holes <b>86</b> for pressing the clearance are respectively formed in the arc surfaces <b>85</b> of the upper shell <b>83</b> and the lower shell <b>84</b>. Therefore, the housing <b>81</b> and the supporting rod <b>60</b> can be detachably connected. For those skilled in the art, it is apparent that the present disclosure is not limited to the details of the demonstrative embodiments mentioned above, and that the present disclosure can be realized in other specific forms without departing from the spirit or basic features of the present disclosure. Therefore, from any point of view, the embodiments should be regarded as exemplary and non-limiting. The scope of the present disclosure is defined by the appended claims rather than the above description. Therefore, all changes falling within the meanings and scope of equivalent elements of the claims are intended to be included in the present disclosure.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A double-swing-rod mechanism, comprising a supporting main body used for rigidly supporting a fruit picking machine, a rotating shaft component connected to the supporting main body, two conical gears that axially rotate around the rotating shaft component, two swing rods movably connected to the two conical gears respectively to achieve a swing effect, and a drive gear movably connected to the supporting main body, wherein eccentric wheels that rotates around the rotating shaft component are arranged on the conical gears; the swing rods rotate around the eccentric wheels; the two conical gears are oppositely disposed; and the drive gear is engaged between the two conical gears.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The double-swing-rod mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the supporting main body comprises a backplane and supporting plates arranged in front of the backplane; a space for accommodating a gear is formed between the backplane and the two supporting plates; the rotating shaft component is fixedly connected between the two supporting plates; the conical gears are restrained between the two supporting plates through the rotating shaft component; and the drive gear is movably connected to the backplane.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The double-swing-rod mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein a barrier structure corresponding to the drive gear is arranged in a middle portion of the rotating shaft component; and the two conical gears are separated by the barrier structure.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The double-swing-rod mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the conical gears are bevel gears, and the conical gears are engaged with the drive gear by helical tooth structures.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The double-swing-rod mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the eccentric wheels are formed on the conical gears; rotating shaft holes penetrating through the eccentric wheels are formed in the axial lines of the conical gears; first bearings are arranged in the rotating shaft holes; and the conical gears and the eccentric wheels rotate around the rotating shaft component through the first bearings.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The double-swing-rod mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein connection sleeves surrounding the rotating shaft component are also arranged on the eccentric wheels; peripheries of the connection sleeves are sleeved with flat washers and second bearings; the flat washers are located between the first bearings and the second bearings; and the connection sleeves are movably connected with the supporting plates through the second bearings.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The double-swing-rod mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein third bearings are arranged at peripheries of the eccentric wheels; and one ends of the swing rods are provided with annular portions sleeving the third bearings.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. A fruit picking machine using a double-swing-rod mechanism, comprising the double-swing-rod mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a supporting rod, a power drive main body and two striking members, wherein the power drive main body comprises a housing and a drive motor; the double-swing-rod mechanism is arranged inside the housing; the drive motor is arranged at a back portion of a supporting main body; the drive motor is in power connection with the drive gear; rotating shaft sleeve holes and power sleeve holes are formed in the two striking members; the two striking members are both rotatably connected to a front end of the housing through the rotating shaft sleeve holes; the two striking members are both hinged and cooperate with the two swing rods through the power sleeve holes; and a rear portion of the housing is fixed on the supporting rod.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The fruit picking machine using the double-swing-rod mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the housing comprises an upper shell and a lower shell that are in longitudinal symmetry; the upper shell and the lower shell fixedly cover each other through a bolt; mounting openings are formed in front ends of the upper shell and the lower shell; two ends of the mounting openings are respectively provided with rotating shaft structures connected to the upper shell and the lower shell; and the rotating shaft structures are rotatably connected with the rotating shaft sleeve holes.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The fruit picking machine using the double-swing-rod mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the rotating shaft structures comprise bolt rod pieces, fourth bearings and fifth bearings; the front ends of the upper shell and the lower shell are tightened by using the bolt rod pieces; the fourth bearings and the fifth bearings sleeve the bolt rod pieces; first conical sleeves are also arranged on the bolt rod pieces and located between the fourth bearings and the fifth bearings; second conical sleeves are respectively arranged at positions, located between the fourth bearings and the upper shell, on the bolt rod pieces and positions, located between the fifth bearings and the lower shell, on the bolt rod pieces; the rotating shaft sleeve holes are rotatably connected with the fourth bearings and the fifth bearings; and positioning rings limited between the fourth bearings and the fifth bearings are arranged on inner sides of the rotating shaft sleeve holes.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The fruit picking machine using the double-swing-rod mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein shielding structures located in middle portions of the mounting openings are further respectively formed at the front ends of the upper shell and the lower shell; the two shielding structures are fixedly abutted through bolts; and positions, hinged to the swing rods, of the power sleeve holes are shielded by the shielding structures.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The fruit picking machine using the double-swing-rod mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein fixing bolts connected to the rotating shaft component are respectively arranged on the upper shell and the lower shell; and two ends of the rotating shaft component are respectively in threaded connection with the two fixing bolts.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. The fruit picking machine using the double-swing-rod mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein arc surfaces used for wrapping the supporting rod are respectively arranged at rear portions of the upper shell and the lower shell; a clearance capable of being flexibly pressed is reserved between the arc surfaces of the upper shell and the lower shell; and bolt holes for pressing the clearance are respectively formed in the arc surfaces of the upper shell and the lower shell.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The fruit picking machine using the double-swing-rod mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the striking members comprise a plurality of long and narrow rod-like or strip-shaped striking components; the striking members further comprise swing arm components for carrying the striking components and driving the striking components to complete striking actions; the rotating shaft sleeve holes and the power sleeve holes are both arranged on the swing arm components; and the two swing arm components are located on a same plane.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
