<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225437A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225437</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18096955</doc-number>
<date>20230113</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>31</main-group>
<subgroup>10</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>06</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20190201</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>31</main-group>
<subgroup>10</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>06</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Lower-Body Garment With Leak Protection Features</invention-title>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>63299644</doc-number>
<date>20220114</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="obligated-assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>NIKE, Inc.</orgname>
<address>
<city>Beaverton</city>
<state>OR</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Carlino</last-name>
<first-name>Shannan C.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Portland</city>
<state>OR</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="01" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Jackson</last-name>
<first-name>Cara</first-name>
<address>
<city>Portland</city>
<state>OR</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="02" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Koshkarooff</last-name>
<first-name>lustinia</first-name>
<address>
<city>Portland</city>
<state>OR</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="03" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Stauffer</last-name>
<first-name>Raegen A.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Portland</city>
<state>OR</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="04" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lo</last-name>
<first-name>Iris</first-name>
<address>
<city>New Talpel City</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A lower-body garment that has built-in leak protection. The built-in leak protection can be achieved through an integral gusset or an internal assembly that is positioned interior to an exterior layer that forms the lower-body garment. The internal assembly can include a front torso portion, a back torso portion, and a crotch portion. The crotch portion can include a spacer fabric layer configured to be positioned adjacent to a wearer's body surface, and a moisture-barrier layer secured to the spacer fabric layer and configured to be face outward.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="142.41mm" wi="89.07mm" file="US20230225437A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="254.00mm" wi="159.51mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225437A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="260.86mm" wi="159.51mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225437A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="260.94mm" wi="154.77mm" file="US20230225437A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="238.59mm" wi="147.66mm" file="US20230225437A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="257.22mm" wi="124.54mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225437A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="209.13mm" wi="126.66mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225437A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="98.13mm" wi="150.45mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225437A1-20230720-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="255.69mm" wi="153.33mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225437A1-20230720-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="184.23mm" wi="145.12mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225437A1-20230720-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="143.34mm" wi="143.09mm" file="US20230225437A1-20230720-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="260.43mm" wi="166.45mm" file="US20230225437A1-20230720-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00012" num="00012">
<img id="EMI-D00012" he="238.93mm" wi="169.76mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225437A1-20230720-D00012.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">Aspects herein are directed to a lower-body garment that includes leak protection features.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Women who exercise during their menstrual cycle may wear disposable menstrual pads to provide leak protection. Similarly, women that have incontinence issues may also feel the need to wear disposable pads for leak protection. In some instances, garments can have built-in leak protection</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The following clauses represent example aspects of concepts contemplated herein. Any one of the following clauses may be combined in a multiple dependent manner to depend from one or more other clauses. Further, any combination of dependent clauses (clauses that explicitly depend from a previous clause) may be combined while staying within the scope of aspects contemplated herein. The following clauses are examples and are not limiting.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Clause 1. A lower-body garment comprising: an external layer forming a torso portion, the torso portion having a waist opening, a first leg opening, and a second leg opening; and an internal assembly positioned internal to the external layer, the internal assembly comprising: a front torso portion, a back torso portion, at least one of the front torso portion or the back torso portion being coupled to the external layer, and a crotch panel between the first leg opening and the second leg opening, the crotch panel comprising a spacer fabric layer and a moisture-barrier layer secured to the spacer fabric layer.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Clause 2. The lower-body garment of clause 1, wherein the front torso portion of the internal assembly includes a front upper edge secured to the external layer, and wherein the back torso portion of the internal assembly includes a back upper edge secured to the external layer.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Clause 3. The lower-body garment of clause 1 or clause 2, wherein: the front torso portion has a first side edge that is located on a first side of the lower-body garment and that includes a lower end positioned a first distance below the waist opening, and the back torso portion has a first side edge that is located on the first side of the lower-body garment and that includes a lower end positioned a second distance below the waist opening, the second distance being greater than the first distance.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Clause 4. The lower-body garment of any of clauses 1 through 3, wherein the internal assembly further comprises a crotch area that continuously extends between the front torso portion and the back torso portion and that includes an inner-facing surface facing towards the crotch panel.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Clause 5. The lower-body garment of any of clauses 1 through 4, wherein: the front torso portion has a first side edge located on a first side of the lower-body garment, the back torso portion has a first side edge that is located on the first side of the lower-body garment, and the first side edge of the front torso panel is spaced apart from the first side edge of the back torso panel.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Clause 6. The lower-body garment of clause 5, wherein the crotch panel joins the front torso portion to the back torso portion.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Clause 7. The lower-body garment of any of clauses 1 through 6, wherein the front torso portion and the back torso portion comprise a durable water repellant (DWR) treatment.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Clause 8. The lower-body garment of any of clauses 1 through 8, wherein the internal assembly further comprises a crotch area that continuously extends between the front torso portion and the back torso portion and that wraps around side edges of the crotch panel.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Clause 9. The lower-body garment of any of clauses 1 through 8, wherein the spacer fabric layer comprises an innermost surface of the lower-body garment and comprises a first layer, a second layer, and a plurality of tie yarns that interconnect the first layer and the second layer, the plurality of tie yarns comprising elastic yarns.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Clause 10. The lower-body garment of any of clauses 1 through 9, wherein the moisture-barrier layer comprises a thermoplastic polymer material.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Clause 11. The lower-body garment of any of clauses 1 through 10, wherein: the front torso portion has a first side edge located on a first side of the lower-body garment, the back torso portion has a first side edge that is located on the first side of the lower-body garment, and the first side edge of the front torso portion is affixed to the first side edge of the back torso portion.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Clause 12. A garment comprising: a torso portion comprising a first leg opening and a second leg opening; and a crotch portion between the first leg opening and the second leg opening, wherein the crotch portion comprises a composite textile, which comprises a spacer fabric and a moisture-barrier layer; and wherein the moisture-barrier layer comprises a thermoplastic polymer film.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Clause 13. The garment of clause 12, wherein the crotch portion further comprises a textile layer treated with a durable water repellant (DWR) solution and at least a portion of the moisture-barrier layer is layered between the spacer knit textile and the textile layer.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Clause 14. The garment of clause 13, wherein the spacer knit textile comprises a side edge proximate the first leg opening; and wherein the textile layer wraps over the side edge to form a hem.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Clause 15. The garment of clause 13, wherein the spacer knit textile comprises a front edge coupled to a front of the torso portion; and wherein the garment further comprises a DWR-treated bonding strip that at least partially overlaps the front edge and the front of the torso portion.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Clause 16. The garment of clause 15, wherein the DWR-treated bonding strip comprises a textile layer and an adhesive layer, and wherein the textile layer comprises a DWR solution.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Clause 17. The garment of any of clauses 12 through 16, wherein the spacer fabric comprises a spacer knit textile comprising a first knit layer, a second knit layer, and tie yarns connecting the first knit layer to the second knit layer.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Clause 18. The garment of clause 17, wherein the tie yarns comprise a first yarn having a first denier and a second yarn having a second denier, which is different size from the first denier.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Clause 19. The garment of any of clauses 12 through 18, wherein: the garment comprises an internal assembly and an external layer; the torso portion and the crotch portion comprise at least a portion of the internal assembly; and the torso portion comprises a front upper edge and a back upper edge, at least one of the front upper edge and the back upper edge being affix to the external layer.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Clause 20. The garment of any of clauses 12 through 19, wherein garment comprises an undergarment configured to be selectively worn underneath a variety of external lower-body garments.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Clause 21. A method of manufacturing a lower-body garment, the method comprising: forming a torso portion from an external layer of material, the torso portion having a waist opening, a first leg opening, and a second leg opening; positioning an internal assembly interior to the external layer of material, the internal assembly comprising: a front torso panel, a back torso panel, and a crotch panel between the first leg opening and the second leg opening and joining the front torso panel to the back torso panel, the crotch panel comprising a spacer fabric layer forming, in part, an innermost-facing surface of the lower-body garment, and a moisture-barrier layer laminated to the spacer fabric layer; and securing the internal assembly to the external layer of material at a plurality of securement areas.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Clause 22. A method comprising: affixing, as part of an internal assembly for a lower-body garment, a crotch gusset to a front torso portion and to a back torso portion, the crotch gusset comprising a spacer fabric textile and a moisture-barrier layer; affixing the front torso portion to an exterior layer of the lower-body garment, the exterior layer comprising a torso portion having a waist opening, a first leg opening, and a second leg opening; and affixing the rear torso portion to the exterior layer of the lower-body garment</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Clause 23. The method of clause 22, wherein: the front torso portion is continuous with the back torso portion, based on a crotch area extending between the front torso portion and the back torso portion; and affixing the crotch gusset to the front torso portion and to the back torso portion comprises wrapping an edge of the crotch area around a side edge of the spacer fabric textile and affixing the edge of the crotch area to the spacer fabric textile.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Clause 24. The method of clause 22 or clause 23, wherein: the front torso portion comprises a side edge and affixing the front torso portion to the external layer comprises affixing the side edge of the front torso portion to a side of the torso portion; and the back torso portion comprises a side edge and affixing the back torso portion to the external layer comprises affixing the side edge of the back torso portion to the side of the torso portion and spaced apart from the side edge of the front torso portion.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Clause 25. The method of any of clauses 22 through 24 further comprising, laminating the spacer fabric textile and the moisture-barrier layer.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Clause 26. A lower-body garment comprising: a composite laminate associated with a crotch area of the lower-body garment; the composite laminate comprising: a spacer fabric layer, and a moisture-barrier layer secured to the spacer fabric layer.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Clause 27. The lower-body garment of clause 26 further comprising, a textile layer, wherein the moisture-barrier layer is layered between the textile layer and the spacer fabric layer.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Clause 28. The lower-body garment of clause 27, wherein the textile layer comprises a durable water repellant (DWR) treatment.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Clause 29. The lower-body garment of clause 27 or clause 28, wherein the spacer fabric layer, the moisture-barrier layer, and the textile layer comprise an integral crotch gusset associated with the lower-body garment.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Clause 30. The lower-body garment of any of clauses 26 through clause 29, wherein the lower-body garment comprises a first leg portion and a second leg portion.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Clause 31. The lower-body garment of any of clauses 27 through 30, wherein the spacer fabric layer, the moisture-barrier layer, and the textile layer comprise a crotch area of a built-in undergarment that is affixed in an interior of the lower-body garment.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Clause 32. The lower-body garment of any of clauses 27 through 31, wherein: the spacer fabric layer comprises a first edge: the moisture-barrier layer comprises a second edge; and the textile layer comprises a third edge that wraps around the first edge and the second edge.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Clause 33. The lower-body garment of any of clauses 27 through 32, wherein the textile layer is laminated together with the spacer fabric layer and the moisture-barrier layer.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Clause 34. The lower-body garment of any of clauses 26 through 33, wherein the composite laminate comprises a second spacer fabric layer that is layered between the spacer fabric layer and the moisture-barrier layer.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Clause 35. The lower-body garment of any of clauses 26 through 34, wherein the composite laminate comprises natural-fiber layer that is layered between the spacer fabric layer and the moisture-barrier layer.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Clause 36. The lower-body garment of any of clauses 26 through 35, wherein: the spacer fabric layer includes a first knit layer, a second knit layer, and tie yarns connecting the first knit layer to the second knit layer; and the tie yarns comprise a first yarn having a first denier and a second yarn having a second denier, which is different from the first denier.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Examples of aspects herein are described in detail below with reference to the attached drawing figures, wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> illustrates a front view of an exterior of a first example lower-body garment in accordance with aspects herein;</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> illustrates a back view of the exterior of the first example lower-body garment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> in accordance with aspects herein;</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> illustrates a side view of the exterior of the first example lower-body garment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> in accordance with aspects herein where an opposite side view would be the same;</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> illustrates a front view of an interior of the first example lower-body garment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> in accordance with aspects herein;</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> illustrates a back view of the interior of the first example lower-body garment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> in accordance with aspects herein;</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> illustrates a side view of the interior of the first example lower-body garment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> in accordance with aspects herein where an opposite side view would be the same;</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> illustrates a bottom-up view of a crotch panel from the interior of the first example lower-body garment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> in accordance with aspects herein;</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b>A</figref> illustrates a perspective view of a first surface of a leak protection composite structure for use in example lower-body garments described herein in accordance with aspects herein;</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b>B</figref> illustrates a perspective view of an opposite second surface of the leak protection composite structure of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b>A</figref> in accordance with aspects herein;</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref> illustrates a cross section of a portion of an example lower-body garment described herein taken at one or more of a front torso panel and a back torso panel of an internal assembly of the lower-body garment in accordance with aspects herein;</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref> illustrates a first example cross section taken at a crotch panel of an internal assembly of an example lower-body garment described herein in accordance with aspects herein;</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b></figref> illustrates a second example cross section taken at a crotch panel of an internal assembly of an example lower-body garment described herein in accordance with aspects herein;</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>12</b></figref> illustrates a front view of an exterior of a second example lower-body garment in accordance with aspects herein;</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>13</b></figref> illustrates a back view of the exterior of the second example lower-body garment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>12</b></figref> in accordance with aspects herein;</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>14</b></figref> illustrates a side view of the exterior of the second example lower-body garment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>12</b></figref> in accordance with aspects herein wherein an opposite side view would be the same;</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>15</b></figref> illustrates a front view of an interior of the second example lower-body garment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>12</b></figref> in accordance with aspects herein;</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>16</b></figref> illustrates a back view of the interior of the second example lower-body garment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>12</b></figref> in accordance with aspects herein;</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>17</b></figref> illustrates a side view of the interior of the second example lower-body garment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>12</b></figref> in accordance with aspects herein where an opposite side view would be the same;</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>18</b></figref> illustrates an example process for incorporating a crotch panel into an internal assembly in accordance with aspects herein;</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>19</b>-<b>20</b></figref> illustrate various examples of bonded seams for use in the lower-body garment described herein in accordance with aspects herein;</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>21</b></figref> illustrates a flow diagram of an example method of manufacturing a lower-body garment having leak protection features in accordance with aspects herein;</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>22</b>A</figref> illustrates a composite textile including two or more layers of spacer fabric according to an example;</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>22</b>B</figref> illustrates a composite textile including at least one additional textile layer between a spacer fabric and a moisture-barrier membrane according to an example;</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>22</b>C</figref> illustrates a composite textile including one or more additional textile layers affixed to a moisture-barrier membrane according to an example; and</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>23</b>A-<b>23</b>E</figref> depict another lower-body garment with a leak protection composite structure according to examples of this disclosure.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">The subject matter of the present invention is described with specificity herein to meet statutory requirements. However, the description itself is not intended to limit the scope of this disclosure. Rather, the inventors have contemplated that the claimed or disclosed subject matter might also be embodied in other ways, to include different steps or combinations of steps similar to the ones described in this document, in conjunction with other present or future technologies. Moreover, although the terms &#x201c;step&#x201d; and/or &#x201c;block&#x201d; might be used herein to connote different elements of methods employed, the terms should not be interpreted as implying any particular order among or between various steps herein disclosed unless and except when the order of individual steps is explicitly stated.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">Women who exercise during their menstrual cycle may wear disposable menstrual pads to provide leak protection. Similarly, women that have incontinence issues may also feel the need to wear disposable pads for leak protection. These pads are often secured to garments through use of a releasable adhesive and are disposed of after use. The extra pads not only create unsightly panty lines but may become displaced during activity which negates any protection the pad may provide. Some garments that have built-in leak protection are generally in the form of underwear that is worn as a separate article under athletic clothing, and these garments can be bulky, uncomfortable, and create unsightly (e.g., exaggerated) panty lines. In addition, they can require an extra apparel layer, which can create additional cost and affect overall breathability, moisture management, thermal management (e.g., associated with heating and/or cooling), and the like.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">At least some examples of the present disclosure are related to a leak-protection composite structure, textile, or laminate that can be incorporated into various types of garments. In some examples, the composite textile can include multiple layers of textiles that cooperate with one another to absorb moisture on the inside of a garment and reduce the likelihood of the moisture being viewable (e.g., showing through) on the outside of the garment. For example, the leak-protection composite textile can include a spacer fabric combined with a moisture-barrier layer, with the spacer fabric being configured to face towards the wearer (e.g., on the inner face of the garment). In examples, the leak-protection composite textile can be relatively thin, while still operating to absorb moisture. The leak-protection composite textile can be integrated into various garments and into various locations within a garment. For example, the leak-protection composite can be integrated into a crotch area of a lower-body garment (e.g., to help absorb and hide menstrual blood, urine, sweat, etc.).</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">At least some aspects herein are directed to a lower-body garment (e.g., a form-fitting athletic short or athletic capri or pant) that has built-in leak protection where the lower-body garment is configured for repeated use and can be washed without impacting the leak protection features of the garment. The built-in leak protection is achieved through use of an internal assembly that is positioned interior to an exterior layer that forms the lower-body garment. The internal assembly includes a front torso panel, a back torso panel, and a crotch panel that extends between the front torso panel and the back torso panel and is positioned between leg openings of the lower-body garment (i.e., in a crotch area of the lower-body garment). In example aspects, the crotch panel includes a spacer fabric (e.g., spacer knit textile, spacer mesh textile, or other type of spacer fabric) configured to be positioned adjacent to a wearer's body surface, and a moisture-barrier layer secured to the spacer fabric and configured to be face outward (i.e., away from the wearer's body surface). Bodily fluids generated by the wearer such as menstrual blood and/or urine may be stored in the space between the first and second layers of the spacer fabric. The moisture-barrier layer prevents any bodily fluids that escape the spacer fabric from leaking through to the exterior layer. The different portions of the internal assembly are patterned and secured to the external layer in such a way that panty lines are minimized, which is important considering that the lower-body garment is form fitting. The result is an athletic garment with a clean aesthetic and aerodynamic profile that can be repeatedly worn by women during menstruation or as needed.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">The term &#x201c;lower-body garment&#x201d; as used herein means a garment configured to be worn on the lower-torso of a wearer. The lower-body garment may be in the form of an underwear-type garment with no leg portions (e.g., a brief-style undergarment), a boxer brief, a boy-short style undergarment, a short, a capri, a legging, and the like. When describing the lower-body garment as &#x201c;form fitting,&#x201d; it is meant that the lower-body garment closely conforms to the underlying morphology of the wearer. This is usually achieved through use of elastic yarns that have stretch and recovery properties.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">Positional terms used when describing the lower-body garment are with respect to the lower-body garment being worn as intended by a wearer standing upright. In aspects herein, the lower-body garment is intended to be worn such that the spacer mesh layer in the crotch panel is in contact with a wearer's body surface such that the garment cannot be worn inside-out because the intended purpose of the garment would not be achieved (e.g., to provide leak protection). The term &#x201c;front torso&#x201d; as used herein refers to portions of the lower-body garment configured to be positioned adjacent to a lower front torso area of a wearer, and the term &#x201c;back torso&#x201d; as used herein refers to portions of the lower-body garment configured to be positioned adjacent to a back lower torso area of the wearer. The term &#x201c;side&#x201d; as used herein refers to portions of the lower-body garment configured to be positioned adjacent to a side torso area and/or side leg area of the wearer. The term &#x201c;crotch&#x201d; as used herein refers to portions of the lower-body garment configured to be positioned adjacent to a crotch area of the wearer as that term is generally recognized.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">The terms &#x201c;upper&#x201d; and &#x201c;lower&#x201d; as used herein are relative terms such that, for example, an &#x201c;upper edge&#x201d; is located closer to a waist opening of the lower-body garment compared to a &#x201c;lower edge,&#x201d; and a &#x201c;lower edge&#x201d; is located closer to a leg opening of the lower-body garment compared to an &#x201c;upper edge.&#x201d;</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">The terms &#x201c;external&#x201d; and &#x201c;internal&#x201d; as used herein are relative terms such that a layer that is external is positioned external to one or more internal layers, and a layer that is internal is positioned internal to one or more external layers. In example aspects, the external layer is exposed to an external environment, and the internal layer is not exposed to the external environment. The term &#x201c;innermost-facing surface&#x201d; when used with respect to the lower-body garment means a layer that is positioned closest to a body surface of a wearer compared to other layers of the lower-body garment. The term &#x201c;outermost-facing surface&#x201d; when used with respect to the lower-body garment means a layer that is positioned closest to the external environment with respect to other layers of the lower-body garment.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">The term &#x201c;spacer fabric&#x201d; as used herein is meant to encompass both warp knit and weft knit spacer knit textiles. Spacer fabrics can be generally formed by utilizing at least one tie yarn to interknit first and second layers of the textile. More specifically, each of the first layer and the second layer may be knit separately, and the tie yarn(s) is used to connect the first layer and the second layer. For instance, the tie yarns may have &#x201c;loop&#x201d; portions that extend into each of the first layer and the second layer where the loop portions are interlooped with yarns in the first layer and the second layer to connect the two layers. In example aspects, the tie yarns are oriented generally orthogonal to the surface planes of the first and second layers and act to space apart the first and second layers. The result is that a space is formed between the first and second layers that may be used to retain or store fluids such as menstrual fluids and/or urine. Because the first layer and the second layer are knit separately, each of the first layer, the second layer, and the tie yarns may be knit with different yarns and/or different yarn types. For example, the tie yarns can include different compositional materials and/or different sizes (e.g., different lengths between knit layers, different diameters, different deniers, etc.).</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">The term &#x201c;moisture-barrier layer&#x201d; as used herein generally refers to a layer that is impervious or substantially impervious to moisture penetration especially moisture in the form of a liquid. The layer may be in the form of a waterproof film such as, for example, a thermoplastic polymer (e.g., thermoplastic elastomer film) although other types of films are contemplated herein.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">In example aspects, the moisture-barrier layer may be secured to the spacer fabric layer through a lamination process (e.g., by a dot glue lamination process) such that the spacer fabric layer and the moisture-barrier layer form a composite, unitary structure. In at least some examples, a dot lamination process can improve the flexibility of the laminate structure, as compared an alternative lamination process in which the glue or adhesive is more widely distributed.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">In at least some examples, the moisture-barrier layer can allow at least some vapor to pass through, and also be substantially impervious to moisture penetration (e.g., liquid moisture penetration), such that it significantly impedes moisture from penetrating entirely through the moisture-barrier layer (e.g., entirely through the film from one side through the other side).</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">As used herein, the term &#x201c;about&#x201d; means within &#xb1;10% of a given value.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>-<b>3</b></figref> respectively illustrate a front view, a back view, and a side view of an exterior of a first example lower-body garment <b>100</b> where the exterior would be viewable by an observer viewing the lower-body garment <b>100</b> as worn by a wearer. The lower-body garment <b>100</b> is shown in the form of a short but aspects herein contemplate that the lower-body garment <b>100</b> may be in the form of an &#x201c;underwear-type&#x201d; garment (which may also be known as a boy short), a capri, a legging, a unitard, and the like.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">In example aspects, the exterior of the lower-body garment <b>100</b> is formed from an external layer <b>110</b> such that the external layer <b>110</b> forms a torso portion <b>111</b> including a front torso portion <b>112</b> (seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>) and a back torso portion <b>210</b> (seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>) that together define, at least in part, a waist opening <b>116</b>. In example aspects, the lower-body garment <b>100</b> may optionally include a waistband <b>114</b> that further defines the waist opening <b>116</b>. The external layer <b>110</b> also optionally forms a first leg portion <b>118</b> having a first leg opening <b>120</b> and a second leg portion <b>122</b> having a second leg opening <b>124</b>. In example aspects where the lower-body garment <b>100</b> does not include the first and second leg portions <b>118</b> and <b>122</b>, the first and second leg openings <b>120</b> and <b>124</b> would be located on the torso portion <b>111</b> (similar to an underwear-type garment).</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">In the side view of the lower-body garment <b>100</b> depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, the external layer <b>110</b> further includes a side panel <b>310</b> that extends generally vertically from a lower edge of the waistband <b>114</b> to the first leg opening <b>120</b>. The side panel <b>310</b> may be formed from the same material as the external layer <b>110</b>. An opposite side view of the lower-body garment <b>100</b> would also include a side panel that extends from the lower edge of the waistband <b>114</b> to the second leg opening <b>124</b>. As such, the description of the side panel <b>310</b> is also applicable to the side panel located on the opposite side. The side panel <b>310</b> may be a separate panel that is secured or joined to portions of the external layer <b>110</b> forming the front torso portion <b>112</b>, the first leg portion <b>118</b>, and the back torso portion <b>210</b> at a first seam <b>312</b> and a second seam <b>314</b>. The first and second seams <b>312</b> and <b>314</b> may be formed using affixing technologies such as stitching, bonding, adhesives, welding, and the like.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">In example aspects, the external layer <b>110</b> comprises, for example, a knit or woven textile having elastic yarns. As used herein, the term &#x201c;elastic yarn&#x201d; means a yarn having stretch and recovery properties such that the elastic yarn may be stretched up to about 100% to 200% of its resting length and substantially return to its resting length when the stretching force is removed. In examples including elastic yarns, the external layer <b>110</b> can closely conforms to the underlying morphology of a wearer as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>-<b>3</b></figref> (i.e., the external layer <b>110</b> is form fitting). In at least some examples, the external layer <b>110</b> can be more loose fitting (e.g., more loose fitting than a tight-style lower-body garment). In some examples, the external layer can include yarns with less elasticity (e.g., that stretch less than 100% of a resting length before returning to the resting length) or yarns that are considered non-elastic (e.g., as that term is understood in the industry). The lower-body garment <b>100</b> includes an example panel construction (e.g., example panel sizes, shapes, etc.) that forms the body of the lower-body garment <b>100</b>, and in other examples, a lower-body garment can include a different panel construction (e.g., panels with different size, shapes, positions, etc.).</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>-<b>6</b></figref> respectively illustrate, from a perspective inside the lower-body garment <b>100</b>, front, back, and side views of the lower-body garment <b>100</b> based on the respective reference positions identified in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> and <b>3</b></figref> (e.g., where the interior would not necessarily be viewable by an observer viewing the lower-body garment <b>100</b> as worn by a wearer). In example aspects, the lower-body garment <b>100</b> includes an internal assembly referenced generally by the numeral <b>405</b>. With respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>, the internal assembly <b>405</b> includes a front torso portion <b>410</b> (indicated with hatching) configured to cover a front lower torso of a wearer. In example aspects, and as shown, the front torso portion <b>410</b> does not include leg portions.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">In some examples, the front torso portion <b>410</b> can include a front part of a larger brief-type article that is coupled inside the lower-body garment <b>100</b>. In examples, the front torso portion <b>410</b> can continuously extend through a crotch area of the brief-type article and transition to a back torso portion (e.g., a back torso portion <b>510</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>), and an example similar to this is also depicted with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>18</b></figref>. In some examples, the front torso portion <b>410</b> can include a panel that attaches to a crotch panel <b>412</b> (e.g., the front torso portion <b>410</b> can terminate at the crotch panel <b>412</b> and does not extend through the crotch area).</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">The front torso portion <b>410</b> includes a front upper edge <b>414</b> and front lower edges <b>416</b>. In example aspects, the front upper edge <b>414</b> is permanently secured to the external layer <b>110</b> by way of, for example, stitching, bonding, and the like. Further, in example aspects, the front upper edge <b>414</b> is permanently secured adjacent to (e.g., from about 0.1 mm to about 8 cm) the waist opening <b>116</b>. When the lower-body garment <b>100</b> includes a waistband such as the waistband <b>114</b>, the front upper edge <b>414</b> is permanently secured to a lower edge of the waistband <b>114</b>. In example aspects, the front lower edges <b>416</b> are free, terminal edges that are not secured or affixed to the external layer <b>110</b>. In further example aspects, the front lower edges <b>416</b> may include raw, cut edges of the material used to form the front torso portion <b>410</b>. Stated differently, the front lower edges <b>416</b> may be unhemmed and may not include any trim pieces to provide a clean aesthetic and minimize the appearance of panty lines on the lower-body garment <b>100</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> further depicts a portion of the crotch panel <b>412</b>, which will be described in additional detail below.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">With respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, the internal assembly <b>405</b> further includes a back torso portion <b>510</b> (shown with hatching) configured to cover a back lower torso of a wearer. In some examples, the back torso portion <b>510</b> can include a back part of a larger brief-type article that is coupled inside the lower-body garment <b>100</b>. In examples, the back torso portion <b>510</b> can continuously extend through the crotch area of the brief-type article and transition to the front torso portion <b>410</b>, and an example similar to this is also depicted with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>18</b></figref>. In some examples, the back torso portion <b>510</b> can include a panel that attaches to the crotch panel <b>412</b> (e.g., the back torso portion <b>510</b> terminates at the crotch panel <b>412</b> and does not extend through the crotch area).</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">In example aspects, and as shown, the back torso portion <b>510</b> does not include leg portions. The back torso portion <b>510</b> includes a back upper edge <b>512</b> and back lower edges <b>514</b>. In example aspects, the back upper edge <b>512</b> is permanently secured to the external layer <b>110</b> by way of, for example, stitching, bonding, and the like. Further, in example aspects, the back upper edge <b>512</b> is permanently secured adjacent to (e.g., from about 0.1 mm to about 8 cm) the waist opening <b>116</b>. When the lower-body garment <b>100</b> includes a waistband such as the waistband <b>114</b>, the back upper edge <b>512</b> is permanently secured to a lower edge of the waistband <b>114</b>. In example aspects, the back lower edges <b>514</b> are free, terminal edges that are not secured or affixed to the external layer <b>110</b>. In further example aspects, the back lower edges <b>514</b> may include raw, cut edges of the material used to form the back torso portion <b>510</b>. Stated differently, the back lower edges <b>514</b> may be unhemmed and may not include any trim pieces to provide a clean aesthetic and minimize the appearance of panty lines on the lower-body garment <b>100</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> further depicts a portion of the crotch panel <b>412</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">In example aspects, the front torso portion <b>410</b> and the back torso portion <b>510</b> may both be formed of a lightweight knit material having elastic yarns. For example, the material forming the front torso portion <b>410</b> and the back torso portion <b>510</b> may have a weight from about 100 grams per square meter (gsm) to about 150 gsm, from about 120 gsm to about 140 gsm, or about 125 gsm. The lightweight features of the material may be achieved by using a single knit construction such as a single knit plain tricot. In example aspects, the material may include both polyester yarns and elastic yarns to achieve a desired degree of stretch and recovery while still providing a soft feel and good moisture management features. For example, the material may include about 60% polyester, including recycled polyester, and about 40% elastane.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">In at least some examples, the front torso portion <b>410</b> and the back torso portion <b>510</b> can include moisture-repellant properties. For example, the textile forming the front torso portion <b>410</b> and the back torso portion <b>510</b> can include a durable water repellant (DWR) treatment. In some examples, the DWR is applied to one or both surfaces of the textile (e.g., the inner facing surface and/or the outer facing surface).</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">In some examples, the textile forming the front torso portion <b>410</b> and the back torso portion <b>510</b> treated with DWR during padding and then heat set. In some instances, the textile can be dipped in a DWR solution, which can in turn be incorporated throughout the textile. In some examples, the DWR is integrated with yarn(s) constructing the front torso portion <b>410</b> and the back torso portion <b>510</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> depicts the side view of the lower-body garment <b>100</b> including the side panel <b>310</b> formed from the external layer <b>110</b>. As depicted, the front torso portion <b>410</b> includes a first side edge <b>610</b> that has an upper end <b>612</b> and a lower end <b>614</b>. In example aspects, the first side edge <b>610</b> is secured along its length <b>626</b> to the side panel <b>310</b> of the external layer <b>110</b> at the first seam <b>312</b>. In example aspects, the lower end <b>614</b> of the first side edge <b>610</b> is positioned a first distance <b>622</b> below the waist opening <b>116</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">The back torso portion <b>510</b> further includes a first side edge <b>616</b> that has an upper end <b>618</b> and a lower end <b>620</b>. In example aspects, the first side edge <b>616</b> is secured along its length <b>628</b> to the side panel <b>310</b> at the second seam <b>314</b>. Additionally, the lower end <b>620</b> of the first side edge <b>616</b> is positioned a second distance <b>624</b> below the waist opening <b>116</b>, where the second distance <b>624</b> is greater than the first distance <b>622</b>. To describe this differently, the length <b>626</b> of the first side edge <b>610</b> of the front torso portion <b>410</b> is less than the length <b>628</b> of the first side edge <b>616</b> of the back torso portion <b>510</b>. As depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>, the first side edge <b>610</b> of the front torso portion <b>410</b> is spaced apart from the first side edge <b>616</b> of the back torso portion <b>510</b> by the side panel <b>310</b> such that the first side edge <b>610</b> is unaffixed from or is not directly secured to the first side edge <b>616</b>. The same configuration is present on the second opposite side of the lower-body garment <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">The configuration shown, for example, in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> provides a number of different advantages. For example, in a traditional undergarment having a front torso panel and a back torso panel, the respective side edges include equal lengths such that they can be joined or affixed together at the sides of the undergarment without excess material. This can restrain how the front and back panels can be patterned. By decoupling the front torso portion <b>410</b> from the back torso portion <b>510</b> at the respective first side edges <b>610</b> and <b>616</b>, the panels <b>410</b> and <b>510</b> may be patterned in such a way to provide functional benefits to a wearer when the lower-body garment <b>100</b> is worn. For example, the front lower edges <b>416</b> may be positioned significantly higher than the back lower edges <b>514</b> to provide a generally unrestricted range of motion when the wearer raises their leg in a forward direction. Stated differently, the front lower edge <b>416</b> is generally positioned above a hip flexion area. This is achieved, at least in part, by positioning the lower end <b>614</b> of the first side edge <b>610</b> of the front torso portion <b>410</b> closer to the waist opening <b>116</b> than the lower end <b>620</b> of the first side edge <b>616</b> of the back torso portion <b>510</b>. This configuration also minimizes panty lines. The back lower edges <b>514</b> may be positioned significantly lower than the front lower edges <b>416</b> to provide to provide full coverage of the wearer's buttocks. Stated differently, the back lower edges <b>514</b> may be positioned below the gluteal fold. This is achieved, at least in part, by positioning the lower end <b>620</b> of the first side edge <b>616</b> of the back torso portion <b>510</b> farther away from the waist opening <b>116</b> compared to the lower end <b>614</b> of the first side edge <b>610</b> of the front torso portion <b>410</b>. This configuration also minimizes panty lines. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>-<b>6</b></figref> depict one example in which the respective side edges of the front and back portions are spaced apart and not directly connected (e.g., along a side seam) to one another. In at least some examples, the respective side edges of the front and back torso portions can be joined along the sides edges.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">As described, the internal assembly <b>405</b> further includes the crotch panel <b>412</b> which is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b> and <b>5</b></figref> and which is further depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref>. The crotch panel <b>412</b> is located between the first leg opening <b>120</b> and the second leg opening <b>124</b>. In some examples, the crotch panel <b>412</b> extends between the front torso portion <b>410</b> and the back torso portion <b>510</b> thereby joining the front torso portion <b>410</b> to the back torso portion <b>510</b>. In some examples the front torso portion <b>410</b> and the back torso portion <b>510</b> are connected by a crotch area portion (e.g., a continuous panel material), and the crotch panel <b>412</b> is coupled to the crotch portion.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">The crotch panel <b>412</b> is sized and positioned to cover a crotch area of a wearer and particularly a female wearer. With respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref>, the crotch panel <b>412</b> includes a front edge <b>710</b> joined near the front torso portion <b>410</b>, and a back edge <b>712</b> joined near the back torso portion <b>510</b>. In examples, the front edge <b>710</b> and the back edge <b>712</b> are not affixed to the external layer <b>110</b> to allow some relative movement of the crotch panel <b>412</b> with respect to the external layer <b>110</b>. The crotch panel <b>412</b> further includes a first side edge <b>714</b> and an opposite second side edge <b>716</b>. In example aspects, the first side edge <b>714</b> and the second side edge <b>716</b> are unaffixed from or not attached to the external layer <b>110</b> which also facilitates some relative movement of the crotch panel <b>412</b> with respect to the external layer <b>110</b>. The size and shape of the crotch panel <b>412</b> may be configured to minimize the surface area of the crotch panel <b>412</b> while still providing an adequate coverage surface area to capture, for example, menstrual blood flow and/or urine. In some examples, the crotch panel <b>412</b> can include a different size than that depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref>. For example, the back edge <b>712</b> can extend further up the back torso portion <b>510</b>. In some examples, the back edge <b>712</b> can extend to, and attach near, a yoke seam. In some examples, the back edge <b>712</b> can extend to, and attach near, a waistband.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">In at least some examples, the crotch panel <b>412</b> includes a spacer fabric layer <b>718</b> that forms, at least in part, an innermost-facing surface <b>720</b> of the lower-body garment <b>100</b> such that the spacer fabric layer <b>718</b> is in contact with a wearer's crotch area when the lower-body garment <b>100</b> is worn. In example aspects, a moisture-barrier layer (not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref>) is secured to an outer-facing surface of the spacer fabric layer <b>718</b> to form a leak protection composite structure as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>8</b>A and <b>8</b>B</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b>A</figref> depicts a perspective view of a first surface <b>810</b> of a leak protection composite structure <b>800</b> that may form, at least in part, the crotch panel <b>412</b>. The first surface <b>810</b> may correspond to the innermost-facing surface <b>720</b> of the crotch panel <b>412</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b>B</figref> depicts a perspective view of an opposite second surface <b>826</b> of the leak protection composite structure <b>800</b>. The second surface <b>826</b> may correspond, in some aspects, to an outer-facing surface of the crotch panel <b>412</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0098">The leak protection composite structure <b>800</b> includes the spacer fabric layer <b>718</b> of the crotch panel <b>412</b>. The first surface <b>810</b> of the leak protection composite structure <b>800</b> corresponds to the first surface of the spacer fabric layer <b>718</b>. A moisture-barrier layer <b>814</b> is secured to an opposite second surface <b>816</b> of the spacer fabric layer <b>718</b> and forms the second surface <b>826</b> of the leak protection composite structure <b>800</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0099">As depicted in the enlarged view, the spacer fabric layer <b>718</b> includes a first layer <b>818</b> that forms the first surface <b>810</b>, an opposite second layer <b>820</b> that forms the second surface <b>816</b> of the spacer fabric layer <b>718</b>, and a plurality of tie yarns <b>822</b> that interconnect the first layer <b>818</b> and the second layer <b>820</b>. The plurality of tie yarns <b>822</b> are oriented generally orthogonal to a surface plane of each of the first layer <b>818</b> and the second layer <b>820</b>. In example aspects, the spacer fabric layer <b>718</b> may have a weight from about 200 gsm to about 300 gsm, from about 220 gsm to about 280 gsm, or about 240 gsm. In example aspects, the first layer <b>818</b> and the second layer <b>820</b> may be formed from the same yarn types. For example, both the first layer <b>818</b> and the second layer <b>820</b> may include about 60% polyester, including recycled polyester, and about 40% elastane, from about 65% polyester and about 35% elastane, or about 66% polyester and about 34% elastane. In some examples, the polyester can be recycled polyester or virgin polyester or a combination thereof. The polyester yarns may, in example aspects, wick menstrual blood and/or urine to the space between the first and second layers <b>818</b> and <b>820</b> via capillary action between filaments forming the individual yarns and between the yarns themselves.</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0100">In some examples, the first layer <b>818</b> and the second layer <b>820</b> can include 30D/36F polyester (e.g., virgin or recycled) and <b>20</b>D elastane.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0101">The plurality of tie yarns <b>822</b> may include elastic yarns (e.g., elastane). For example, the tie yarns <b>822</b> may include elastic yarns having a denier of about 40.</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0102">In some examples, the first layer <b>818</b> and the second layer <b>820</b> can be formed of different yarn types. For example, the first layer <b>818</b> can comprise a yarn that is more hydrophilic. In some example, the tie yarns <b>822</b> can include varied properties, such as compositional material, denier, and the like. For example, the tie yarns within the same spacer fabric panel can include different compositional materials and/or different sizes (e.g., different lengths between knit layers, different diameters, different deniers, etc.).</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0103">In example aspects, the moisture-barrier layer <b>814</b> is secured to the spacer fabric layer <b>718</b> through a lamination process such that a cohesive, unitary structure is formed. In example aspects, the lamination process may include a dot lamination process. As stated, the moisture-barrier layer <b>814</b> may be formed of a material that is substantially or totally impervious to moisture or liquid include menstrual blood and/or urine. In one example, the moisture-barrier layer <b>814</b> may include a thermoplastic material (e.g., film), such as a thermoplastic elastomer (TPE) film, although other moisture impervious materials are contemplated as being within aspects herein. In some examples, the moisture-barrier layer <b>814</b> is relatively thin. For example, the moisture-barrier layer <b>814</b> can include a thickness in a range of about 10 micrometers to about 15 micrometers. In some examples, the moisture-barrier layer <b>814</b> is about 12 micrometers. The relatively thin construction of the moisture-barrier layer <b>814</b> can, in at least some instances, contribute to a thin overall construction, which can provide for a less bulky (but still absorbent) textile for imparting leak protection functionality to various garments.</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0104"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>9</b>-<b>11</b></figref> depict some example cross-sectional views of different portions of the lower-body garment <b>100</b>. For example, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref> represents an example cross-section taken at the front torso portion <b>410</b> and/or the back torso portion <b>510</b>. As depicted, the front torso portion <b>410</b> and/or the back torso portion <b>510</b> is positioned adjacent to a wearer's skin surface <b>910</b> and is further positioned internal to the external layer <b>110</b>. The front torso portion <b>410</b> and/or the back torso portion <b>510</b> is generally unaffixed from or not attached to the external layer <b>110</b> as shown except for the respective upper edges <b>414</b> and <b>512</b> and the respective side edges <b>610</b> and <b>616</b> of the front torso portion <b>410</b> and the back torso portion <b>510</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0105"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref> depicts a first example cross-section taken at the area of the lower-body garment <b>100</b> corresponding to the crotch panel <b>412</b>. As depicted, the spacer fabric layer <b>718</b> is positioned adjacent to a skin surface <b>1010</b> of a wearer, and the moisture-barrier layer <b>814</b> is shown secured to the spacer fabric layer <b>718</b>. In at least some examples, an additional layer <b>1012</b> may be positioned external to the moisture-barrier layer <b>814</b>, and the additional layer <b>1012</b> may comprise a continuous extension of the front torso portion <b>410</b> and the back torso portion <b>510</b>. The additional layer <b>1012</b> may be wrapped around the first and second side edges <b>714</b> and <b>716</b> of the crotch panel <b>412</b> to prevent the edges of the moisture-barrier layer <b>814</b> from contacting, for example, the wearer's legs thereby improving wearer comfort. The external layer <b>110</b> of the lower-body garment <b>100</b> is positioned external to the additional layer <b>1012</b>. As shown, the external layer <b>110</b> may not be directly secured to the additional layer <b>1012</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0107" num="0106"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b></figref> depicts a second example cross-section taken at the area of the lower-body garment <b>100</b> corresponding to the crotch panel <b>412</b>. As depicted, the spacer fabric layer <b>718</b> is positioned adjacent to a skin surface <b>1110</b> of a wearer, and the moisture-barrier layer <b>814</b> is shown secured to the spacer fabric layer <b>718</b>. The cross-section depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b></figref> does not include the additional layer <b>1012</b>. As such, the external layer <b>110</b> of the lower-body garment <b>100</b> is positioned external to the moisture-barrier layer <b>814</b>. As shown, the external layer <b>110</b> may not be directly secured to the moisture-barrier layer <b>814</b> such that a potential space is present between the external layer <b>110</b> and the moisture-barrier layer <b>814</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0108" num="0107"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>12</b>-<b>17</b></figref> depict a second example lower-body garment <b>1200</b> that has built-in leak protection features in accordance with aspects herein. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>12</b>-<b>14</b></figref> respectively illustrate a front view, a back view, and a side view of an exterior of the lower-body garment <b>1200</b>. The lower-body garment <b>1200</b> is shown in the form of a short but aspects herein contemplate that the lower-body garment <b>1200</b> may be in the form of an &#x201c;underwear-type&#x201d; garment (also known as a boy short), a capri, a legging, a unitard, and the like.</p>
<p id="p-0109" num="0108">In example aspects, the exterior of the lower-body garment <b>1200</b> is formed from an external layer <b>1210</b> such that the external layer <b>1210</b> forms a torso portion <b>1211</b> including a front torso portion <b>1212</b> (seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>12</b></figref>) and a back torso portion <b>1310</b> (seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>13</b></figref>) that together define, at least in part, a waist opening <b>1216</b>. In example aspects, the lower-body garment <b>1200</b> may optionally include a waistband <b>1214</b> that further defines the waist opening <b>1216</b>. The external layer <b>1210</b> also optionally forms a first leg portion <b>1218</b> having a first leg opening <b>1220</b> and a second leg portion <b>1222</b> having a second leg opening <b>1224</b>. In example aspects where the lower-body garment <b>1200</b> does not include the first and second leg portions <b>1218</b> and <b>1222</b>, the first and second leg openings <b>1220</b> and <b>1224</b> would be located on the torso portion <b>1211</b> (similar to an underwear-type garment).</p>
<p id="p-0110" num="0109">In the side view of the lower-body garment <b>1200</b> depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>14</b></figref>, the external layer <b>1210</b> further includes a side panel <b>1410</b> that extends generally vertically from a lower edge of the waistband <b>1214</b> to the first leg opening <b>1220</b>. An opposite side view of the lower-body garment <b>1200</b> would also include a side panel that extends from the lower edge of the waistband <b>1214</b> to the second leg opening <b>1224</b>. As such, the description of the side panel <b>1410</b> is also applicable to the side panel located on the opposite side. The side panel <b>1410</b> may be a separate panel that is secured or joined to portions of the external layer <b>1210</b> forming the front torso portion <b>1212</b>, the first leg portion <b>1218</b>, and the back torso portion <b>1310</b> at a first seam <b>1412</b> and a second seam <b>1414</b>. The first and second seams <b>1412</b> and <b>1414</b> may be formed using affixing technologies such as stitching, bonding, adhesives, welding, and the like.</p>
<p id="p-0111" num="0110">Similar to the external layer <b>110</b>, the external layer <b>1210</b> comprises, for example, a knit or woven textile having elastic yarns. Because the external layer <b>1210</b> is formed using, at least in part, elastic yarns, the external layer <b>1210</b> closely conforms to the underlying morphology of a wearer as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>12</b>-<b>14</b></figref> (i.e., the external layer <b>1210</b> is form fitting).</p>
<p id="p-0112" num="0111"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>15</b>-<b>17</b></figref> respectively illustrate front, back, and side views of the lower-body garment <b>1200</b> but from the perspective of the interior of the lower-body garment <b>1200</b> where the interior would not be viewable by an observer viewing the lower-body garment <b>1200</b> as worn by a wearer. In example aspects, the lower-body garment <b>1200</b> includes an internal assembly referenced generally by the numeral <b>1505</b>. With respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>15</b></figref>, the internal assembly <b>1505</b> includes a front torso panel <b>1510</b> (shown with hatching) configured to cover a front lower torso of a wearer. In example aspects, and as shown, the front torso panel <b>1510</b> does not include leg portions.</p>
<p id="p-0113" num="0112">The front torso panel <b>1510</b> includes a front upper edge <b>1514</b> and front lower edges <b>1516</b>. In example aspects, the front upper edge <b>1514</b> is permanently secured to the external layer <b>1210</b> by way of, for example, stitching, bonding, and the like. Further, in example aspects, the front upper edge <b>1514</b> is permanently secured adjacent to (e.g., from about 0.1 mm to about 4 cm) the waist opening <b>1216</b>. When the lower-body garment <b>1200</b> includes a waistband such as the waistband <b>1214</b>, the front upper edge <b>1514</b> is permanently secured to a lower edge of the waistband <b>1214</b>. In example aspects, the front lower edges <b>1516</b> are free, terminal edges that are not secured or affixed to the external layer <b>1210</b>. In further example aspects, the front lower edges <b>1516</b> may include raw, cut edges of the material used to form the front torso panel <b>1510</b>. Stated differently, the front lower edges <b>1516</b> may be unhemmed and may not include any trim pieces to provide a clean aesthetic and minimize the appearance of panty lines on the lower-body garment <b>1200</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>15</b></figref> further depicts a portion of the crotch panel <b>412</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0114" num="0113">With respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>16</b></figref>, the internal assembly <b>1505</b> further includes a back torso panel <b>1610</b> (shown with hatching) configured to cover a back lower torso of a wearer. In example aspects, and as shown, the back torso panel <b>1610</b> does not include leg portions. The back torso panel <b>1610</b> includes a back upper edge <b>1612</b> and back lower edges <b>1614</b>. In example aspects, the back upper edge <b>1612</b> is permanently secured to the external layer <b>1210</b> by way of, for example, stitching, bonding, and the like. Further, in example aspects, the back upper edge <b>1612</b> is positioned lower than the front upper edge <b>1514</b> of the front torso panel <b>1510</b> with respect to the waist opening <b>1216</b>. When the lower-body garment <b>1200</b> includes a waistband such as the waistband <b>1214</b>, the back upper edge <b>1612</b> is permanently secured below a lower edge of the waistband <b>1214</b> such as, for example, about 2 cm to about 15 cm below the lower edge of the waistband <b>1214</b>. In example aspects, the back lower edges <b>1614</b> are free, terminal edges that are not secured or affixed to the external layer <b>1210</b>. In further example aspects, the back lower edges <b>1614</b> may include raw, cut edges of the material used to form the back torso panel <b>1610</b>. Stated differently, the back lower edges <b>1614</b> may be unhemmed and may not include any trim pieces to provide a clean aesthetic and minimize the appearance of panty lines on the lower-body garment <b>1200</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>16</b></figref> further depicts a portion of the crotch panel <b>412</b>. In example aspects, the front torso panel <b>1510</b> and the back torso panel <b>1610</b> may both be formed of the same lightweight knit material having elastic yarns and polyester yarns that was described with respect to front torso portion <b>410</b> and back torso portion <b>510</b> of the lower-body garment <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0115" num="0114"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>17</b></figref> depicts the side view of the interior of the lower-body garment <b>1200</b> including the side panel <b>1410</b> formed from the external layer <b>1210</b>. As depicted, the front torso panel <b>1510</b> includes a first side edge <b>1710</b> that has an upper end <b>1712</b> and a lower end <b>1714</b>. In example aspects, the first side edge <b>1710</b> is secured along its length <b>1726</b> to the side panel <b>1410</b> of the external layer <b>1210</b> at the first seam <b>1412</b>. In example aspects, the upper end <b>1712</b> of the first side edge <b>1710</b> is positioned a distance <b>1722</b> below the waist opening <b>1216</b>. The back torso panel <b>1610</b> further includes a first side edge <b>1716</b> that has an upper end <b>1718</b> and a lower end <b>1720</b>. In example aspects, the first side edge <b>1716</b> is secured along its length <b>1728</b> to the side panel <b>1410</b> at the second seam <b>1414</b>. Additionally, the upper end <b>1718</b> of the first side edge <b>1716</b> is positioned a distance <b>1724</b> below the waist opening <b>1216</b>, where the distance <b>1724</b> is greater than the distance <b>1722</b>. As depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>17</b></figref>, the first side edge <b>1710</b> of the front torso panel <b>1510</b> is spaced apart from the first side edge <b>1716</b> of the back torso panel <b>1610</b> by the side panel <b>1410</b> such that the first side edge <b>1710</b> is unaffixed from or is not directly secured to the first side edge <b>1716</b>. The same configuration is present on the second opposite side of the lower-body garment <b>1200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0116" num="0115">Similar to the lower-body garment <b>100</b>, the configuration shown, for example, in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>17</b></figref> provides a number of different advantages. By decoupling the front torso panel <b>1510</b> from the back torso panel <b>1610</b> at the respective first side edges <b>1710</b> and <b>1716</b>, the front lower edges <b>1516</b> may be positioned significantly higher than the back lower edges <b>1614</b> to provide a generally unrestricted range of motion when the wearer raises their leg in a forward direction (e.g., the front lower edge <b>1516</b> is positioned above a hip flexion area). This is achieved, at least in part, by positioning the lower end <b>1714</b> of the first side edge <b>1710</b> of the front torso panel <b>1510</b> closer to the waist opening <b>1216</b> than the lower end <b>1720</b> of the first side edge <b>1716</b> of the back torso panel <b>1610</b>. This configuration also minimizes panty lines. The back lower edges <b>1614</b> may be positioned significantly lower than the front lower edges <b>1516</b> to provide to provide full coverage of the wearer's buttocks (e.g., the back lower edges <b>1614</b> may be positioned below the gluteal fold). This is achieved, at least in part, by positioning the lower end <b>1720</b> of the first side edge <b>1716</b> of the back torso panel <b>1610</b> farther away from the waist opening <b>1216</b> compared to the lower end <b>1714</b> of the first side edge <b>1710</b> of the front torso panel <b>1510</b>. This configuration also minimizes panty lines.</p>
<p id="p-0117" num="0116">Moreover, positioning the back upper edge <b>1612</b> of the back torso panel <b>1610</b> below or inferior to the front upper edge <b>1514</b> of the front torso panel <b>1510</b> may minimize material waste by ensuring that only the fuller, more rounded parts of the wearer's buttocks are covered by the back torso panel <b>1610</b>. To describe this differently, positioning the upper end <b>1718</b> of the first side edge <b>1716</b> of the back torso panel <b>1610</b> a greater distance (e.g., distance <b>1724</b>) below the waist opening <b>1216</b> compared to the upper end <b>1712</b> of the first side edge <b>1710</b> of the front torso panel <b>1510</b> (e.g., distance <b>1722</b>) minimizes material waste by ensuring that only the fuller, more rounded parts of the wearer's buttocks are covered by the back torso panel <b>1610</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>12</b>-<b>16</b></figref> depict an example in which the back upper edge <b>1612</b> is lower. In other examples, the back upper edge <b>1612</b> can extend all the way up to the waist opening and/or to the waistband <b>1214</b> (e.g., the back upper edge <b>1612</b> can attach closer to the waistband <b>1214</b> and above the yoke seam).</p>
<p id="p-0118" num="0117"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>18</b></figref> depicts an example way of incorporating the crotch panel <b>412</b> into various types of lower-body garments or internal assemblies, such as the lower-body garment <b>100</b>, the lower-body garment <b>1200</b>, the lower-body garment <b>2310</b>, or any other lower-body garment described in this disclosure, or the equivalent thereof. Reference numeral <b>1810</b><i>a </i>indicates a portion of an internal assembly that includes a front torso portion <b>1812</b> which may be the front torso portion <b>410</b> or <b>1510</b>, a back torso portion <b>1814</b> which may be the back torso portion <b>510</b> or <b>1610</b>, and a crotch area <b>1816</b> that continuously extends between the front torso portion <b>1812</b> and the back torso portion <b>1814</b>. In example aspects, the front torso portion <b>1812</b>, the back torso portion <b>1814</b>, and the crotch area <b>1816</b> may include a continuous panel of material without seams.</p>
<p id="p-0119" num="0118">At reference numeral <b>1810</b><i>b</i>, a leak protection composite structure <b>1818</b> which may be the leak protection composite structure <b>800</b> is positioned on an inner-facing surface of the crotch area <b>1816</b> (e.g., configured to face towards the wearer) and is secured thereto as described with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>19</b> and <b>20</b></figref>. In examples, the material forming the crotch area <b>1816</b> can protect a moisture-barrier layer (e.g., <b>814</b>) associated with the leak protection composite structure <b>1818</b>. For example, the material forming the crotch area <b>1816</b> (e.g., as well as the front torso portion <b>1812</b> and the back torso portion <b>1814</b>) can include a DWR treated textile, such as a DWR treated knit textile (e.g., similar to the knit textile forming the portions <b>410</b> and <b>510</b>). The leak protection composite structure <b>1818</b> includes a front edge <b>1820</b>, a back edge <b>1822</b>, a first side edge <b>1824</b>, and an opposite second side edge <b>1826</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0120" num="0119"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>19</b></figref> illustrates one example way of securing the front edge <b>1820</b> and/or the back edge <b>1822</b> of the leak protection composite structure <b>1818</b> to the front torso portion <b>1812</b> and/or the back torso portion <b>1814</b> respectively. In one example aspect, a bonding strip <b>1910</b>, such as a hotmelt tape or other type of adhesive tape, may be positioned to cover the front edge <b>1820</b> and/or the back edge <b>1822</b> of the leak protection composite structure <b>1818</b> and to also partially cover the front torso portion <b>1812</b> and/or the back torso portion <b>1814</b>. Application of heat and/or pressure to the bonding strip <b>1910</b> causes it to bond the front edge <b>1820</b> and/or the back edge <b>1822</b> to the respective front torso portion <b>1812</b> and/or the back torso portion <b>1814</b>. Using a bonding strip as opposed to, for example, stitching creates a low-profile bonded area to minimize panty lines and to reduce the chance of chafing due to threads used in stitching.</p>
<p id="p-0121" num="0120">In at least some examples, the bonding strip <b>1910</b> can include a multi-layer bonding strip, which includes an outer textile layer (e.g., knit, nonwoven, or woven) on an outer face <b>1912</b> and an inner adhesive layer on an inner face <b>1914</b> and between the outer textile layer and the leak protection composite structure <b>1818</b>. In some examples, the outer textile layer comprises a knit textile (e.g., similar to the knit textile forming the portions <b>410</b>, <b>510</b>, <b>1812</b>, and <b>1814</b>). In some examples, the outer textile layer an include a DWR treated textile layer. The multi-layer bonding strip can, in some instances, operate to help seal the edges (e.g., <b>1820</b>) of the leak protection composite structure <b>1818</b> to reduce the likelihood of moisture leaking. In addition, the outer textile layer can provide a softer finish (e.g., as compared to bare seam tape, stitching, or other seaming structures) the reduce the likelihood of discomfort to the wearer.</p>
<p id="p-0122" num="0121"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>20</b></figref> illustrates one example way of finishing the first and second side edges <b>1824</b> and <b>1826</b> of the leak protection composite structure <b>1818</b>. As shown, material from the crotch area <b>1816</b> may be wrapped around each of the first and second side edges <b>1824</b> and <b>1826</b> and secured thereto using an adhesive tape <b>2020</b> such as a hotmelt adhesive tape. In some examples, the edge of the material from the crotch area wrapping around the first and second side edges <b>1824</b> and <b>1826</b> can form a hem. Wrapping the first and second side edges <b>1824</b> and <b>1826</b> of the leak protection composite structure <b>1818</b> can prevent the moisture barrier layer from contacting a wearer's skin surface, which may improve wearer comfort. Other example ways of attaching the leak protection composite structure <b>1818</b> to the front and back torso panels <b>1812</b> and <b>1814</b>, including stitching, are contemplated as being within aspects herein.</p>
<p id="p-0123" num="0122">In some examples, the edge finishing associated with the first and second side edges <b>1824</b> and <b>1826</b> can reduce the likelihood of moisture leaking from the leak protection composite structure <b>1818</b>. For example, as depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>20</b></figref>, the wrapping side edge (e.g., hem) of the crotch area <b>1816</b> forms an envelope that binds the edge <b>1826</b> of the leak protection composite structure <b>1818</b>. In at least some examples, the textile forming the crotch area <b>1816</b> and the wrapping side edge includes a DWR treatment (e.g., such as the DWR treatment incorporated throughout the textile as described in other parts of this disclosure), which can significantly reduce the likelihood of leakage (e.g., as compared to a non-DWR treated textile).</p>
<p id="p-0124" num="0123"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>21</b></figref> illustrates a flow diagram of an example method <b>2100</b> of manufacturing a lower-body garment such as the lower-body garment <b>100</b> or <b>1200</b> described herein. At a step <b>2110</b>, a torso portion of the lower-body garment is formed from an external layer of material such as the external layer <b>110</b> or <b>1210</b> where the torso portion has at least a waist opening, a first leg opening, and a second leg opening. At a step <b>2112</b>, an internal assembly such as the internal assembly <b>405</b> or <b>1505</b> is positioned internal to the external layer of material. The internal assembly includes a front torso panel such as the front torso portion <b>410</b> or <b>1510</b>, a back torso panel such as the back torso portion <b>510</b> or <b>1610</b>, and a crotch panel such as the crotch panel <b>412</b>. The crotch panel is positioned between the first and second leg openings and joins the front torso panel to the back torso panel. The crotch panel includes a spacer fabric layer such as the spacer fabric layer <b>718</b> and a moisture barrier layer such as the moisture-barrier layer <b>814</b> where the spacer fabric layer forms, in part, an innermost-facing surface of the lower-body garment. At a step <b>2114</b>, the internal assembly is secured to the external layer of material at a plurality of securement areas such as, for example, at a waistband of the lower-body garment and at side panels of the lower-body garment (e.g., seams <b>312</b> and <b>314</b> of the lower-body garment <b>100</b>, and seams <b>1412</b> and <b>1414</b> of the lower-body garment <b>1200</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0125" num="0124">In examples of the present disclosure, a leak protection composite structure (e.g., textile, multi-layer textile, laminate, etc.) can include various features and properties and can be incorporated into a variety of different articles (e.g., articles of apparel). For example, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> is associated with an example leak protection composite structure <b>800</b>, which includes a spacer textile <b>718</b> and a moisture-barrier layer <b>814</b>. In at least some examples, a leak protection composite structure can include one or more additional layers, such as depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>22</b>A-<b>22</b>C</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0126" num="0125">In at least some examples, and referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>22</b>A</figref>, a leak protection composite structure <b>2200</b>A can include a plurality of layers of spacer textile, which can be coupled to a moisture-barrier layer <b>2202</b> (e.g., having any of the properties of a moisture-barrier textile described in this disclosure). For example, the leak protection composite structure <b>2200</b>A includes a first layer of spacer textile <b>2204</b> and a second layer of spacer textile <b>2206</b>, and each of the layers <b>2204</b> and <b>2206</b> can include a spacer textile having any of the properties associated with spacer textiles described in this disclosure (e.g., first textile layer and second textile layer connected by tie yarns). In at least some examples, the moisture-barrier layer <b>2202</b> and the spacer textiles <b>2204</b> and <b>2206</b> are bonded (e.g., laser bonded, adhesively bonded, or otherwise combined) together as a laminate. Among other things, the plurality of layers of spacer textile <b>2204</b> and <b>2206</b> can increase the moisture absorption and capture capabilities associated with the leak protection composite structure <b>2200</b>A (e.g., as compared to the composite <b>800</b>). In examples, the leak protection composite structure <b>2200</b>A can be incorporated into any of the garments or articles of apparel described in this disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0127" num="0126">In at least some examples, a leak protection composite structure <b>2200</b>B (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>22</b>B</figref>) can include one or more additional layers of textile positioned between a moisture-barrier layer <b>2208</b> (e.g., having any of the properties of a moisture-barrier textile described in this disclosure) and a spacer textile <b>2210</b> (e.g., having any of the properties of a spacer textile described in this disclosure). For example, the leak protection composite structure <b>2200</b>B can include one or more additional absorptive layers <b>2212</b> coupled between the moisture-barrier layer <b>2208</b> and the spacer textile <b>2210</b>. Examples of an additional absorptive layer <b>2212</b> can include a textile having yarns (e.g., fibers) with absorptive properties. In at least some examples, the additional absorptive layer <b>2212</b> can include a textile (e.g., knit, woven, nonwoven, etc.) with natural fibers (e.g., cotton). In at least some examples, the moisture-barrier layer <b>2208</b>, the spacer textile <b>2210</b>, and the additional absorptive layer <b>2212</b> are bonded (e.g., laser bonded, adhesively bonded, or otherwise combined) together as a laminate. Among other things, the combination of the spacer textile <b>2210</b> and the additional absorptive layer <b>2212</b> can increase the moisture absorption and capture capabilities associated with the leak protection composite structure <b>2200</b>B (e.g., as compared to the composite <b>800</b>). In examples, the leak protection composite structure <b>2200</b>B can be incorporated into any of the garments or articles of apparel described in this disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0128" num="0127">In at least some examples, a leak protection composite structure <b>2200</b>C (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>22</b>C</figref>) can include a moisture-barrier layer <b>2214</b> with a spacer textile <b>2216</b> bonded to one side (e.g., similar to the leak protection composite structure <b>800</b>) and with one or more additional layers of textile <b>2218</b> bonded to the opposing side. In at least some examples, the one or more additional layers of textile <b>2218</b> can include any of a variety of different textiles (e.g., knit, woven, nonwoven, etc.), including textiles that could form an outer face of an article of apparel.</p>
<p id="p-0129" num="0128">In at least some examples, the one or more additional layers of textile <b>2218</b> can include a lightweight knit material having elastic yarns, such as the material forming the front torso portion <b>410</b> and the back torso portion <b>510</b>. For example, the one or more additional layers of textile <b>2218</b> can have a weight from about 100 grams per square meter (gsm) to about 150 gsm, from about 120 gsm to about 140 gsm, or about 125 gsm. The lightweight features of the material may be achieved by using a single knit construction such as a single knit plain tricot. In example aspects, the material may include both polyester yarns and elastic yarns to achieve a desired degree of stretch and recovery while still providing a soft feel and good moisture management features. For example, the material may include about 60% polyester, including recycled polyester, and about 40% elastane. In at least some examples, the one or more additional layers of textile <b>2218</b> can include moisture-repellant properties, such as a durable water repellant (DWR) treatment. In at least some examples, the moisture-barrier layer <b>2208</b>, the spacer textile <b>2210</b>, and the additional textile layer(s) <b>2218</b> are bonded (e.g., laser bonded, adhesively bonded, or otherwise combined) together as a laminate.</p>
<p id="p-0130" num="0129">Among other things, the combination of the moisture-barrier layer <b>2214</b>, the spacer textile <b>2216</b>, and the additional layer(s) <b>2218</b> can provide a textile that can be used to construct both internal assemblies (e.g., built-in briefs or built-in gussets), as well as external panels of an apparel article (e.g., by forming the external-layer crotch gusset in a lower-body garment). The laminate can, in some instances, improve manufacturability, based on only having a single composite textile as opposed to multiple discrete textile layers. In addition, the laminate can, in some cases be less insulative (e.g., as compared to a construction of multiple discrete layers that might trap heat in between the layers). In examples, the leak protection composite structure <b>2200</b>C can be incorporated into any of the garments or articles of apparel described in this disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0131" num="0130">In examples, a leak protection composite structure (e.g., any of the leak protection composite structures <b>800</b>, <b>1818</b>, <b>2202</b>A, <b>2202</b>B, <b>2202</b>C, or any other leak protection composite structure described in this disclosure) can be incorporated into a variety of different articles of apparel, such as articles of apparel that might include regions in which it is desirable to mask moisture (e.g., blood, urine, sweat, milk, etc.). For example, a leak protection composite structure can be incorporated into various lower-body garments, such as in various regions of the lower-body torso, including the crotch. In some examples, a leak protection composite structure can be incorporated into various upper-body garments, such as in breast-support portions of bras (e.g., nursing bras, pumping bras, sports bras, tank-style support garments) or other breast-supporting garments.</p>
<p id="p-0132" num="0131">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>23</b>A-<b>23</b>E</figref>, an example lower-body garment <b>2310</b> can include a leak protection composite structure <b>2312</b> (e.g., any of the leak protection composite structures <b>800</b>, <b>1818</b>, <b>2202</b>A, <b>2202</b>B, <b>2202</b>C, or any other leak protection composite structure described in this disclosure). In examples, the leak protection composite structure <b>2312</b> is integrated directly into a gusset of the lower-body garment <b>2310</b>. In some examples, the lower-body garment <b>2310</b> includes underwear configured to be worn beneath another lower-body garment (e.g., shorts, tights, pants, skirt, etc.). That is, the lower-body garment <b>2310</b> can include an undergarment configured to be selectively worn underneath a variety of external lower-body garments. In general, the lower-body garment <b>2310</b> includes a torso portion (e.g., front torso portion, back torso portion, right side torso portion or right hip, and left side torso portion or left hip) with leg openings (e.g., right leg opening and left leg opening).</p>
<p id="p-0133" num="0132">The style depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>23</b>A-<b>23</b>E</figref> is an example, and in other instances the style of underwear can include boy-short, thong, etc. In some examples, the lower-body garment <b>2310</b> includes a portion of a swimsuit. In some examples, the lower-body garment <b>2310</b> is configured to be worn for athletic or fitness activities (e.g., track-and-field, distance running, triathlons, duathlons, volleyball, etc.). In some examples, the leak protection composite structure <b>2312</b> can comprise at least most of the underwear garment (e.g., areas in addition to just the crotch area, such as the torso front portion and/or the torso back portion). In some examples, the lower-body garment <b>2310</b> can be coupled (e.g., as an internal assembly) to the interior of a lower-body garment (e.g., shorts, tights, pants, skirt, etc.) to provide built-in underwear.</p>
<p id="p-0134" num="0133">In some examples, the leak protection composite structure <b>2312</b> is positioned in select areas (e.g., in the crotch area), similar to the construction associated with <b>1810</b><i>a </i>and <b>1810</b><i>b</i>. In addition, similar to the construction associated with <b>1810</b><i>a </i>and <b>1810</b><i>b</i>, the lower-body garment <b>2310</b> can include an outer layer that is similar to the layer <b>1816</b> and that is coupled to the leak protection composite structure <b>2312</b> similar to the constructions shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>19</b></figref> and/or <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>20</b></figref>. For example, the outer layer of the lower-body garment <b>2310</b> can include side edges that wrap around the sides of the leak protection composite structure (e.g., similar to the structure depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>20</b></figref>) and are secured to the leak protection composite structure (e.g., via bonding). In some examples, the front and/or back edges of the leak protection composite structure <b>2312</b> can be coupled to the outer layer via seam tape (e.g., similar to the tape <b>1910</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0135" num="0134">In examples, a panel comprising a leak protection composite structure for lower-body garments can include various shapes and sizes. The figures described above include various examples, which are non-limiting. For example, in some instances, a rear top edge of the leak protection composite structure can extend at least up to a yoke seam, and in some examples to a waistband. In some examples, a rear top edge that extends further up on the lower-body garment can provide more coverage, as compared to a structure with a rear top edge that terminates lower on the garment.</p>
<p id="p-0136" num="0135">Aspects of the present disclosure have been described with the intent to be illustrative rather than restrictive. Alternative aspects will become apparent to those skilled in the art that do not depart from its scope. A skilled artisan may develop alternative means of implementing the aforementioned improvements without departing from the scope of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0137" num="0136">It will be understood that certain features and subcombinations are of utility and may be employed without reference to other features and subcombinations and are contemplated within the scope of the claims. Not all steps listed in the various figures need be carried out in the specific order described.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A lower-body garment comprising:
<claim-text>an external layer forming a torso portion, the torso portion having a waist opening, a first leg opening, and a second leg opening; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an internal assembly positioned internal to the external layer, the internal assembly comprising:
<claim-text>a front torso portion,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a back torso portion, at least one of the front torso portion or the back torso portion being coupled to the external layer, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a crotch panel between the first leg opening and the second leg opening, the crotch panel comprising a spacer fabric layer and a moisture-barrier layer secured to the spacer fabric layer.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The lower-body garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the front torso portion of the internal assembly includes a front upper edge secured to the external layer, and wherein the back torso portion of the internal assembly includes a back upper edge secured to the external layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The lower-body garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the front torso portion has a first side edge that is located on a first side of the lower-body garment and that includes a lower end positioned a first distance below the waist opening, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the back torso portion has a first side edge that is located on the first side of the lower-body garment and that includes a lower end positioned a second distance below the waist opening, the second distance being greater than the first distance.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The lower-body garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the internal assembly further comprises a crotch area that continuously extends between the front torso portion and the back torso portion and that includes an inner-facing surface facing towards the crotch panel.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The lower-body garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the front torso portion has a first side edge located on a first side of the lower-body garment,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the back torso portion has a first side edge that is located on the first side of the lower-body garment, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first side edge of the front torso panel is spaced apart from the first side edge of the back torso panel.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The lower-body garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the crotch panel joins the front torso portion to the back torso portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The lower-body garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the front torso portion and the back torso portion comprise a durable water repellant (DWR) treatment.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The lower-body garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the internal assembly further comprises a crotch area that continuously extends between the front torso portion and the back torso portion and that wraps around side edges of the crotch panel.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The lower-body garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the spacer fabric layer comprises an innermost surface of the lower-body garment and comprises a first layer, a second layer, and a plurality of tie yarns that interconnect the first layer and the second layer, the plurality of tie yarns comprising elastic yarns.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The lower-body garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the moisture-barrier layer comprises a thermoplastic polymer material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The lower-body garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the front torso portion has a first side edge located on a first side of the lower-body garment,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the back torso portion has a first side edge that is located on the first side of the lower-body garment, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first side edge of the front torso portion is affixed to the first side edge of the back torso portion.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. A garment comprising:
<claim-text>a torso portion comprising a first leg opening and a second leg opening; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a crotch portion between the first leg opening and the second leg opening, wherein the crotch portion comprises a composite textile, which comprises a spacer fabric and a moisture-barrier layer; and wherein the moisture-barrier layer comprises a thermoplastic polymer film.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. The garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the crotch portion further comprises a textile layer treated with a durable water repellant (DWR) solution and at least a portion of the moisture-barrier layer is layered between the spacer knit textile and the textile layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the spacer knit textile comprises a side edge proximate the first leg opening; and wherein the textile layer wraps over the side edge to form a hem.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. The garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the spacer knit textile comprises a front edge coupled to a front of the torso portion; and wherein the garment further comprises a DWR-treated bonding strip that at least partially overlaps the front edge and the front of the torso portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. The garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the DWR-treated bonding strip comprises a textile layer and an adhesive layer, and wherein the textile layer comprises a DWR solution.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. The garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the spacer fabric comprises a spacer knit textile comprising a first knit layer, a second knit layer, and tie yarns connecting the first knit layer to the second knit layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. The garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein the tie yarns comprise a first yarn having a first denier and a second yarn having a second denier, which is different size from the first denier.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. The garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the garment comprises an internal assembly and an external layer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the torso portion and the crotch portion comprise at least a portion of the internal assembly; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the torso portion comprises a front upper edge and a back upper edge, at least one of the front upper edge and the back upper edge being affix to the external layer.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. The garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein garment comprises an undergarment configured to be selectively worn underneath a variety of external lower-body garments.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text><b>21</b>. A lower-body garment comprising:
<claim-text>a composite laminate associated with a crotch area of the lower-body garment;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the composite laminate comprising:
<claim-text>a spacer fabric layer, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a moisture-barrier layer secured to the spacer fabric layer.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text><b>22</b>. The lower-body garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00021">claim 21</claim-ref> further comprising, a textile layer, wherein the moisture-barrier layer is layered between the textile layer and the spacer fabric layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text><b>23</b>. The lower-body garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00022">claim 22</claim-ref>, wherein the textile layer comprises a durable water repellant (DWR) treatment.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024" num="00024">
<claim-text><b>24</b>. The lower-body garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00023">claim 23</claim-ref>, wherein the spacer fabric layer, the moisture-barrier layer, and the textile layer comprise an integral crotch gusset associated with the lower-body garment.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025" num="00025">
<claim-text><b>25</b>. The lower-body garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00024">claim 24</claim-ref>, wherein the lower-body garment comprises a first leg portion and a second leg portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026" num="00026">
<claim-text><b>26</b>. The lower-body garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00023">claim 23</claim-ref>, wherein the spacer fabric layer, the moisture-barrier layer, and the textile layer comprise a crotch area of a built-in undergarment that is affixed in an interior of the lower-body garment.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027" num="00027">
<claim-text><b>27</b>. The lower-body garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00023">claim 23</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the spacer fabric layer comprises a first edge:</claim-text>
<claim-text>the moisture-barrier layer comprises a second edge; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the textile layer comprises a third edge that wraps around the first edge and the second edge.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028" num="00028">
<claim-text><b>28</b>. The lower-body garment of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00023">claim 23</claim-ref>, wherein the textile layer is laminated together with the spacer fabric layer and the moisture-barrier layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
