<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225516A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225516</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17579663</doc-number>
<date>20220120</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>17</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>11</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>11</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Bench Assembly</invention-title>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Simonelli</last-name>
<first-name>Xavier A</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hopewell</city>
<state>NJ</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Simonelli</last-name>
<first-name>Xavier A</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hopewell</city>
<state>NJ</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A bench assembly includes a frame that extends between ground and an elevated portion spaced apart from the ground. A rail is fixedly secured to the elevated portion. The rail extends parallel to the ground between first and second rail ends. At least one pedestal is secured to the rail and slides between the first and second rail ends. At least one seat is mounted on top of the at least one pedestal allowing a user to slide between the first and second rail ends while seated on the at least one seat. This allows someone sitting on the bench to move along the bench without having to stand up first.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="44.70mm" wi="158.75mm" file="US20230225516A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="237.57mm" wi="86.19mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225516A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="160.02mm" wi="159.00mm" file="US20230225516A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="155.11mm" wi="158.83mm" file="US20230225516A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="221.15mm" wi="130.22mm" file="US20230225516A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND ART</heading>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">1. Field of the Invention</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The invention relates to a bench for humans to use for sitting. More particularly, the invention relates to a bench assembly capable of allowing users to move along the bench without standing up first.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">2. Description of the Related Art</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Traditional benches allow one or more persons to sit. There are times, however, when a person wants to sit on a bench but does not want to be near any other person that might also be using the bench. In these instances, a person must get up and move if the personal space or social distancing space has been breached. There is a need for a bench that facilitates the ability for a bench user to quickly distance himself or herself from other bench users without requiring the person to stand up to move.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">A bench assembly includes a frame that extends between ground and an elevated portion spaced apart from the ground. A rail is fixedly secured to the elevated portion. The rail extends parallel to the ground between first and second rail ends. At least one pedestal is secured to the rail and slides between the first and second rail ends. At least one seat is mounted on top of the at least one pedestal allowing a user to slide between the first and second rail ends while seated on the at least one seat.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Advantages of the invention will be readily appreciated as the same becomes better understood by reference to the following detailed description when considered in connection with the accompanying drawings, wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a cross-sectional side view of one embodiment of a bench assembly;</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is an end view of the embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is an end view of the embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> with a stop removed; and</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is an exploded perspective view of a portion of the internal elements of the bench assembly.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> through <b>3</b></figref>, one embodiment of a bench assembly is generally indicated at <b>10</b>. The bench assembly <b>10</b> is a bench that allows multiple people to sit at one time. The bench assembly defines a length A. Unlike a standard bench, which has an elongated horizontal sitting surface, the bench assembly <b>10</b> includes at least one seat <b>12</b> that is not elongated. It is designed to extend over only a portion of the bench assembly length A. In the embodiment shown in the Figures, there are three seats <b>12</b>, each designed of a size to have a single person <b>15</b> (one person <b>15</b> shown in phantom in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>) occupy the seat at a time. It should be appreciated by those skilled in the art that any sized seat to accommodate multiple persons may be incorporated into the design as long as the seat <b>12</b> is not as long as the length A of the bench assembly <b>10</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> shows a bench assembly <b>10</b> connected to a second bench assembly <b>10</b> in end-to-end fashion.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The bench assembly <b>10</b> includes a frame, generally shown at <b>14</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>. The frame <b>14</b> extending between ground <b>16</b> and an elevated portion <b>20</b> spaced apart from the ground <b>16</b>. In one embodiment (not shown), the frame <b>14</b> could be formed to be inserted into the ground <b>16</b> to make the location of the bench assembly <b>10</b> more permanent. In the embodiment shown in the Figures, the frame <b>14</b> includes a base <b>22</b> with base pads <b>24</b> that sits on the ground <b>16</b>. It should be appreciated by those skilled in the art that the base <b>22</b> may sit directly on the ground, avoiding the need for base pads <b>24</b>. As may be seen when looking at <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b> and <b>3</b></figref>, the base <b>22</b> is the widest portion of the frame <b>14</b>. This is properly engaging the ground <b>16</b> in a stable manner.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The frame <b>14</b> includes to first <b>26</b> and second <b>30</b> stops at either end of the bench assembly <b>10</b>. These stops <b>26</b>, <b>30</b> function as end plates for the bench assembly <b>10</b> to enhance the look thereof. Additional functionality of the stops <b>26</b>, <b>30</b> will be discussed in greater detail subsequently.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The bench assembly <b>10</b> includes a pedestal <b>32</b>. The pedestal <b>32</b> extends operatively between the frame <b>14</b> and the at least one seat <b>12</b>. The pedestal <b>32</b> may define a fixed height or it may be used to adjust the height of the at least one seat <b>12</b>, as is well known in the art.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">A rail <b>34</b> is fixedly secured to the elevated portion <b>20</b> of the frame <b>14</b>. In the embodiment shown, there are two rails <b>34</b> parallel to each other. The rails <b>34</b> also extend parallel to the ground <b>16</b> between the first <b>26</b> and second <b>30</b> rail ends. More specifically, the rails <b>34</b> may extend along the entire bench assembly <b>10</b>. One type of rail <b>34</b> that may be employed is a supported smooth rod (SBR) system having model number SBR16-2000 mm manufactured by Cinso. These are supported round rails. While the bench assembly <b>10</b> is shown to be linear, it should be appreciated by those skilled in the art that the bench assembly <b>10</b> may be extend through a curved plane; in which case, the rails <b>34</b> would also extend through curved planes.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The pedestal <b>32</b> includes at least one slide <b>36</b> that matingly engages the rail <b>34</b>. The slides <b>36</b> provide reduced friction when moving with respect to the rails <b>34</b> using lubricants, bearings, and the like. Because there are two rails <b>34</b> shown, there are also two rows of slides <b>36</b> shown. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>, there are four slides <b>36</b> shown&#x2014;two rows of two slides <b>36</b>, one row for each of the rails <b>34</b> shown. All four slides <b>36</b> are fixedly secured to a slide plate <b>40</b> of the pedestal <b>32</b>. Several threaded holes <b>42</b> are shown in the slides <b>36</b> to provide a standard means for securing the slides <b>36</b> to the slide plate <b>40</b>. One type of slide <b>36</b> that may be employed is the SBR Bearing Blocks, also manufactured by Cinso.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">A swivel plate <b>44</b> is fixedly secured to a top portion of the pedestal <b>32</b>. A swivel <b>46</b> is secured to the swivel plate <b>44</b> using bolts, rivets, adhesive, and the like. Threaded holes <b>50</b> illustrate that the swivel <b>46</b> may be secured to the swivel plate with bolts (not shown). Although not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>, the at least one seat <b>12</b> is mounted to the swivel <b>46</b> giving the at least one seat <b>12</b> its second degree of freedom to rotate when the user wants to rotate the at least one seat <b>12</b>. One type of swivel <b>44</b> that may be employed is the Fasmov 7&#x2033; Heavy Duty Bar Stool Swivel.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The bench assembly <b>10</b> also includes at least one side panel <b>52</b> extending between the base <b>22</b> and the pedestal <b>32</b>. In the embodiment shown in the Figures, there are two side panels <b>52</b>, one on either side of the bench assembly <b>10</b> and each side panel <b>52</b> is also a part of the frame <b>14</b>. It should be appreciated by those skilled in the art that in some designs, the at least one side panel <b>52</b> may be decorative only or not even included.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The at least one side panel <b>52</b> includes extensions <b>54</b> that extend up over the rail <b>34</b> and a portion of the pedestal <b>32</b>. This provides some protection for the rails <b>34</b> and slides <b>36</b> by shield that portion of the bench assembly <b>10</b> from debris.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In operation, a person will be able to sit on the at least one seat <b>12</b> in its current location on the bench assembly <b>10</b> and then slide it to a desired location along the bench assembly <b>10</b>. Conversely, the person may move the at least one seat <b>12</b> prior to sitting on it. This will allow a user to move the at least one seat <b>12</b> when another user decides to use another of the at least one seat <b>12</b> to space one user from another appropriately as determined by both users.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The invention has been described in an illustrative manner. It is to be understood that the terminology, which has been used, is intended to be in the nature of words of description rather than of limitation.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Many modifications and variations of the invention are possible in light of the above teachings. Therefore, within the scope of the appended claims, the invention may be practiced other than as specifically described.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>I claim:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A bench assembly comprising:
<claim-text>a frame extending between ground and an elevated portion spaced apart from the ground;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a rail fixedly secured to said elevated portion, and extending parallel to the ground between first and second rail ends;</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one pedestal secured to said rail and slidable between said first and second rail ends; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one seat mounted on top of said at least one pedestal allowing a user to slide between said first and second rail ends while seated on said at least one seat.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. A bench assembly as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein said frame includes a base engageable with the ground to stabilize said bench assembly.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. A bench assembly as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref> wherein said base is wider than said pedestal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. A bench assembly as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref> including at least one side panel extending between said base and said pedestal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. A bench assembly as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref> including a swivel extending between said seat and said pedestal allowing said seat to rotate with respect to said pedestal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. A bench assembly as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein said rail includes at least one slide slidable along said rail.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. A bench assembly as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref> wherein said at least one pedestal is fixedly secured to said at least one slide.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. A bench assembly as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref> wherein said at least one pedestal is fixedly secured to a plurality of slides.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. A bench assembly as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> including a first stop fixedly secured to said first rail end and a second stop fixedly secured to said second rail end preventing said at least one pedestal from moving past either of said first and second rail ends.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
