<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225536A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225536</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18079894</doc-number>
<date>20221213</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>202220124928.0</doc-number>
<date>20220118</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>29</main-group>
<subgroup>08</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>29</main-group>
<subgroup>08</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e61">FINGER RING HOLDER</invention-title>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Jicheng Technology (Shenzhen) Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Zhu</last-name>
<first-name>Hua</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A finger ring holder includes a protective case and a finger ring on an outer side of the protective case. The outer side of the protective case has a recess. The finger ring and an elastic movable base are installed in the recess. The finger ring has a first end and a second end opposite to the first end. The first end of the finger ring is connected to the elastic movable base through a rotating shaft. The elastic movable base is movably connected to the protective case. An elastic return member is disposed between the elastic movable base and the protective case. The elastic return member is configured to apply a return force to the elastic movable base. The second end of the finger ring is selectively locked to the protective case.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="193.97mm" wi="125.31mm" file="US20230225536A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="218.19mm" wi="127.34mm" file="US20230225536A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="215.31mm" wi="155.53mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225536A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="193.97mm" wi="150.62mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225536A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="183.64mm" wi="128.35mm" file="US20230225536A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="196.17mm" wi="123.19mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225536A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">1. Field of the Invention</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention relates to a holder, and more particularly to a finger ring holder.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">2. Description of the Prior Art</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">With the development of science and technology, there are various accessories on the market for electronic devices. Mobile phones are one of the most widely used electronic devices. People are increasingly demanding mobile phone protective case accessories. The mobile phone protective case not only needs to protect the mobile phone from breaking, but also needs to meet the support function of the mobile phone.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Most of the existing finger ring brackets are separated from the protective case. The finger ring bracket is attached to the outer side of the protective case by adhesive. When in use, the user needs to tum the finger ring bracket outward about the rotating shaft, so that the finger ring bracket and the outer side of the protective case form a certain angle, so as to realize the support function of the finger ring bracket for the electronic device. However, in the process of turning the finger ring bracket, the adhesive of the finger ring bracket is easily separated from the protective case due to the action of external force, which affects the normal use of the finger ring bracket.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">An improved finger ring bracket is developed accordingly. A rotating shaft is arranged on the outer side of the protective case. The finger ring bracket is connected to the rotating shaft to realize the connection between the finger ring bracket and the protective case. However, because the finger ring bracket has a certain thickness, it is not easy to place the electronic device on a horizontal workbench stably. In addition, since the finger ring bracket is protruded outside the protective case, it is easy to affect the wireless charging of the electronic device. In general, a raised portion is disposed on the back of the protective case. The raised portion has a groove matching the finger ring bracket for receiving and positioning the finger ring bracket. Alternatively, an annular groove is formed on the outer circumference of the raised portion for receiving and positioning the finger ring bracket. In actual use, after the finger ring bracket is unfolded and folded repeatedly, the finger ring bracket cannot be positioned in the recess stably and may be disengaged from the recess. Therefore, some finger ring brackets are designed into a non-closed ring structure having a notch. Both ends of the notch are formed with slightly larger interference portions. In this way, when the finger ring bracket is folded, the interference portions are in interference fit with the recess. Compared with the closed-ring finger ring bracket, it can form a more stable positioning relationship with the recess. However, after the finger ring bracket is unfolded and folded repeatedly, the finger ring bracket cannot be positioned in the recess stably and may be disengaged from the recess due to repeated wear and deformation.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Accordingly, the inventor of the present invention has devoted himself based on his many years of practical experiences to solve these problems.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In view of the deficiencies of the prior art, the primary object of the present invention is to provide a finger ring holder. The finger ring holder comprises a protective case. The protective case has a recess. A finger ring and an elastic movable base are installed in the recess. The finger ring is connected to the elastic movable base through a rotating shaft. The elastic movable base is movably connected to the protective case. In a folded state, the elastic movable base enables one end of the finger ring to be locked on the protective case. This solves the problem that the finger ring cannot be positioned in the recess firmly. When it is necessary to unfold the finger ring, the protective case or the elastic movable base is directly pushed. The finger ring holder has a simple structure and is easy to assemble and produce.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In order to achieve the above object, the present invention adopts the following solutions.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">A finger ring holder comprises a protective case and a finger ring on an outer side of the protective case. The outer side of the protective case has a recess. The finger ring and an elastic movable base are installed in the recess. The finger ring has a first end and a second end opposite to the first end. The first end of the finger ring is connected to the elastic movable base through a rotating shaft. The elastic movable base is movably connected to the protective case. An elastic return member is disposed between the elastic movable base and the protective case. The elastic return member is configured to apply a return force to the elastic movable base. The second end of the finger ring is selectively locked to the protective case.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Compared with the prior art, the present invention has obvious advantages and beneficial effects. Specifically, in the finger ring holder provided by the present invention, the protective case has the recess. The finger ring and the elastic movable base are installed in the recess. The finger ring is connected to the elastic movable base through the rotating shaft. The elastic movable base is movably connected to the protective case. In a folded state, the elastic movable base enables the second end of the finger ring to be locked on the protective case. This solves the problem that the finger ring cannot be positioned in the recess firmly. When it is necessary to unfold the finger ring, the protective case or the elastic movable base is directly pushed. The finger ring holder has a simple structure and is easy to assemble and produce.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a perspective view according to an embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is an exploded view according to the embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is another exploded view according to the embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is a perspective view of the elastic movable base according to the embodiment of the present invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is a cross-sectional view according to the embodiment of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Embodiments of the present invention will now be described, by way of example only, with reference to the accompanying drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> to <b>5</b></figref> show the specific structure of an embodiment of the present invention. A finger ring holder comprises a protective case <b>10</b> and a finger ring <b>30</b> on the outer side of the protective case <b>10</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a perspective view according to an embodiment of the present invention. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is an exploded view according to the embodiment of the present invention. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is another exploded view according to the embodiment of the present invention. The outer side of the protective case <b>10</b> has a recess. The finger ring <b>30</b> and an elastic movable base <b>20</b> are installed in the recess. The lower end of the finger ring <b>30</b> is connected to the elastic movable base <b>20</b> through a rotating shaft <b>40</b>. The elastic movable base <b>20</b> is movably connected to the protective case <b>10</b>. In this embodiment, the recess includes a first recess <b>11</b> and a second recess <b>12</b> adjacent to and communicating with the first recess <b>11</b>. The first recess <b>11</b> is located above the second recess <b>12</b>. The finger ring <b>30</b> is located in the first recess <b>11</b>. The elastic movable base <b>20</b> is located in the second recess <b>12</b>. The elastic movable base <b>20</b> is movable along the second recess <b>12</b>. The lower end of the finger ring <b>30</b> is connected to the elastic movable base <b>20</b> through the rotating shaft <b>40</b>. An elastic return member <b>50</b> is disposed between the second recess <b>12</b> and the elastic movable base <b>20</b>. The elastic return member <b>50</b> is configured to apply an upward return force to the elastic movable base <b>20</b>, so that the elastic movable base <b>20</b> can be moved up and down in the second recess <b>12</b>. The elastic return <b>50</b> enables the upper end of the finger ring <b>30</b> to be locked on the protective case <b>10</b>. When the elastic movable base <b>20</b> is moved up and down in the second recess <b>12</b>, the elastic movable base <b>20</b> drives the finger ring <b>30</b> to move up and down, so that the finger ring <b>30</b> can be folded in the recess.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The first recess <b>11</b> is formed on the outer side of the protective case <b>10</b>. In this embodiment, the first recess <b>11</b> has a circular shape. A locking hook <b>111</b> protrudes outward from the upper end of the first recess <b>11</b>, so that the finger ring <b>30</b> can be locked to the outer side of the protective case <b>10</b>. Preferably, the inner side of the locking hook <b>111</b> has a guide slope. A restricting block <b>113</b> is disposed on the lower end of the first recess <b>11</b>. A U-shaped hollow portion <b>112</b> is disposed on the lower end of the first recess <b>11</b>. The U-shaped hollow portion <b>112</b> includes a first hollow portion and two second hollow portions at the left and right sides of the first hollow portion. The first hollow portion is arranged horizontally. The second hollow portions are arranged longitudinally. The restricting block <b>113</b> is formed in the area surrounded by the U-shaped hollow portion <b>112</b> to restrict the upper end of the elastic movable base <b>20</b>, so as to prevent the elastic movable base <b>20</b> from disengaging from the protective case <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The second recess <b>12</b> is beside the first recess <b>11</b>. In this embodiment, the second recess <b>12</b> has a U shape. The second recess <b>12</b> has a restricting edge <b>121</b>. The restricting edge <b>121</b> has a U shape. The restricting edge <b>121</b> is configured to restrict the lower peripheral side of the elastic movable base <b>20</b> for restricting the elastic movable base <b>20</b> to be moved in the second recess <b>12</b>. A positioning block <b>122</b> is disposed in the second recess <b>12</b>. The positioning block <b>122</b> extends upward from the lower end of the second recess <b>12</b> for positioning and installing the elastic return member <b>50</b>. In addition, the restricting block <b>113</b> is located at the upper end of the second recess <b>12</b> for restricting the upper end of the elastic movable base <b>20</b>, so as to prevent the elastic movable base <b>20</b> from disengaging from the upper end of the second recess <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is a perspective view of the elastic movable base according to the embodiment of the present invention. The elastic movable base <b>20</b> is installed in the second recess <b>12</b>. The elastic movable base <b>20</b> is movably connected to the protective case <b>10</b>. The lower peripheral side of the elastic movable base <b>20</b> has a restricting groove <b>21</b>. The restricting groove <b>21</b> is a U-shaped groove. The restricting groove <b>21</b> is restricted by the restricting edge <b>121</b>. Through the cooperation between the restricting edge <b>121</b> and the restricting groove <b>21</b>, the elastic movable base <b>20</b> is guided and restricted to move in the second recess <b>12</b>. The lower end of the elastic movable base <b>20</b> is recessed to form an accommodating groove <b>22</b>. The accommodating groove <b>22</b> faces the positioning block <b>122</b>. In this embodiment, the accommodating groove <b>22</b> is located at the upper end of the positioning block <b>122</b>. The elastic return member <b>50</b> is disposed between the accommodating groove <b>22</b> and the positioning block <b>122</b>. Specifically, the upper end of the elastic return member <b>50</b> is inserted into the accommodating groove <b>22</b>, and the lower end of the elastic return member <b>50</b> is fitted on the positioning block <b>122</b>, such that the elastic movable base <b>20</b> is moved up and down between the lower end of the restricting block <b>113</b> and the lower end of the second recess <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The upper end of the elastic movable base <b>20</b> protrudes inwardly to form a stop block <b>23</b>. A guide surface <b>24</b> is connected between the lower end surface of the stopper block <b>23</b> and the inner surface of the elastic movable base <b>20</b>. The guide surface <b>24</b> is inclined to facilitate the installation of the elastic movable base <b>20</b> in the second recess <b>12</b>. In addition, the rear end of the stop block <b>23</b> extends into the first hollow portion of the U-shaped hollow portion <b>112</b> for positioning the upper end of the elastic movable base <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is a cross-sectional view of the finger ring holder. The upper end of the elastic movable base <b>20</b> is connected to the finger ring <b>30</b> through the rotating shaft <b>40</b>. A magnetic member <b>32</b> is disposed in the finger ring <b>30</b>. The magnetic member <b>32</b> is an iron sheet or a magnet. The magnetic member <b>32</b> is configured to be magnetically attracted with a vehicle charger or a wireless charger, so that the electronic device can be installed and positioned in a vehicle. In this embodiment, the inner side of the finger ring <b>30</b> has an annular groove <b>31</b>. The magnetic member <b>32</b> is installed in the annular groove <b>31</b>. In actual implementation, the magnetic member <b>32</b> may be attached to the annular groove <b>31</b> by using adhesive, so that the magnetic member <b>32</b> can be connected to the finger ring <b>30</b> firmly. In addition, a locking block <b>311</b> is disposed on the inner side of the finger ring <b>30</b>. Both the locking hook <b>111</b> and the locking block <b>311</b> are opposite to the rotating shaft <b>40</b>. In this embodiment, the rotating shaft <b>40</b> is located on the lower end of the finger ring <b>30</b>. The locking block <b>311</b> is located on the upper end of the inner side of the annular groove <b>31</b>. The locking block <b>311</b> is engaged with the lower end of the locking hook <b>111</b>. The finger ring <b>30</b> is rotatable about the rotating shaft <b>40</b>. When the finger ring <b>30</b> is located in the first recess <b>11</b>, the locking block <b>311</b> is engaged with the lower end of the locking hook <b>111</b>, so that the finger ring <b>30</b> is locked to the protective case <b>10</b>. The finger ring <b>30</b> can be folded easily.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Next, the operational of the present invention is described as follows:</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">When the elastic movable base <b>20</b> is moved downward, the restricting groove <b>21</b> of the lower peripheral side of the elastic movable base <b>20</b> is moved downward along the restricting edge <b>121</b> in the second recess <b>12</b>. The inner wall of the upper end of the accommodating groove <b>22</b> in the elastic movable base <b>20</b> is pressed against the elastic return member <b>50</b>. The upper and lower ends of the elastic return member <b>50</b> are confined by the accommodating groove <b>22</b> and the positioning block <b>122</b>, respectively. At this time, the locking block <b>311</b> of the finger ring <b>30</b> is disengaged from the lower end of the locking hook <b>111</b>, and the finger ring <b>30</b> is turned outward about the rotating shaft <b>40</b>, so as to realize the support function of the finger ring holder.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">When the finger ring <b>30</b> needs to be folded, the finger ring <b>30</b> is rotated inward about the rotating shaft <b>40</b> until the finger ring <b>30</b> is located in the first recess <b>11</b>. The finger ring <b>30</b> is released, and the elastic return member <b>50</b> is returned. Under the action of the elastic return member <b>50</b>, the elastic movable base <b>20</b> is moved upward along the restricting edge <b>121</b>. The elastic movable base <b>20</b> drives the finger ring <b>30</b> to move upward. The locking block <b>311</b> of the finger ring <b>30</b> is engaged with the lower end of the locking hook <b>111</b>, so as to lock the finger ring <b>30</b> on the protective case <b>10</b>. It should be noted that, if the locking block <b>311</b> and the locking hook <b>111</b> are not provided, the elastic return member <b>50</b> can exert a return force to the elastic movable base <b>20</b>, so that the other end of the finger ring <b>30</b> is tightly pressed in the recess. In this way, the positioning stability of the finger ring <b>30</b> to be folded relative to the protective case <b>10</b> can be improved, so as to prevent the finger ring <b>30</b> from being disengaged from the recess.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A finger ring holder, comprising a protective case and a finger ring on an outer side of the protective case, the outer side of the protective case having a recess, the finger ring and an elastic movable base being installed in the recess, the finger ring having a first end and a second end opposite to the first end, the first end of the finger ring being connected to the elastic movable base through a rotating shaft, the elastic movable base being movably connected to the protective case, an elastic return member being disposed between the elastic movable base and the protective case, the elastic return member being configured to apply a return force to the elastic movable base, the second end of the finger ring being selectively locked to the protective case.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The finger ring holder as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein a locking hook protrudes outward from an inner surface of the first recess, a locking block is disposed on an inner side of the second end of the finger ring, the locking hook and the locking block are opposite to the rotating shaft, and the locking block is selectively engaged with a lower end of the locking hook.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The finger ring holder as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the recess includes a first recess and a second recess adjacent to the first recess, the finger ring is located in the first recess, the elastic movable base is located in the second recess, one end of the second recess communicates with the first recess, a first end of the elastic return member acts on another end of the second recess, a second end of the elastic return member acts on the elastic movable base, and the elastic movable base is movable along the second recess.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The finger ring holder as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein a positioning block is disposed in the second recess, the elastic movable base has an accommodating groove, the accommodating groove faces the positioning block, the first end of the elastic return member is fitted on the positioning block, and the second end of the elastic return member is inserted into the accommodating groove.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The finger ring holder as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein a peripheral side of the elastic movable base has a restricting groove, a restricting edge is disposed on a peripheral side of the second recess, and the restricting edge extends into the restricting groove.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The finger ring holder as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein a peripheral side of the elastic movable base has a restricting groove, a restricting edge is disposed on a peripheral side of the second recess, and the restricting edge extends into the restricting groove.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The finger ring holder as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein a magnetic member is disposed in the finger ring, and the magnetic member is one of an iron sheet and a magnet.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
