<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225556A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225556</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17580373</doc-number>
<date>20220120</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>17</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>37</main-group>
<subgroup>06</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>37</main-group>
<subgroup>07</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>24</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>24</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>20</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>37</main-group>
<subgroup>0658</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>37</main-group>
<subgroup>0763</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>F</section>
<class>24</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>022</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>F</section>
<class>24</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>202</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">PORTABLE OVEN CONFIGURED FOR MULTIPLE DIFFERENT FUEL TYPES</invention-title>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="obligated-assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>InstaFire, LLC</orgname>
<address>
<city>Ogden</city>
<state>UT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Williams</last-name>
<first-name>Garold H.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Logan</city>
<state>UT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="01" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Banner</last-name>
<first-name>Konel S.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Ogden</city>
<state>UT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A heating device having a burn chamber that includes at least one opening, a conduction chamber adjacent to the burn chamber and including at least one aperture, a heat manifold including a first port and a second port, and at least one source vent extending between and coupling the first port of the heat manifold to the at least one opening of the burn chamber, and at least one exhaust vent, protruding from a surface of the heat manifold and extending between and coupling the second port of the heat manifold to the at least one aperture of the conduction chamber.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="175.18mm" wi="158.75mm" file="US20230225556A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="227.67mm" wi="190.75mm" file="US20230225556A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="206.93mm" wi="183.98mm" file="US20230225556A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="210.99mm" wi="171.79mm" file="US20230225556A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="216.41mm" wi="180.68mm" file="US20230225556A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="216.92mm" wi="168.32mm" file="US20230225556A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="221.83mm" wi="192.19mm" file="US20230225556A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present disclosure relates to heating devices, and more particularly relates to a portable oven configure for multiple different fuel types.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">There are two types of conventional portable ovens for outdoor use: a thermal container that is placed on a separate heating device with a fuel source, and a portable heating device housing a heating source and including one or more openings to exhaust smoke and debris. Thermal containers completely enclose the food item and include a swing door and metal rack for placing the food item between interior surfaces of the thermal container. Portable heating devices (e.g., BBQ grills, pizza ovens, etc.) have an interior surface for holding and/or using the heat source, the same interior surface or metal racks for holding the food item, and a lid, cover, or opening for exhausting smoke and debris. Although, conventional portable ovens may be transportable and can warm up food, establishing proper cooking times for various food items and weather conditions tends to be challenging and frustrating for users which limits users to cooking specific food items that can be properly cooked. For example, in thermal containers, the heating source and fuel source are detached from the oven which requires users to monitor the fuel source, the heating source, and the thermal container to ensure consistent cooking temperature in the thermal container. In portable heating devices, the fuel source and/or heating source is too close to the food item leaving users with a very narrow window of time for removing the food item before it gets burned or requiring users to constantly turn the food item to properly cook both sides of the food item. Thus, controlling heat flow, accounting for weather conditions (e.g., wind, rain, airflow, etc.) substantially arbitrary cooking times or establishing proper cooking times for various foods may be challenging using conventional portable ovens which often causes many users to experience loss of time and money from uncooked or overcooked food, and frustration from numerous attempts to establish proper cooking times for different food items and weather conditions.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a left perspective view of an exemplary portable oven in accordance with an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>A</figref> is top perspective view of heat flow through an exemplary heat chamber interior of an exemplary portable oven in accordance with an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>B</figref> is top perspective view of an exemplary heat chamber interior and heat chamber cover of an exemplary portable oven in accordance with an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a right perspective view of an exemplary conduction chamber interior of an exemplary portable oven in accordance with an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is a flow chart illustrating an exemplary method of making the portable oven in accordance with an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is a left perspective view of an assembled exemplary portable oven in accordance with an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">While the disclosure is susceptible to various modifications and alternative forms, specific embodiments have been shown by way of example in the drawings and will be described in detail herein. However, it should be understood that the disclosure is not intended to be limited to the particular forms disclosed. Rather, the intention is to cover all modifications, equivalents and alternatives falling within the scope of the disclosure as defined by the appended claims.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Specific details of several embodiments of portable ovens, and associated systems and methods, are described below. A person skilled in the relevant art will recognize that suitable stages of the methods described herein for making a heating device or portable oven can be performed using various equipment, materials, and design parameters as desired, as well as such constructing components in a manner to be easily assembled or disassembled by a user. Furthermore, unless the context indicates otherwise, structures disclosed herein can be formed using conventional equipment and/or fabrication techniques for building ovens, portable ovens, or heating devices. Ovens, portable ovens, heating devices, and materials and components thereof may be built, for example, using industrial and commercial as well as private or proprietary equipment.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In this disclosure, numerous specific details are discussed to provide a thorough and enabling description for embodiments of the present disclosure. One of ordinary skill in the art will recognize that the disclosure can be practiced without one or more of the specific details. Well-known structures and/or operations often associated with portable ovens may not be shown and/or may not be described in detail to avoid obscuring other aspects of the disclosure. In general, it should be understood that various other devices, systems, and/or methods in addition to those specific embodiments disclosed herein may be within the scope of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The term &#x201c;heating device&#x201d; can refer to an assembly of one or more components, chambers, containers, plates, sliders, trays, racks, tubes, pipes, vents, exhausts, and/or manifolds, which may include interposers, supports, fixtures, and/or other suitable materials. The heating device may be manufactured as, but not limited to, as a unitary portable device, a collapsible, foldable, or otherwise dismountable device, and/or modular or compartmentalizable device. A heating device can include, for example, a fuel source, a heating mechanism, one or more spaces, compartments, or chambers, and one or more openings, vents, fans, heatsinks or exhausts. A heating device may further include non-planar surfaces, regular and irregular (e.g., non-polygonal) apertures, and removeable or moveable partitions within the one or more spaces, compartments, or chambers. A heating device may refer herein to an oven or portable oven, but heating devices are not limited to ovens or portable ovens.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The term &#x201c;portable oven&#x201d; can refer to an arrangement with one or more heating devices, systems, or mechanism incorporated into an enclosure or housing. The portable oven can include a housing or casing that partially or completely encapsulates at least one heating device, system, or mechanism.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">As set forth above, conventional ovens cannot control heat flow and are susceptible to weather conditions which causes arbitrary cooking times, restricts users to cooking specific food items (e.g., thick or meaty foods), and requires users to monitor the fuel source, the heating source, and the food item to ensure consistent cooking temperatures. Embodiments of the present disclosure solve this challenge, and others, by providing a portable oven with separate chambers that direct air and heat flow onto various interior spaces and surfaces of the oven. The separate chambers allow the burning fuel source and air flow to constructively flow into and radiate the cooking space of the portable oven. In this manner, the portable oven of the present disclosure allows users to consistently cook various food items while inhibiting weather conditions from altering cooking times and cooking temperature.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a left perspective view of an exemplary portable oven in accordance with an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure. As can be seen with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, an exemplary portable oven <b>100</b> may include one or more conduction chambers <b>102</b>, burn chambers <b>103</b>, heat chambers <b>105</b>, source vents <b>107</b>, exhaust vents <b>109</b>, and slidable and/or removable ash trays <b>111</b><i>a </i>and <b>111</b><i>b. </i>The portable oven <b>100</b> includes heating space <b>110</b> on and/or between the interior surfaces of the conduction chamber <b>102</b>, burn chamber <b>103</b>, and heat chamber <b>105</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The exemplary conduction chamber <b>102</b> may have a regular polygon shape, for example, a rectangular, oval, or square box or cylinder. The surfaces, sides, corners, or edges of the conduction chamber <b>102</b> may be curved or non-linear to optimize heat and air flow within the conduction chamber <b>102</b>. The conduction chamber <b>102</b> may be fixed to the portable oven <b>100</b>. In some embodiments, the conduction chamber <b>102</b> may be removably coupled to the portable oven <b>100</b>. The conduction chamber <b>102</b> may be adjacent to, or abut, one or more sides or surfaces of other chambers (e.g., heat chamber <b>105</b> or burn chamber <b>103</b>), source vents <b>107</b>, exhaust vents <b>109</b>, or a combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The conduction chamber <b>102</b> may include a plurality of apertures <b>102</b><i>a, </i><b>102</b><i>b, </i><b>102</b><i>c </i>and <b>102</b><i>d </i>(hereinafter &#x201c;apertures <b>102</b><i>n</i>&#x201d;) to, for example, receive fuel or a fuel source, couple to fittings or components (e.g., exhaust vent <b>109</b>), or direct heat, smoke, debris, or air (e.g., wind from the outside environment), or any combination thereof. In some embodiments, apertures <b>102</b><i>n </i>may be permanently open, for example, to receive a fuel source, exhaust smoke, or provide access to debris. In some embodiments, the conduction chamber <b>102</b> may include a slidable cover, swing door, or retractable cover to allow the apertures <b>102</b><i>n </i>to partially open or fully close to further direct heat, exhaust smoke and debris, or reduce weather conditions from altering heat flow, air flow, or cooking temperature.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Food items may be placed on an upper surface <b>102</b>-<b>1</b> of the conduction chamber <b>102</b>. In some embodiments, the upper surface <b>102</b>-<b>1</b> may include a plurality of protrusions <b>104</b> to direct radiated heat or separate food items. In some embodiments, the upper surface <b>102</b>-<b>1</b> may include one or more apertures <b>102</b><i>n </i>to drain excess fluid, oil, or other cooking byproducts. Further, in some embodiments one or more apertures <b>102</b><i>n </i>may be adjacent to the one or more protrusions <b>104</b>. Further, in some embodiments, one or more interior spaces of the conduction chamber <b>102</b> may include interior protrusions <b>342</b> (as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>) along the lower surface <b>102</b>-<b>2</b> of the conduction chamber <b>102</b> that partition the interior spaces to, for example, direct heat and air flow and radiate heat to the upper surface <b>102</b>-<b>1</b> and/or drain excess fluid or oil from the upper surface <b>102</b>-<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In some embodiments, the conduction chamber <b>102</b> may be fixed or positioned directly above ash tray <b>111</b><i>a </i>such that the lower surface <b>102</b>-<b>2</b> of the conduction chamber <b>102</b> and the upper surface <b>111</b><i>a</i>-<b>1</b> of the ash tray <b>111</b><i>a </i>are shared, that is, the conduction chamber <b>102</b> and the ash tray <b>111</b><i>a </i>are attached together by the same barrier or surface. Further, in this embodiment, the conduction chamber <b>102</b> may include one or more apertures <b>102</b><i>c </i>that extend through and partially across the interior surface of the lower surface <b>102</b>-<b>2</b> of the conduction chamber <b>102</b>, such that, for example, a fuel source, heat, or drained fluid moves from between the interior surface of the lower surface <b>102</b>-<b>2</b> of the conduction chamber <b>102</b> and the interior surface of the lower surface <b>111</b><i>a</i>-<b>2</b> of the ash tray <b>111</b><i>a. </i>In some embodiments, one or more apertures <b>102</b><i>n </i>may be recesses that extend laterally across the upper surface <b>102</b> to, for example, collect excess fluid or oil from the upper surface <b>102</b>-<b>1</b>. In some embodiments, the one or more apertures <b>102</b><i>n </i>may be configured to direct or collimate radiated heat from the interior space of the conduction chamber <b>102</b> into a space. In some embodiments, the aperture <b>102</b><i>c </i>may extend through and completely or substantially across the interior surface of the lower surface <b>102</b>-<b>2</b> of the conduction chamber <b>102</b>, such that the conduction chamber <b>102</b> excludes a lower surface <b>102</b>-<b>2</b> and the interior space of the conduction chamber <b>102</b> is bounded by the upper surface <b>102</b>-<b>1</b> of the conduction chamber <b>102</b> and the interior lower surface <b>111</b><i>a</i>-<b>2</b> of the ash tray <b>111</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Moreover, in some embodiments the conduction chamber <b>102</b> may provide users with an auxiliary burn chamber for adding additional fuel and heat to the portable oven <b>100</b>, as well as providing a compartment to burn wood chips, wood pellets, charcoal, wood chunks or the like to infuse flavor and enhance the taste of the food item.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The exemplary burn chamber <b>103</b> may have a regular polygon shape, for example, a rectangular, oval, or square box or cylinder. The surfaces, sides, corners, or edges of the burn chamber <b>103</b> may be curved or non-linear to optimize heat and air flow within the burn chamber <b>103</b>. The burn chamber <b>103</b> may be fixed to the portable oven <b>100</b>. In some embodiments, the burn chamber <b>103</b> may be removably coupled to the portable oven <b>100</b>. The burn chamber <b>103</b> may be adjacent to, or abut, one or more sides or surfaces of other chambers (e.g., conduction chamber <b>102</b> or heat chamber <b>105</b>), source vents <b>107</b>, exhaust vents <b>109</b>, or a combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The burn chamber <b>103</b> may include a plurality of openings <b>103</b><i>a, </i><b>103</b><i>b, </i>and <b>103</b><i>c </i>(hereinafter &#x201c;openings <b>103</b><i>n</i>&#x201d;) to, for example, receive fuel or a fuel source, couple to fittings or components (e.g., source vent <b>107</b>), or direct heat, smoke, debris, or air (e.g., wind from the outside environment), or any combination thereof. In some embodiments, openings <b>103</b><i>n </i>may be permanently open, for example, to receive a fuel source, exhaust smoke, or provide access to debris. In some embodiments, the burn chamber <b>103</b> may include a slidable cover, swing door, or retractable cover to allow the openings <b>103</b><i>n </i>to partially open or fully close to further direct heat, exhaust smoke and debris, or reduce weather conditions from altering heat flow, air flow, or cooking temperature.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In some embodiments, the interior lower surface <b>103</b>-<b>2</b> of the burn chamber <b>103</b> may include one or more recesses <b>106</b> that partitioning the interior spaces of the burn chamber <b>103</b> to, for example, protect the fuel source or heat from environmental conditions, protect users from embers, smoke or debris, to prevent fuel source from sliding, shifting or falling out of the burn chamber <b>103</b>, or prevent fuel source from and/or direct heat and air flow through the source vent <b>107</b>, or any combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">In some embodiments, the burn chamber <b>103</b> may be fixed or positioned directly above ash tray <b>111</b><i>b </i>such that the lower surface <b>103</b>-<b>2</b> of the burn chamber <b>103</b> and the upper surface <b>111</b><i>b</i>-<b>1</b> of the ash tray <b>111</b><i>b </i>are shared, that is, the burn chamber <b>103</b> and the ash tray <b>111</b><i>b </i>are attached together by the same barrier or surface. Further, in this embodiment, the burn chamber <b>103</b> may include one or more apertures <b>103</b><i>c </i>that extend partially across the interior lower surface <b>103</b>-<b>2</b> of the burn chamber <b>103</b>, such that, for example, a fuel source or heat may be directed between the interior lower surface <b>103</b>-<b>2</b> of the burn chamber <b>103</b> and the interior lower surface <b>111</b><i>b</i>-<b>2</b> of the ash tray <b>111</b><i>b. </i>In some embodiments, the aperture <b>103</b><i>c </i>may extend through and completely or substantially across the interior surface of the lower surface <b>103</b>-<b>2</b> of the burn chamber <b>103</b>, such that the burn chamber <b>103</b> excludes a lower surface <b>103</b>-<b>2</b> and the interior space of the burn chamber <b>103</b> is bounded by the upper surface <b>103</b>-<b>1</b> of the burn chamber <b>103</b> and the interior lower surface <b>111</b><i>b</i>-<b>2</b> of the ash tray <b>111</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In some embodiments, the dimensions of the burn chamber <b>103</b> may be configured such at least a portion of the upper surface <b>103</b>-<b>1</b> of the burn chamber <b>103</b> is flush with the upper surface <b>102</b>-<b>1</b> to provide more surface area for food items. In some embodiments, the upper surface <b>103</b>-<b>1</b> of the burn chamber <b>103</b> may be configured to be completely flush with the upper surface <b>102</b>-<b>1</b> of the conduction chamber <b>102</b> such that the portable oven <b>100</b> has the maximum cooking surface area for food items.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The exemplary heat chamber <b>105</b> may have a regular polygon shape, for example, a rectangular, oval, or square box or cylinder. The surfaces, sides, corners, or edges of the heat chamber <b>105</b> may be curved or non-linear to optimize heat and air flow within the heat chamber <b>105</b>. The heat chamber <b>105</b> may be fixed to the portable oven <b>100</b>. In some embodiments, the heat chamber <b>105</b> may be movably or removably coupled to the portable oven <b>100</b>. The heat chamber <b>105</b> may be adjacent to, or abut, one or more sides or surfaces of other chambers (e.g., conduction chamber <b>102</b> or heat chamber <b>105</b>), source vents <b>107</b>, exhaust vents <b>109</b>, or a combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The heat chamber <b>105</b> may include a plurality of ports <b>105</b><i>a, </i><b>105</b><i>b, </i><b>105</b><i>c, </i>and <b>105</b><i>d </i>(hereinafter &#x201c;ports <b>105</b><i>n</i>&#x201d;) to, for example, couple to one or more fittings or components (e.g., source vent <b>107</b> and exhaust vent <b>109</b>), to direct heat, smoke, debris, or air (e.g., wind from the outside environment), or any combination thereof. In some embodiments, ports <b>105</b><i>n </i>may be permanently open, for example, to direct heat and air, exhaust smoke, or provide access to debris. In some embodiments, the heat chamber <b>105</b> may include a slidable cover, a flap, a swing door, or retractable cover to allow the ports <b>105</b><i>n </i>to partially open or fully close to further direct heat, exhaust smoke and debris, or reduce weather conditions from altering heat flow, air flow, or cooking temperature.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">As will be further discussed in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>A-<b>2</b>B</figref>, in some embodiments, the heat chamber <b>105</b> may include one or more partitions <b>251</b> separating interior spaces of the heat chamber <b>105</b> to, for example, direct heat and air flow through the heat chamber <b>105</b> to exhaust vent <b>109</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">In some embodiments, the heat chamber <b>105</b> may include one or more openings <b>108</b> that extend partially across the interior lower surface <b>105</b>-<b>2</b> of the heat chamber <b>105</b>, such that, for example, a portion of heat flow may be direct from below the lower surface <b>105</b>-<b>2</b> into heating space <b>110</b>. In some embodiments, the openings <b>108</b> may extend along one or more edges, sides, or surfaces of the heat chamber <b>105</b>, such that heat may be circulated back into the portable oven <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">In some embodiments, the dimensions of the heat chamber <b>105</b> may be configured such that at least the lower surface <b>105</b>-<b>2</b> of the heat chamber <b>105</b> substantially overlays the total area of the upper surface <b>102</b>-<b>1</b> of the conduction chamber <b>102</b> thereby confining heat flow between the lower surface <b>105</b>-<b>2</b> of the heat chamber <b>105</b> and the upper surface <b>102</b>-<b>1</b> of the conduction chamber <b>102</b>. Moreover, in some embodiments, the dimensions of the heat chamber <b>105</b> may be configured such that one or more sides, portions, or edges of the exterior peripheral surface(s) <b>105</b>-<b>3</b> of the heat chamber <b>105</b> contacts one or more sides, portions or edges of an interior surface of one or more peripheral surfaces <b>500</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>500</b>-<b>2</b>, <b>500</b>-<b>3</b> and <b>500</b>-<b>4</b> of the portable oven <b>500</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> and <b>2</b>A</figref> for the exemplary source vent <b>107</b> and exhaust vent <b>109</b>. The exemplary source vent <b>107</b> extends between the heat chamber <b>105</b> and burn chamber <b>103</b> to direct heat, air, smoke and debris away from the burn chamber <b>103</b>. The source vent <b>107</b> may comprise a single piece extending between the burn chamber <b>103</b> and heat chamber <b>105</b>, or a plurality of segments where each segment couples to one of the openings <b>103</b><i>n </i>of the burn chamber <b>103</b> and ports <b>105</b><i>n </i>of the heat chamber <b>105</b>. Moreover, source vent <b>107</b> may further protrude from upper surface <b>105</b>-<b>1</b> and port <b>105</b><i>a </i>of heat chamber <b>105</b>. The source vent <b>107</b> need not be limited to a cylinder as shown and described, and instead may be rectangular, oval, trapezoidal, or other polygonal shape. Each of the one or more segments of the source vent <b>107</b> may have the same or different shape, the same or different thickness (e.g., the same or different inner and outer surfaces, where the inner surface is a first distance from the centerline of the vent segment and the outer surface is a second distance from the centerline that extends vertically along the center of vent segment), and the same or different size and dimensions.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">In some embodiments, the source vent <b>107</b> may include one or more cut-outs <b>271</b> to direct heat flow from burn chamber <b>103</b> into heat chamber <b>105</b>. Similarly, the source vent <b>107</b> may include one or more openings <b>272</b> between the burn chamber <b>103</b> and heat chamber <b>105</b> to direct heat into heating space <b>110</b>. Moreover, the opening <b>107</b><i>b </i>of the source vent <b>107</b> may have a predetermined thickness <b>107</b>-<b>1</b> (e.g., an inner surface) to reduce heat loss. In some embodiments, the inner surface may include apertures <b>107</b><i>a </i>extending vertically through the top and bottom ends of the source vent <b>107</b> to channel or circulate air or heat within the portable oven <b>100</b>. Further, the inner surface <b>107</b>-<b>1</b> and outer surface <b>107</b>-<b>2</b> of the source vent <b>107</b> may each have separate openings <b>272</b> to channel heat, air, smoke or debris through the source vent <b>107</b>. For example, to direct heat and air into the portable oven <b>100</b> and heat chamber <b>105</b>, the source vent <b>107</b> may include openings <b>272</b> in only the outer surface <b>107</b>-<b>2</b>, apertures <b>107</b><i>a </i>between inner and outer surfaces <b>107</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>107</b>-<b>2</b>, and cut-outs <b>271</b> that extend through both inner and outer surfaces <b>107</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>107</b>-<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The exemplary exhaust vent <b>109</b> extends between the heat chamber <b>105</b> and conduction chamber <b>102</b> to direct heat, air, smoke and debris away from the conduction chamber <b>102</b>. The exhaust vent <b>109</b> may comprise a single piece extending between the conduction chamber <b>102</b> and heat chamber <b>105</b>, or a plurality of segments where each segment couples to one of the openings <b>102</b><i>n </i>of the conduction chamber <b>102</b> and ports <b>105</b><i>n </i>of the heat chamber <b>105</b>. Moreover, exhaust vent <b>109</b> may further protrude from upper surface <b>105</b>-<b>1</b> and port <b>105</b><i>c </i>of heat chamber <b>105</b>. The exhaust vent <b>109</b> need not be limited to a cylinder as shown and described, and instead may be rectangular, oval, trapezoidal, or other polygonal shape. Each of the one or more segments of the exhaust vent <b>109</b> may have the same or different shape, the same or different thickness (e.g., the same or different inner and outer surfaces, where the inner surface is a third distance from the centerline of the vent segment and the outer surface is a fourth distance from the centerline that extends vertically along the center of the vent segment), and the same or different size and dimensions. In some embodiments, the first, second, third and fourth distances may be the same or different.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">In some embodiments, the exhaust vent <b>109</b> may include one or more cut-outs <b>291</b> to direct heat flow from conduction chamber <b>102</b> into heat chamber <b>105</b>, and vice versa. Similarly, the exhaust vent <b>109</b> may include one or more openings <b>292</b> between the conduction chamber <b>102</b> and heat chamber <b>105</b> to direct heat into heating space <b>110</b>. Moreover, the opening <b>109</b><i>b </i>of the exhaust vent <b>109</b> may have a predetermined thickness <b>109</b>-<b>1</b> (i.e., includes inner and outer surfaces) to reduce heat loss. In some embodiments, the inner surface may include apertures <b>109</b><i>a </i>extending vertically through the top and bottom ends of the exhaust vent <b>109</b> to channel or circulate air or heat within the portable oven <b>100</b>. Further, the inner surface <b>109</b>-<b>1</b> and outer surface <b>109</b>-<b>2</b> of the exhaust vent <b>109</b> may each have separate openings <b>292</b> to channel heat, air, smoke or debris through the exhaust vent <b>109</b>. For example, to direct heat and air into the portable oven <b>100</b> and heat chamber <b>105</b>, the exhaust vent <b>109</b> may include openings <b>292</b> in only the outer surface <b>109</b>-<b>2</b>, apertures <b>109</b><i>a </i>between inner and outer surfaces <b>109</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>109</b>-<b>2</b>, and cut-outs <b>291</b> that extend through both inner and outer surfaces <b>109</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>109</b>-<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The exemplary ash tray <b>111</b> may comprises of individual ash trays <b>111</b><i>a </i>and <b>111</b><i>b </i>that slide out from the portable oven <b>100</b>. Each ash tray <b>111</b><i>a </i>and <b>111</b><i>b </i>may be slidably and/or removably positioned below the conduction chamber <b>102</b> and burn chamber <b>103</b>, respectively. As described above, in some embodiments, the upper surface <b>103</b>-<b>1</b> of the burn chamber <b>103</b> and the lower surface <b>111</b><i>b</i>-<b>2</b> of the ash tray <b>111</b><i>b </i>may form the interior space of the burn chamber <b>103</b>. That is, the burn chamber <b>103</b> and ash tray <b>111</b><i>b </i>do not share a barrier or surface. In such embodiments, the ash tray <b>111</b><i>b </i>may have sliders <b>121</b> that partition, bound, and isolate the interior space of the burn chamber <b>103</b> from the rest of the portable oven <b>100</b>. In such embodiments, the ash tray <b>111</b><i>b </i>serves to both bound the interior space of the burn chamber <b>103</b> and to provide access for removing used fuel (e.g., charcoal, wood, etc.).</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Similarly, as described above, in some embodiments, the upper surface <b>102</b>-<b>1</b> of the conduction chamber <b>102</b> and the lower surface <b>111</b><i>a</i>-<b>2</b> of the ash tray <b>111</b><i>a </i>may form the interior space of the conduction chamber <b>102</b>. That is, the conduction chamber <b>102</b> and ash tray <b>111</b><i>a </i>do not share a barrier or surface. In such embodiments, the ash tray <b>111</b><i>a </i>may have sliders <b>121</b> that partition, bound, and isolate the interior space of the conduction chamber <b>102</b> from the rest of the portable oven <b>100</b>. In such embodiments, the ash tray <b>111</b><i>a </i>serves to both bound the interior space of the conduction chamber <b>102</b> and to provide access for removing used fuel (e.g., charcoal, wood, etc.). One or more ash trays <b>111</b><i>a, </i><b>111</b><i>b </i>may include an opening feature <b>114</b><i>a, </i><b>114</b><i>b </i>such as a handle, hook, or aperture that can be pulled, pressed, latched or hooked onto, for example, by an end of a brush, cooking tool, or other tool to slide out and open the ash tray <b>111</b><i>a </i>and <b>111</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>A</figref> is top perspective view of heat flow through an exemplary heat chamber interior of an exemplary portable oven in accordance with an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure. As can be seen with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>A</figref>, an exemplary heat chamber <b>205</b> may include a plurality of ports <b>205</b><i>n </i>and one or more partitions <b>251</b> separating interior spaces of the heat chamber <b>205</b> to, for example, direct heat and air flow through the interior spaces of the heat chamber <b>105</b> and to exhaust vent <b>209</b>. The heat chamber <b>105</b> may have a regular polygon shape, for example, a curved rectangular box. The interior and exterior surfaces of the one or more partitions <b>251</b>, ports <b>205</b><i>n, </i>upper surface <b>205</b>-<b>1</b>, lower surface <b>205</b>-<b>2</b>, and peripheral surface <b>205</b>-<b>3</b> of the heat chamber <b>105</b> may be, in part or in whole, coarse, smooth, textured, dimpled, flat, curved or rounded. Thus, the interior surfaces, sides, corners, or edges of the heat chamber <b>105</b> may be configured as stated above or as desired to optimize heat and air flow within heat chamber <b>105</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The partition <b>251</b> need not be limited to one partition (i.e., one wall) as shown and described, and instead the partition <b>251</b> may include one or more segments. Each partition <b>251</b> segment may be of the same or different shape. For example, square, rectangular, oval, trapezoidal, or other polygonal shaped partitions or protrusions may be used as partition <b>251</b> in the interior of the heat chamber <b>105</b>. Each of the one or more segments of the partition <b>251</b> may have the same or different thickness, and the same or different size and dimensions.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">As shown, heat flows from burn chamber <b>203</b> through source vent <b>207</b> into heat chamber <b>205</b> and out of exhaust vent <b>209</b>. As will be further described in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>B</figref>, one or more chambers (e.g., upper, lower and peripheral surfaces <b>205</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>205</b>-<b>2</b>, and <b>205</b>-<b>3</b> of heat chamber <b>205</b>) and/or vents may include one or more openings, apertures, or ports to further guide heat and/or air flow as desired, as well as to direct additional and/or excess heat into heating space <b>210</b>. Heat flow within the portable oven <b>200</b> may be described as occurring through a plurality of stages <b>280</b>, <b>282</b>, <b>284</b> and <b>286</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">In stage <b>280</b>, a fuel source (e.g., biofuel, sterno canned heat, gas, coal, etc.) and/or heating source (e.g., fire, propane and/or electric stove or ignitor, etc.) may be placed or installed in burn chamber <b>203</b> and used (e.g., burning biofuel) to produce heat. Upon use of the fuel source, heat, air, smoke, gas, embers, debris, and other byproducts of the spent fuel may radiate and flow from within burn chamber <b>203</b> into one or more source vents <b>207</b>. The source vent <b>207</b> may be fixed or removably coupled to port <b>205</b><i>b </i>of the heat chamber <b>205</b>. The source vent <b>207</b> may portion out, for example, flowing, radiated or emanating heat, air, smoke, and other byproducts of the used fuel source into one or more portions. The source vent <b>207</b> may include one or more apertures <b>207</b><i>a, </i><b>207</b><i>c, </i>and openings <b>207</b> formed between top and bottom ends, inner surface <b>207</b>-<b>1</b>, and outer surface <b>207</b>-<b>2</b> of the source vent <b>207</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">In some embodiments, one or more apertures <b>207</b><i>a </i>may direct, for example, a portion of heat and air flow into heating space <b>210</b> through one or more openings <b>272</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Still, in some embodiments, one or more apertures <b>207</b><i>c </i>may extend through a lower surface of the cut-out <b>271</b> and the surface of the bottom end of the source vent <b>270</b> to direct, for example, a portion of heat and air flow from burn chamber <b>203</b> into the heat chamber <b>205</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Moreover, in some embodiments, one or more apertures <b>207</b><i>a </i>may extend through the top and bottom ends of the source vent <b>207</b> such that a portion of heat and air flowing into one or more apertures <b>207</b><i>a </i>from the bottom end of the source vent <b>207</b> may flow between the inner and outer surfaces <b>207</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>207</b>-<b>2</b> of the source vent <b>207</b> and out from one or more apertures <b>207</b><i>a </i>on the top end of the source vent <b>207</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">In stage <b>282</b>, another portion of heat and air may flow from burn chamber <b>203</b> into opening <b>207</b><i>b </i>of source vent <b>207</b> and out from cut out <b>271</b> of source vent <b>207</b> into heat chamber <b>203</b>. In some embodiments, the source vent <b>207</b> may have one or more segments A, B, C . . . etc. In some embodiments, source vent <b>207</b> may include one or more slidable covers, flaps, swing doors, retractable covers, screens, or other covers or partitions at, or between, each end of the source vent <b>207</b> to, for example, capture or prevent byproducts and debris from entering heat chamber <b>205</b> and/or prevent embers from escaping the portable oven <b>200</b> into the environment (e.g., the camp site, forest, etc.). In some embodiments, source vent <b>207</b> may include one or more slidable covers, flaps, swing doors, retractable covers, screens, or other covers or partitions positioned between each end of the source vent <b>207</b> that fully open, partially open, or fully closed during use of the portable oven <b>200</b> to further guide heat and air flow into heat chamber <b>205</b> or out of the portable oven <b>200</b> through source vent <b>207</b>. Still, another portion of heat and air may flow within source vent <b>207</b> and out from the top surface or top end of the source vent <b>207</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">In stage <b>284</b>, heat and air flow within the interior space of heat chamber <b>205</b>. The heat chamber <b>205</b> may be bounded by the upper, lower and peripheral interior surfaces <b>205</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>205</b>-<b>2</b>, <b>205</b>-<b>3</b>, and one or more partitions <b>251</b> of a predetermined length, width and thickness. In some embodiments, one or more partitions <b>251</b> may extend substantially widthwise, for example, across the width of the heat chamber <b>205</b> thereby forming one or more separate but adjoining interior spaces within the heat chamber <b>205</b>. In some embodiments, one or more partitions <b>251</b> may extend substantially lengthwise, vertically, or any combination thereof. In some embodiments, one or more partitions <b>251</b> may be fixed to, removable coupled to, or slidably inserted in, the interior side of the peripheral surface <b>205</b>-<b>3</b>. In some embodiments, one or more partitions <b>251</b> may be fixed to, removable coupled to, or slidably inserted in, the interior side of the top surface <b>205</b>-<b>1</b> of the heat chamber <b>205</b>. In some embodiments, one or more partitions <b>251</b> may be fixed to, removable coupled to, or slidably inserted in, the interior side of the bottom surface <b>205</b>-<b>2</b> of the heat chamber <b>205</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Heat flowing within heat chamber <b>205</b> may radiate from the sides, edges and surfaces of the upper, lower and peripheral interior surfaces <b>205</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>205</b>-<b>2</b>, <b>205</b>-<b>3</b> out into heating space <b>210</b>. Moreover, air flowing within heat chamber <b>205</b> may direct heat to flow along and between the one or more partitions <b>251</b> and interior surfaces of the peripheral surface <b>205</b>-<b>3</b>. Thus, one or more portions of heat flowing within heat chamber <b>205</b> may radiate from the upper, lower and peripheral interior surfaces <b>205</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>205</b>-<b>2</b>, <b>205</b>-<b>3</b> out into heating space <b>210</b>, and one or more portions of heat flowing with heat chamber <b>205</b> may flow from the source vent <b>207</b> to the exhaust vent <b>209</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">In stage <b>286</b>, heat and air within the interior space of heat chamber <b>205</b> flow out from one or more ports <b>205</b><i>c </i>and <b>205</b><i>d </i>and into the exhaust vent <b>209</b>. In some embodiments, the exhaust vent <b>209</b> may have one or more segments V, W, X . . . etc.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">In some embodiments, exhaust vent <b>209</b> may include one or more slidable covers, flaps, swing doors, retractable covers, screens, or other covers or partitions at, or between, each end of the exhaust vent <b>209</b> to, for example, capture or prevent byproducts and debris from entering the conduction chamber <b>202</b> and/or prevent embers from escaping the portable oven <b>200</b> into the environment (e.g., the camp site, forest, etc.). In some embodiments, exhaust vent <b>209</b> may include one or more slidable covers, flaps, swing doors, retractable covers, screens, or other covers or partitions positioned between each end of the exhaust vent <b>209</b> that fully open, partially open, or fully closed during use of the portable oven <b>200</b> to further guide heat and air flow from the heat chamber <b>205</b> out to the conduction chamber <b>202</b> and/or out of the portable oven <b>200</b> into the environment.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">As described above, the exhaust vent <b>209</b> may include two segments; a first segment V with cutout <b>291</b> coupled between the heat chamber <b>205</b> and conduction chamber <b>202</b>, and a second segment W spaced from the first segment V and attached to port <b>205</b><i>c </i>of the heat chamber <b>205</b>. Although a gap is provided between the two segments V, W of exhaust vent <b>209</b>, in some embodiments, the exhaust vent <b>209</b> may be one segment with an upper cutout <b>293</b> to direct heat and air flow into the conduction chamber <b>202</b> and out from the portable oven <b>200</b> into the environment.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The exhaust vent <b>209</b> may circulate heat and air into the heating space <b>210</b> and into the interior of the conduction chamber <b>202</b> where food items are placed for cooking. In some embodiments, a portion of heat and air may flow from the heat chamber <b>205</b> into the interior of conduction chamber <b>202</b> through cutout <b>291</b>. In some embodiments, a portion of heat and air may flow out from the portable oven through the exhaust vent <b>209</b>. In some embodiments, a portion of heat and air may flow into the heating space <b>210</b> through openings <b>292</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>B</figref> is top perspective view of an exemplary heat chamber interior and heat chamber cover of an exemplary portable oven in accordance with an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure. As can be seen with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>B</figref>, exemplary exterior surfaces of the heating chamber <b>205</b> may include one or more apertures <b>252</b><i>a, </i><b>252</b><i>b, </i><b>252</b><i>c, </i><b>252</b><i>d, </i><b>254</b><i>a </i>and <b>254</b><i>b </i>extending through and along one or more upper, lower and peripheral surfaces <b>205</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>205</b>-<b>2</b>, and <b>205</b>-<b>3</b>. In some embodiments, a portion of heat and air may flow into the heating space <b>210</b> through openings <b>292</b>. In some embodiments, the heat chamber <b>205</b> may include one or more apertures <b>252</b><i>a, </i><b>252</b><i>b, </i><b>252</b><i>c, </i><b>252</b><i>d, </i><b>254</b><i>a </i>and <b>254</b><i>b </i>extending through one or more upper, lower and peripheral interior surfaces <b>205</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>205</b>-<b>2</b>, and <b>205</b>-<b>3</b> to direct, for example, a portion of heat and air flow into heating space <b>210</b>. In some embodiments, the exhaust vent <b>209</b> may be formed of one segment with two cutouts <b>291</b> and <b>293</b>. The lower cutout <b>291</b> directing a portion of heat and airflow from the upper cutout <b>293</b> into the conduction chamber <b>202</b>, and the upper cutout <b>293</b> directing a portion of heat and airflow out from the portable oven <b>200</b> and into the environment. In some embodiments, the exhaust vent <b>209</b> may include two segments V, W and each segment have one or more cutouts <b>291</b>, and <b>293</b>, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">In some embodiments, opening <b>209</b><i>b </i>of the exhaust vent <b>209</b> may have a predetermined thickness <b>209</b>-<b>1</b> (i.e., includes inner and outer surfaces) to reduce heat loss. Moreover, each segment V, W, . . . etc., of the exhaust vent <b>209</b> may have the same or different thickness or inner surface. Further, the cutouts <b>291</b> and <b>293</b> may be of the same or different shape to reduce heat loss and further direct heat and air flow into the heating space <b>210</b> and out from the portable oven <b>200</b> into the environment. The shape of the cutouts <b>291</b> and <b>293</b> may be, for example, square, rectangular, oval, trapezoidal, or other polygonal shaped cutouts. Moreover, each of the cutouts <b>291</b> and <b>293</b> may have the same or different thickness, and the same or different size and dimensions.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">In some embodiments, opening <b>207</b><i>b </i>of the source vent <b>207</b> may have a predetermined thickness <b>207</b>-<b>1</b> (i.e., includes inner and outer surfaces) to reduce heat loss. Moreover, each segment A, B, . . . etc., of the source vent <b>207</b> may have the same or different thickness or inner surface. Further, one or more the cutouts <b>271</b> may be of the same or different shape to reduce heat loss and further direct heat and air flow into the heat chamber <b>205</b> and heating space <b>210</b>, and out from the portable oven <b>200</b> into the environment. The shape of the one or more cutouts <b>271</b> may be, for example, square, rectangular, oval, trapezoidal, or other polygonal shaped cutouts. Moreover, each of the cutouts <b>271</b> may have the same or different thickness, and the same or different size and dimensions.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">In some embodiments, one or more partitions <b>251</b> of the heat chamber <b>205</b> may include one or more openings <b>251</b><i>b </i>to, for example, direct heat and airflow within the heat chamber <b>205</b>. The shape of the one or more openings <b>251</b><i>b </i>may be, for example, square, rectangular, oval, trapezoidal, or other polygonal shaped cutouts. Moreover, each of the openings <b>251</b><i>b </i>may have the same or different size and dimensions.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a right perspective view of an exemplary conduction chamber interior of an exemplary portable oven in accordance with an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure. As can be seen with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, an exemplary conduction chamber <b>302</b> may a include top, bottom, and peripheral surfaces <b>302</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>302</b>-<b>2</b> and <b>303</b>-<b>3</b>, respectively. The top surface <b>302</b>-<b>2</b> may be a cooking surface for food items. In some embodiments, the conduction chamber <b>302</b> may include one interior space bounded by the top, bottom, and peripheral surfaces <b>302</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>302</b>-<b>2</b> and <b>303</b>-<b>3</b>, respectively. In some embodiments, the conduction chamber <b>302</b> may include one or more partitions <b>342</b> and/or walls <b>343</b> that partition the interior space of the conduction chamber <b>302</b> into a plurality of interior spaces. One or more partitions <b>342</b> may be formed on either interior space <b>346</b>, that is, adjacent to the bottom surface <b>302</b>-<b>2</b>, or on interior space <b>382</b>, that is adjacent to top surface <b>302</b>-<b>1</b>. For example, interior space <b>346</b> may be formed by a plurality of walls <b>343</b> extending along, but not contacting, the perimeter of each peripheral surface <b>302</b>-<b>3</b> of the conduction chamber <b>302</b>. The interior space <b>346</b> may restrict heat and air flow from the cutout <b>391</b> of the exhaust vent <b>309</b> to within certain regions of the conduction chamber <b>302</b>. For example, partitions <b>342</b> and/or walls <b>343</b> may be configured such that higher surface heat areas on the conduction surface <b>302</b>-<b>1</b> are formed by constraining heat and air flow between the cutout <b>391</b> and the leftmost wall of the partition <b>342</b>. Subsequently, the adjoining interior space <b>382</b> may provide lower surface heat areas on the conduction surface <b>302</b>-<b>1</b>, for example, near opening <b>302</b><i>d </i>where heat and air flow are reduced through one or more partitions <b>342</b>. Thus, food items requiring longer cooking times may be placed on or near portions of the conduction surface <b>302</b>-<b>1</b> configured to receive greater surface heat.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The conduction chamber <b>302</b> may have a regular polygon shape, for example, a curved rectangular box. The interior and exterior surfaces of the one or more partitions <b>342</b>, walls <b>343</b>, apertures <b>302</b><i>a, </i><b>302</b><i>b, </i><b>302</b><i>c, </i>top surface <b>302</b>-<b>1</b>, bottom surface <b>302</b>-<b>2</b>, and peripheral surface <b>302</b>-<b>3</b> of the conduction chamber <b>302</b> may be, in part or in whole, coarse, smooth, textured, dimpled, flat, curved or rounded. Thus, the interior surfaces, sides, corners, or edges of the conduction chamber <b>302</b> may be configured as stated above or as desired to optimize heat and air flow within burn chamber <b>302</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">The partition <b>342</b> need not be limited to one partition (i.e., one wall) as shown and described, and instead the partition <b>342</b> may include one or more segments. Each partition <b>342</b> segment may be of the same or different shape. For example, square, rectangular, oval, trapezoidal, or other polygonal shaped partitions or protrusions may be used as partition <b>342</b> in the interior of the conduction chamber <b>302</b>. Each of the one or more segments of the partition <b>342</b> may have the same or different thickness, and the same or different size and dimensions.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">As shown, heat flows into and out from the conduction chamber <b>302</b> through exhaust vent <b>309</b>. Moreover, like stage <b>280</b> of the burn chamber <b>203</b> above, heat can also be generated using a fuel source and/or heating source placed or installed in conduction chamber <b>302</b>. Heat flow within the portable oven <b>300</b> may be described as occurring through a plurality of stages <b>350</b> and <b>352</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">In stage <b>350</b>, a fuel source (e.g., biofuel, sterno canned heat, gas, coal, etc.) and/or heating source (e.g., fire, propane and/or electric stove or ignitor, etc.) may be placed or installed in conduction chamber <b>302</b> and used (e.g., burning biofuel) to produce heat. Upon use of the fuel source, heat, air, smoke, gas, embers, debris, and other byproducts of the spent fuel may radiate and flow from within conduction chamber <b>302</b> into one or more exhaust vents <b>309</b>. The exhaust vent <b>309</b> may be fixed or removably coupled to aperture <b>102</b><i>a </i>of the burn chamber <b>302</b>. The exhaust vent <b>309</b> may portion out, for example, flowing, radiated or emanating heat, air, smoke, and other byproducts of the used fuel source into one or more portions. The conduction chamber <b>302</b> may include one or more apertures <b>302</b><i>d </i>for heat to flow or radiate into heating space <b>310</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">In stage <b>352</b>, a portion of heat and air may flow from heat chamber <b>305</b> into the conduction chamber <b>302</b> from exhaust vent <b>309</b>, and a portion of heat and air may flow from the conduction chamber <b>302</b> into the exhaust vent <b>309</b>. The heat chamber <b>305</b> and conduction chamber <b>302</b> together provide heat and airflow within the heating space <b>310</b>. The conduction chamber <b>302</b> may further provide an additional fuel or heating source to cook food items. Food items may be placed on an upper surface <b>302</b>-<b>1</b> of the conduction chamber <b>302</b> where heat may flow and radiate into the heating space <b>310</b> from heat chamber <b>305</b>, conduction chamber <b>302</b>, and source vent <b>307</b> and exhaust vent <b>309</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">In some embodiments, the exemplary portable oven <b>300</b> may include one or more hot plates <b>361</b> and <b>363</b>, hot plate controls <b>365</b> and <b>367</b>, indicators <b>366</b> and <b>367</b>, and power on/off switch <b>369</b>. The hot plates <b>361</b> and <b>363</b> may be used as a warming plate for cooked food items or as a stove top for heating food items. In some embodiments, the one or more hot plates <b>361</b> and <b>363</b> may be incorporated into the body of the heat chamber <b>305</b> where the hot plate controls <b>365</b> and <b>367</b> may close or partially close one or more segments of exhaust vent <b>309</b>, source vent <b>307</b>, or opening <b>251</b><i>b, </i>or any combination thereof to direct heat flow to radiate from the one or more hot plates <b>361</b> and <b>363</b>. In some embodiments, one or more hot plates <b>361</b> and <b>363</b> may be formed on, or attached onto, the heat chamber <b>305</b> where a separate power source and/or fuel source, for example electrical power, together with the power switch <b>369</b> and hot plate controls <b>365</b> and <b>367</b> may be used to operate hot plates <b>361</b> and <b>363</b>. In some embodiments, one or more segments of exhaust vent <b>309</b>, source vent <b>307</b>, or openings <b>252</b><i>a, </i><b>252</b><i>c, </i><b>254</b><i>a, </i><b>254</b><i>b, </i>or any combination thereof may be closed or partially closed by the hot plate controls <b>365</b> and <b>367</b> to direct heat flow underneath one or more hot plates <b>361</b> and <b>363</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">Examples of material which could be used in the making the conduction chamber <b>302</b>, burn chamber <b>303</b>, heat chamber <b>305</b>, source vent <b>307</b>, exhaust vent <b>309</b> and ash tray <b>311</b> may include, for example, one of aluminum, aluminum alloy, steel, stainless steel, zinc, magnesium, cast iron, ceramic, or any other metals, corrosion resistant metals such as titanium, copper, bronze or brass, precious metals, or metal alloy, or a combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is a flow chart illustrating an exemplary method of making the portable oven in accordance with an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure. The exemplary method is provided by way of example, as there are a variety of ways to carry out the method. Each box shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> represents one or more processes, methods or subroutines, carried out in the exemplary method. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>, <b>2</b>A-<b>2</b>B, <b>3</b> and <b>5</b></figref> show exemplary embodiments of carrying out the method of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>. The exemplary method may begin at box <b>402</b>. Further for explanatory purposes, the boxes of the example process <b>400</b> are described herein as occurring in serial, or linearly. However, multiple boxes of the example process <b>400</b> may occur in parallel. In addition, the boxes of the example process <b>400</b> may be performed a different order than the order shown and/or one or more of the boxes of the example process <b>400</b> may not be performed.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">The exemplary method of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> includes forming at least one opening in a first chamber (box <b>402</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">The method further includes forming at least one aperture in a second chamber (box <b>404</b>). In some embodiments, the second chamber may be adjacent and fixed to the first chamber.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">The method further includes forming at least one port in a heat manifold (box <b>406</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">The method further includes forming at least one wall inside the heat manifold to partition the heat manifold (box <b>408</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">The method further includes coupling at least one source vent to the heat manifold and the first chamber (box <b>410</b>). In some embodiments, the at least one source vent extends between and couples the at least one port of the heat manifold to the at least one opening of the first chamber.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">In some embodiments, the method of coupling the at least one source vent to the heat manifold and the first chamber further comprises of coupling the at least one source vent to a first port of the heat manifold and coupling at least one exhaust vent to the heat manifold to thereby protrude from a surface of the heat manifold, wherein the heat manifold includes a second port, and a first end of the at least one exhaust vent couples to the second port of the heat manifold.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">In some embodiments, the method of coupling the at least one exhaust vent to the heat manifold to thereby protrude from the surface of the heat manifold, further comprises coupling a second end of the at least one exhaust vent to the at least one aperture of the second chamber.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">In some embodiments, the second chamber includes an upper surface and a lower surface and the at least one aperture is positioned on the upper surface of the second chamber, and the method of coupling the second end of the at least one exhaust vent to the at least one aperture of the second chamber further comprises the at least one exhaust vent protruding through the at least one aperture of the second chamber and including a cutout extending between the upper surface and the lower surface of the second chamber.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">In some embodiments, the heat manifold includes a top surface and a bottom surface and the method further comprises a third port positioned at the top surface and the first port positioned at the bottom surface, wherein coupling at least one source vent to the heat manifold and the first chamber, further comprises the at least one source vent extending through the first and third ports of the heat manifold and including a cutout extending between the top surface and the bottom surface of the heat manifold.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is a left perspective view of an assembled exemplary portable oven in accordance with an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure. As can be seen with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, an exemplary portable oven <b>500</b> may include a top surface <b>500</b>-<b>5</b> and one or more peripheral surfaces <b>500</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>500</b>-<b>2</b>, <b>500</b>-<b>3</b> and <b>500</b>-<b>4</b> that cover and house the conduction chamber <b>502</b>, burn chamber <b>503</b>, heat chamber <b>505</b>, source vent <b>507</b>, and exhaust vent <b>509</b>. The portable oven <b>500</b> may include one or more doors <b>500</b><i>a, </i><b>500</b><i>b, </i><b>500</b><i>c. </i>In some embodiments, door <b>500</b><i>a </i>may be used to cover, enclose, or seal the components (e.g., heat chamber <b>505</b>, etc.) and food items inside the portable oven <b>500</b>. The door <b>500</b><i>a </i>may be a swing door, a retractable door, a slidable door, a removably fixed or secure door, or any combination thereof. In some embodiments, door <b>500</b><i>b </i>may be used to cover, enclose, or seal the interior space of the conduction chamber <b>502</b> from the outside environment. In some embodiments, the door <b>500</b><i>b </i>may a swing door, a retractable door, a slidable door, a removably fixed or secured door or cover, a snap on door or cover, or any combination thereof. In some embodiments, door <b>500</b><i>c </i>may be used to cover, enclose, or seal the interior space of the burn chamber <b>503</b> from the outside environment. In some embodiments, the door <b>500</b><i>c </i>may a swing door, a retractable door, a slidable door, a removably fixed or secured door or cover, a snap on door or cover, or any combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">In some embodiments, the portable oven <b>500</b> may include one or more fans <b>500</b><i>d. </i>In some embodiments, the one or more fans <b>500</b><i>d </i>may slide into and replace a panel of the burn chamber <b>503</b>. In some embodiments, the one or more fans <b>500</b><i>d </i>may be installed inside the burn chamber <b>503</b>, and on a distal end of the burn chamber <b>503</b>. In some embodiments, one or more fans <b>500</b><i>d </i>may be installed on and over the opening <b>103</b><i>b. </i>Although the fan <b>500</b><i>d </i>is shown as being installed on a side surface of the burn chamber <b>503</b>, one or more fans <b>500</b><i>d </i>may be installed on a bottom interior surface <b>103</b>-<b>2</b> and around a perimeter of the fuel source or heating source. Moreover, in some embodiments, one or more apertures <b>103</b><i>c </i>may be formed to provide air flow from one or more fans <b>500</b><i>d </i>installed in ash tray <b>111</b><i>b </i>and around a perimeter of the fuel source or heating source. In some embodiments, one or more fans <b>500</b><i>d </i>may be installed or attached to the opening <b>103</b><i>b </i>of the burn chamber <b>503</b>, for example, one or more fans <b>500</b><i>d </i>may be inserted, attached, or slidably installed as a front panel and cover of the opening <b>103</b>. In some embodiments, in addition to, or in alternative to the above, the portable oven <b>500</b> may include one or more fans <b>500</b><i>d </i>that slide into and replace a panel of the conduction chamber <b>502</b>, the heat chamber <b>505</b>, and/or replace any surface <b>500</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>500</b>-<b>2</b>, <b>500</b>-<b>3</b>, <b>500</b>-<b>4</b>, or <b>500</b>-<b>5</b> or any combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">In some embodiments, the exterior surface of the top surface <b>500</b>-<b>5</b> may be a warming surface to keep food items warm. The top surface <b>500</b>-<b>5</b> may be heated through by heat and air flow from the one or more apertures <b>252</b><i>a, </i><b>252</b><i>b, </i><b>252</b><i>c, </i><b>252</b><i>d, </i><b>254</b><i>a </i>and <b>254</b><i>b </i>extending through one or more upper, lower and peripheral interior surfaces <b>205</b>-<b>1</b>, <b>205</b>-<b>2</b>, and <b>205</b>-<b>3</b> of the heat chamber <b>505</b>. Moreover, in some embodiments, heat radiated from the top surface <b>505</b>-<b>1</b> of the heat chamber <b>505</b> may provide heat to the top surface <b>500</b>-<b>5</b> to warm or keep warm food items placed on the top surface <b>500</b>-<b>5</b>. In some embodiments, the heat chamber <b>505</b> of the portable oven <b>500</b> may be configured to be closer to the top surface <b>500</b>-<b>5</b> of the portable oven <b>500</b> to provide enough heat and air flow or radiated heat to warm, or keep warm, food items placed on the top surface <b>500</b>-<b>5</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">The devices, systems and functions described herein may be implemented in interior and exterior heating devices, ovens, and other portable devices used to heat, cook, or warm food items. Other examples and implementations are within the scope of the disclosure and appended claims. Features implementing these devices, systems and functions may also be physically located at various positions, including being distributed such that portions of these devices, systems and functions are implemented at different physical locations.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">As used herein, including in the claims, &#x201c;or&#x201d; as used in a list of items (for example, a list of items prefaced by a phrase such as &#x201c;at least one of&#x201d; or &#x201c;one or more of&#x201d;) indicates an inclusive list such that, for example, a list of at least one of A, B, or C means A or B or C or AB or AC or BC or ABC (i.e., A and B and C). Also, as used herein, the phrase &#x201c;based on&#x201d; shall not be construed as a reference to a closed set of conditions. For example, an exemplary step that is described as &#x201c;based on condition A&#x201d; may be based on both a condition A and a condition B without departing from the scope of the present disclosure. In other words, as used herein, the phrase &#x201c;based on&#x201d; shall be construed in the same manner as the phrase &#x201c;based at least in part on.&#x201d;</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">As used herein, the terms &#x201c;vertical,&#x201d; &#x201c;lateral,&#x201d; &#x201c;upper,&#x201d; &#x201c;lower,&#x201d; &#x201c;above,&#x201d; and &#x201c;below&#x201d; can refer to relative directions or positions of features in the semiconductor devices in view of the orientation shown in the Figures. For example, &#x201c;upper&#x201d; or &#x201c;uppermost&#x201d; can refer to a feature positioned closer to the top of a page than another feature. These terms, however, should be construed broadly to include semiconductor devices having other orientations, such as inverted or inclined orientations where top/bottom, over/under, above/below, up/down, and left/right can be interchanged depending on the orientation.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">It should be noted that the methods described above describe possible implementations, and that the operations and the steps may be rearranged or otherwise modified and that other implementations are possible. Furthermore, embodiments from two or more of the methods may be combined.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">From the foregoing, it will be appreciated that specific embodiments of the present disclosure have been described herein for purposes of illustration, but that various modifications may be made without deviating from the scope of the present disclosure. Rather, in the foregoing description, numerous specific details are discussed to provide a thorough and enabling description for embodiments of the present disclosure. One skilled in the relevant art, however, will recognize that the disclosure can be practiced without one or more of the specific details. In other instances, well-known structures or operations often associated with memory systems and devices are not shown, or are not described in detail, to avoid obscuring other aspects of the present disclosure. In general, it should be understood that various other devices, systems, and methods in addition to those specific embodiments disclosed herein may be within the scope of the present disclosure.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. An oven comprising:
<claim-text>a burn chamber, the burn chamber including at least one opening;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a conduction chamber, the conduction chamber being adjacent to the burn chamber and including at least one aperture;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a heat manifold, the heat manifold including a first port and a second port;</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one source vent extending between and coupling the first port of the heat manifold to the at least one opening of the burn chamber; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one exhaust vent, the at least one exhaust vent protruding from a surface of the heat manifold and extending between and coupling the second port of the heat manifold to the at least one aperture of the conduction chamber.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The oven of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the conduction chamber includes an upper surface and a lower surface, the at least one aperture being positioned on the upper surface of the conduction chamber, wherein the at least one exhaust vent protrudes through the at least one aperture of the conduction chamber and includes a cutout extending between the upper surface and the lower surface of the conduction chamber.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The oven of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein either the at least one source vent or the at least one exhaust vent, or both, comprise an inner surface and an outer surface, and wherein gas can travel within the outer surface or between the inner surface and the outer surface.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The oven of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the inner surface and outer surface include one or more cutouts.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The oven of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the heat manifold includes at least one notch, cutout, hole, slit, or combination thereof extending from an interior surface of the heat manifold through to an exterior surface of the heat manifold.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The oven of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the heat manifold includes at least one wall partitioning the heat manifold.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The oven of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one wall includes at least one notch, cutout, hole, slit, or combination thereof extending through to an exterior surface of the wall.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The oven of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the heat manifold includes a top and bottom surface, wherein the first port is positioned at the bottom surface, and the heat manifold further comprises a third port positioned at the top surface, wherein the at least one source vent extends through the first and third ports and includes a cutout extending between the top and bottom surfaces of the heat manifold.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The oven of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the heating device further comprises at least one flap cover positioned over an end of either the at least one source vent, the at least one exhaust vent, or both.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The oven of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a movable tray positioned below the burn chamber and conduction chamber.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The oven of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the burn chamber is dimensioned to accept and position below the at least one source vent a prepackaged can of liquid fuel.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The oven of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one source vent includes a screen configured to support a solid fuel positioned between the burn chamber and the heat manifold.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. An oven comprising:
<claim-text>a burn chamber, the burn chamber including at least one opening;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a conduction chamber, the conduction chamber being adjacent to the burn chamber and including at least one aperture;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a heat manifold, the heat manifold including a plurality of ports and at least one wall partitioning the heat manifold into an elongated path between the plurality of ports;</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one source vent extending between and coupling a first port of the plurality of ports of the heat manifold to the at least one opening of the burn chamber;</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one exhaust vent extending between and coupling a second port of the plurality of ports of the heat manifold to the at least one aperture of the conduction chamber; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a movable tray positioned below the burn chamber and conduction chamber.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The heating device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the heat manifold includes a top surface, a bottom surface and a third port, the first port being positioned at the bottom surface and the third port positioned at the top surface, wherein the at least one source vent extends through the first and third ports and includes a cutout extending between the top surface and the bottom surface of the heat manifold.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. The heating device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the conduction chamber includes an upper surface and a lower surface, the aperture being positioned on the upper surface of the conduction chamber, and wherein the at least one exhaust vent protrudes through the aperture of the conduction chamber and includes a cutout extending between the upper surface and the lower surface of the conduction chamber.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. A method of making an oven, the method comprising:
<claim-text>forming at least one opening in a first chamber;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming at least one aperture in a second chamber, the second chamber being adjacent and fixed to the first chamber;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming at least one port in a heat manifold;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming at least one wall inside the heat manifold to partition the heat manifold;</claim-text>
<claim-text>coupling at least one source vent to the heat manifold and the first chamber, wherein the at least one source vent extends between and couples the at least one port of the heat manifold to the at least one opening of the first chamber.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein coupling the at least one source vent to the heat manifold and the first chamber further comprises of coupling the at least one source vent to a first port of the heat manifold, the method further comprising:
<claim-text>coupling at least one exhaust vent to the heat manifold to thereby protrude from a surface of the heat manifold, wherein the heat manifold includes a second port, and a first end of the at least one exhaust vent couples to the second port of the heat manifold.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein coupling the at least one exhaust vent to the heat manifold to thereby protrude from the surface of the heat manifold, further comprises:
<claim-text>coupling a second end of the at least one exhaust vent to the at least one aperture of the second chamber.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein the second chamber includes an upper surface and a lower surface and the at least one aperture is positioned on the upper surface of the second chamber, and wherein coupling the second end of the at least one exhaust vent to the at least one aperture of the second chamber further comprises:
<claim-text>the at least one exhaust vent protruding through the at least one aperture of the second chamber and including a cutout extending between the upper surface and the lower surface of the second chamber.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein the heat manifold includes a top surface and a bottom surface and further comprises a third port positioned at the top surface and the first port positioned at the bottom surface, wherein coupling at least one source vent to the heat manifold and the first chamber, further comprises:
<claim-text>the at least one source vent extending through the first and third ports of the heat manifold and including a cutout extending between the top surface and the bottom surface of the heat manifold.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
