<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225440A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225440</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17988487</doc-number>
<date>20221116</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>17</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>0073</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>0046</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">SYSTEMS AND METHODS FOR HAIR EXTENSIONS</invention-title>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation-in-part>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17579316</doc-number>
<date>20220119</date>
</document-id>
<parent-status>ABANDONED</parent-status>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17988487</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation-in-part>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Aneehs Corp.</orgname>
<address>
<city>Newport Coast</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kalantari</last-name>
<first-name>Sheena Raji</first-name>
<address>
<city>Newport Beach</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Aneehs Corp.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Newport Coast</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A method for attaching a hair extension to natural hair of an individual includes threading portions of natural hair through a first mesh and a fixing element. The first mesh including a first grid-based mesh with two or more openings and two or more first portions of snap buttons, where the natural hair is threaded through the two or more openings. The method further includes positioning the first mesh against the scalp, fixing the first mesh to the portions of natural hair with the fixing element positioned against the mesh, and fastening, with the snap buttons, a second mesh to the first mesh. The second mesh includes a second grid-based mesh with hair extensions affixed thereto, and two or more second portions of the snap buttons fixed to the second grid-based mesh where the first portions of the snap buttons align with the second portions of the snap buttons.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="78.91mm" wi="158.75mm" file="US20230225440A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="228.43mm" wi="150.96mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225440A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="180.26mm" wi="160.19mm" file="US20230225440A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="212.77mm" wi="117.77mm" file="US20230225440A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="222.33mm" wi="160.95mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225440A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="214.71mm" wi="138.60mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225440A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="229.45mm" wi="145.80mm" file="US20230225440A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="225.47mm" wi="159.00mm" file="US20230225440A1-20230720-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="221.15mm" wi="164.93mm" file="US20230225440A1-20230720-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="228.43mm" wi="167.05mm" file="US20230225440A1-20230720-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="230.12mm" wi="175.43mm" file="US20230225440A1-20230720-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">RELATED U.S. APPLICATION DATA</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims priority to, and is a continuation-in-part of, Non-Provisional patent application Ser. No. 17/579,316, filed on Jan. 19, 2022.</p>
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="tail"?>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">This disclosure relates to the field of hair extensions.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Hair extensions are attachable hair that are fastened to an individual's natural hair to improve its appearance. The attachable processed hair of hair extensions may comprise pre-cut human hair or artificial hair. Hair extensions may be attached to an individual's natural hair in various ways. For example, hair extensions may be fastened to an individual's natural hair via a glue. In another example, hair extensions may be sewn to the individual's natural hair. In yet another example, hair extensions may be clipped to the individual's natural hair. For instance, hair extensions may be fixed to beads or micro-rings. The individual's natural hair may be threaded through the beads or micro-rings to attach the hair extensions to the natural hair.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The various techniques have advantages and disadvantages. In general, hair extensions tend to be expensive and/or time consuming to install and maintain. Further, many types of hair extensions are semi-permanent whereby they are not easily removed. Further, hair extensions are often attached to natural hair near the roots. However, the attachment position changes as the roots grow out, which could result in issues related to maintenance, styling, and appearance.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Washing and maintaining natural hair while hair extensions are attached can be difficult and tiresome given that the hair extensions must be washed, styled and dried along with the rest of the natural hair, which results in the need for additional maintenance time and hair product usage. Even when hair extensions improve the look and feel of natural hair, they often limit styling options based on the position of the hair extensions. Issues may arise when hair extensions get wet or pulled. Additionally, playing sports, exercising, or pursuing an active lifestyle effectively limits one's ability to wear hair extensions given the burden associated with re-stalling or adjusting existing hair extensions.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Accordingly, there is a need in the art for hair extensions that improve upon the stated drawbacks of hair extensions. The disclosed subject matter advances the art in multiple ways including but not limited to reducing the time to attach hair extensions, making it easier to remove and reattach hair extensions, and reducing the time to adjust hair extensions after natural hair has grown out.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Methods and systems for hair extensions are provided. An exemplary embodiment is a method for attaching a hair extension to natural hair of an individual. The method includes threading portions of natural hair through a first mesh. The first mesh includes a first grid-based mesh and two or more openings in the first grid-based mesh. The first mesh further includes two or more first portions of snap buttons fixed to the first grid-based mesh where the natural hair is threaded through the two or more openings in the first grid-based mesh. The method includes positioning the first mesh against a scalp of an individual and fixing the first mesh to the portions of natural hair of the individual. The method includes fastening, with the snap buttons, a second mesh to the first mesh. The second mesh includes a second grid-based mesh and hair extensions fixed to the second grid-based mesh. The second mesh further includes two or more second portions of the snap buttons fixed to the second grid-based mesh where the first portions of the snap buttons align with the second portions of the snap buttons.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The method may further include adjusting a position of the first mesh after the natural hair of the individual has grown out. The adjustment includes unfixing the first mesh from the portions of natural hair of the individual and positioning the first mesh against the scalp of the individual by pulling the portion of natural hair through the two or more openings in the first mesh. The adjustment further includes fixing the first mesh to the portions of natural hair of the individual. The first mesh may include interwoven strands of inert material. The first mesh may further include regular spaces in between the strands of inert material. The two or more openings may be larger than the regular spaces. The second mesh may include interwoven strands of inert material. The method may further include unfastening the second mesh from the first mesh and fastening, with the snap buttons, a third mesh to the first mesh. The third mesh includes a third grid-based mesh and hair extensions fixed to the third grid-based mesh. The third mesh further includes two or more second portions of the snap buttons fixed to the third grid-based mesh where the first portions of the snap buttons align with the second portions of the snap buttons.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Another general aspect is a hair extension system. The hair extension system includes a first mesh. The first mesh includes a first grid-based mesh, two or more openings in the first grid-based mesh, and two or more first portions of snap buttons fixed to the first grid-based mesh. The hair extension system further includes a second mesh. The second mesh includes a second grid-based mesh, hair extensions fixed to the second grid-based mesh, and two or more second portions of the snap buttons fixed to the second grid-based mesh where the first portions of the snap buttons align with the second portions of the snap buttons. The second mesh is attachable to the first mesh. The hair extension system may further include a fixing element that fastens natural hair, which is threaded through at least one of the two or more openings, to the first mesh. The first mesh may include interwoven strands of inert material. The first mesh may further include regular spaces in between the strands of inert material. The two or more openings may be larger than the regular spaces. The second mesh includes interwoven strands of inert material and regular spaces in between the strands of inert material. The hair extension system may further include a third mesh. The third mesh includes a third grid-based mesh, hair extensions fixed to the third grid-based mesh, and two or more second portions of the snap buttons fixed to the third grid-based mesh where the first portions of the snap buttons align with the second portions of the snap buttons.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">An exemplary embodiment is a hair extension system. The hair extension system includes an anchor that is fixable to a scalp of an individual. The anchor includes a grid-based mesh, two or more openings in the grid-based mesh, and two or more first portions of snap buttons fixed to the grid-based mesh. The hair extension system may further include a first hair extension. The first hair extension includes processed hair attached to a strip of material and two or more second portions of the snap buttons fixed to the strip of material where the first portions of the snap buttons align with the second portions of the snap buttons. The grid-based mesh may include interwoven strands of inert material. The grid-based mesh may further include regular spaces in between the strands of inert material. The two or more openings may be larger than the regular spaces. The hair extension system may further include a second hair extension. The second hair extension includes processed hair attached to a strip of material and two or more second portions of the snap buttons fixed to the strip of material where the first portions of the snap buttons align with the second portions of the snap buttons. The first hair extension and second hair extension may be attachable to the anchor. The first hair extension and second hair extension may be interchangeably attachable to the anchor while the anchor is fixed to the scalp of the individual.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is an illustration of an anchor that may be installed in an embodiment of the disclosed hair extension system.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is an illustration of a hair extension that may be installed in an embodiment of the disclosed hair extension system.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a flow diagram of a process for installing a disclosed hair extension system.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is another illustration of a hair extension that may be installed in an embodiment of the disclosed hair extension system.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is an illustration of a portion of natural hair that is threaded through one of the openings in the anchor.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is an illustration of an anchor that is installed to a scalp of an individual in an embodiment of the disclosed hair extension system.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> is another illustration of an anchor that is installed to a scalp of an individual in an embodiment of the disclosed hair extension system.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> is yet another illustration of an anchor that is installed to a scalp of an individual in an embodiment of the disclosed hair extension system.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref> is an illustration of a fixing element being installed onto the threaded natural hair in an embodiment of the disclosed hair extension system.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref> is an illustration of the fixing element being secured in place via clamping in an embodiment of the disclosed hair extension system.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b></figref> is an illustration of an anchor with two rows of first portion buttons that each accept a hair extension in an embodiment of the disclosed hair extension system.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In the following discussion, numerous specific details are set forth to provide a thorough understanding of the disclosed subject matter. However, those skilled in the art will appreciate that the present disclosed subject matter may be practiced without such specific details. In other instances, well-known elements, processes or techniques have been briefly mentioned and not elaborated on in order not to obscure the disclosed subject matter in unnecessary detail and description. Moreover, specific details and the like may have been omitted inasmuch as such details are not deemed necessary to obtain a complete understanding of the disclosed subject matter, and are considered to be within the understanding of persons having ordinary skill in the relevant art.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The disclosed subject matter includes systems and methods for hair extensions. The hair extension system improves upon the art by simplifying the steps for fixing hair extensions to a scalp of an individual. A larger segment of the population will have access to the disclosed subject matter as the ease of installation allows hair extensions to be applied in potentially less time and with less expense than the contemporary art.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The disclosed hair extension system further advances the art by allowing for an improved process of maintaining hair extensions. Once installation is complete, the disclosed hair extensions may be removed and reattached with relative ease in a modular manner. Accordingly, the hair extensions may be removed for various reasons including strenuous activity, bad weather, professional demands, and leisure while allowing for the hair extensions to be quickly and easily reattached. In one example, the disclosed hair extensions, once installed, may be easily removed by unsnapping them from an anchor that is fixed to the scalp. The same or different hair extension may be easily re-snapped back into place with minimal effort. Accordingly, individuals that ordinarily could not wear hair extensions due to demands that proscribe the use of hair extensions, may easily remove the disclosed hair extensions for a prohibitive activity and reattach the hair extensions afterward.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The disclosed hair extensions comprise an anchor that may be fixed to the scalp of an individual. In various embodiments, the anchor is attached by threading portions of natural hair through holes in the anchor. Once fixed to the scalp, hair extensions may be fastened to the anchor with the aid of snap buttons. A first part of a multitude of snap buttons may be affixed to the anchor. Hair extensions may be fastened to the anchor by snapping them into the first part of the multitude of buttons. To facilitate attachment, the hair extensions are fixed to a strip of material that includes the second part of the multitude of buttons. Accordingly, various hair extensions may be attached and removed with ease after the anchor is in place.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">As the anchor is attached to the scalp via threading portions of natural hair through holes in the anchor, there is an issue that exists with most hair extensions in that the position of the anchor changes as the natural hair grows. Ordinarily, the portions of natural hair are pulled through the holes in the anchor until the anchor is fixed against the root of the natural hair. However, the natural hair grows over time, which disengages the anchor from the scalp. The disclosed hair extension system allows for the anchor to be easily readjusted to account for this. The natural hair may be unfastened from the anchor and then further pulled until the anchor is fixed against the scalp. Thus, the position of the anchor may be adjusted with minimal time and effort, and without additional expense or the need for professional servicing.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Hair extensions often wear out over a period of time. The disclosed system allows for easy replacement of worn hair extensions. The installed and worn hair extensions may be unfastened from the anchor by unsnapping the hair extensions from the anchor. Another newer hair extension may subsequently be attached to the anchor while the anchor is still fastened to the scalp of the individual. Accordingly, an individual may exchange a multitude of hair extensions while a single anchor is installed.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The hair extensions may comprise a variety of lengths, sizes and shapes. Accordingly, the anchor may also comprise a variety of lengths, sizes and shapes. Each anchor may include a multitude of first portions of snap buttons. In various embodiments, the anchor has only two first portions of snap buttons. In various embodiments, the anchor may include as many as twelve first portions of snap buttons over a length of approximately one foot. The anchor in the disclosed hair extension system may even comprise longer anchors depending on the needs of the individual. An individual may attach multiple hair extension anchors to the roots of their natural hair, the positions of which may be determined by preference and style.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, an illustration shows an anchor <b>100</b> that may be installed in an embodiment of the disclosed hair extension system. The anchor <b>100</b> may be attached to the scalp of an individual by threading the individual's natural hair through openings <b>115</b> in the anchor. The term &#x201c;natural hair&#x201d; used herein refers to hair that is growing from a hair follicle that is located in an outer skin layer of the scalp of an individual. Natural hair is growing and is a part of an individual, while the terms &#x201c;processed hair&#x201d;, &#x201c;artificial hair&#x201d;, &#x201c;synthetic hair&#x201d;, and &#x201c;hair extensions&#x201d; used herein refer to hair that is not growing, nor is it a part of the individual. Instead, the individual is indirectly combining the hair extensions with their natural hair via the anchor <b>100</b>, to enhance the look and effect of the natural hair.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">To attach the hair extensions to the natural hair, the anchor <b>100</b> is first fastened to the natural hair. The natural hair, portions of which are threaded through the openings <b>115</b> in the anchor, helps to secure the anchor <b>100</b> to the scalp. Accordingly, the portions of natural hair are pulled through the openings <b>115</b> of the anchor <b>100</b> until the anchor is positioned against the roots of the natural hair. In this way, only the anchor <b>100</b> is attached to an individual's head, so that a hair extension or processed hair is not attached directly to the head, natural hair, or scalp. Furthermore, the anchor <b>100</b> itself does not include processed hair, such that no hair extension is attached to the anchor <b>100</b>. Clips, beads, or other fastening elements may be used to fasten to the portions of natural hair and secure the anchor <b>100</b> against the scalp of the individual. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref>, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> illustrate embodiments of the fastening elements, which are widely sold and come in a variety of shapes and types.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The anchor <b>100</b> includes a first grid mesh <b>105</b> that comprises a long strip of variable length depending on the needs of the individual user. In various embodiments, the grid mesh <b>105</b> is made of interwoven strands of inert material such as nylon. Regular gaps (or spaces) <b>106</b> in between the strands of inert material provide for circulation as the anchor <b>100</b> is secured to the scalp of the individual. Perspiration may evaporate through the gaps <b>106</b> and oils on the skin may be washed away through the gaps <b>106</b>. While the grid mesh <b>105</b> is depicted as a long rectangular strip, the grid mesh may take the form of other dimensions or shapes in other embodiments that are within the scope of the present disclosure. By way of example, the grid mesh may have an elongated elliptical or semicircle shape. Again, no processed hair or hair extension is attached to the first grid-based mesh <b>105</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Attached to the grid mesh <b>105</b> at regular intervals are a multitude of buttons <b>110</b>. Specifically, the buttons <b>110</b> are first portions of two-part buttons that can be snapped together to fasten them. Various styles and types of buttons <b>110</b> may be attached to the grid mesh <b>105</b>. In an exemplary embodiment, a first portion of the button <b>110</b> comprises a protrusion or cap. A second portion includes a socket. The cap of the first portion of the button <b>110</b> is inserted into the socket of the second portion of the button. A socket includes a spring portion that surrounds the cap of the first portion. An applied force will push the cap past the spring portion to snap the button together. Likewise, force is used to unsnap the button and remove the cap from the socket. Once snapped, the button <b>110</b> remains snapped until enough force is applied to separate the cap from the socket. Buttons <b>110</b> may be manufactured such that the force required to snap and unsnap the button <b>110</b> may be controlled. In various embodiments, the buttons <b>110</b> may be configured to unsnap with less force than could damage the hair extensions. Thus, a pulling force that would otherwise damage the hair extensions would instead detach the hair extensions from the anchor <b>100</b>. Neither first nor second portions of the buttons <b>110</b> are designed to fasten, thread, or otherwise make any intended contact with natural hair, such that an individual's natural hair is not clamped between any portions of the buttons <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The anchor <b>100</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> includes five buttons <b>110</b> and six openings <b>115</b>, which are spaced at regular intervals along the length of the anchor <b>100</b>. Each of the openings has a perimeter edge formed by the inert material of the grid mesh <b>105</b>. The ends of the anchor <b>100</b> terminate with an opening rather than a button <b>110</b>, as the opening fastens the grid mesh <b>105</b> to the scalp and is the primary means by which the anchor <b>100</b> and hair extensions remain stationary on the scalp. The anchor <b>100</b> may comprise various lengths which comprise a variable number of buttons <b>110</b> and openings <b>115</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref>, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> each show an embodiment of the anchor <b>100</b> with a different length and different numbers of buttons <b>110</b> and openings <b>115</b>. Moreover, other embodiments of the anchor may comprise buttons <b>110</b> and openings <b>115</b> that are spaced at irregular intervals.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is an illustration of a hair extension <b>220</b> that may be installed in an embodiment of the disclosed hair extension system. The hair extension <b>220</b> may be attached to the anchor <b>100</b> by fastening the second portion snap buttons <b>230</b>, which are included in the hair extensions, to the first portion snap buttons <b>110</b> of the anchor <b>100</b>. Again, natural hair is not clamped between any portions of the buttons, and the hair extension or processed hair is not attached directly to an individual's head, natural hair, or scalp, providing a safer and more convenient system for the natural hair. In an exemplary embodiment, the hair extension <b>220</b> includes a second grid mesh <b>225</b>, a multitude of second portion snap buttons <b>230</b> attached to the grid mesh <b>225</b>, and processed hair <b>240</b> that is also attached to the grid mesh <b>225</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The hair extension <b>220</b> may be attached and detached from the anchor <b>100</b>. To install the hair extension <b>220</b> onto the scalp of an individual (ideally to enhance or otherwise style their natural hair), the anchor <b>100</b> is first fastened to the scalp of the individual. Subsequently, the hair extension <b>220</b> is secured to the anchor <b>100</b> by snapping the hair extension <b>220</b> to the first portion snap buttons <b>110</b> on the anchor <b>100</b>, without clamping any natural hair between the buttons. The hair extension <b>220</b> is easily removed or detached from the anchor <b>100</b> by applying enough force to unsnap the hair extension <b>220</b> from the buttons <b>110</b> on the anchor <b>100</b>. Multiple hair extensions <b>220</b> may be used with a single anchor <b>100</b>, which gives the individual maximal versatility with hair styling.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">For instance, the individual may easily install the hair extension <b>220</b> for a professional setting and uninstall the hair extension <b>220</b> for leisure in a short time. Hair extensions <b>220</b> may be swapped using the same anchor <b>100</b>, providing for significantly different hair styling in a short amount of time and with minimal professional aid. Because artificial hair wears out over time, the hair extension <b>220</b> may be easily replaced without replacement of the anchor <b>100</b>, thus saving time and money. As well, the integrity of the processed hair can be preserved for much longer since the individual need not wash, cut, or color it, instead conveniently unbuttoning and removing it from the anchor <b>100</b> as necessary prior to such activities. Thus the hair extension <b>220</b> can last years longer than conventional extensions.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The second grid mesh <b>225</b> may comprise interwoven strands of inert material. In various embodiments, which are not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the grid mesh <b>225</b> comprises a fabric material such as cotton. In another embodiment, grid mesh <b>225</b> comprises a polymeric material. Like the first grid mesh <b>105</b> that forms the anchor <b>100</b>, the second grid mesh <b>225</b> may include regular gaps <b>226</b> in between the strands of interwoven material. Thus fluids, such as perspiration and oils that are secreted from pores in the scalp may be easily washed away.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Attached to the second grid mesh <b>225</b> are a multitude of second portion snap buttons <b>230</b>. The buttons <b>230</b> are second portions of two-part buttons that snap into the first part of the buttons that are fixed to the anchor <b>100</b>. In various embodiments, such as those shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the buttons comprise a first portion that include a cap and a second portion that include a socket. The portion of the button that is fixed to the anchor <b>100</b> and the portion that is fixed to the hair extension <b>220</b> may be interchanged. The embodiments shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> show a first portion of the button that includes a cap attached to the anchor <b>100</b> and a second portion that includes a socket attached to the hair extension <b>220</b>. In various embodiments, different types of buttons may be employed to accomplish the function of securing the hair extension <b>220</b> to the anchor <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The processed hair <b>240</b> is attached to the grid mesh <b>225</b> and represents the ultimate purpose of the disclosed subject matter. The processed hair <b>240</b> may comprise synthetic hair that is manufactured or natural hair that once grew on an individual. In many cases, the individual may select the processed hair <b>240</b> such that it seamlessly blends with their own natural hair. The processed hair <b>240</b> may come in a variety of colors, lengths, and retain various properties that control how the processed hair <b>240</b> responds to optional styling, washing, and treatment.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Multiple anchors <b>100</b> may be installed on a single individual, whereby a separate hair extension <b>220</b> can be separately secured to each anchor <b>100</b>. In cases where multiple anchors <b>100</b> are attached to an individual, the multiple anchors <b>100</b> need not be the same lengths or have the same numbers of buttons. In various embodiments not shown in the figures, two or more hair extensions <b>220</b> may be secured to a single anchor <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Hair extension <b>220</b> may comprise different hair styles, such as straight, wavy, or curly hair. Hair extension <b>220</b> may also comprise different lengths and colors. Further, the hair extension <b>220</b> can be treated, for example highlighted or balayage. Thus, the interchangeable functionality of the disclosed hair extension system allows a user to wear different hairstyles on a daily basis without having to change their own natural hair. This may include the installation of a plurality of hair extensions <b>220</b> on a user's head. Another advantage of the disclosed hair extension system is that it allows the user to install the hair extensions upside-down in order to wear their hair high up on their head. With conventional hair extension systems, users cannot wear their hair high up on their head because the hair extension base will be visible (i.e. exposed) and/or because the installation method or hair extension type does not allow the hair to be pulled up to a sufficient height on the head.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a flow diagram of a process <b>350</b> for installing a disclosed hair extension system. The process <b>350</b> can be used to attach one or more hair extensions <b>220</b> to an individual. Once the hair extensions <b>220</b> are attached, the hair extensions <b>220</b> may be removed while the anchor <b>100</b> remains, which makes for easy replacement of the same or different hair extension <b>220</b>. The process <b>350</b> may be performed by a trained hair stylist, an amateur stylist, or the individual may perform the process <b>350</b> themselves. In all cases, the person performing the process <b>350</b> herein is referred to as the &#x201c;stylist.&#x201d;</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">At step <b>351</b>, the stylist may thread portions of natural hair through a first mesh. An embodiment of the first mesh is the grid mesh <b>105</b> that is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>. As already stated, the natural hair is hair that is attached and growing from follicles in the scalp of the individual. In various embodiments, the natural hair may be bundled into a portion such that the cross section of a tip of the bundle is less than the cross section of an opening <b>115</b> in the first mesh. The tip of the bundle is accordingly threaded through the opening <b>115</b>. A strength by which the anchor is held is limited by the amount of natural hair that is threaded through the openings <b>115</b> in the first mesh. Ideally, to maximize the strength that the anchor <b>100</b> can be secured to the scalp, a portion of the natural hair is threaded through each opening <b>115</b> in the first mesh.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">At step <b>352</b>, the stylist may position the first mesh against the scalp of an individual. The stylist may pull the threaded portions of natural hair through the openings <b>115</b> until the first mesh is pressed against the scalp of the individual. Invariably, the natural hair grows over time causing the first mesh to loosen from the individual's scalp. In such cases, the stylist may easily reposition the first mesh by further pulling the portions of natural hair through the openings <b>115</b> until the first mesh is once again pressing against the scalp.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">At step <b>353</b>, the stylist may fix the first mesh to the portions of natural hair of the individual. In various embodiments, the portions of natural hair may be secured by fixing elements such as hair extension beads, which are widely available. A separate hair extension bead may be threaded over each individual portion of natural hair that has been threaded through an opening <b>115</b> in step <b>352</b> of the process <b>350</b>. Each hair extension bead is threaded along the portion of natural hair until the hair extension bead is pressed against the opening <b>115</b> of the first mesh. The hair extension bead must be larger than the opening <b>115</b>, or else it could go through the opening <b>115</b> and would fail to secure the anchor <b>100</b> to the scalp. Once the hair extension bead is in place, hair extension pliers may be used to clamp the hair extension bead to the portion of natural hair. The flattened fixing element is positioned against the mesh and is larger than, and cannot pass through, the openings in the mesh. Accordingly, the clamped hair extension bead prevents the first mesh from moving past the position of the hair extension bead along the portion of natural hair. Thus, the first mesh is fastened or locked in place between the hair extension bead (fixing element) and the scalp of the individual.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">At step <b>354</b>, the stylist may fasten, with the snap buttons, a second mesh to the first mesh. The second mesh may comprise the grid mesh <b>225</b> of the hair extension <b>220</b>. A first portion of the snap buttons may be attached to the first mesh and a second portion of the snap buttons may be attached to the second mesh. Accordingly, the second mesh may be snapped into the first mesh. In an exemplary embodiment, the stylist may fasten the hair extension <b>220</b> to the anchor <b>100</b> by aligning the buttons on the anchor with the buttons of the hair extension <b>220</b> and pressing on the back of each button of the hair extension with enough force to cause the cap of each button to penetrate the socket of the oppositely aligned button and thereby engage with it, again without clamping any natural hair.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Similarly, the stylist may unfasten the hair extension <b>220</b> from the anchor <b>100</b> by pulling the hair extension <b>220</b> from a portion in close proximity to each of the buttons, thus unsnapping each button in succession. The hair extension <b>220</b> may be fastened and unfastened any number of times until a part of the hair extension system wears out or the anchor <b>100</b> loosens from the scalp of the individual. Further, the stylist may fasten a third mesh that comprises a second hair extension to the first mesh after the second mesh is unfastened. Regardless of the number of added hair extensions and/or meshes, the activity of button snapping does not cause the securing or clamping of natural hair through or between any of the buttons.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is another illustration of a hair extension <b>420</b> that may be installed in an embodiment of the disclosed hair extension system. As already disclosed, the anchor <b>100</b> and the hair extension <b>420</b> may comprise a variety of lengths which can be made to accommodate a multitude of styles and head sizes depending on the needs of the individual. Often, an individual may require multiple hair extensions to be worn simultaneously. Each of the simultaneously worn hair extensions need not be the same size, have the same processed hair length, or even have the same processed hair color.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Like the hair extension <b>220</b> that is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the hair extension <b>420</b> includes a grid mesh <b>425</b> that has attached to it a multitude of second portion snap buttons <b>430</b>, which are regularly spaced. Also attached to the grid mesh <b>425</b> is processed hair <b>440</b>. The grid mesh <b>425</b> may be made of interwoven strands of inert material with regular gaps <b>426</b> in between the interwoven strands. The hair extension <b>420</b> could be worn for an extended period of time, thus the gaps <b>426</b> allow underlying skin access to air and water. The gaps <b>426</b> reduce the incidence of trapped particles under the grid mesh <b>425</b>. Conveniently, the hair extension <b>420</b> can just as easily be removed during strenuous activity or treatment of natural hair and quickly buttoned back onto the installed anchor <b>100</b> as needed, or simply stored and replaced on the anchor later to further extend the lifespan of the processed hair.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The hair extension <b>420</b> may be snapped into an anchor <b>100</b> that is fixed to the scalp of an individual. Ideally, the anchor <b>100</b> will include the same number of buttons <b>110</b> as the hair extension <b>420</b> whereby the buttons <b>110</b> on the anchor <b>100</b> and the buttons <b>430</b> on the hair extension <b>420</b> are perfectly aligned. In various embodiments, one anchor <b>100</b> may be fixed to multiple hair extensions. And although not ideal, a single hair extension <b>420</b> may be snapped into multiple anchors <b>100</b>. However, in the case where one hair extension <b>420</b> is paired with more than one anchor <b>100</b>, great care must be taken to position the anchors <b>100</b> such that spacing between buttons <b>430</b> is in perfect alignment.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, an illustration shows a portion of natural hair <b>560</b> that is threaded through one of the openings <b>515</b> in the anchor <b>500</b>. The anchor <b>500</b> is configured to be secured to the scalp by portions of natural hair <b>560</b> that are threaded through each of the openings <b>515</b>. Once the natural hair <b>560</b> is threaded through each opening <b>515</b>, the natural hair <b>560</b> is pulled through the opening until the anchor <b>500</b> is pressed against the scalp of the individual.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">In the exemplary embodiment that is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, there are six openings <b>515</b>, two of which are on the ends of the anchor <b>500</b>, while four openings <b>515</b> are interspaced between the ends. The multitude of buttons <b>510</b> are positioned in between each of the openings <b>515</b>. The anchor <b>500</b> should be secured to the scalp of the individual before snapping hair extensions to the anchor <b>500</b> as the hair extensions would block a stylist from threading the natural hair <b>560</b> through the openings <b>515</b>. Again, the anchor <b>500</b> have processed hair or hair extensions already attached to it.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">Once the natural hair <b>560</b> is pulled through such that the anchor <b>500</b> is next to the scalp, a fixing element may be used to clamp the natural hair <b>560</b> to prevent the anchor <b>500</b> from moving away from the scalp. In various embodiments, hair extension beads are used to clamp the natural hair <b>560</b> and secure the anchor <b>500</b> to the scalp. The hair extension beads should be positioned such that each portion of natural hair <b>560</b> is threaded through the hair extension beads after the portion of natural hair <b>560</b> is threaded through the opening. After the portion of natural hair <b>560</b> is pulled all the way through the opening <b>515</b> and the anchor <b>500</b> is positioned against the scalp, the same portion of natural hair <b>560</b> is pulled through the hair extension bead until the hair extension bead is touching the grid mesh of the anchor <b>500</b>. Pliers, which are shaped to manipulate the hair extension beads, may be used to clamp the hair extension beads when they are in place. A hair extension bead or other fixing element should be applied to each portion of natural hair <b>560</b> that is threaded through the openings <b>515</b> in the anchor <b>500</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>, an illustration shows an anchor <b>600</b> that is installed on a scalp <b>665</b> of an individual in an embodiment of the disclosed hair extension system. An installed anchor <b>600</b> is a base for which hair extensions can be easily secured. The anchor <b>600</b> comprises a grid mesh, which is flexible and conforms to the scalp <b>665</b> of the individual. As shown in the illustration, portions of natural hair <b>660</b> are threaded through each of the six openings in the anchor <b>600</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">The portions of natural hair <b>660</b> are each secured by a fixing element <b>670</b>. The fixing element <b>670</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is a hair extension bead that has been clamped by hair extension pliers once the hair extension bead was positioned at the anchor <b>600</b>. The flattened fixing element (hair extension bead) is positioned against the anchor (grid mesh) and is larger than, and cannot pass through, the openings in the mesh. The hair extension beads effectively pin the anchor <b>600</b> against the scalp <b>665</b> of the individual. Various hair extensions may be snapped into the multitude of buttons <b>610</b> of the anchor <b>600</b>. The hair extensions may be snapped and unsnapped (i.e., attached and detached) any number of times. The individual may easily remove and reinstall hair extensions without professional help. The individual may, for instance, remove the hair extensions while taking part in physical activity and may subsequently quickly snap the hair extensions back in.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref>, an illustration shows another anchor <b>700</b> that is installed to a scalp <b>765</b> of an individual in an embodiment of the disclosed hair extension system. The anchor <b>700</b> includes nine first portions of buttons <b>710</b>, which may be snapped into second portions of the buttons that are secured to hair extensions. The anchor <b>700</b> is secured by the portions of natural hair <b>760</b> that are threaded through openings in the anchor <b>700</b>. The ends of the anchor <b>700</b>, which are not visible in this illustration, terminate in openings that are threaded with natural hair.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Each of the visible portions of natural hair <b>760</b> are clamped by hair extension beads <b>770</b>, which secure the anchor <b>700</b> to the scalp <b>765</b> of the individual. As shown in the illustration, the anchor <b>700</b> wraps around and conforms to the contours of the scalp <b>765</b>. In various embodiments, additional anchors may be positioned above and below the anchor <b>700</b> to provide for multiple hair extensions to be secured to the scalp <b>765</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref>, an illustration shows yet another anchor <b>800</b> that is installed to a scalp <b>865</b> of an individual in an embodiment of the disclosed hair extension system. The illustration shows the scalp <b>865</b> from a side view as the secured anchor <b>800</b> wraps around the back of the head. The fixing element <b>870</b> in the illustration is a hair extension bead that is clamped by pliers in a position that fixes the anchor <b>800</b> against the scalp <b>865</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">As the natural hair grows, the portions of natural hair <b>860</b> that are threaded through the openings in the anchor also grow and cause the anchor <b>800</b> to loosen. Accordingly, the fixing element <b>870</b> can be removed and the natural hair <b>860</b> pulled through the anchor <b>800</b> to fix the anchor <b>800</b> once again against the scalp <b>865</b>. New fixing elements <b>870</b> may be secured to the portions of natural hair <b>860</b> after the anchor <b>800</b> is repositioned. Thus, the anchor <b>800</b> may be repositioned against the scalp <b>865</b> after the anchor <b>800</b> loosens due to growing natural hair. Repositioning the anchor <b>800</b> is easily done as the stylist does not have to thread the portions of natural hair <b>860</b> through the openings again.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref>, an illustration shows a fixing element <b>970</b> being installed onto the portion of natural hair <b>960</b> that has been threaded through one of the openings <b>915</b> found in the first grid mesh <b>905</b>. Here, the anchor <b>900</b> (with an abridged length indicated by a break line) has already been pressed against the scalp of the individual, and the portion of natural hair <b>960</b> is positioned in line with the fixing element <b>970</b> such that the tip of the bundle of natural hair is facing an opening of the fixing element. The natural hair <b>960</b> should be pulled through the hollow fixing element <b>970</b>, and the fixing element moved along the natural hair toward the scalp, all the way to the grid mesh <b>905</b> of the anchor <b>900</b>, as indicated by motion arrow <b>990</b>. The fixing element <b>970</b> should finally be positioned so that it is touching the grid mesh <b>905</b> of the anchor <b>900</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">The fixing element <b>970</b> can consist of a cylindrical bead with a thickness comprising one or more layers of compressible material that can be deformed into a secondary shape with more rectangular dimensions, so that at least one of these dimensions shortens, causing the interior of the bead to make substantial contact with natural hair <b>960</b>. This heavy contact fixes both the bead <b>970</b> in place and the anchor <b>900</b> in place as a secondary consequence.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref>, an illustration shows a fixing element or bead <b>1070</b> being compressed, flattened, and secured in place via clamping with appropriately shaped pliers <b>1075</b>, or other similar fixing tool designed for this particular purpose, such that the bead <b>1070</b> is fastened to the natural hair <b>1060</b>. Once again, a break line indicates an abridged length of the anchor <b>1000</b>. With the previously threaded portion of natural hair <b>1060</b> pulled through the bead <b>1070</b> so that the bead is now touching the first grid mesh <b>1005</b>, the fixing tool, which can be shaped to manipulate the bead, may be used to clamp the bead into place. The flattened fixing element or bead <b>1070</b> possesses sufficient size in at least one dimension to exceed that of any dimension of the anchor's opening <b>1015</b>, so the installed bead is always touching the grid mesh <b>1005</b> and cannot be pulled loose from it under everyday circumstances. Thus, the contact made between bead <b>1070</b> and threaded natural hair <b>1060</b> is enough to prevent both movement of the bead and anchor <b>1000</b> away from the scalp, since one surface of the anchor is contacted by the individual's natural hair/scalp, and a second surface is contacted by the secured bead. As natural hair growth occurs, loosening and migration of the anchor <b>1000</b> will follow. At this point, a user or stylist can reposition both anchor <b>1000</b> and bead <b>1070</b> and secure these elements at the scalp area once again. The installed bead may be reshaped and clamped into place again, or an entirely new bead can be installed using the above techniques. A fixing element <b>1070</b> should be fastened to each portion of natural hair <b>1060</b> that is threaded through each opening <b>1015</b> in the anchor <b>1000</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b></figref>, an illustration shows an anchor <b>1100</b> that includes two parallel rows of first portion snap buttons <b>1110</b> on its first grid-based mesh <b>1105</b>, placed in an alternating pattern with respect to the mesh openings <b>1115</b>, and having a first row <b>1180</b> and second row <b>1181</b>. In this example, the two parallel rows of first portion buttons <b>1110</b> are also positioned in an alternating pattern with respect to each other, such that the first row <b>1180</b> is vertically staggered relative to the second row <b>1181</b>. The first mesh <b>1105</b> itself does not have hair extensions or processed hair <b>1140</b> already attached to it. This example of an anchor <b>1100</b> allows for two different placement options of a hair extension <b>1120</b> on the head of an individual. It also allows for simultaneous attachment of two separate hair extensions, a first hair extension <b>1120</b> and a second hair extension <b>1135</b>, onto the single anchor <b>1100</b>. Once again, natural hair <b>1160</b> is shown threaded through a mesh opening <b>1115</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">In the illustrated example, two hair extensions are shown, including a first hair extension <b>1120</b> and a second hair extension <b>1135</b>. The first hair extension <b>1120</b> further comprises a second grid-based mesh <b>1125</b> formed by interwoven strands of inert material that form regular gaps or spaces <b>1126</b> between them. The second grid-based mesh <b>1125</b> further comprises two or more second portion snap buttons <b>1130</b> which are fixed to the second mesh <b>1125</b>, as well as hair extensions or processed hair <b>1140</b> which is also fixed to the second mesh <b>1125</b>. The second hair extension <b>1135</b> further comprises a third grid-based mesh <b>1136</b> formed by interwoven strands of inert material that form regular gaps or spaces <b>1137</b> between them. The third grid-based mesh <b>1136</b> further comprises two or more second portion snap buttons <b>1138</b> which are fixed to the third mesh <b>1136</b>, as well as hair extensions or processed hair <b>1141</b> which is also fixed to the third mesh <b>1136</b>. The first row <b>1180</b> of the first portions of the snap buttons <b>1110</b> aligns with the second portions of the snap buttons <b>1130</b> of the first hair extension <b>1120</b>, while the second row <b>1181</b> of the first portions of the snap buttons <b>1110</b> aligns with the second portions of the snap buttons <b>1138</b> of the second hair extension <b>1135</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">Both hair extensions <b>1120</b> and <b>1135</b> are shown in reversed positions relative to one another, highlighting the ability of an individual to install them in different rotated orientations relative to the first mesh <b>1105</b> of the anchor <b>1100</b>, including an upside-down orientation&#x2014;as indicated by the position of the second hair extension <b>1135</b>, which has its hair extensions or processed hair <b>1141</b> directed upward and away from both the first hair extension <b>1120</b> and the anchor <b>1100</b> with first grid mesh <b>1105</b>. Motion arrows <b>1195</b> indicate the mating of the first row <b>1180</b> of first portion buttons <b>1110</b> of the anchor <b>1100</b> and the second portion buttons <b>1130</b> of the first hair extension <b>1120</b>, such that the second portion buttons <b>1130</b> are snapped onto the first row <b>1180</b> of first portion buttons <b>1110</b>. Motion arrows <b>1196</b> indicate the mating of the second row <b>1181</b> of first portion buttons <b>1110</b> of the anchor <b>1100</b> and the second portion buttons <b>1138</b> of the second hair extension <b>1135</b>, such that the second portion buttons <b>1138</b> are snapped onto the second row <b>1181</b> of first portion buttons <b>1110</b>. Thus, the second mesh <b>1125</b> and third mesh <b>1136</b> are attachable to the first mesh <b>1105</b> via the mating of the first portion buttons <b>1110</b> and second portion buttons <b>1130</b> and <b>1138</b> after natural hair <b>1160</b> has been threaded through the mesh openings <b>1115</b> of the first mesh <b>1105</b>. The natural hair <b>1160</b> is not clamped between the first portion buttons <b>1110</b> and second portion buttons <b>1130</b> and <b>1138</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">Many variations may be made to the embodiments described herein. All variations are intended to be included within the scope of this disclosure. The description of the embodiments herein can be practiced in many ways. Any terminology used herein should not be construed as restricting the features or aspects of the disclosed subject matter. The scope should instead be construed in accordance with the appended claims.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">There may be many other ways to implement the disclosed embodiments. Various functions and elements described herein may be partitioned differently from those shown without departing from the scope of the disclosed embodiments. Various modifications to these implementations may be readily apparent to those skilled in the art, and generic principles defined herein may be applied to other implementations. Thus, many changes and modifications may be made to the disclosed embodiments, by one having ordinary skill in the art, without departing from the scope of the disclosed embodiments. For instance, different numbers of a given element or module may be employed, a different type or types of a given element or module may be employed, a given element or module may be added, or a given element or module may be omitted.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">It should be appreciated that all combinations of the foregoing concepts and additional concepts discussed in greater detail below (provided such concepts are not mutually inconsistent) are contemplated as being part of the inventive subject matter disclosed herein. In particular, all combinations of claimed subject matter appearing at the end of this disclosure are contemplated as being part of the inventive subject matter disclosed herein.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A method for attaching a hair extension to natural hair of an individual, the method comprising:
<claim-text>threading portions of natural hair through a first mesh and a fixing element;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first mesh comprising:
<claim-text>a first grid-based mesh;</claim-text>
<claim-text>two or more openings in the first grid-based mesh, the openings configured for the threading of natural hair of an individual through said openings;</claim-text>
<claim-text>two or more first portions of snap buttons fixed to the first grid-based mesh; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the portions of natural hair are threaded through the two or more openings in the first grid-based mesh;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>positioning the first mesh against a scalp of an individual;</claim-text>
<claim-text>positioning the fixing element against the first mesh;</claim-text>
<claim-text>fixing the first mesh to the portions of natural hair, and to the scalp of the individual, by compressing the fixing element such that it flattens and becomes fastened to the natural hair, wherein the flattened fixing element is larger than, and cannot pass through, the openings;</claim-text>
<claim-text>fastening, with the snap buttons, a second mesh to the first mesh;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second mesh comprising:
<claim-text>a second grid-based mesh;</claim-text>
<claim-text>hair extensions fixed to the second grid-based mesh;</claim-text>
<claim-text>two or more second portions of the snap buttons fixed to the second grid-based mesh; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first portions of the snap buttons align with the second portions of the snap buttons.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising adjusting a position of the first mesh after the natural hair of the individual has grown out, the adjusting comprising:
<claim-text>unfixing the first mesh from the portions of natural hair of the individual;</claim-text>
<claim-text>positioning the first mesh against the scalp of the individual by pulling the portion of natural hair through the two or more openings in the first mesh; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>fixing the first mesh to the portions of natural hair of the individual.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first mesh comprises interwoven strands of inert material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the first mesh further comprises regular spaces in between the strands of inert material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the two or more openings are larger than the regular spaces.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the second mesh comprises interwoven strands of inert material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising unfastening the second mesh from the first mesh; and
<claim-text>fastening, with the snap buttons, a third mesh to the first mesh;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the third mesh comprising:
<claim-text>a third grid-based mesh;</claim-text>
<claim-text>hair extensions fixed to the third grid-based mesh;</claim-text>
<claim-text>two or more second portions of the snap buttons fixed to the third grid-based mesh; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first portions of the snap buttons align with the second portions of the snap buttons.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. A hair extension system, the hair extension system comprising:
<claim-text>a first mesh, the first mesh comprising:
<claim-text>a first grid-based mesh having no hair extensions attached hereto;</claim-text>
<claim-text>two or more openings in the first grid-based mesh, each of the openings configured for the threading of natural hair of an individual through said openings; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>two or more first portions of snap buttons fixed to the first grid-based mesh wherein the openings and the first portions of the snap buttons are positioned on the first mesh in an alternating pattern, wherein the first portions of snap buttons are arranged in a first row and a second row that are parallel to one another;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second mesh, the second mesh comprising:
<claim-text>a second grid-based mesh;</claim-text>
<claim-text>hair extensions fixed to the second grid-based mesh;</claim-text>
<claim-text>two or more second portions of the snap buttons fixed to the second grid-based mesh; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first row of the first portions of the snap buttons aligns with the second portions of the snap buttons;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third mesh, the third mesh comprising:
<claim-text>a third grid-based mesh;</claim-text>
<claim-text>hair extensions fixed to the third grid-based mesh;</claim-text>
<claim-text>two or more second portions of the snap buttons fixed to the third grid-based mesh; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second row of the first portions of the snap buttons aligns with the second portions of the snap buttons;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second mesh and third mesh are attachable to the first mesh via mating of the first and second portions of the snap buttons, and wherein the natural hair is not clamped between the snap buttons.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The hair extension system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, further comprising a fixing element that fastens natural hair, which is threaded through at least one of the two or more openings, to the first mesh.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The hair extension system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the first mesh comprises interwoven strands of inert material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The hair extension system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the first mesh further comprises regular spaces in between the strands of inert material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The hair extension system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the two or more openings are larger than the regular spaces.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. The hair extension system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the second mesh comprises:
<claim-text>interwoven strands of inert material; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>regular spaces in between the strands of inert material.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The hair extension system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the first row of the first portions of snap buttons are vertically staggered relative to the second row of the first portions of the snap buttons.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. A hair extension system, the hair extension system comprising:
<claim-text>an anchor that is fixable to a scalp of an individual, the anchor comprising:
<claim-text>a grid-based mesh formed by interwoven strands of inert material;</claim-text>
<claim-text>two or more openings in the grid-based mesh, each of the openings having a perimeter edge formed by the inert material and configured for the threading of natural hair of an individual through said openings; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>two or more first portions of snap buttons fixed to the grid-based mesh;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the anchor has no hair extensions attached thereto;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fixing element that is in contact with the grid-based mesh and that fastens natural hair, which is threaded through at least one of the two or more openings and the fixing element, to the anchor, wherein the natural hair is not clamped between the snap buttons, and wherein the fixing element is larger than, and cannot pass through, the openings.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. The hair extension system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, further comprising a first hair extension, the first hair extension comprising:
<claim-text>hair attached to a strip of material;</claim-text>
<claim-text>two or more second portions of the snap buttons fixed to the strip of material; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first portions of the snap buttons align with the second portions of the snap buttons.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. The hair extension system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, further comprising a second hair extension, the second hair extension comprising:
<claim-text>hair attached to a strip of material;</claim-text>
<claim-text>two or more second portions of the snap buttons fixed to the strip of material;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first portions of the snap buttons align with the second portions of the snap buttons;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first hair extension and second hair extension are attachable to the anchor; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first hair extension and second hair extension are interchangeably attachable to the anchor while the anchor is fixed to the scalp of the individual.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. The hair extension system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the first portions of snap buttons are arranged in a first row and a second row that are parallel to one another, and wherein the first row of the first portions of snap buttons are vertically staggered relative to the second row of the first portions of the snap buttons.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. The hair extension system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the grid-based mesh further comprises regular spaces in between the strands of inert material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. The hair extension system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the two or more openings are larger than the regular spaces.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
