<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225502A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230711" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225502</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18092283</doc-number>
<date>20221231</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>13</main-group>
<subgroup>08</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>11</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>13</main-group>
<subgroup>08</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>11</main-group>
<subgroup>006</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>2200</main-group>
<subgroup>0001</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>2200</main-group>
<subgroup>0084</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>2220</main-group>
<subgroup>0091</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="dlmiy0cpdgk5y">Energy efficient outdoor heating device</invention-title>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>63300917</doc-number>
<date>20220119</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Eagle Design LLC</orgname>
<address>
<city>Falls Church</city>
<state>VA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Adler</last-name>
<first-name>Kenneth J</first-name>
<address>
<city>Falls Church</city>
<state>VA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Embodiments herein disclose a device for people to stay warm outdoors. A preferred embodiment comprises a heating device and method for warming people who are sitting outdoors using a table, a heater located under the table, and a blanket that encircles the tabletop, and has an inner edge that is removably secured to the tabletop. The heater includes a supply line and a regulator to control the quantity of fuel to the heater. The embodiment includes a blanket support that encircles and is attached to the table. When the device is not in use, the blanket can be stored in the blanket support. The opening in the middle of the blanket approximates the perimeter of the tabletop. People sit in chairs around the table, pick up the blanket from the blanket support and place the outer portion of the blanket on their laps.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="121.07mm" wi="198.04mm" file="US20230225502A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="188.81mm" wi="117.60mm" file="US20230225502A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="205.91mm" wi="137.58mm" file="US20230225502A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="179.83mm" wi="153.50mm" file="US20230225502A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="182.80mm" wi="138.01mm" file="US20230225502A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="183.47mm" wi="141.39mm" file="US20230225502A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="149.18mm" wi="159.17mm" file="US20230225502A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading level="1" id="h-0001">FIELD OF INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention pertains to the field of outdoor accessories, and more specifically to the field of outdoor heaters.</p>
<heading level="1" id="h-0002">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The objective of this invention is to provide a device for people to stay warm outdoors. Another objective of this invention is to reduce the amount of fuel used and greenhouse gas emissions emitted in comparison to existing outdoor heaters and fire pits.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading level="1" id="h-0003">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The invention will now be described in more detail, by way of examples which in no way are meant to limit the scope of the invention, but, rather, these examples will serve to illustrate the invention with reference to the accompanying drawings, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a perspective view of invention, according to an embodiment herein;</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is an isolated view of the table, glass tabletop, blanket clips, and the blanket covering lap of one person sitting in a chair, according to an embodiment herein;</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a perspective view of the glass tabletop, blanket clips, and &#x201c;U&#x201d; shaped blanket support that cradles the blanket, according to an embodiment herein;</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is a perspective view of another embodiment of the frame and a half-torus shaped blanket support, according to an embodiment herein;</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is a side view of another embodiment of the invention with details of the firebox, according to an embodiment herein; and</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is a top view of another embodiment of the invention with details of the firebox, according to an embodiment herein.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading level="1" id="h-0004">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The embodiments herein and the various features and advantageous details thereof are explained more fully with reference to the non-limiting embodiments that are illustrated in the accompanying drawings and detailed in the following description. Descriptions of well-known components and processing techniques are omitted to not unnecessarily obscure the embodiments herein. The examples used herein are intended merely to facilitate an understanding of ways in which the embodiments herein may be practiced and to further enable those of skill in the art to practice the embodiments herein. Accordingly, the examples should not be construed as limiting the scope of the embodiments herein.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">This invention comprises a new heating device and method for warming people who are sitting outdoors. The invention (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> and <b>3</b></figref>) comprises a table <b>21</b>, a heater <b>22</b> located under the table, and a blanket <b>1</b> that encircles the tabletop <b>3</b>, and has an inner edge that is removably secured to the tabletop. The heater <b>22</b> includes a supply line <b>11</b> and a regulator <b>27</b> to control the quantity of fuel to the heater. The tabletop <b>3</b> can be made from glass so that a gas flame or electric light can be displayed. The invention includes a blanket support <b>9</b> that encircles and is attached to said table <b>21</b>. When the device is not in use, the blanket <b>1</b> is stored in the blanket support <b>9</b>. The opening in the middle of the blanket <b>1</b> approximates the perimeter of the tabletop <b>3</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> and <b>2</b></figref>, people sit in chairs <b>4</b> around the table <b>21</b>, pick up the blanket <b>1</b> from the blanket support <b>9</b> and place the outer portion of the blanket on their laps. Warm air from the heater <b>22</b> is trapped under the blanket <b>1</b> and warms the people sitting around the table. Warm air travels from under the stretched-out blanket to users laps and under the blanket <b>1</b> and chair <b>4</b> to warm the air all around the people as shown by flow of hot air <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In one embodiment, the table <b>21</b> is similar in size and shape to a typical round or rectangular coffee table and can include a glass tabletop, which would allow an electric light to be displayed under the table <b>21</b>. Alternatively, the glow and flames of a gas heater could be displayed. Radiant heat can also be emitted through the glass tabletop <b>3</b> to warm users. The heated tabletop may also be used to keep food and drink warm. In one embodiment, the glass tabletop is made from heat resistant glass and may include a coating to reflect the heat downward, while still transmitting the light from the flames or electric lights. A second tabletop may be added on top of the first, with an air gap between, to provide a second tabletop that is insulated from the heat to prevent a burn hazard. A screen mesh could also be attached with screws and spacers above the glass tabletop to prevent accidental burns. A noncombustible surface, such as tiles or metal, may extend outward from the edge of the glass tabletop. A fan may be positioned to blow cooler air on the tabletop to keep it from overheating. The tabletop may also include a vent that is automatically opened using a heat sensitive piston that expands a hinge to open the vent when the heat under the table exceeds a certain temperature. In another embodiment, the tabletop vent may also be opened manually. The tabletop can be supported by a multiplicity of legs <b>8</b> or other traditional table bases. Both the tabletop <b>3</b> and legs <b>8</b> are manufactured from heat resistant materials such as heat resistant glass or metal.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In another embodiment, the device can accommodate just one or two people sitting across from each other. In this embodiment, the table is just large enough to accommodate a small heater. A small version of the device has the advantage that it can use a traditional sized blanket and does not need a custom blanket made. In addition, a small version could be operated in smaller locations like a small balcony of an apartment building.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The heater <b>22</b> can be powered with either electricity or gas, such as propane or natural gas, or wood. In one embodiment, shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, the heater includes, but is not limited to, a gas burner <b>6</b>, gas line <b>11</b>, regulator <b>27</b> and a firebox <b>17</b> that is open on the top. In another embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>5</b> and <b>6</b></figref>, a gas fueled heater <b>22</b> has a firebox <b>17</b>, a tabletop <b>3</b> substantially sealed to the firebox, and a multiplicity of vents <b>15</b> below the tabletop that vent the hot air in an outwardly direction toward the people sitting around the heater. The firebox includes a gas burner <b>6</b> that provides a flame and heat source to generate hot air that exits through said openings. The firebox <b>17</b> may also include inlet vents <b>14</b> to allow air into the firebox <b>17</b>. The firebox also includes side walls <b>18</b> and a bottom wall <b>19</b>. In one embodiment, the firebox <b>17</b> has outlets <b>15</b> that include a catalyst <b>13</b> through which the hot exhaust gases flow, as shown by the flow path <b>16</b>, wherein the gases are catalyzed to remove some or all the harmful pollutants including carbon monoxide.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The heater <b>22</b> may include a fan located in a hole in the tabletop <b>3</b>, and connected to said tabletop with screws, to propel the air from above the tabletop outwards under the blanket <b>1</b>. The heater may also include a thermostat, located under the tabletop, and connected with screws to said tabletop, to regulate the temperature. A gas heater could also include an electronic ignition system <b>7</b>, a regulator to control the flow of gas, and safety features like oxygen and carbon monoxide sensors. The hot air from a gas heater may also be vented through a catalytic converter <b>13</b> to reduce emissions of harmful gas components. A gas heater <b>22</b> may also include an exhaust stack to release combustion gases away from users. In one embodiment, the exhaust stack is located in a hole cut into the tabletop and connected to said tabletop with screws. In another embodiment, an electric heater may be combined with decorative artificial logs and flames. The heater may also include a deflector between it and the tabletop to direct the hottest air away from the tabletop so that the tabletop does not overheat. In one embodiment, the deflector is made of ceramic glass, so as not to block the display of fire, and is attached to crossbars <b>27</b>, shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, with screws located between the heater and the tabletop. The heater <b>22</b> may also include adjustable baffles connected to the heater frame on hinges that can be raised and lowered to direct the heated air to one side of the device. This would be used when, for example, only one person <b>5</b> is using the device and they do not want the heated air escaping where no one is sitting.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The invention includes a blanket <b>1</b> whose inner edge is removably attached to the tabletop <b>3</b>. The outer edge of the blanket <b>1</b> is placed on the laps of the people <b>5</b> who are sitting around the table, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> and <b>2</b></figref>. The blanket&#x2019;s size/radius and shape is determined by the size/shape of table <b>21</b> and the number of people who can be accommodated around the table. The blanket <b>1</b> can be large enough to cover a person&#x2019;s lap or can be larger to cover a person&#x2019;s shoulders. The blanket has an opening in the middle that approximates the perimeter of the table. In one embodiment, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, the blanket <b>1</b> is attached with fasteners <b>2</b> to the top of tabletop <b>3</b> near the tabletop&#x2019;s outer edge so that the inner edge of the blanket overlaps with the outer edge of the tabletop. The fasteners <b>2</b> may be in the form of spring-loaded clips that are attached to the tabletop. In another embodiment, the fasteners may include magnets placed around the rim of the tabletop and steel discs sewn into the blanket that align with the magnets and hold the blanket in place. Alternatively, the magnets may be sewn into the blanket and steel discs, or a steel edge or trim is placed around the tabletop. The blanket <b>1</b> can be made of a variety or combination of fabrics including cotton, wool, polyester, or flame-resistant cloth, and may be treated with chemicals to reduce flammability. In one embodiment, the blanket <b>1</b> may be made of a fabric with natural insulating properties or fabric fashioned into an insulating design, e.g., quilted, to help reduce heat loss as the heated air is traveling from the heater to the person. The blanket may be made of multiple types of fabrics. For example, the fabric closest to the heater may be made from heat resistant material, or the underside of fabric may be made of fabric that is easier to clean. In another embodiment, the blanket may include electric heating elements and a power cord, like an electric blanket, to provide additional warmth.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> and <b>2</b></figref>, one function of the blanket <b>1</b> and chair <b>4</b> is to channel the hot air, as shown by pathway <b>24</b>, from the heater <b>22</b> to the people sitting around the device. Another function of the blanket is to insulate the users from the cold air. The invention provides several ways to keep people warm including radiant and convection heat that directly warms user&#x2019;s legs and feet. Secondly, as shown by pathway <b>24</b>, heated air travels from under the blanket and chair to warm the user&#x2019;s arms, torso, back, shoulders and head. People can adjust the blanket to warm different parts of their body. For example, they can form an opening between the blanket and their laps so that the heated air is directed up the front of their body to provide additional warm air for their chest, arms, and face. Unlike other outdoor heating systems, the invention can warm all sides of the users while they are facing the heater.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The table <b>21</b> can include a compartment, platform, or other feature to physically attach the heater <b>22</b> to the table. In one embodiment, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> and6, the firebox <b>17</b> that contains the burner <b>6</b> may also be used to support the tabletop <b>3</b> and may include a multiplicity of legs <b>8</b> attached to the firebox to keep it off the ground.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The invention can include a &#x201c;U&#x201d; shaped blanket support <b>9</b> that encircles the table and is removably attached to said table, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>. The blanket <b>1</b> is stored in the blanket support <b>9</b> when not in use. These blanket supports <b>9</b> can hold the blanket until someone sits down in a chair <b>4</b> and pulls the blanket onto their laps.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The blanket support <b>9</b> can also act as a baffle to prevent or reduce the amount of heat escaping if no one is sitting on that side of the device. If people <b>5</b> are not sitting on one or more sides of the table <b>21</b>, the blanket <b>1</b> is left in the channel, and it helps conserve heat by fully or partially blocking the flow of heated air in the direction no one is sitting. The blanket support can also serve as a wind break for the burner <b>6</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In one embodiment, the bottom of the blanket support <b>9</b> can be a few inches off the ground so that cold air can still flow under the stored blanket <b>1</b>, which can help keep the device from overheating and provide a pathway for air to the firebox. The blanket support <b>9</b> can help keep the stored blanket <b>1</b> from getting dirty or wet when not in use. The blanket support <b>9</b> can also be integrated with a footrest. The table <b>21</b>, tabletop <b>3</b>, or blanket support <b>9</b> may also include fasteners <b>2</b> to help keep the blanket in place. The table <b>21</b> may also have a cover to keep the entire device clean and dry when not in use.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In one embodiment, the invention may also include a wind break around the heater <b>22</b> that can keep the flames from blowing out and help let the heater work more efficiently. The wind break can take the form of a vertical barrier that forms a cylindrical shape below the tabletop <b>3</b>. There is a gap between the top of the barrier and the tabletop <b>3</b> so that the heated air can flow out toward the people. There is another gap between the bottom of the wind break and the ground so that air can travel under the wind break. Another function is improving the heating efficiency by allowing cold air to travel under the barrier where it can be warmed by the heater and then the warm air, via convection, can be channeled to the people sitting around the device. The barrier could be made from fabric, sheet metal, or brick pavers. In one embodiment, a fabric curtain is hung on the tabletop <b>3</b> so that it encircles the heater and/or the table. In another embodiment, the barrier is made from brick pavers that can also serve as a footrest.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In one embodiment, cold air is drawn in through gaps under the circular barrier, the heater warms the cold air, and the warm air becomes less dense and rises along the blanket to heat the people sitting around the device. The use of convection allows the device to heat the air more efficiently, while also allowing the discharge of combustion gas.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The foregoing description of the specific embodiments will so fully reveal the general nature of the embodiments herein that others can, by applying current knowledge, readily modify and/or adapt for various applications such specific embodiments without departing from the generic concept, and, therefore, such adaptations and modifications should and are intended to be comprehended within the meaning and range of equivalents of the disclosed embodiments. It is to be understood that the phraseology or terminology employed herein is for the purpose of description and not of limitation. Therefore, while the embodiments herein have been described in terms of preferred embodiments, those skilled in the art will recognize that the embodiments herein can be practiced with modification within the spirit and scope of the claims as described herein.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A heating apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a table, the table further comprising: 
<claim-text>a tabletop and multiplicity of legs connected at one end to said tabletop,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a retention compartment for a heater under said tabletop,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a heater located in said retention compartment of said table,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a supply line for connecting said heater to a source of fuel,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a regulator for controlling quantity of fuel to said heater;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a blanket that encircles the tabletop, with an opening in the center that approximates the perimeter of the tabletop; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>fastening means to attach said blanket to said tabletop, allowing inner edge of said blanket to be fastened to outer edge of the tabletop.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The heating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, said table further comprising:
<claim-text>a second tabletop on top of the tabletop, with an air gap between the two tabletops,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second tabletop is insulated from heat generated by the heater to prevent burn hazard.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The heating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, said table further comprising a screen mesh connected above the tabletop with spacers and screws to prevent accidental burns, wherein the tabletop is made of heat resistant material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The heating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, said table further comprising a non-combustible surface extending outward from the edge of the tabletop.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The heating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the tabletop includes a vent to dissipate heat, when the heat under the table exceeds a certain temperature.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The heating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the tabletop and the multiplicity of legs are made of heat resistant glass.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The heating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the tabletop and the multiplicity of legs are made of heat resistant metal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The heating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, the heater further comprises 
<claim-text>a firebox comprising:
<claim-text>a gas burner;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an ignitor; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a regulator to control flow of gas,</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>where the heater is gas powered and the supply line is a gas line.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The heating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the firebox has outlets that include a catalyst through which the hot exhaust gases flow to remove harmful pollutants, where the pollutants removed include at least carbon monoxide.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The heating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the ignitor is an electronic ignition system.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The heating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the heater further comprises a fan to propel hot air outwards with an on/off switch.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The heating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the heater further comprises a thermostat to regulate the temperature.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. The heating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the heater further comprises an exhaust stack to release combustion gases away from users.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The heating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the heater further comprises a deflector to direct hottest air away from the tabletop, where the deflector is made of transparent ceramic glass.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. The heating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the heater further comprises adjustable baffles to direct heated air to one side of the device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. The heating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the blanket attached with fasteners to the top of the tabletop&#x2019;s outer edge, so that inner edge of the blanket overlaps with the outer edge of the tabletop.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. The heating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the fasteners are spring-loaded clips attached to the tabletop.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. The heating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the fasteners are:
<claim-text>magnets placed along the outer edge of the tabletop, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>steel discs sewn into the blanket along the inner edge of the blanket, the steel discs aligning with the magnets and hold the blanket in place.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. The heating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the fasteners are:
<claim-text>steel discs placed along the outer edge of the tabletop, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>magnets sewn into the blanket along the inner edge of the blanket, the magnets aligning with the steel discs to hold the blanket in place.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. The heating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the blanket is made of one or more among the materials: cotton, wool, polyester, and flame-resistant cloth.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text><b>21</b>. The heating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00020">claim 20</claim-ref>, wherein the blanket is treated with chemicals to reduce flammability.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text><b>22</b>. The heating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the blanket is quilted to help reduce heat loss.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text><b>23</b>. The heating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the blanket is made of a combination of materials, where the portion closest to the heater is made from heat resistant material, and where portion facing ground is made of fabric that is easier to clean.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024" num="00024">
<claim-text><b>24</b>. The heating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, said heating apparatus further comprising:
<claim-text>a blanket support encircling the table and removably attached to the table, where the blanket support is shaped to hold the blanket when not in use.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025" num="00025">
<claim-text><b>25</b>. The heating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00024">claim 24</claim-ref>, wherein the blanket support further comprises one or more support arms that encircle the table.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026" num="00026">
<claim-text><b>26</b>. The heating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, said heating apparatus further comprising:
<claim-text>a windbreak around the heater to keep flames from blowing out and to increase heater efficiency.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027" num="00027">
<claim-text><b>27</b>. The heating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00026">claim 26</claim-ref>, wherein the windbreak is a cylindrical shaped vertical barrier below the tabletop.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028" num="00028">
<claim-text><b>28</b>. The heating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00027">claim 27</claim-ref>, wherein the barrier is made from one among:
<claim-text>fabric;</claim-text>
<claim-text>sheet metal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>brick pavers.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029" num="00029">
<claim-text><b>29</b>. The heating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00026">claim 26</claim-ref>, wherein there is a gap between the windbreak and the tabletop to allow heated air flow outwards.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030" num="00030">
<claim-text><b>30</b>. The heating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00026">claim 26</claim-ref>, wherein there is a gap between the bottom of the windbreak and the ground to allow air travel under the windbreak.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031" num="00031">
<claim-text><b>31</b>. A heating apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a table, the table further comprising: 
<claim-text>a tabletop,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a retention compartment for a heater under said tabletop,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a heater located in said retention compartment of said table, the heater and the tabletop supported by multiplicity of legs attached to one side to keep the heater off the ground,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a supply line for connecting said heater to a source of fuel,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a regulator for controlling quantity of fuel to said heater;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a blanket that encircles the tabletop, with an opening in the center that approximates the perimeter of the tabletop; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>fastening means to attach said blanket to said tabletop, allowing inner edge of said blanket to be fastened to outer edge of the tabletop.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032" num="00032">
<claim-text><b>32</b>. A gas-fueled heater, comprising:
<claim-text>a firebox having a multiplicity of outlets located below said tabletop;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a gas burner disposed within said firebox, said gas burner to provide a flame; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a catalyst element in communication with said multiplicity of firebox outlets, to catalyze at least some of the combustion products.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033" num="00033">
<claim-text><b>33</b>. A gas-fueled heater, comprising:
<claim-text>an outer shell including side panels, and a bottom panel;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a firebox being constructed and arranged with a primary combustion portion and a secondary combustion portion, said primary combustion portion including a gas burner, said secondary combustion portion including one or more catalytic converters, and said combustion chamber including a transparent top panel, side panels, and a base panel;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of air chambers disposed between said combustion chamber and said outer shell, each air chamber of said plurality being separated from and free of any flow communication with said combustion chamber and including side air chambers defined by the side panels of said combustion chamber and the side panels of said outer shell; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an air inlet for providing combustion air into said combustion chamber, a second air inlet for providing air into said plurality of air chambers, a multiplicity of air exhaust in communication with said secondary combustion portion and a multiplicity of air exhaust in flow communication with said top air chamber and exiting below said tabletop.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034" num="00034">
<claim-text><b>34</b>. An electric heater, comprising:
<claim-text>a firebox having a multiplicity of outlets located below a tabletop; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an electric heating element disposed within said firebox, said element providing heat when connected to a source of electricity.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
