<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225244A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230711" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225244</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17923279</doc-number>
<date>20210422</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>17</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>SE</country>
<doc-number>2050522-8</doc-number>
<date>20200507</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>34</main-group>
<subgroup>73</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>34</main-group>
<subgroup>733</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>34</main-group>
<subgroup>008</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="bykvlwoedrc3p">ROBOTIC LAWNMOWER CUTTER ASSEMBLY, ROBOTIC LAWNMOWER, AND METHOD OF ATTACHING A LAWNMOWER CUTTER ASSEMBLY TO A LAWNMOWER</invention-title>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>HUSQVARNA AB</orgname>
<address>
<city>Huskvana</city>
<country>SE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>SE</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Larsson</last-name>
<first-name>Svante</first-name>
<address>
<city>Eksj&#xf6;</city>
<country>SE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="01" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Danling</last-name>
<first-name>Anders</first-name>
<address>
<city>Bankeryd</city>
<country>SE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="02" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Svensson</last-name>
<first-name>Mats</first-name>
<address>
<city>Huskvarna</city>
<country>SE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="03" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ekdahl</last-name>
<first-name>Albin</first-name>
<address>
<city>Huskvarna</city>
<country>SE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="04" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Olsen</last-name>
<first-name>Ronny</first-name>
<address>
<city>N&#xe4;ssj&#xf6;</city>
<country>SE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="05" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Swalbring</last-name>
<first-name>Johan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Forserum</city>
<country>SE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/SE2021/050367</doc-number>
<date>20210422</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c12-date><date>20221104</date></us-371c12-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A lawnmower cutter assembly (<b>22</b>) comprises a knife carrier arrangement (<b>26</b>) and a skid plate arrangement (<b>30</b>), which are axially held between an axial stop shoulder (<b>60</b>) of the cutter drive shaft (<b>34</b>) and an end piece (<b>54</b>) rigidly connected to the cutter drive shaft (<b>34</b>), the end piece (<b>54</b>) thereby vertically carrying the skid plate arrangement (<b>30</b>) and the knife carrier arrangement (<b>26</b>). The cutter assembly (<b>22</b>) may be attached to a lawnmower, which may be a robotic lawnmower, by positioning the knife carrier arrangement (<b>26</b>) and the skid plate arrangement (<b>30</b>) on the cutter drive shaft (<b>34</b>); and thereafter, axially locking the axial position of the knife carrier arrangement (<b>26</b>) and the skid plate arrangement (<b>30</b>) in relation to the cutter drive shaft (<b>34</b>).</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="150.88mm" wi="178.31mm" file="US20230225244A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="225.13mm" wi="175.34mm" file="US20230225244A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="247.40mm" wi="171.45mm" file="US20230225244A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="224.37mm" wi="156.04mm" file="US20230225244A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="253.83mm" wi="167.81mm" file="US20230225244A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="257.13mm" wi="163.83mm" file="US20230225244A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="239.27mm" wi="166.62mm" file="US20230225244A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="234.70mm" wi="141.39mm" file="US20230225244A1-20230720-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading level="1" id="h-0001">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention relates to a lawnmower cutter assembly, to a robotic lawnmower comprising such a lawnmower cutter assembly, and to a method of attaching a lawnmower cutter assembly to a lawnmower.</p>
<heading level="1" id="h-0002">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Since their introduction on the market, robotic lawnmowers have facilitated lawn maintenance considerably. However, even though robotic lawnmowers facilitate mowing the lawn, like most equipment, they still require some care and maintenance, and may generate some cost during the lifespan of the robotic lawnmower. By way of example, grass cutting knives may require occasional resharpening or replacement. Moreover, robotic lawnmowers consume energy, and keeping energy consumption low may keep operating cost down, and/or enable the robotic lawnmower to treat a relatively larger work area. WO2015165506A1 discloses an energy-efficient robotic lawnmower provided with a cutter assembly configured to carry grass cutting knives. A skid plate keeps friction losses in the engagement between the cutter assembly and the grass low. There is however a need for a robotic lawnmower which may even further reduce the cost of operation. This may be particularly important for large installations, which may involve large areas to be treated, high-capacity robotic lawnmowers, and/or installations comprising more than one robotic lawnmower.</p>
<heading level="1" id="h-0003">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">It is an object of the present invention to solve, or at least mitigate, parts or all of the above mentioned problems. To this end, there is provided a lawnmower cutter assembly adapted to move one or several grass cutting knives in a cutting plane to cut grass, comprising: a knife carrier arrangement configured to carry one or several grass cutting knives, the knife carrier arrangement configured to be rotated about a cutter rotation axis by a cutter drive shaft; a skid plate arrangement comprising a skid plate suspended, when in use, below the knife carrier arrangement, the skid plate arrangement being rotatably connected to the knife carrier arrangement to enable rotation of the knife carrier arrangement in relation to the skid plate about the cutter rotation axis, wherein the skid plate arrangement and the knife carrier arrangement are configured to be axially held, when in use, between an axial stop shoulder of the cutter drive shaft and an end piece rigidly connected to the cutter drive shaft, the end piece thereby vertically carrying the skid plate arrangement and the knife carrier arrangement. Thereby, removal of the end piece may axially release both the knife carrier arrangement and the skid plate arrangement, allowing them both to be removed in a single operation, which facilitates service. The skid plate may be circular. According to embodiments, the skid plate may be flat; for example, it may be cut from a single piece of sheet metal. The skid plate may typically be shaped to cover the knife carrier arrangement from below in such a manner that the knife carrier arrangement does not substantially engage with the grass to be cut, whereas the knives carried by the knife carrier arrangement extend radially beyond the skid plate. The lawnmower cutter assembly may be attached to a wheeled lawnmower, which may be of self-propelled type or configured to be pushed by an operator. The end piece may be removably attached to the cutter drive shaft.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">According to embodiments, the lawnmower cutter assembly may be configured to be axially clamped against the axial stop shoulder by the end piece. Thereby, a firm and precise positioning of the skid plate arrangement and the knife carrier arrangement may be ascertained. According to embodiments, the knife carrier arrangement and/or any bearing arrangement of the lawnmower cutter assembly may be configured to be vertically clamped between the end piece and the axial stop shoulder, whereas the skid plate arrangement may be axially locked to the knife carrier arrangement, for example via a bearing arrangement.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">According to embodiments, the end piece may be concentric with the cutter rotation axis. Such an embodiment is particularly well suited for an arrangement comprising only one single end piece.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">According to embodiments, the knife carrier arrangement may have a keyed interface for rotationally locking the knife carrier arrangement to the cutter drive shaft. The keyed interface may comprise teeth facing axially, to mesh with mating, axially facing teeth of the cutter drive shaft, for example in a Hirth-type interface manner. Alternatively or additionally, the keyed interface may comprise teeth facing radially, such as splines. The keyed interface may have a functionally and/or geometrically uniform profile along the rotation axis, thereby enabling an adjustable axial position of the knife carrier arrangement on the cutter drive shaft, while rotationally locking the knife carrier to the cutter drive shaft.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">According to embodiments, the knife carrier arrangement may comprise a shaft socket configured to receive the cutter drive shaft.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">According to embodiments, the shaft socket may have a cross-section shaped to mate with a D-shaped cutter drive shaft.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">According to embodiments, the shaft socket may comprise an alignment section which tapers axially downwards. The tapering section may radially align the knife carrier arrangement to the cutter drive shaft when the knife carrier arrangement is pressed upwards, towards the cutter drive shaft.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">According to embodiments, the skid plate arrangement may be rotatably connected to the knife carrier arrangement via a bearing arrangement comprising at least one bearing having an inner race rotationally fixed to the cutter drive shaft, and an outer race rotationally fixed to the skid plate arrangement.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">According to embodiments, the inner race of the bearing may be clamped towards the axial stop shoulder by the end piece. The inner race of the bearing may be clamped either into direct abutment with the axial stop shoulder, or may be clamped against the axial stop shoulder via another axially rigid structure, such as the knife carrier arrangement. The bearing arrangement may comprise two coaxial bearings separated along the cutter rotation axis. The two coaxial bearings may be axially separated by a support sleeve.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">According to embodiments, the end piece may axially abut the bearing arrangement, and the bearing arrangement may axially abut the knife carrier arrangement.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">According to embodiments, the skid plate arrangement may comprise a bearing housing. The skid plate may be integrally formed with the bearing housing. Alternatively, it may be fixedly attached to the bearing housing, for example by means of screws.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">According to embodiments, the skid plate arrangement may comprise a skid plate clamp arrangement comprising a lower skid plate clamping element and an upper skid plate clamping element, which skid plate clamping elements clamp the skid plate between them.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">According to embodiments, the bearing housing may be integrally formed with the lower skid plate clamping element.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">According to embodiments, clamping screws may be screwed into the lower skid plate clamping element from above. Such an arrangement protects the clamping screws from dirt, and reduces the risk of erroneous disassembly of the lawnmower cutter assembly. The clamping screws may penetrate the upper skid plate clamping element to engage with the lower skid plate clamping element. Alternatively, screw heads of the clamping screws may themselves form the upper skid plate clamping elements.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">According to embodiments, at least one of the lower and upper skid plate clamping elements may define an end piece housing, and the lawnmower cutter assembly may further comprise an end piece lid movable between a closed position, in which it covers a lower side of the end piece housing, and an open position, in which it exposes the end piece for access from below. Thereby, the end piece may be protected from dirt, and still remain accessible via the end piece lid in the event it needs to be removed or manipulated. The end piece may be housed in the same housing as the bearing defined hereinabove. Hence, the end piece housing may also be a bearing housing.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">According to embodiments, the end piece lid may comprise a bayonet interface for connecting to a mating bayonet interface of the end piece housing, wherein a tangential, with regard to the cutter rotation axis, wall of the end piece housing is provided with at least one skid plate access aperture, and the skid plate may comprise a central aperture provided with at least one support tab extending radially inwards, through the skid plate access aperture, wherein the bayonet interface of the end piece lid is configured to, when the end piece lid is in the closed position, be axially supported by the support tab. Thereby, the skid plate will form part of the bayonet interface of the end piece housing. It may be preferable to make the skid plate of a relatively strong material, such as metal, for example aluminium plate. Thanks to the support tabs, the end piece housing need not be made of an equally strong material. According to the embodiments, the wall of the end piece housing may have several skid plate access apertures, and the skid plate may comprise several support tabs extending radially inwards through respective skid plate access apertures.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">According to embodiments, the upper skid plate clamping element may comprise a cover tab configured to abut and cover at least a portion of an upper face of the support tab. Thereby, the bayonet interface of the end piece lid may engage with the surface of the cover tab instead of the surface of the support tab. This may reduce wear on the bayonet interface of the end piece lid.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">According to embodiments, the end piece lid, when in the open position, may be connected to the skid plate arrangement via a flexible strap.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">According to embodiments, the axial position of the end piece, in relation to the cutter drive shaft, may be reconfigurable to enable the end piece to clamp the skid plate arrangement and the knife carrier arrangement against the axial stop shoulder. The axial position of the end piece may be reconfigurable by turning the end piece in a threaded engagement with the cutter drive shaft.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">According to embodiments, the end piece may be in threaded engagement with the cutter drive shaft.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">According to embodiments, the end piece may be configured to be axially held to the cutter drive shaft by a screw configured to engage with an inner thread of the cutter drive shaft. The end piece may be formed by a screw head integrally formed with the screw. In an alternative embodiment, the cutter drive shaft may be provided with an outer thread, and the end piece may be configured as a nut provided with an inner thread mating with the outer thread of the cutter drive shaft.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">According to embodiments, the knife carrier arrangement may have an internal thread, and the screw may be configured as an unlosable screw having a screw head, a threaded section mating with the internal thread of the knife carrier arrangement, and a reduced-width section between the screw head and the threaded section, the reduced-width section having a radial width inferior to the radial width of the threaded section. Thereby, the knife carrier arrangement may remain attached to the skid plate arrangement after having removed the two from the cutter drive shaft. The threaded section may be configured to mate with each of the internal thread of the cutter drive shaft and the internal thread of the knife carrier arrangement.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">According to a second aspect, parts or all of the above mentioned problems are solved, or at least mitigated, by a lawnmower cutter assembly adapted to move one or several grass cutting knives in a cutting plane to cut grass, and comprising: a knife carrier arrangement configured to carry one or several grass cutting knives, the knife carrier arrangement configured to be rotated about a cutter rotation axis by a cutter drive shaft; a skid plate arrangement comprising a skid plate suspended, when in use, below the knife carrier arrangement, the skid plate arrangement being rotatably connected to the knife carrier arrangement to enable rotation of the knife carrier arrangement in relation to the skid plate about the cutter rotation axis, wherein the skid plate arrangement and the knife carrier arrangement are configured to be axially held to the cutter drive shaft via one single fastener. Such an arrangement facilitates removing the knife carrier arrangement for servicing.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">According to a third aspect, parts or all of the above mentioned problems are solved, or at least mitigated, by a lawnmower cutter assembly adapted to move one or several grass cutting knives in a cutting plane to cut grass, and comprising: a knife carrier arrangement configured to carry one or several grass cutting knives, the knife carrier arrangement configured to be rotated about a cutter rotation axis by a cutter drive shaft; a skid plate arrangement comprising a skid plate suspended, when in use, below the knife carrier arrangement, the skid plate arrangement being rotatable relative to the knife carrier arrangement via a bearing, to enable rotation of the knife carrier arrangement in relation to the skid plate about the cutter rotation axis, the bearing being arranged in a bearing housing, wherein the skid plate arrangement comprises a skid plate clamp arrangement comprising a lower skid plate clamping element and an upper skid plate clamping element, which skid plate clamping elements clamp the skid plate between them, wherein the bearing housing is integrally formed with the lower skid plate clamping element. Such an arrangement reduces the height required by the lawnmower cutter assembly, thereby enabling obtaining an overall lower height of the lawnmower.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">According to a fourth aspect, parts or all of the above mentioned problems are solved, or at least mitigated, by a lawnmower cutter assembly adapted to move one or several grass cutting knives in a cutting plane to cut grass, comprising: a knife carrier arrangement configured to carry one or several grass cutting knives, the knife carrier arrangement configured to be rotated about a cutter rotation axis by a cutter drive shaft; a skid plate arrangement comprising a skid plate suspended, when in use, below the knife carrier arrangement, the skid plate arrangement being rotatably connected to the knife carrier arrangement to enable rotation of the knife carrier arrangement in relation to the skid plate about the cutter rotation axis, wherein the skid plate arrangement and the knife carrier arrangement are axially held together by an unlosable screw. Such an arrangement facilitates handling of the lawnmower cutter assembly, particularly when bringing multiple cutting assemblies of a fleet of multiple lawnmowers in for service. The unlosable screw may be configured to engage with an inner thread of the cutter drive shaft. The unlosable screw may have a screw head, a threaded section mating with an internal thread of at least one of the knife carrier arrangement and the skid plate arrangement, and a reduced-width section between the screw head and the threaded section, the reduced-width section having a radial width inferior to the radial width of the threaded section.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">According to a fifth aspect, parts or all of the above mentioned problems are solved, or at least mitigated, by a lawnmower cutter assembly adapted to move one or several grass cutting knives in a cutting plane to cut grass, comprising: a knife carrier arrangement configured to carry one or several grass cutting knives, the knife carrier arrangement configured to be rotated about a cutter rotation axis by a cutter drive shaft; a skid plate arrangement comprising a skid plate suspended, when in use, below the knife carrier arrangement, the skid plate arrangement being rotatable relative to the knife carrier arrangement via a bearing, to enable rotation of the knife carrier arrangement in relation to the skid plate about the cutter rotation axis, the bearing being arranged in a bearing housing; and a bearing housing lid movable between a closed position, in which it covers a lower side of the bearing housing, and an open position, in which it exposes the bearing housing for access from below, wherein the bearing housing lid is configured to be axially supported, when in the closed position, by an edge of the skid plate. By way of example, the skid plate may have a central aperture defining an inner skid plate edge, with which the bearing housing lid may engage.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">According to a sixth aspect, parts or all of the above mentioned problems are solved, or at least mitigated, by a lawnmower cutter assembly adapted to move one or several grass cutting knives in a cutting plane to cut grass, comprising: a knife carrier arrangement configured to carry one or several grass cutting knives, the knife carrier arrangement configured to be rotated about a cutter rotation axis by a cutter drive shaft; a skid plate arrangement comprising a skid plate suspended, when in use, below the knife carrier arrangement, the skid plate arrangement being rotatable relative to the knife carrier arrangement via a bearing, to enable rotation of the knife carrier arrangement in relation to the skid plate about the cutter rotation axis, the bearing being arranged in a bearing housing; and a bearing housing lid movable between a closed position, in which it covers a lower side of the bearing housing, and an open position, in which it exposes the bearing housing for access from below, wherein the skid plate arrangement comprises a skid plate clamp arrangement comprising a lower skid plate clamping element and an upper skid plate clamping element, which skid plate clamping elements clamp the skid plate between them, wherein the skid plate clamping elements are configured to clamp the skid plate between them when the bearing housing lid is in the open position. Thereby, removal of the bearing housing lid does not release the skid plate from the skid plate clamp arrangement. This facilitates removal and service of the lawnmower cutter assembly, for example for replacing grass cutting knives.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">According to a seventh aspect, parts or all of the above mentioned problems are solved, or at least mitigated, by a robotic lawnmower comprising a lawnmower cutter assembly as defined hereinabove. The robotic lawnmower may be a high-capacity lawnmower comprising a plurality of lawnmower cutting assemblies as defined above.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">According to an eighth aspect, parts or all of the above mentioned problems are solved, or at least mitigated, by a method of attaching a lawnmower cutter assembly to a lawnmower, the method comprising: positioning a knife carrier arrangement and a skid plate arrangement on a cutter drive shaft; and thereafter, axially locking the axial position of the knife carrier arrangement and the skid plate arrangement in relation to the cutter drive shaft.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">According to embodiments, the knife carrier arrangement and the skid plate arrangement may be positioned on the cutter drive shaft in one single manoeuvre. The knife carrier arrangement and the skid plate arrangement may be axially locked to the cutter drive shaft using a single fastener.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">It is noted that embodiments of the invention may be embodied by all possible combinations of features recited in the claims. Further, it will be appreciated that the various embodiments described for the lawnmower cutter assembly according to the first, second, third, fourth, fifth and sixth aspects are all combinable with each other, as well as with the method as defined in accordance with the eighth aspect of the present invention, and vice versa.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading level="1" id="h-0004">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The above, as well as additional objects, features and advantages of the present invention, will be better understood through the following illustrative and nonlimiting detailed description of preferred embodiments of the present invention, with reference to the appended drawings, where the same reference numerals will be used for similar elements, wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a view in perspective of a robotic lawnmower system comprising a robotic lawnmower;</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a perspective view of the robotic lawnmower of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> as seen obliquely from below;</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a perspective view of a first embodiment of a lawnmower cutter assembly and a cutter drive assembly of the robotic lawnmower of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> and <b>2</b></figref> as seen obliquely from below;</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> illustrates a section of the lawnmower cutter assembly and cutter drive assembly of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> in a disconnected state, the section taken along a vertical plane coinciding with a cutter rotation axis;</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is a magnified view of a portion of the cutter assembly of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is an exploded view of the cutter assembly of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>3</b>-<b>5</b></figref> as seen in perspective, obliquely from above;</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> is an exploded view of the cutter assembly of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>3</b>-<b>6</b></figref> as seen in perspective, obliquely from below;</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b>A</figref> illustrates a section of the lawnmower cutter assembly and cutter drive assembly of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> in an interconnected state, the section again taken along a vertical plane coinciding with the cutter rotation axis, wherein the lawnmower cutter assembly is illustrated with an end piece housing lid in a closed position;</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b>B</figref> is a magnified view corresponding to a portion of the view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b>A</figref>, wherein the lawnmower cutter assembly is illustrated with the end piece housing lid in an open position;</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b>C</figref> is a magnified view corresponding to a portion of the view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b>B</figref>, and illustrates an alternative position of a clamping screw;</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref> is a flow chart illustrating a method of attaching a lawnmower cutter assembly to a lawnmower;</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref> is a perspective view of a cutter drive shaft, a portion of a knife carrier arrangement, and an end piece according to a second embodiment; and</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b></figref> is a perspective view of a cutter drive shaft, a portion of a knife carrier arrangement, and an end piece according to a third embodiment.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">All the figures are schematic, not necessarily to scale, and generally only show parts which are necessary in order to elucidate the embodiments, wherein other parts may be omitted.</p>
<heading level="1" id="h-0005">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE EXEMPLARY EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> schematically illustrates an overview of a robotic lawnmower system <b>10</b> configured to mow a lawn within a work area <b>12</b> such as a garden, a park, a football field or a golf court, the work area <b>12</b> being defined by a work area boundary <b>13</b>. The robotic lawnmower system <b>10</b> comprises a self-propelled robotic lawnmower <b>14</b> and a battery charging station <b>16</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, the robotic lawnmower <b>14</b> is a multi-chassis lawnmower comprising a drive unit <b>14</b><i>a</i> and a cutting deck <b>14</b><i>b</i>, which are connected to each other via a joint arrangement <b>14</b><i>c</i>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> illustrates the robotic lawnmower <b>14</b> as seen from below. As is apparent from the bottom view, the drive unit <b>14</b><i>a</i> comprises a single pair of drive wheels <b>18</b> which are driven by respective wheel motors (not illustrated) for propelling the robotic lawnmower <b>14</b> across the work area <b>12</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>). The drive wheels <b>18</b> are arranged to rotate about a drive wheel axis A, which is perpendicular to a main propulsion direction D of the robotic lawnmower <b>14</b>. The cutting deck <b>14</b><i>b</i> comprises a set of caster wheels <b>20</b> configured to roll on the ground to support the cutting deck <b>14</b><i>b</i> during operation of the lawnmower <b>14</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, the robotic lawnmower <b>14</b> a high-capacity robotic lawnmower provided with multiple cutter assemblies <b>22</b><i>a</i>, <b>22</b><i>b</i>, <b>22</b><i>c</i>, which may be distributed along the width W of the cutting deck to enable a wide cutting width. Each cutter assembly <b>22</b><i>a</i>-<i>c</i> holds a set of grass cutting knives <b>24</b>, and is configured to, when in the normal operating position of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, rotate the respective set of grass cutting knives <b>24</b> in a substantially horizontal cutting plane to cut grass. The cutting assemblies <b>22</b><i>a</i>-<b>22</b><i>c</i> may be substantially identical; hence, for reasons of simplicity, only one cutting assembly <b>22</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>) will be described in the following, and it will be appreciated that all details of the cutter assembly <b>22</b> may be applicable to each of the three cutter assemblies <b>22</b><i>a</i>-<i>c</i> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> illustrates a lawnmower cutter assembly <b>22</b> as seen obliquely from below, when the robotic lawnmower <b>14</b> is i in the normal working posture of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> also illustrates a portion of a cutter drive assembly <b>23</b>, including the housing of a cutter drive motor <b>28</b>, which motor holds and drives the cutter assembly <b>22</b>. The cutter assembly <b>22</b> comprises a knife carrier arrangement <b>26</b> carrying a plurality of grass cutting knives <b>24</b>. The knife carrier arrangement <b>26</b> is operably connected to the cutter drive motor <b>28</b> via a drive shaft (not illustrated), such that the cutter drive motor <b>28</b> may transfer rotary power to the knife carrier arrangement <b>26</b> to rotate the grass cutting knives <b>24</b> about a common cutter rotation axis C. Thereby, the grass cutting knives <b>24</b> are rotated in a common cutting plane (not illustrated) perpendicular to the cutter rotation axis C. The cutter assembly <b>22</b> further comprises a skid plate arrangement <b>30</b> comprising a skid plate <b>32</b> which is suspended below the knife carrier arrangement. The skid plate arrangement <b>30</b> is rotatably connected to the knife carrier arrangement <b>26</b> to enable the knife carrier arrangement <b>26</b> to rotate about the cutter rotation axis C without rotating the skid plate <b>32</b>. Thereby, the skid plate <b>32</b> shields the rotating knife carrier arrangement <b>26</b> from excessive engagement with the grass (not illustrated), such that friction between the grass and the knife carrier arrangement <b>26</b> is kept low. Typically, the skid plate <b>32</b> may be made of a reasonably strong material, such as sheet metal.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> illustrates a vertical section of the cutter drive assembly <b>23</b> and the cutter assembly <b>22</b>, wherein the cutter assembly <b>22</b> is illustrated separated from the cutter drive assembly <b>23</b>. A tapering end of a cutter drive shaft <b>34</b>, rotated by the cutter drive motor <b>28</b>, is configured to be inserted into a likewise tapering drive shaft socket <b>36</b> of the knife carrier arrangement <b>26</b>, and attached thereto via a shaft connector screw <b>38</b> concentric with the cutter rotation axis C. As may be better seen in the magnified view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, the tapering section of the drive shaft socket <b>36</b> radially aligns the knife carrier arrangement <b>26</b> to the cutter drive shaft <b>34</b> when the knife carrier arrangement <b>26</b> is pressed upwards, towards the cutter drive shaft <b>34</b>, and thereby operates as an alignment section <b>61</b>. Referring again to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>, the knife carrier arrangement <b>26</b> comprises a hub portion <b>26</b><i>a</i> and a knife disc <b>26</b><i>b</i>, which are rigidly interconnected by screws <b>27</b>. Grass cutting knives <b>24</b> are pivotally attached along the radial periphery of the knife carrier arrangement <b>26</b> by knife attachment screws <b>29</b>, the pivotal attachment enabling the knives <b>24</b> to pivot about respective knife pivot axes K defined by the respective knife attachment screws <b>29</b>. Each of the cutter rotation axis C and the knife pivot axes K is substantially perpendicular to the cutting plane P. Referring back to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, the knife attachment screws <b>29</b> can be accessed via holes <b>31</b> in the skid plate <b>32</b>, for replacement of the respective knives <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">Still referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>, the lower face of the cutter drive assembly <b>23</b> and the upper face of the knife carrier arrangement <b>26</b> are provided with axially extending structures <b>40</b>, coaxial with the cutter rotation axis C, configured to intermesh with each other, to form a labyrinth seal against dirt entering the interface between the cutter drive shaft <b>34</b> and the drive shaft socket <b>36</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">Now referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, illustrating a magnified portion of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>, the skid plate arrangement <b>30</b> further comprises a skid plate clamp arrangement <b>42</b> comprising a lower skid plate clamping element <b>42</b><i>a</i> and an upper skid plate clamping element <b>42</b><i>b</i>, which clamp the skid plate <b>32</b> between them. The skid plate clamping elements <b>42</b><i>a</i>, <b>42</b><i>b</i> are tightened together by means of clamping screws <b>44</b>, the screw heads of which are accessible from below. In the alternative, the heads of the clamping screws <b>44</b> may be accessible from above, which may in a more intuitive manner guide disassembly of the cutting assembly <b>22</b> as will be apparent further below. The skid plate arrangement <b>30</b> is rotatably connected to the knife carrier arrangement <b>26</b> via a bearing arrangement <b>46</b> comprising an upper bearing <b>46</b><i>a</i> and a lower bearing <b>46</b><i>b</i>, which are axially separated by an axial support sleeve <b>48</b>. Each of the bearings <b>46</b><i>a</i>, <b>46</b><i>b</i> has a respective inner race <b>50</b><i>a</i> rotationally fixed to the knife carrier arrangement <b>26</b>, and thereby to the cutter drive shaft <b>34</b>, and a respective outer race <b>50</b><i>b</i> rotationally fixed to the skid plate arrangement <b>30</b>. The bearings <b>46</b><i>a</i>, <b>46</b><i>b</i> are arranged in a circular-cylindrical bearing housing <b>52</b>, which is integrally formed with the lower skid plate clamping element <b>42</b><i>a</i>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> also illustrates in greater detail the screw interface <b>53</b> of the cutter drive shaft <b>34</b>, which screw interface <b>53</b> is provided with internal threads <b>49</b> for engaging with external threads of a threaded section <b>51</b> of the shaft connector screw <b>38</b>. When carried by the cutting deck <b>14</b><i>b</i> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>), the skid plate arrangement <b>30</b> and the knife carrier arrangement <b>26</b> are attached solely to the cutter drive shaft <b>34</b>, and solely by means of the shaft connector screw <b>38</b>. The shaft connector screw <b>38</b> has a screw head <b>54</b>, which operates as an end piece axially abutting against, and vertically carrying, the inner race <b>50</b><i>a</i> of the lower bearing <b>46</b><i>b</i> of the bearing arrangement <b>46</b>. The inner race <b>50</b><i>a</i> of the lower bearing <b>46</b><i>b</i> axially abuts, and vertically carries, the axial support sleeve <b>48</b>, which in turn axially abuts, and vertically carries, the inner race <b>50</b><i>a</i> of the upper bearing <b>46</b><i>a</i>. The inner race <b>50</b><i>a</i> of the upper bearing <b>46</b><i>a</i> axially abuts, and vertically carries, an axial support shoulder <b>56</b> of the knife carrier arrangement <b>26</b>, whereas the skid plate arrangement <b>30</b> is vertically carried by the outer race <b>50</b><i>b</i> of the lower bearing <b>46</b><i>b</i> via a lower axial support shoulder <b>58</b> of the bearing housing <b>52</b>. Thereby, the screw head <b>54</b> vertically carries the bearing arrangement <b>46</b>, which vertically carries both the skid plate arrangement <b>30</b> and the knife carrier arrangement <b>26</b> in a rotational relationship with each other. The tapering end of the cutter drive shaft <b>34</b> forms, when connected to the drive shaft socket <b>36</b> of the knife carrier arrangement <b>26</b>, an upper axial stop shoulder <b>60</b> for the knife carrier arrangement <b>26</b>. Thereby, the skid plate arrangement <b>30</b>, the knife carrier arrangement <b>26</b>, and the bearing arrangement <b>46</b> are axially held between the axial stop shoulder <b>60</b> of the cutter drive shaft <b>34</b> and the end piece formed by the screw head <b>54</b>. If the shaft connector screw <b>38</b> is tightened firmly to the cutter drive shaft <b>34</b>, the inner races <b>50</b><i>a</i> of the bearing arrangement <b>46</b>, and the knife carrier arrangement <b>26</b>, are firmly clamped to the cutter drive shaft <b>34</b>, to form a completely rigid connection therewith. A lower portion of the bearing housing <b>52</b> also receives the screw head <b>54</b>, such that the lower portion of the bearing housing <b>52</b> defines an end piece housing <b>55</b>. The end piece housing <b>55</b> is provided with an end piece lid <b>62</b>, which is movable between a closed position, illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, in which it covers a lower side of the end piece housing <b>55</b>, and an open position (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b>B</figref>), in which it exposes the screw head <b>54</b> for access from below. Clearly, the end piece lid <b>62</b> also operates as a bearing housing lid.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">Similar to the cutter drive shaft <b>34</b>, also the knife carrier arrangement <b>26</b> has an internal thread <b>57</b> mating with the external thread of the threaded section <b>51</b> of the shaft connector screw <b>38</b>. The shaft connector screw <b>38</b> further has a reduced-width section <b>59</b> extending between the screw head <b>54</b> and the threaded section <b>51</b>. The reduced-width section <b>59</b> of the shaft connector screw <b>38</b> has a radial width inferior to the radial width of the internal thread <b>57</b> of the knife carrier arrangement <b>26</b>, and an axial length exceeding the axial length of the internal thread <b>57</b> of the knife carrier arrangement <b>26</b>. Thereby, the threaded section <b>51</b> of the screw may be screwed all the way through the internal thread <b>57</b> of the knife carrier arrangement <b>26</b>, to become an unlosable screw held to the knife carrier arrangement <b>26</b>, and still enabling attachment to the cutter drive shaft <b>34</b>. When in the unlosable position, the shaft connector screw <b>38</b> still holds the skid plate arrangement <b>26</b> and the knife carrier arrangement <b>30</b> together if removed from the cutter drive shaft <b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is an exploded view of the lawnmower cutter assembly <b>22</b> as seen obliquely from above, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> is an exploded view of the lawnmower cutter assembly as seen obliquely from below. The skid plate <b>32</b> has a central aperture <b>64</b>, defined by an inner skid plate edge <b>65</b>, and three support tabs <b>66</b> of the skid plate <b>30</b> extend radially towards the centre of the central aperture <b>64</b>. The tangential wall <b>68</b> of the end piece housing <b>55</b> is provided with three skid plate access apertures <b>70</b>, which are adapted to receive the support tabs <b>66</b>, enabling the support tabs <b>66</b> to extend into the end piece housing <b>55</b>. The upper skid plate clamping element <b>42</b><i>b</i> is provided with cover tabs <b>72</b> coinciding with the support tabs <b>66</b>, such that when the skid plate <b>30</b> is clamped between the clamping elements <b>42</b><i>a</i>, <b>42</b><i>b</i>, also the cover tabs <b>72</b> extend into the end piece housing <b>55</b> to cover an upper face of the support tabs <b>66</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">The end piece lid <b>62</b> comprises a circular-cylindrical body <b>73</b> provided with an external bayonet interface <b>74</b> configured to, when inserted into the end piece housing <b>55</b> and twisted about the cutter rotation axis C, engage with the support and cover tabs <b>66</b>, <b>72</b> extending into the end piece housing. The skid plate <b>32</b> including the support tabs <b>66</b> may be made of e.g. sheet metal, such as aluminium plate, which may give the support tabs <b>66</b> a certain resilience in the direction of the cutter rotation axis C, thereby generating added axial bias improving the locking of the bayonet interface <b>74</b>. A rubber seal <b>76</b>, configured as an O-ring, seals tightly between the end piece lid <b>62</b> and the end piece housing <b>55</b>, and also generates even further axial bias to lock the bayonet interface <b>74</b>. As is apparent from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, the rubber seal <b>76</b> is arranged inside the circular-cylindrical body <b>73</b> of the end piece lid <b>62</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">The end piece lid <b>62</b> is functionally independent from the clamping of the skid plate <b>32</b> between the upper and lower skid plate clamping elements <b>42</b><i>b</i>, <b>42</b><i>a</i>. Thereby, the skid plate clamping elements <b>42</b><i>a</i>, <b>42</b><i>b</i> clamp the skid plate <b>32</b> between them regardless of whether the end piece housing lid <b>62</b> is in the open position or in the closed position, such that removal of the end piece lid <b>62</b> does not release the skid plate <b>32</b> from the skid plate clamp arrangement <b>42</b>. As visible in the view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref>, the lower face of the end piece lid <b>62</b> is provided with a wrench interface <b>77</b>. As illustrated, the wrench interface <b>77</b> may be shaped to mate with a hexagonal socket wrench.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">The end piece lid <b>62</b> is connected to the skid plate arrangement <b>30</b> via a flexible strap <b>78</b>. A first end of the flexible strap <b>78</b> is provided with a first loop <b>80</b> configured to enclose the circular-cylindrical body <b>73</b> of the end piece lid <b>62</b>, and a second end of the flexible strap <b>78</b> is provided with a second loop <b>82</b> configured to be attached to the skid plate arrangement <b>30</b>. The second loop <b>82</b> may, by way of example, extend through a skid plate aperture <b>70</b>, to be clamped between the skid plate clamping elements <b>42</b><i>a</i>, <b>42</b><i>b</i>, or to be attached to the upper skid plate clamping element <b>42</b><i>b</i> via e.g. a screw (not illustrated).</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> also illustrates that the grass cutting knives <b>24</b> are rotatably connected to the knife disc <b>26</b><i>b</i> to enable rotating about the respective knife rotation axes K. A circular-cylindrical outer hub mantle <b>84</b>, which is integrally formed with the knife disc <b>26</b><i>b</i>, extends axially along the bearing housing <b>52</b>, and defines, together with the bearing housing <b>52</b>, a labyrinth seal protecting the bearings <b>46</b><i>a</i>, <b>46</b><i>b</i> against dirt entering from the radial direction; this may be better seen in the section of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b>A</figref> illustrates the lawnmower cutter assembly <b>22</b> after having been connected to the cutting deck <b>14</b><i>b</i> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>) via the cutter drive shaft <b>34</b>. When connected, the knife carrier arrangement <b>26</b> and the skid plate arrangement <b>30</b> are axially held to the cutter drive shaft <b>34</b> via one single fastener only, i.e. via the shaft connector screw <b>38</b> only.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">The magnified view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b>B</figref>, corresponding to the area indicated by a dashed rectangle in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b>A</figref>, illustrates the end piece lid <b>62</b> in the open position, in which the end piece lid <b>62</b> has been turned about the cutter rotation axis C to release the bayonet interface <b>74</b> from the end piece housing <b>55</b>. Thereby, the end piece lid <b>62</b> is attached to the end piece housing <b>55</b> via the flexible strap <b>78</b> only.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">The magnified view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b>C</figref> corresponds to the area indicated by a dashed rectangle in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b>B</figref>, and illustrates an alternative embodiment of the clamp arrangement, according to which alternative embodiment the skid plate clamping elements <b>42</b><i>a</i>, <b>42</b><i>b</i> are clamped together by a clamping screw <b>144</b> which has been screwed into the clamping elements <b>42</b><i>a</i>, <b>42</b><i>b</i> from above.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">The flow chart of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref> illustrates a method of attaching the lawnmower cutter assembly <b>22</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>) to the lawnmower <b>14</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>). With reference to the components illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, the method comprises 
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
<li id="ul0001-0001" num="0066"><b>901</b>: positioning the knife carrier arrangement <b>26</b> and the skid plate arrangement <b>30</b> on the cutter drive shaft <b>34</b>;</li>
<li id="ul0001-0002" num="0067">thereafter, <b>902</b>: axially locking the axial position of the knife carrier arrangement <b>26</b> and the skid plate arrangement <b>30</b> in relation to the cutter drive shaft <b>34</b>.</li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0068"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref> illustrates a lower end of the cutter drive shaft and parts of the lawnmower cutter assembly <b>22</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>) according to a second embodiment. The second embodiment may be identical to the first embodiment of e.g. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>, with the exception of the components illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref>. According to the second embodiment, the interface between the cutter drive shaft <b>134</b> and the knife carrier arrangement <b>126</b>, here represented by the hub portion <b>126</b><i>a</i> of the knife carrier arrangement <b>126</b>, may be keyed. In the illustrated example, the keyed interface is defined by a D-shaped cross-section of the cutter drive shaft <b>134</b> engaging with a D-shaped drive shaft socket <b>136</b> in the knife carrier arrangement <b>126</b>. In comparison, in the first embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>, the knife carrier arrangement <b>26</b> is rigidly attached to the cutter drive shaft <b>34</b> via a clamping force from the shaft connector screw <b>38</b> only, whereas in the second embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref>, the keyed interface rotationally interlocks the cutter drive shaft <b>134</b> and the knife carrier arrangement <b>126</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0069">The end piece according to the second embodiment is configured as a clamp <b>154</b>, which is radially clamped to the flat side <b>188</b> of the D-shaped cutter drive shaft <b>134</b> by means of an end-piece clamping screw <b>190</b>. Thereby, no axial clamping pressure is generated by the clamp <b>154</b>; in fact, the knife carrier <b>126</b> and the skid plate arrangement <b>30</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>) may be axially floating along the cutter drive shaft <b>134</b>. An upper axial end of the D-shaped section of the cutter drive shaft <b>134</b> defines an upper axial stop shoulder <b>160</b> for the knife carrier arrangement <b>126</b> and the skid plate arrangement <b>30</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>), such that the skid plate arrangement <b>30</b> and the knife carrier arrangement <b>126</b> are axially held between the end piece <b>154</b> and the axial stop shoulder <b>160</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0070"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b></figref> illustrates a lower end of the cutter drive shaft parts of the lawnmower cutter assembly <b>22</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>) according to a third embodiment. The third embodiment may be identical to the first embodiment of e.g. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>, with the exception of the components illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b></figref>. According to the third embodiment, the interface between the cutter drive shaft <b>234</b> and the knife carrier arrangement <b>226</b>, here represented by the hub portion <b>226</b><i>a</i> of the knife carrier arrangement <b>226</b>, may be keyed by splines <b>294</b> in the drive shaft socket <b>236</b> as well as on the cutter drive shaft <b>234</b>. The cutter drive shaft <b>234</b> may be provided with external threads <b>249</b>, whereas the end piece, here configured as a shaft connector nut <b>254</b>, may be provided with a mating internal thread. A radially extending collar <b>260</b> of the cutter drive shaft <b>234</b> may provide an upper axial end stop for the knife carrier arrangement <b>226</b> and the skid plate arrangement <b>30</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>). A washer <b>292</b> may be provided between the shaft connector nut <b>254</b> and the bearing arrangement <b>46</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0071">The invention has mainly been described above with reference to a few embodiments. However, as is readily appreciated by a person skilled in the art, other embodiments than the ones disclosed above are equally possible within the scope of the invention, as defined by the appended patent claims. For example, the cutter drive shaft need not be elongate or have a circular cross-section. Nor does it need to be formed in a single piece; similar to the knife carrier arrangement, the cutter drive shaft may consist of several components attached to each other. In the claims, the word &#x201c;comprising&#x201d; does not exclude other elements or steps, and the indefinite article &#x201c;a&#x201d; or &#x201c;an&#x201d; does not exclude a plurality.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A lawnmower cutter assembly adapted to move one or several grass cutting knives in a cutting plane to cut grass, comprising:
<claim-text>a knife carrier arrangement configured to carry one or several grass cutting knives, the knife carrier arrangement configured to be rotated about a cutter rotation axis by a cutter drive shaft;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a skid plate arrangement comprising a skid plate suspended, when in use, below the knife carrier arrangement, the skid plate arrangement being rotatably connected to the knife carrier arrangement to enable rotation of the knife carrier arrangement in relation to the skid plate about the cutter rotation axis,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the skid plate arrangement and the knife carrier arrangement are configured to be axially held, when in use, between an axial stop shoulder of the cutter drive shaft and an end piece rigidly connected to the cutter drive shaft,the end piece thereby vertically carrying the skid plate arrangement and the knife carrier arrangement (<b>26</b>; <b>126</b>; <b>226</b>).</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The lawnmower cutter assembly according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the lawnmower cutter assembly is configured to be axially clamped against the axial stop shoulder by the end piece.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The lawnmower cutter assembly according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the end piece is concentric with the cutter rotation axis.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The lawnmower cutter assembly according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the knife carrier arrangement has a keyed interface for rotationally locking the knife carrier arrangement to the cutter drive shaft .</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The lawnmower cutter assembly according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the knife carrier arrangement comprises a shaft socket configured to receive the cutter drive shaft.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The lawnmower cutter assembly according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the shaft socket has a cross-section shaped to mate with a D-shaped cutter drive shaft, and
<claim-text>wherein the shaft socket comprises an alignment section which tapers axially downwards.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. (canceled)</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The lawnmower cutter assembly according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the skid plate arrangement is rotatably connected to the knife carrier arrangement via a bearing arrangement comprising at least one bearing having an inner race rotationally fixed to the cutter drive shaft, and an outer race rotationally fixed to the skid plate arrangement.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The lawnmower cutter assembly according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the inner race of the bearing is clamped towards the axial stop shoulder by the end piece,or
<claim-text>wherein the end piece axially abuts the bearing arrangement and the bearing arrangement axially abuts the knife carrier arrangement.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. (canceled)</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The lawnmower cutter assembly according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the skid plate arrangement (<b>30</b>) comprises a bearing housing .</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The lawnmower cutter assembly according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the skid plate arrangement comprises a skid plate clamp arrangement comprising a lower skid plate clamping element and an upper skid plate clamping element, the upper and lower skid plate clamping elements clamping the skid plate between them,
<claim-text>wherein the bearing housing is integrally formed with the lower skid plate clamping element, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein clamping screws are screwed into the lower skid plate clamping element from above.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. (canceled)</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. (canceled)</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. The lawnmower cutter assembly according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein at least one of the lower and upper skid plate clamping elements defines an end piece housing, and the lawnmower cutter assembly further comprises an end piece lid movable between a closed position, in which the end piece lid covers a lower side of the end piece housing, and an open position, in which the end piece lid exposes the end piece for access from below.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. The lawnmower cutter assembly according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the end piece lid comprises a bayonet interface for connecting to a mating bayonet interface of the end piece housing, wherein a tangential, with regard to the cutter rotation axis, wall of the end piece housing is provided with at least one skid plate access aperture, and the skid plate comprises a central aperture provided with at least one support tab extending radially inwards, through the skid plate access aperture, wherein the bayonet interface of the end piece lid is configured to, when the end piece lid is in the closed position, be axially supported by the support tab.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. The lawnmower cutter assembly according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the upper skid plate clamping element comprises a cover tab configured to abut and cover at least a portion of an upper face of the support tab, and
<claim-text>wherein the end piece lid, when in the open position, is connected to the skid plate arrangement via a flexible strap.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. (canceled)</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. The lawnmower cutter assembly according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the axial position of the end piece, in relation to the cutter drive shaft, is reconfigurable to enable the end piece to clamp the skid plate arrangement and the knife carrier arrangement against the axial stop shoulder.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. The lawnmower cutter assembly according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the end piece is in threaded engagement with the cutter drive shaft.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text><b>21</b>. The lawnmower cutter assembly according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the end piece is configured to be axially held to the cutter drive shaft by a screw configured to engage with an inner thread of the cutter drive shaft.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text><b>22</b>. The lawnmower cutter assembly according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00021">claim 21</claim-ref>, wherein the knife carrier arrangement has an internal thread, and the screw is configured as an unlosable screw having a screw head, a threaded section mating with the internal thread of the knife carrier arrangement-(<b>26</b>), and a reduced-width section between the screw head and the threaded section, the reduced-width section having a radial width inferior to a radial width of the threaded section.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text><b>23</b>. A lawnmower cutter assembly adapted to move one or several grass cutting knives in a cutting plane to cut grass, and comprising:
<claim-text>a knife carrier arrangement configured to carry one or several grass cutting knives, the knife carrier arrangement configured to be rotated about a cutter rotation axis by a cutter drive shaft;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a skid plate arrangement comprising a skid plate suspended, when in use, below the knife carrier arrangement, the skid plate arrangement being rotatably connected to the knife carrier arrangement to enable rotation of the knife carrier arrangement in relation to the skid plate about the cutter rotation axis,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the skid plate arrangement and the knife carrier arrangement are configured to be axially held to the cutter drive shaft via one single fastener.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024" num="00024">
<claim-text><b>24</b>. The lawnmower cutter assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00023">claim 23</claim-ref>, wherein the skid plate arrangement is rotatable relative to the knife carrier arrangement via a bearing, to enable rotation of the knife carrier arrangement in relation to the skid plate about the cutter rotation axis, the bearing being arranged in a bearing housing, wherein the skid plate arrangement comprises a skid plate clamp arrangement comprising a lower skid plate clamping element and an upper skid plate clamping element, the upper and lower skid plate clamping elements clamping the skid plate between them, and wherein the bearing housing is integrally formed with the lower skid plate clamping element.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025" num="00025">
<claim-text><b>25</b>. The lawnmower cutter assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00023">claim 23</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the skid plate arrangement and the knife carrier arrangement are axially held together by an unlosable screw.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026" num="00026">
<claim-text><b>26</b>. The lawnmower cutter assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00023">claim 23</claim-ref>, wherein the skid plate arrangement is rotatable relative to the knife carrier arrangement via a bearing, to enable rotation of the knife carrier arrangement in relation to the skid plate about the cutter rotation axis, the bearing being arranged in a bearing housing; and 
<claim-text>further comprising a bearing housing lid movable between a closed position, in which the bearing housing lid covers a lower side of the bearing housing, and an open position, in which the bearing housing lid exposes the bearing housing for access from below,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the bearing housing lid is configured to be axially supported, when in the closed position, by an edge of the skid plate (<b>32</b>).</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027" num="00027">
<claim-text><b>27</b>. The lawnmower cutter assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00023">claim 23</claim-ref>, wherein the skid plate arrangement is rotatable relative to the knife carrier arrangement via a bearing, to enable rotation of the knife carrier arrangement in relation to the skid plate about the cutter rotation axis, the bearing being arranged in a bearing housing; and 
<claim-text>further comprising a bearing housing lid movable between a closed position, in which the bearing housing lid covers a lower side of the bearing housing, and an open position, in which the bearing housing lid exposes the bearing housing for access from below,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the skid plate arrangement comprises a skid plate clamp arrangement comprising a lower skid plate clamping element and an upper skid plate clamping element, the lower and upper skid plate clamping elements clamping the skid plate between them,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the lower and upper skid plate clamping elements are configured to clamp the skid plate between them when the bearing housing lid is in the open position.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028" num="00028">
<claim-text><b>28</b>. (canceled)</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029" num="00029">
<claim-text><b>29</b>. A method of attaching a lawnmower cutter assembly to a lawnmower, the method comprising:
<claim-text>positioning a knife carrier arrangement and a skid plate arrangement on a cutter drive shaft; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>thereafter, axially locking the axial position of the knife carrier arrangement and the skid plate arrangement in relation to the cutter drive shaft .</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
