<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225450A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225450</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18125737</doc-number>
<date>20230324</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>43</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>11</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>43</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>21</main-group>
<subgroup>433</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>43</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>24</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>43</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>11</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>43</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>21</main-group>
<subgroup>433</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>43</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>248</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">RAPID-ENTRY FOOTWEAR HAVING A ROTATING REAR PORTION AND A FULCRUM</invention-title>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>PCT/US21/54817</doc-number>
<date>20211013</date>
</document-id>
<parent-status>PENDING</parent-status>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18125737</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>63091290</doc-number>
<date>20201013</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>FAST IP, LLC</orgname>
<address>
<city>Lindon</city>
<state>UT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Cheney</last-name>
<first-name>Craig</first-name>
<address>
<city>Lindon</city>
<state>UT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="01" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hermann</last-name>
<first-name>Steven</first-name>
<address>
<city>Eagle Mountain</city>
<state>UT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>FAST IP, LLC</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Lindon</city>
<state>UT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A rapid-entry shoe having a rotating rear portion configured to be rotated around an axis of rotation and deflected at a fulcrum to create a stress in the rotating rear portion when the shoe is in a collapsed configuration to bias the shoe toward an uncollapsed configuration.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="162.81mm" wi="157.65mm" file="US20230225450A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="184.83mm" wi="159.68mm" file="US20230225450A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="191.01mm" wi="160.10mm" file="US20230225450A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="212.26mm" wi="153.84mm" file="US20230225450A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="213.95mm" wi="117.86mm" file="US20230225450A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="210.57mm" wi="116.50mm" file="US20230225450A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a continuation of, claims priority to and the benefit of PCT Serial No. PCT/US21/54817 filed Oct. 13, 2021 and entitled &#x201c;RAPID-ENTRY FOOTWEAR HAVING A ROTATING REAR PORTION AND A FULCRUM.&#x201d; PCT Serial No. PCT/US21/54817 claims the benefit of U.S. Provisional Patent Application No. 63/091,290, filed Oct. 13, 2020 and entitled &#x201c;RAPID-ENTRY FOOTWEAR HAVING A ROTATING REAR PORTION AND A FULCRUM.&#x201d; All of the aforementioned applications are incorporated herein by reference in their entireties.</p>
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="tail"?>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates to footwear, and more particularly to rapid-entry footwear having a rotating rear portion and a fulcrum.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Whether due to inconvenience or inability, donning and doffing of shoes, including tying or otherwise securing the same, may be undesirable and/or present difficulties to some individuals. The present disclosure addresses this need.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">A rapid-entry shoe in accordance with example embodiments of the present disclosure comprises a sole portion, an upper, a rotating rear portion coupled to the upper at an axis of rotation, a fulcrum, and a rear stabilizer coupled to the rotating rear portion. In example embodiments, the rear stabilizer is configured to prevent inward deflection of the rotating rear portion.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In example embodiments, the rapid-entry shoe has an uncollapsed configuration and further has a collapsed configuration to facilitate donning and doffing of the rapid-entry shoe. In example embodiments, in the collapsed configuration, the rotating rear portion is rotated around the axis of rotation toward the sole portion and deflected at the fulcrum to create a stress in the rotating rear portion. In example embodiments, the rapid-entry shoe is biased by the stress toward the uncollapsed configuration.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The accompanying drawings may provide a further understanding of example embodiments of the present disclosure and are incorporated in, and constitute a part of, this specification. In the accompanying drawings, only one rapid-entry shoe (either a left shoe or a right shoe) may be illustrated, however, it should be understood that in such instances, the illustrated shoe may be mirror-imaged so as to be the other shoe. The use of like reference numerals throughout the accompanying drawings is for convenience only, and should not be construed as implying that any of the illustrated embodiments are equivalent. The accompanying drawings are for purposes of illustration and not of limitation.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A and <b>1</b>B</figref> illustrate an example embodiment of a rapid-entry shoe having a fulcrum coupled to an upper, in uncollapsed and collapsed configurations, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>A and <b>2</b>B</figref> illustrate an example embodiment of a rapid-entry shoe having a fulcrum having a curved or rounded or elongated upper edge, and being coupled to an upper, in uncollapsed and collapsed configurations, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>3</b>A and <b>3</b>B</figref> illustrate an example embodiment of a rapid-entry shoe having a fulcrum comprising a slot or lateral flange, and being coupled to an upper, in uncollapsed and collapsed configurations, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>3</b>C and <b>3</b>D</figref> illustrate cross sections of a fulcrum comprising a slot and a fulcrum comprising a lateral flange, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>A and <b>4</b>B</figref> illustrate an example embodiment of a rapid-entry shoe having a fulcrum coupled to a rotating rear portion, in uncollapsed and collapsed configurations, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>C</figref> illustrates a cross section of the embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>A-<b>4</b>B</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>5</b>A and <b>5</b>B</figref> illustrate another example embodiment of a rapid-entry shoe having a fulcrum coupled to a rotating rear portion, in uncollapsed and collapsed configurations, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b>C</figref> illustrates a cross section of the embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>5</b>A-<b>5</b>B</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Example embodiments of the present disclosure are described in sufficient detail in this detailed description to enable persons having ordinary skill in the relevant art to practice the present disclosure, however, it should be understood that other embodiments may be realized and that mechanical and chemical changes may be made without departing from the spirit or scope of the present disclosure. Thus, this detailed description is for purposes of illustration and not of limitation.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">For example, unless the context dictates otherwise, example embodiments described herein may be combined with other embodiments described herein. Similarly, references to &#x201c;example embodiment,&#x201d; &#x201c;example embodiments&#x201d; and the like indicate that the embodiment(s) described may comprise a particular feature, structure, or characteristic, but every embodiment may not necessarily comprise the particular feature, structure, or characteristic.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Moreover, such references may not necessarily refer to the same embodiment(s). Any reference to singular includes plural embodiments, and any reference to plural includes singular embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Any reference to coupled, connected, attached or the like may be temporary or permanent, removeable or not, non-integral or integral, partial or full, and may be facilitated by one or more of adhesives, stitches, hook and loop fasteners, buttons, clips, grommets, zippers and other means known in the art or hereinafter developed.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">As used herein, the transitional term &#x201c;comprising&#x201d;, which is synonymous with &#x201c;including,&#x201d; &#x201c;containing,&#x201d; or &#x201c;characterized by,&#x201d; is inclusive or open-ended and does not exclude additional, unrecited elements or method steps. The transitional phrase &#x201c;consisting of&#x201d; excludes any element, step, or ingredient not specified in the claim. The transitional phrase &#x201c;consisting essentially of&#x201d; limits the scope of a claim to the specified materials or steps &#x201c;and those that do not materially affect the basic and novel characteristic(s)&#x201d; of the claimed invention.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">No claim limitation is intended to invoke 35 U.S.C. 112(f) or pre-AIA 35 U.S.C. 112, sixth paragraph or the like unless it explicitly uses the term &#x201c;means&#x201d; and includes functional language.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In describing example embodiments of the rapid-entry footwear, certain directional terms may be used. By way of example, terms such as &#x201c;right,&#x201d; &#x201c;left,&#x201d; &#x201c;medial,&#x201d; &#x201c;lateral,&#x201d; &#x201c;front,&#x201d; &#x201c;back,&#x201d; &#x201c;forward,&#x201d; &#x201c;backward,&#x201d; &#x201c;rearward,&#x201d; &#x201c;top,&#x201d; &#x201c;bottom,&#x201d; &#x201c;upper,&#x201d; &#x201c;lower,&#x201d; &#x201c;up,&#x201d; &#x201c;down,&#x201d; and the like may be used to describe example embodiments of the rapid-entry footwear. These terms should be given meaning according to the manner in which the rapid-entry footwear is most typically designed for use, with the rapid-entry footwear on a user's foot and with the user's shod foot disposed on or ready for placement on an underlying surface. Thus, these directions may be understood relative to the rapid-entry footwear in such use. Similarly, as the rapid-entry footwear is intended primarily for use as footwear, terms such as &#x201c;inner,&#x201d; &#x201c;inward,&#x201d; &#x201c;outer,&#x201d; &#x201c;outward,&#x201d; &#x201c;innermost,&#x201d; &#x201c;outermost,&#x201d; &#x201c;inside,&#x201d; &#x201c;outside,&#x201d; and the like should be understood in reference to the rapid-entry footwear's intended use, such that inner, inward, innermost, inside, and the like signify relatively closer to the user's foot, and outer, outward, outermost, outside, and the like signify relatively farther from the user's foot when the rapid-entry footwear is being used for its intended purpose. Notwithstanding the foregoing, if the foregoing definitional guidance is contradicted by an individual use herein of any of the foregoing terms, the term should be understood and read according to the definition that gives life and meaning to the particular instance of the term.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">As used herein, unless the context dictates otherwise, a &#x201c;rapid-entry shoe&#x201d; refers to an athleisure shoe, a casual shoe, a formal shoe, a dress shoe, a heel, a sports/athletic shoe (e.g., a tennis shoe, a golf shoe, a bowling shoe, a running shoe, a basketball shoe, a soccer shoe, a ballet shoe, etc.), a walking shoe, a sandal, a boot, or other suitable type of shoe. Additionally, a rapid-entry shoe can be sized and configured to be worn by men, women, or children.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">As used herein, unless the context dictates otherwise, a &#x201c;sole portion&#x201d; of a rapid-entry shoe refers to an outsole or portions thereof, a midsole or portions thereof, an insole or portions thereof, a wedge or portions thereof, or other suitable structure disposed between and/or adjacent to the foregoing parts of a rapid-entry shoe, for example, an insole or an internal cushion.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">With reference to the drawings, a rapid-entry shoe <b>100</b> in accordance with the present disclosure comprises a sole portion, an upper <b>106</b> coupled to the sole portion, a rotating rear portion <b>102</b> coupled to the upper <b>106</b> (e.g., at an axis of rotation), and a fulcrum <b>104</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In example embodiments, the rotating rear portion <b>102</b> extends between opposing sides of the rapid-entry shoe <b>100</b> (e.g., rotating rear portion <b>102</b> is v-shaped, u-shaped or horse-shoe-shaped (with consistent or inconsistent curvature as it rounds a rear portion of an upper)). In other embodiments, the rotating rear portion <b>102</b> is on a single side of the rapid-entry shoe <b>100</b> (e.g., rotating rear portion <b>102</b> is j-shaped, I-shaped).</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">In example embodiments, the rotating rear portion <b>102</b> is a strap, such that there is a window defined between the rotating rear portion <b>102</b> and a rear portion of the upper <b>106</b>. In other embodiments, the rotating rear portion <b>102</b> is a heel cup.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">In example embodiments, the rotating rear portion <b>102</b> has a perimeter greater than a perimeter of a rear portion of the upper <b>106</b> such that the rotating rear portion <b>102</b> could be rotated downward past the rear portion of the upper <b>106</b> (but for the intervention of fulcrum <b>104</b>). In example embodiments, the rotating rear portion <b>102</b> has a perimeter greater than a perimeter of a rear portion of the sole portion such that the rotating rear portion <b>102</b> could be rotated downward past the rear portion of the sole portion (but for the intervention of fulcrum <b>104</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">In example embodiments, a rapid-entry shoe <b>100</b> in accordance with the present disclosure comprises a coupling <b>112</b> between the rotating rear portion <b>102</b> and the upper <b>106</b>. The coupling <b>112</b> can be fixed (e.g., and permit only resilient deformation of the rotating rear portion <b>102</b> relative to the upper <b>106</b>) or the coupling <b>112</b> can permit rotational relative movement (e.g., <b>360</b> degrees, or at least until movement of the rotating rear portion <b>102</b> is prevented by the upper <b>106</b> or the sole portion) between the rotating rear portion <b>102</b> and the upper <b>106</b>. In this regard, a single coupling <b>112</b> (or a pair of opposing couplings <b>112</b>) can define an axis of rotation between a rotating rear portion <b>102</b> and an upper <b>106</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">In example embodiments, the fulcrum <b>104</b> is a protrusion, extension or other structure configured to act as a pivot, deflector or stopper. In this regard, in some example embodiments, the fulcrum <b>104</b> has a hardness greater than a hardness of the rotating rear portion <b>102</b>, and in other example embodiments, a topline edge of upper <b>106</b> has a hardness greater than a hardness of the fulcrum <b>104</b>. In example embodiments, the fulcrum <b>104</b> is spaced apart from the coupling <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">While the rapid-entry shoe <b>100</b> may be described herein in connection with a single fulcrum, it will be apparent to those skilled in the art that a plurality of fulcrums <b>104</b> are also contemplated (e.g., two fulcrums <b>104</b>, on opposing sides of the rapid-entry shoe <b>100</b>, but otherwise structurally the same).</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A and <b>1</b>B</figref>, in example embodiments a fulcrum <b>104</b> is coupled to a lateral side of the upper <b>106</b> (i.e., and not coupled to the rotating rear portion <b>102</b>) and a stress in the rotating rear portion <b>102</b> (as described below) results from a force applied against the fulcrum <b>104</b> by the rotating rear portion <b>102</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">In some embodiments, and with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>A and <b>2</b>B</figref>, the fulcrum <b>104</b> comprises a curved, rounded and/or elongated upper edge to distribute the force applied by it to the rotating rear portion <b>102</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">In example embodiments, the fulcrum <b>104</b> has a thickness greater than a thickness of the rotating rear portion <b>102</b> at their respective contact surfaces, so as to prevent the rotating rear portion <b>102</b> from rotating beyond the fulcrum <b>104</b> (or otherwise prevent lateral motion).</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">In some embodiments, and with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>3</b>A and <b>3</b>B</figref>, the fulcrum <b>104</b> (e.g., an upper edge of the fulcrum <b>104</b>) comprises a slot <b>105</b> within which to receive (e.g., as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>C</figref>) or lateral flange <b>107</b> with which to support (e.g., as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>D</figref>) the rotating rear portion <b>102</b> so as to prevent the rotating rear portion <b>102</b> from rotating beyond the fulcrum <b>104</b> (or otherwise prevent lateral motion of the rotating rear portion <b>102</b>). In example embodiments, the depth of the slot <b>105</b> is less than the width of the rotating rear portion <b>102</b>, while in other embodiments, the depth of the slot <b>105</b> is greater than such width. In example embodiments, the height of the lateral flange <b>107</b> is less than the width of the rotating rear portion <b>102</b>, while in other embodiments, the height of the lateral flange <b>107</b> is greater than such width. In example embodiments, an edge of the slot <b>105</b> or lateral flange <b>107</b> can be tapered so as to direct movement of an edge of the rotating rear portion <b>102</b> therein.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>A-<b>4</b>C</figref>, in example embodiments a fulcrum <b>104</b> is coupled to a medial side of the rotating rear portion <b>102</b> (i.e., and not coupled to the upper <b>106</b>) and a stress in the rotating rear portion <b>102</b> (as described below) results a force applied against a topline edge of upper <b>106</b> by the fulcrum <b>104</b> (to which the rotating rear portion <b>102</b> is coupled). In such embodiments, fulcrum <b>104</b> may have a width greater than a width of the rotating rear portion <b>102</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In other embodiments, and with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b>A-<b>5</b>C</figref>, fulcrum <b>104</b> may have a width smaller than a width of the rotating rear portion <b>102</b> and be configured to contact a topline edge of upper <b>106</b> or move within a slot cut into a topline edge of upper <b>106</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Optionally, and in connection with any of the foregoing embodiments, a rapid-entry shoe <b>100</b> in accordance with the present disclosure can further comprise a rear stabilizer <b>108</b> coupled to the rotating rear portion <b>102</b>, the rear stabilizer <b>108</b> configured to prevent inward deflection of the rotating rear portion <b>102</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">In general, rear stabilizer <b>108</b> can be configured to direct a rear portion of an upper to compress downward and/or lean rearward (and prevent a rear portion of an upper from deflecting inward, which would reduce the perimeter of the opening of rapid-entry shoe <b>100</b>). In this regard, in example embodiments, rear stabilizer <b>108</b> is configured to prevent inward deflection of the rotating rear portion when the rapid entry shoe is deformed to the collapsed configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">In some embodiments, the rear stabilizer <b>108</b> is v-shaped, u-shaped, horse-shoe-shaped (with consistent or inconsistent curvature as it rounds a rear portion of an upper), or otherwise has an elongated shape, and thus extends around a rear portion of an upper. Rear stabilizer <b>108</b> can be coupled to an inside or outside surface of rotating rear portion <b>102</b>, or be embedded within rotating rear portion <b>102</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">In example embodiments, rear stabilizer <b>108</b> comprises a mechanical property different from that of an adjacent rotating rear portion <b>102</b>, the mechanical property being one or more of material, cross-section, thickness, geometry, twisting and density. For instance, rear stabilizer <b>108</b> can comprise a reinforced section of rotating rear portion <b>102</b>. In example embodiments, rear stabilizer <b>108</b> is more rigid than adjacent rotating rear portion <b>102</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Without limiting the foregoing, in some embodiments rear stabilizer <b>108</b> can be comprised of a thicker or more dense section of the same material of which rotating rear portion <b>102</b> is comprised, but geometrically adjusted to provide stability to rotating rear portion <b>102</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Optionally, and with momentary reference back to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>A and <b>2</b>B</figref>, a rapid-entry shoe <b>100</b> in accordance with the present disclosure can further comprise a flare <b>111</b> coupled to the rotating rear portion <b>102</b>, the flare <b>111</b> extending rearward and acting as a shoehorn (e.g., to direct a foot into the foot opening during entry).</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">In example embodiments, the rapid-entry shoe <b>100</b> disclosed herein comprises an uncollapsed configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">In example embodiments, the rapid-entry shoe <b>100</b> disclosed herein comprises a collapsed configuration to facilitate donning and doffing of the rapid-entry shoe <b>100</b> (e.g., a topline edge or opening for receiving a user's foot in the collapsed configuration can have a greater circumference than in the uncollapsed configuration). In accordance with example embodiments, in the collapsed configuration, the rotating rear portion is rotated around the axis of rotation toward the sole portion (e.g., by the downward force of a user's foot) and deflected at the fulcrum to create a stress in the rotating rear portion (e.g., a tensile stress adjacent an upper edge of the rotating rear portion and a compressive stress adjacent a lower edge of the rotating rear portion). In accordance with example embodiments, the rapid-entry shoe <b>100</b> is biased by the stress toward the uncollapsed configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">It will be apparent to those skilled in the art that various modifications and variations can be made in the present disclosure without departing from the spirit or scope of the disclosure. Thus, it is intended that the embodiments described herein cover the modifications and variations of this disclosure provided they come within the scope of the appended claims and their equivalents.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Numerous characteristics and advantages have been set forth in the preceding description, including various alternatives together with details of the structure and function of the devices and/or methods. The disclosure is intended as illustrative only and as such is not intended to be exhaustive. It will be evident to those skilled in the art that various modifications can be made, especially in matters of structure, materials, elements, components, shape, size and arrangement of parts including combinations within the principles of the invention, to the full extent indicated by the broad, general meaning of the terms in which the appended claims are expressed. To the extent that these various modifications do not depart from the spirit and scope of the appended claims, they are intended to be encompassed therein.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A rapid-entry shoe comprising:
<claim-text>a sole portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an upper coupled to the sole portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a rotating rear portion coupled to opposing sides of the upper through an axis of rotation;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fulcrum coupled to the upper and the fulcrum not coupled to the rotating rear portion; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the rapid-entry shoe has an uncollapsed configuration;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the rapid-entry shoe has a collapsed configuration to facilitate donning and doffing of the rapid-entry shoe;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein, in the collapsed configuration, the rotating rear portion is rotated around the axis of rotation toward the sole portion and deflected at the fulcrum to create a stress in the rotating rear portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the stress results from contact between the fulcrum and the rotating rear portion; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the rapid-entry shoe is biased by the stress toward the uncollapsed configuration.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The rapid-entry shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the rotating rear portion is a strap.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The rapid-entry shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the rotating rear portion is a heel cup.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The rapid-entry shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the fulcrum comprises one of a slot and a lateral flange to prevent the rotating rear portion from rotating beyond the fulcrum.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The rapid-entry shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a u-shaped rear stabilizer coupled to the rotating rear portion, the rear stabilizer configured to prevent inward deflection of the rotating rear portion when the rapid-entry shoe is in the collapsed configuration.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The rapid-entry shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein a perimeter of the rotating rear portion is greater than a perimeter of a rear portion of the upper.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The rapid-entry shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the perimeter of the rotating rear portion is greater than a perimeter of a rear portion of the sole portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The rapid-entry shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the fulcrum comprises a curved, rounded or elongated upper edge to evenly distribute the stress along a portion of the rotating rear portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. A rapid-entry shoe comprising:
<claim-text>a sole portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an upper coupled to the sole portion at a coupling;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a rotating rear portion coupled to opposing sides of the upper through an axis of rotation;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of fulcrums coupled to opposing sides of the upper and no fulcrum of the plurality of fulcrums coupled to the rotating rear portion; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the rapid-entry shoe has an uncollapsed configuration;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the rapid-entry shoe has a collapsed configuration to facilitate donning and doffing of the rapid-entry shoe;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein, in the collapsed configuration, the rotating rear portion is rotated around the axis of rotation toward the sole portion and deflected by at least one fulcrum of the plurality of fulcrums to create a stress in the rotating rear portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the stress results from contact between the at least one fulcrum of the plurality of fulcrums and the rotating rear portion; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the rapid-entry shoe is biased by the stress toward the uncollapsed configuration.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The rapid-entry shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the coupling permits rotational relative movement between the rotating rear portion and the upper.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The rapid-entry shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein at least one fulcrum of the plurality of fulcrums comprises one of a slot and a lateral flange to prevent the rotating rear portion from rotating beyond the at least one fulcrum of the plurality of fulcrums.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The rapid-entry shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, further comprising a u-shaped rear stabilizer coupled to the rotating rear portion, the rear stabilizer configured to prevent inward deflection of the rotating rear portion when the rapid-entry shoe is in the collapsed configuration.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. The rapid-entry shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein a perimeter of the rotating rear portion is greater than a perimeter of a rear portion of the upper.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The rapid-entry shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the perimeter of the rotating rear portion is greater than a perimeter of a rear portion of the sole portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. The rapid-entry shoe of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein at least one fulcrum of the plurality of fulcrums comprises a curved, rounded or elongated upper edge to evenly distribute the stress along a portion of the rotating rear portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
