<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225632A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225632</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18188462</doc-number>
<date>20230323</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2020-161414</doc-number>
<date>20200925</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>107</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>8</main-group>
<subgroup>08</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>16</class>
<subclass>H</subclass>
<main-group>30</main-group>
<subgroup>40</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>1075</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>8</main-group>
<subgroup>5223</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20180101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>G</section>
<class>16</class>
<subclass>H</subclass>
<main-group>30</main-group>
<subgroup>40</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e61">SETTING DEVICE, SETTING METHOD, AND SETTING PROGRAM</invention-title>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>PCT/JP2021/028494</doc-number>
<date>20210730</date>
</document-id>
<parent-status>PENDING</parent-status>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18188462</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>FUJIFILM CORPORATION</orgname>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>TSUJI</last-name>
<first-name>Tetsuya</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kanagawa</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A setting device comprising at least one processor, wherein the processor is configured to: acquire imaging part information indicating an imaging part of a subject whose radiographic image is captured by radiation emitted from a radiation emitting device; acquire body thickness information indicating a body thickness of the subject in a direction in which the radiation is transmitted; acquire condition information indicating whether a tube voltage value and a mAs value are each set to variable or fixed; and derive a set value of the tube voltage and a set value of the mAs value of the radiation emitting device for emitting the radiation such that a dose of the radiation transmitted through the imaging part is the same as a dose at a reference body thickness, on the basis of the imaging part information, the body thickness information, and the condition information.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="228.60mm" wi="147.66mm" file="US20230225632A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="218.19mm" wi="163.41mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225632A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="229.79mm" wi="161.54mm" file="US20230225632A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="203.03mm" wi="158.07mm" file="US20230225632A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="246.04mm" wi="143.00mm" file="US20230225632A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="251.21mm" wi="158.67mm" file="US20230225632A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="225.04mm" wi="131.06mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225632A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a continuation of International Application No. PCT/JP2021/028494, filed on Jul. 30, 2021, which claims priority from Japanese Patent Application No. 2020-161414, filed on Sep. 25, 2020. The entire disclosure of each of the above applications is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="tail"?>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">Technical Field</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates to a setting device, a setting method, and a setting program.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">Related Art</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">In general, in a case in which a radiographic image of a subject is captured by radiation emitted from a radiation emitting device, imaging conditions related to a tube voltage and a mAs value of a radiation source that emits the radiation are set for the radiation emitting device. For example, JP2010-102877A discloses a technique that sets either an imaging time priority mode in which an increase in a tube voltage is allowed rather than an extension of an imaging time as imaging conditions or a tube voltage priority mode in which the extension of the imaging time is allowed rather than the increase in the tube voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">However, it is desired to set a tube voltage and a mAs value according to an imaging part and a body thickness of a subject. In some cases, the technique disclosed in JP2010-102877A is not sufficient to set the tube voltage and the mAs value according to the imaging part and the body thickness of the subject for each imaging condition set in the radiation emitting device.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The present disclosure has been made in view of the above circumstances and provides a setting device, a setting method, and a setting program that can easily set a tube voltage and a mAs value corresponding to an imaging part and a body thickness of a subject for each imaging condition set in a radiation emitting device.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">According to a first aspect of the present disclosure, there is provided a setting device comprising at least one processor. The processor acquires imaging part information indicating an imaging part of a subject whose radiographic image is captured by radiation emitted from a radiation emitting device, acquires body thickness information indicating a body thickness of the subject in a direction in which the radiation is transmitted, acquires condition information indicating whether an imaging condition set in the radiation emitting device is a first condition in which a tube voltage value is a fixed value and a mAs value is a variable value, a second condition in which the tube voltage value is a variable value and the mAs value is a fixed value, or a third condition in which the tube voltage value is a variable value and the mAs value is a variable value, and derives a set value of the tube voltage and a set value of the mAs value of the radiation emitting device for emitting the radiation such that a dose of the radiation transmitted through the imaging part is the same as a dose at a reference body thickness, on the basis of the imaging part indicated by the imaging part information, the body thickness indicated by the body thickness information, and the condition indicated by the condition information.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">According to a second aspect of the present disclosure, in the setting device according to the first aspect, the processor may derive the set values using at least one of an SID, the imaging part, a filter added to a radiation source, a type of a radiation detector that detects the radiation, adjustment information related to adjustment of the tube voltage with respect to the body thickness, or a concentration in AEC.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">According to a third aspect of the present disclosure, in the setting device according to the second aspect, the reference body thickness may be determined on the basis of at least one of the imaging part, a race, a gender, an age, or a ratio of muscle to fat in the subject, and the processor may use a reference tube voltage corresponding to the reference body thickness as the adjustment information.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">According to a fourth aspect of the present disclosure, in the setting device according to the first aspect or the second aspect, in a case in which the condition indicated by the condition information is the first condition and the third condition, the processor may derive the set value of the mAs value corresponding to the body thickness indicated by the body thickness information, using a linear attenuation coefficient for the tube voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">According to a fifth aspect of the present disclosure, in the setting device according to any one of the first to fourth aspects, in a case in which the condition indicated by the condition information is the second condition, the processor may derive the set value of the tube voltage on the basis of at least one of the imaging part indicated by the imaging part information, a reference tube voltage corresponding to the reference body thickness, or a filter added to a radiation source and the body thickness indicated by the body thickness information.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">According to a sixth aspect of the present disclosure, in the setting device according to any one of the first to fifth aspects, the processor may acquire the imaging part information from an imaging menu.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">According to a seventh aspect of the present disclosure, in the setting device according to any one of the first to sixth aspects, the processor may acquire the body thickness information by subtracting an SSD from an STD to derive the body thickness.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">According to an eighth aspect of the present disclosure, in the setting device according to any one of the first to sixth aspects, the processor may acquire the body thickness information by subtracting an SSD and a TID from an SID to derive the body thickness.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">According to a ninth aspect of the present disclosure, in the setting device according to any one of the first to eighth aspects, the processor may output the set value of the tube voltage and the set value of the mAs value to the radiation emitting device.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In addition, according to a tenth aspect of the present disclosure, there is provided a setting method executed by a processor. The setting method comprises: acquiring imaging part information indicating an imaging part of a subject whose radiographic image is captured by radiation emitted from a radiation emitting device; acquiring body thickness information indicating a body thickness of the subject in a direction in which the radiation is transmitted; acquiring condition information indicating whether an imaging condition set in the radiation emitting device is a first condition in which a tube voltage value is a fixed value and a mAs value is a variable value, a second condition in which the tube voltage value is a variable value and the mAs value is a fixed value, or a third condition in which the tube voltage value is a variable value and the mAs value is a variable value; and deriving a set value of the tube voltage and a set value of the mAs value of the radiation emitting device for emitting the radiation such that a dose of the radiation transmitted through the imaging part is the same as a dose at a reference body thickness, on the basis of the imaging part indicated by the imaging part information, the body thickness indicated by the body thickness information, and the condition indicated by the condition information.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Further, according to an eleventh aspect of the present disclosure, there is provided a setting program that causes a processor to execute a process comprising: acquiring imaging part information indicating an imaging part of a subject whose radiographic image is captured by radiation emitted from a radiation emitting device; acquiring body thickness information indicating a body thickness of the subject in a direction in which the radiation is transmitted; acquiring condition information indicating whether an imaging condition set in the radiation emitting device is a first condition in which a tube voltage value is a fixed value and a mAs value is a variable value, a second condition in which the tube voltage value is a variable value and the mAs value is a fixed value, or a third condition in which the tube voltage value is a variable value and the mAs value is a variable value; and deriving a set value of the tube voltage and a set value of the mAs value of the radiation emitting device for emitting the radiation such that a dose of the radiation transmitted through the imaging part is the same as a dose at a reference body thickness, on the basis of the imaging part indicated by the imaging part information, the body thickness indicated by the body thickness information, and the condition indicated by the condition information.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">According to the present disclosure, it is possible to easily set the tube voltage and the mAs value corresponding to the imaging part and body thickness of the subject for each imaging condition set in the radiation emitting device.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a diagram schematically illustrating an example of an overall configuration of a radiography system according to an embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a block diagram illustrating an example of a configuration of a console according to the embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a functional block diagram illustrating an example of a functional configuration of the console according to the embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is a diagram illustrating a method for acquiring a body thickness.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is an example of a graph illustrating a correspondence relationship between a body thickness of a subject and a set value of a tube voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is an example of a graph illustrating a correspondence relationship between the set value of the tube voltage and a linear attenuation coefficient.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> is a diagram illustrating an example of correspondence relationship information indicating a correspondence relationship between the type of radiation detector and a dose ratio.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> is a flowchart illustrating an example of a flow of a setting process of the console according to the embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref> is a functional block diagram illustrating an example of a functional configuration of the console according to the embodiment.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">DETTAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Hereinafter, embodiments of the invention will be described in detail with reference to the drawings. In addition, each of the embodiments does not limit the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">First, an example of an overall configuration of a radiography system according to this embodiment will be described. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a diagram illustrating an example of the overall configuration of a radiography system <b>1</b> according to this embodiment. As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, the radiography system <b>1</b> according to this embodiment comprises a console <b>10</b>, a radiation emitting device <b>12</b>, a time-of-flight (TOF) camera <b>14</b>, and a radiography apparatus <b>16</b>. The console <b>10</b> according to this embodiment is an example of a setting device according to the present disclosure. In addition, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> illustrates an aspect in which a radiographic image is captured in a state in which a subject W is standing up (standing state). However, the state of the subject W is not limited. For example, the subject W may be in a state (sitting state) in which it is sitting on a chair including a wheelchair or in a state in which it lies on an imaging table <b>32</b> (lying state).</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The radiation emitting device <b>12</b> according to this embodiment comprises a radiation source <b>20</b> that irradiates the subject W, which is an example of an object to be imaged, with radiation R, such as X-rays, and a collimator <b>24</b> that limits an irradiation field of the radiation R emitted from the radiation source <b>20</b>. In addition, the radiation emitting device <b>12</b> comprises a control unit <b>21</b>A, a storage unit <b>21</b>B, and an interface (I/F) unit <b>21</b>C.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The control unit <b>21</b>A controls the radiation source <b>20</b> and the collimator <b>24</b> under the control of the console <b>10</b>. The control unit <b>21</b>A comprises a central processing unit (CPU), a read only memory (ROM), and a random access memory (RAM) which are not illustrated. Various programs, which include an irradiation processing program for causing the radiation source <b>20</b> to irradiate the subject W with the radiation R in the capture of a radiographic image and are executed by the CPU, are stored in the ROM in advance. The RAM temporarily stores various types of data.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">For example, various types of information are stored in the storage unit <b>21</b>B. Specific examples of the storage unit <b>21</b>B include a hard disk drive (HDD) and a solid state drive (SSD). The I/F unit <b>21</b>C transmits and receives various types of information to and from the console <b>10</b> using wireless communication or wired communication. The irradiation emitting device <b>12</b> receives imaging conditions (which will be described in detail below) derived by the console <b>10</b> through the I/F unit <b>21</b>C.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">A method by which a user, such as a doctor or a technician, instructs the radiation emitting device <b>12</b> to emit the radiation R is not limited. For example, in a case in which the radiation emitting device <b>12</b> comprises an irradiation button or the like, the user, such as a radiology technician, may input an instruction to emit the radiation R with the irradiation button such that the radiation R is emitted from the radiation emitting device <b>12</b>. Further, for example, the user, such as the radiology technician, may operate the console <b>10</b> to input the instruction to emit the radiation R such that the radiation R is emitted from the radiation emitting device <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">In a case in which the radiation emitting device <b>12</b> receives the instruction to emit the radiation R, the control unit <b>21</b>A directs the radiation source <b>20</b> to emit the radiation R from a focus <b>22</b> of a radiation tube according to the imaging conditions, such as a tube voltage, a tube current, and an irradiation time, set by the console <b>10</b>. For example, in this embodiment, the irradiation field has a rectangular shape. Therefore, a rectangular-pyramid-shaped region that has the focus <b>22</b> as the apex and the irradiation field as the base is irradiated with the radiation R emitted from the focus <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Further, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, the TOF camera <b>14</b> is provided in the vicinity of an exit port through which the radiation R is emitted from the radiation emitting device <b>12</b>. The TOF camera <b>14</b> is a camera that captures a distance image indicating a distance to the object to be imaged using the TOF method with an imaging element <b>28</b>. Specifically, the TOF camera <b>14</b> irradiates the object to be imaged with light, such as infrared rays, and measures the distance between the TOF camera <b>14</b> and the object to be imaged on the basis of the time until reflected light is received or a phase change between the emitted light and the received light. In the distance image captured by the TOF camera <b>14</b>, each pixel has distance information indicating the distance between the TOF camera <b>14</b> and the object to be imaged. In addition, in the TOF camera <b>14</b> according to this embodiment, the distance between the imaging element <b>28</b> and the object to be imaged is applied as the distance between the TOF camera <b>14</b> and the object to be imaged. Further, the distance image is an image from which the distance to the object to be imaged can be derived.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The radiography apparatus <b>16</b> comprises a radiation detector <b>30</b>, a control unit <b>31</b>A, a storage unit <b>31</b>B, and an I/F unit <b>31</b>C.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The radiation detector <b>30</b> has a function of generating a radiographic image. As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, the radiation detector <b>30</b> is disposed in the imaging table <b>32</b>. In the radiography apparatus <b>16</b> according to this embodiment, in a case in which imaging is performed, the subject W is positioned on an imaging surface <b>32</b>A of the imaging table <b>32</b> by the user.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The radiation detector <b>30</b> detects the radiation R transmitted through the subject W and the imaging table <b>32</b>, generates a radiographic image on the basis of the detected radiation R, and outputs image data indicating the generated radiographic image. The type of the radiation detector <b>30</b> according to this embodiment is not particularly limited. For example, the radiation detector <b>30</b> may be a radiation detector that uses thallium activated cesium iodide (CsI:Tl) as a scintillator converting the radiation R into light or a radiation detector that uses terbium-activated gadolinium oxysulfide (GOS) (Gd<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub>S:Tb) as the scintillator. Further, for example, the radiation detector <b>30</b> may be a computed radiography (CR) detector. In addition, for example, the radiation detector <b>30</b> may be an indirect-conversion-type radiation detector that converts the radiation R into light using a scintillator and the like and converts the converted light into charge or a direct-conversion-type radiation detector that directly converts the radiation R into charge.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The control unit <b>31</b>A controls the overall operation of the radiography apparatus <b>16</b> under the control of the console <b>10</b>. The control unit <b>31</b>A comprises a CPU, a ROM, and a RAM which are not illustrated. For example, various programs, which include an imaging processing program for performing control related to the capture of radiographic images and are executed by the CPU, are stored in the ROM in advance. The RAM temporarily stores various types of data.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">For example, the image data of the radiographic image captured by the radiation detector <b>30</b> and various other types of information are stored in the storage unit <b>31</b>B. An HDD or an SSD is given as a specific example of the storage unit <b>31</b>B. The I/F unit <b>31</b>C transmits and receives various types of information to and from the console <b>10</b> using wireless communication or wired communication. The image data of the radiographic image captured by the radiation detector <b>30</b> is transmitted to the console <b>10</b> through the I/F unit <b>31</b>C by wireless communication or wired communication.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Meanwhile, the console <b>10</b> according to this embodiment has a function of controlling the radiation emitting device <b>12</b>, the TOF camera <b>14</b>, and the radiography apparatus <b>16</b> using, for example, an imaging order and various types of information acquired from a radiology information system (RIS) (not illustrated), a hospital information system (HIS), and the like through a wireless communication local area network (LAN) or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">For example, the console <b>10</b> according to this embodiment is a server computer. As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the console <b>10</b> comprises a control unit <b>50</b>, a storage unit <b>52</b>, an I/F unit <b>54</b>, an operation unit <b>56</b>, and a display unit <b>58</b>. The control unit <b>50</b>, the storage unit <b>52</b>, the I/F unit <b>54</b>, the operation unit <b>56</b>, and the display unit <b>58</b> are connected to each other through a bus <b>59</b>, such as a system bus or a control bus, such that they can transmit and receive various types of information.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The control unit <b>50</b> according to this embodiment controls the overall operation of the console <b>10</b>. The control unit <b>50</b> comprises a CPU <b>50</b>A, a ROM <b>50</b>B, and a RAM <b>50</b>C. For example, various programs including a setting program <b>51</b> executed by the CPU <b>50</b>A are stored in the ROM <b>50</b>B in advance. The RAM <b>50</b>C temporarily stores various types of data. The CPU <b>50</b>A according to this embodiment is an example of a processor according to the present disclosure. In addition, the setting program <b>51</b> according to this embodiment is an example of a setting program according to the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">For example, the image data of the radiographic image captured by the radiography apparatus <b>16</b> and various types of information including the imaging order acquired from the RIS are stored in the storage unit <b>52</b>. In addition, the storage unit <b>52</b> stores condition information <b>53</b> which will be described in detail below. An HDD or an SSD is given as a specific example of the storage unit <b>52</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The operation unit <b>56</b> is used by the user to designate an imaging menu corresponding to an imaging order and to input instructions related to the capture of a radiographic image including an instruction to emit the radiation R, various types of information, and the like. The operation unit <b>56</b> is not particularly limited. Examples of the operation unit <b>56</b> include various switches, a touch panel, a touch pen, and a mouse. The display unit <b>58</b> is used to display various types of information. In addition, the operation unit <b>56</b> and the display unit <b>58</b> may be integrated into a touch panel display.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The console <b>10</b> displays a plurality of types of imaging menus prepared in advance on the display unit <b>58</b> such that one of the menus can be selected. The user selects one imaging menu that is matched with the content of the imaging order through the operation unit <b>56</b>. In this embodiment, the imaging menu is predetermined for each of imaging parts, such as the head, the chest, the abdomen, and the spine, and the user selects an imaging part to select an imaging menu. Therefore, the console <b>10</b> receives the designation of the imaging menu.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The I/F unit <b>54</b> transmits and receives various types of information to and from the radiography apparatus <b>16</b> and the RIS (not illustrated) using wireless communication or wired communication. In the radiography system <b>1</b> according to this embodiment, the console <b>10</b> receives the image data of the radiographic image captured by the radiography apparatus <b>16</b> from the radiography apparatus <b>16</b> through the I/F unit <b>54</b>, using wireless communication or wired communication.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">In addition, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a functional block diagram illustrating an example of the functional configuration of the console <b>10</b> according to this embodiment. As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, the console <b>10</b> comprises a first acquisition unit <b>60</b>, a second acquisition unit <b>62</b>, a third acquisition unit <b>64</b>, and a derivation unit <b>66</b>. For example, in the console <b>10</b> according to this embodiment, the CPU <b>50</b>A of the control unit <b>50</b> executes the setting program <b>51</b> stored in the ROM <b>50</b>B to function as the first acquisition unit <b>60</b>, the second acquisition unit <b>62</b>, the third acquisition unit <b>64</b>, and the derivation unit <b>66</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">The first acquisition unit <b>60</b> has a function of acquiring imaging part information indicating an imaging part of the subject W. For example, in this embodiment, the imaging part information is acquired from the received imaging menu. In addition, the method by which the first acquisition unit <b>60</b> acquires the imaging part information is not particularly limited. For example, in a case in which the imaging part information is included in the imaging order, the imaging part information may be acquired from the imaging order. The imaging part information acquired by the first acquisition unit <b>60</b> is output to the derivation unit <b>66</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">The second acquisition unit <b>62</b> has a function of acquiring body thickness information indicating a body thickness of the subject W in a direction in which the radiation R is transmitted. In addition, in this embodiment, the term &#x201c;body thickness&#x201d; means a body thickness of the subject W in the direction in which the radiation R is transmitted. For example, the second acquisition unit <b>62</b> according to this embodiment acquires the distance image captured by the TOF camera <b>14</b> and derives the body thickness from the acquired distance image to acquire the body thickness information. For example, the second acquisition unit <b>62</b> according to this embodiment acquires image data indicating the distance image captured by the TOF camera <b>14</b> from the TOF camera <b>14</b> through the I/F unit <b>31</b>C and the I/F unit <b>54</b>. Then, the second acquisition unit <b>62</b> derives the body thickness on the basis of the acquired distance image to acquire the body thickness information. The body thickness information acquired by the second acquisition unit <b>62</b> is output to the derivation unit <b>66</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">An example of a method for deriving the body thickness will be described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">As described above, in this embodiment, the body thickness is derived from the distance image captured by the TOF camera <b>14</b>. The TOF camera <b>14</b> measures a distance between the TOF camera <b>14</b> and an object to be measured. As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> and <b>4</b></figref>, in this embodiment, since the position of the imaging element <b>28</b> of the TOF camera <b>14</b> is different from the position of the focus <b>22</b> of the radiation source <b>20</b>, the distance to the object to be measured which has been measured by the TOF camera <b>14</b> is different from the distance between the radiation source <b>20</b> and the object to be measured. In the radiography system <b>1</b> according to this embodiment, a relative positional relationship between the TOF camera <b>14</b> and the radiation source <b>20</b> is predetermined. Therefore, a conversion coefficient for converting the distance to the object to be measured, which has been measured by the TOF camera <b>14</b>, into the distance between the radiation source <b>20</b> and the object to be measured is stored in advance in the storage unit <b>52</b> of the console <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>, the second acquisition unit <b>62</b> according to this embodiment derives a body thickness t using the following Expression (1) on the basis of a source target distance (STD) and a source-to-skin distance (SSD).</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0000">
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?>t=STD&#x2212;SSD &#x2003;&#x2003;(1)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0053">The STD is a distance between the radiation source <b>20</b> and a target (object to be imaged). In this embodiment, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>, the STD means a distance between the focus <b>22</b> of the radiation source <b>20</b> and the imaging surface <b>32</b>A of the imaging table <b>32</b>. Specifically, the STD means the length of a perpendicular line drawn from the focus <b>22</b> of the radiation source <b>20</b> to the imaging surface <b>32</b>A of the imaging table <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0054">Specifically, the position of the imaging surface <b>32</b>A of the imaging table <b>32</b> which is not hidden by the subject W is predetermined as a measurement position in order to derive the STD. The second acquisition unit <b>62</b> derives the distance between the TOF camera <b>14</b> and the measurement position from distance information included in a pixel which corresponds to the measurement position in the distance image. Further, in a case in which the measurement position is different from the foot of the perpendicular line drawn from the TOF camera <b>14</b> to the imaging surface <b>32</b>A of the imaging table <b>32</b>, the second acquisition unit <b>62</b> converts the derived distance between the TOF camera <b>14</b> and the measurement position into the length of the perpendicular line drawn from the TOF camera <b>14</b> to the imaging surface <b>32</b>A of the imaging table <b>32</b>. Furthermore, the second acquisition unit <b>62</b> derives the STD by converting the distance between the TOF camera <b>14</b> and the imaging surface <b>32</b>A of the imaging table <b>32</b> into the distance between the radiation source <b>20</b> and the imaging surface <b>32</b>A of the imaging table <b>32</b>, using a conversion coefficient for deriving the STD among the conversion coefficients stored in the storage unit <b>52</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0055">In addition, in a case in which the STD is predetermined and is, for example, a fixed value corresponding to the imaging part, the STD may be stored in the storage unit <b>52</b> in advance, and the second acquisition unit <b>62</b> may acquire the STD from the storage unit <b>52</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0056">Further, the SSD is the distance between the radiation source <b>20</b> and the surface (skin) of the subject W, that is, a distance from the radiation source <b>20</b> to the subject W. In this embodiment, the SSD means the distance from the focus <b>22</b> of the radiation source <b>20</b> to the body surface of the subject W facing the focus <b>22</b> as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>. Specifically, the SSD means the length of a perpendicular line drawn from the focus <b>22</b> of the radiation source <b>20</b> to the subject W.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0057">More specifically, the second acquisition unit <b>62</b> derives the distance between the TOF camera <b>14</b> and the subject W from the distance information included in the pixels corresponding to the subject W in the distance image captured by the TOF camera <b>14</b>. Further, the second acquisition unit <b>62</b> derives the SSD by converting the distance between the TOF camera <b>14</b> and the subject W into the distance between the radiation source <b>20</b> and the subject W, using a conversion coefficient for deriving the SSD among the conversion coefficients stored in the storage unit <b>52</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0058">In addition, the method by which the second acquisition unit <b>62</b> derives the body thickness t is not limited to the above-described method. For example, the second acquisition unit <b>62</b> may derive the body thickness t using the following Expression (2) on the basis of a source-to-image receptor distance (SID), the SSD, and a target-to-image receptor distance (TID).</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0000">
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?>t=SID&#x2212;SSD&#x2212;TID &#x2003;&#x2003;(2)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0059">The SID is the distance between the radiation source <b>20</b> and the radiation detector <b>30</b>. Further, in this embodiment, the SID means the length of a perpendicular line drawn from the focus <b>22</b> of the radiation source <b>20</b> to a detection surface <b>30</b>A of the radiation detector <b>30</b> as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>. For example, in this embodiment, the SID is a fixed value predetermined according to the imaging part and is stored in the storage unit <b>52</b> in advance. Therefore, the second acquisition unit <b>62</b> acquires the SID from the storage unit <b>52</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0060">In addition, unlike this embodiment, the SID may be measured whenever a radiographic image is captured. In this case, for example, the second acquisition unit <b>62</b> may acquire a measurement result of the SID by a measurement device such as a linear encoder.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0061">Further, the TID is the distance between the target (object to be imaged) and the radiation detector <b>30</b>. In this embodiment, the TID means the distance from the detection surface <b>30</b>A of the radiation detector <b>30</b> to the imaging surface <b>32</b>A of the imaging table <b>32</b>. For example, in this embodiment, the TID is a fixed value, is predetermined as a design value of the imaging table <b>32</b>, and is stored in the storage unit <b>52</b> in advance. Therefore, the second acquisition unit <b>62</b> acquires the TID from the storage unit <b>52</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0062">The third acquisition unit <b>64</b> has a function of acquiring condition information indicating the imaging conditions set in the radiation emitting device <b>12</b>. The dose of the radiation R transmitted through the subject W varies depending on the body thickness t of the subject W. For example, in a case in which the imaging part of the subject W is the same, the dose of the radiation R transmitted through the subject W is lower as the thickness of the subject W is larger. In the radiography system <b>1</b> according to this embodiment, control is performed such that the dose of the radiation transmitted through the subject W is the same regardless of the body thickness t of the subject W. Specifically, the radiation R is emitted such that the dose of the radiation R transmitted through the imaging part of the subject W is the same as a dose at a reference body thickness t_c. In addition, the term &#x201c;same&#x201d; is not limited to &#x201c;exact same&#x201d; and may have, for example, an error in an allowable range.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0063">Therefore, in the radiation emitting device <b>12</b> according to this embodiment, the dose for the body thickness t of the subject W is set. Specifically, any one of the following three conditions is set as an imaging condition related to the tube voltage value and the mAs value of the radiation source <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0064">A first condition is a condition in which the tube voltage value is set to a fixed value regardless of the body thickness t of the subject W and the mAs value is set to a variable value corresponding to the body thickness t of the subject W. Specifically, in a case in which the first condition is set, for the tube voltage value, a tube voltage value corresponding to the reference body thickness t_c is used as the fixed value. On the other hand, the mAs value is a variable value that corresponds to the body thickness t of the subject W and is larger as the body thickness t is larger.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0065">A second condition is a condition in which the tube voltage value is a variable value corresponding to the body thickness t of the subject W and the mAs value is a fixed value regardless of the body thickness t of the subject W. Specifically, in a case in which the second condition is set, the tube voltage value is a variable value that corresponds to the body thickness t of the subject W and is larger as the body thickness t is larger. On the other hand, for the mAs value, a mAs value corresponding to the reference body thickness t_c, specifically, the current value mA of the tube current and the irradiation time msec of the radiation R are used as fixed values.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0066">A third condition is a condition in which the tube voltage value is a variable value corresponding to the body thickness t of the subject W and the mAs value is a variable value corresponding to the body thickness t of the subject W. Specifically, in a case in which the third condition is set, as the body thickness t of the subject W is larger, at least one of the tube voltage value or the mAs value is larger.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0067">In a case in which the tube voltage value is a variable value corresponding to the body thickness t of the subject W, the tube voltage value is increased in order to suppress an increase in contrast due to the widening of the range of a histogram of the radiation R transmitted through the subject W which is caused by an increase in the body thickness t. It can be expected that the radiographic image will be adjusted to a constant contrast with respect to a change in the body thickness t by increasing the tube voltage value in this way.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0068">Further, since the mAs value, that is, the current value mA of the tube current and the irradiation time msec of the radiation R are set as fixed values regardless of the body thickness t, the stability of image quality for heartbeat and body movement is maintained even in a case in which the body thickness t changes depending on the subject W. In addition, in a case in which the focus size increases, the radiographic image is likely to be blurred. However, the mAs value is set to a fixed value, which makes it possible to keep the focus size of the radiation source <b>20</b> constant as a small focus. Therefore, it can be expected that the sharpness of the radiographic image will be stabilized.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0069">Since each of the first to third conditions has its own characteristics, which of the first to third conditions is set as the imaging condition in the radiation emitting device <b>12</b> may depend on, for example, the facility in which the radiography system <b>1</b> is installed. In addition, in a case in which the quality of the radiation R for the body thickness t, that is, the condition of the tube voltage is converted, for example, the quality of the captured radiographic image is changed. Therefore, even for the same subject W, it may be difficult to compare a past radiographic image with a current radiographic image. For this reason, it is preferable to inherit the setting of which of the first to third conditions is set for each imaging environment in which the same subject W is imaged, for example, for each facility in which the radiography system <b>1</b> is installed.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0070">For example, in the radiography system <b>1</b> according to this embodiment, any one of the first to third conditions is preset as the imaging condition in the console <b>10</b>. Specifically, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the condition information <b>53</b> indicating which of the first to third conditions is set as imaging condition is stored in the storage unit <b>52</b> of the console <b>10</b>. Therefore, the third acquisition unit <b>64</b> has a function of acquiring the condition information indicating the imaging condition from the storage unit <b>52</b>. The condition information acquired by the third acquisition unit <b>64</b> is output to the derivation unit <b>66</b>. In addition, the setting destination of the imaging condition is not limited to the console <b>10</b> and may be, for example, the radiation emitting device <b>12</b>. Further, a method for setting any one of the first to third conditions as the imaging condition is not limited. For example, the imaging condition may be set by the user or may be set by a person who performs the maintenance of the radiography system <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0071">The derivation unit <b>66</b> has a function of deriving the set value of the tube voltage and the set value of the mAs value of the radiation emitting device <b>12</b> for emitting the radiation R such that the dose of the radiation transmitted through the imaging part of the subject W is the same as the dose at the reference body thickness t_c, on the basis of the imaging part indicated by the imaging part information, the body thickness t indicated by the body thickness information, and the condition indicated by the condition information.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0072">In a case in which the imaging condition set in the radiation emitting device <b>12</b> is the third condition, the derivation unit <b>66</b> derives the set value of the tube voltage kV corresponding to the body thickness t of the subject W. A method for deriving the set value of the tube voltage kV corresponding to the body thickness t of the subject W in this embodiment will be described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is an example of a graph illustrating a correspondence relationship between the body thickness t of the subject W and the set value of the tube voltage kV. In this embodiment, for example, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, a correspondence relationship represented by a linear function is established between the body thickness t of the subject W and the set value of the tube voltage kV.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0073">The reference body thickness t_c is the average value of the body thicknesses t of a plurality of subjects W. For example, the reference body thickness t_c is a value that is determined on the basis of at least one of the imaging part, the race of the subject W, the gender of the subject W, the age of the subject W, or the ratio of muscle to fat in the subject W. In this embodiment, information indicating a correspondence relationship between at least one of the imaging part, the race of the subject W, the gender of the subject W, the age of the subject W, or the ratio of muscle to fat in the subject W and the reference body thickness t_c is stored in the storage unit <b>52</b> in advance (not illustrated).</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0074">A reference tube voltage kV_c is a value that is determined according to, for example, the quality of the captured radiographic image. In addition, the reference tube voltage kV_c may be set by the user. A fluctuation range &#x394;kV is a fluctuation range of the tube voltage kV with respect to the reference tube voltage kV_c and is a value that is determined according to, for example, the quality of the captured radiographic image. In addition, the fluctuation range &#x394;kV may be set by the user. Further, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, the fluctuation range &#x394;kV is defined by a magnification x in a case in which the width of the body thickness t is x times a standard deviation &#x3c3;. Similarly to the reference body thickness t_c, the standard deviation &#x3c3; of the body thickness t is determined on the basis of at least one of the imaging part, the race of the subject W, the gender of the subject W, the age of the subject W, or the ratio of muscle to fat in the subject W. At least one of the fluctuation range &#x394;kV or the magnification x can be adjusted to adjust the correspondence relationship between the body thickness t of the subject W and the set value of the tube voltage kV. In addition, in the radiography system <b>1</b> according to this embodiment, the fluctuation range and the magnification x are predetermined values and are stored in the storage unit <b>52</b> in advance (not illustrated). The reference tube voltage kV_c, the fluctuation range &#x394;kV, the standard deviation &#x3c3;, and the magnification x in this embodiment are examples of adjustment information according to the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0075">Therefore, the derivation unit <b>66</b> according to this embodiment derives the set value of the tube voltage kV, using the imaging part, the body thickness t of the subject W, the reference tube voltage kV_c, the fluctuation range &#x394;kV, and the magnification x as parameters, as defined in the following Expression (3).</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0000">
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?>kV=kV(imaging part, t, kV_c, &#x394;kV, x) &#x2003;&#x2003;(3)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0076">The method by which the derivation unit <b>66</b> derives the set value of the tube voltage kV corresponding to the body thickness t of the subject W is not limited to the above-described method. In other words, the adjustment information according to the present disclosure is not limited to the above-described aspect. For example, as the correspondence relationship between the body thickness t of the subject W and the set value of the tube voltage kV, a gradient (dkV/dt) of the set value of the tube voltage kV with respect to the body thickness t of the subject W may be defined, and the set value of the tube voltage kV corresponding to the body thickness t of the subject W may be derived using this definition. Further, for example, in a case in which the body thickness t of the subject W and the set value of the tube voltage kV indicate a non-linear correspondence relationship, a table, such as a lookup table (LUT), indicating the correspondence relationship between the body thickness t of the subject W and the set value of the tube voltage kV may be prepared, and the set value of the tube voltage kV corresponding to the body thickness t of the subject W may be derived using this table.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0077">In addition, the derivation unit <b>66</b> derives a linear attenuation coefficient &#x3c1; corresponding to the set value of the tube voltage kV. A method for deriving the linear attenuation coefficient &#x3c1; corresponding to the set value of the tube voltage kV in this embodiment will be described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is an example of a graph illustrating a correspondence relationship between the set value of the tube voltage kV and the linear attenuation coefficient &#x3c1;.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0078">The linear attenuation coefficient &#x3c1; is determined according to the imaging part, the set value of the tube voltage kV, and a filter applied to the radiation source <b>20</b>. Since gas, blood, muscle, and fat differ depending on the imaging part, the linear attenuation coefficient &#x3c1; differs depending on the imaging part. Therefore, in this embodiment, the graph showing the correspondence relationship between the set value of the tube voltage kV and the linear attenuation coefficient &#x3c1; illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is stored in advance in the storage unit <b>52</b> for each imaging part (not illustrated). Further, a filter (not illustrated) is added to the radiation source <b>20</b>, and the subject W is irradiated with the radiation R transmitted through the filter. Examples of the filter include a filter using copper (Cu), a filter using rhodium (Rh), and a filter using aluminum (Al). The filter used for imaging differs depending on, for example, the intended use. The linear attenuation coefficient &#x3c1; differs depending on the type (material) of the filter. Further, the linear attenuation coefficient &#x3c1; varies depending on the thickness of the filter, specifically, the thickness in the direction in which the radiation R is transmitted. The linear attenuation coefficient &#x3c1; is smaller as the thickness of the filter is larger. In other words, the linear attenuation coefficient &#x3c1; has a value that differs depending on the conditions (material, thickness, and the like) of the filter added to the radiation source <b>20</b>. In addition, even in a case in which the set value of the tube voltage kV and the conditions of the filter added to the radiation source <b>20</b> are the same, radiation quality may be different for each radiation emitting device <b>12</b>. Therefore, it is preferable that calibration or the like is performed for each radiation emitting device <b>12</b> to adjust the correspondence relationship between the set value of the tube voltage kV and the linear attenuation coefficient &#x3c1;.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0079">Therefore, the derivation unit <b>66</b> according to this embodiment derives the linear attenuation coefficient &#x3c1; corresponding to the set value of the tube voltage kV, using the correspondence relationship between the set value of the tube voltage kV and the linear attenuation coefficient &#x3c1; stored in the storage unit <b>52</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0080">In addition, the derivation unit <b>66</b> derives a reference mAs value mAs_c that is used in a case in which a predetermined tube voltage kV at the reference body thickness t_c is applied. The reference mAs value mAs_c corresponds to a target value of the dose of the radiation R transmitted through the imaging part. For example, the reference mAs value mAs_c according to this embodiment is a value that is determined according to the imaging part, the reference tube voltage kV_c, the conditions of the filter, the type of the radiation detector <b>30</b>, the concentration of automatic exposure control (AEC) in the control of the radiation detector <b>30</b>, and the SID.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0081">As defined in the following Expression (4), the derivation unit <b>66</b> according to this embodiment derives the reference mAs value mAs_c, using the imaging part, the reference tube voltage kV_c, the conditions of the filter, the type of the radiation detector <b>30</b>, the concentration of the AEC, and the SID as parameters.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0000">
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?>mAs_c=A(imaging part, kV_c, conditions of filter)&#xd7;(current SID/reference value of SID)<sup>2</sup>&#xd7;B(type of radiation detector <b>30</b>)&#xd7;C(concentration of AEC) &#x2003;&#x2003;(4)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0082">In the above-described Expression (4), &#x201c;A&#x201d; is determined on the basis of the reference value of the SID. Therefore, in a case in which the SID in the current measurement of the subject W is different from the reference value of the SID, &#x201c;A&#x201d; is corrected by integrating (current SID/reference value of SID)<sup>2 </sup>as illustrated in the above-described Expression (4). In addition, in a case in which the reference tube voltage kV_c differs, the reference mAs value mAs_c to be set differs even though the imaging part is the same. Further, the reference mAs value mAs_c to be set differs in a case in which the conditions of the filter applied to the radiation source <b>20</b> differs.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0083">Meanwhile, in the above-described Expression (4), &#x201c;B&#x201d; is a parameter for adjusting the reference mAs value mAs_c and is a dose ratio corresponding to the type of the radiation detector <b>30</b>. An example of a method for deriving &#x201c;B&#x201d; is a method that measures noise equivalent quanta (NEQ) while changing a dose with the corresponding radiation quality for each type of radiation detector <b>30</b> and compares the doses for achieving the same NEQ for each type of radiation detector <b>30</b> to derive a dose ratio. In addition, another example of the method is a method that visually evaluates a radiographic image obtained by imaging a contrast detail radiography (CDRAD) phantom while changing a dose with the corresponding radiation quality, derives IQFinv which is an index for quantifying total image quality including contrast and granularity, and compares the doses for achieving the same IQFinv for each type of radiation detector <b>30</b> to derive a dose ratio.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0084"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> illustrates an example of correspondence relationship information (hereinafter, referred to as &#x201c;dose ratio information&#x201d;) indicating a correspondence relationship between the type of the radiation detector <b>30</b> and the dose ratio. In the example of the dose ratio information illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref>, in a case in which a dose for the radiation detector <b>30</b>, which is a type using GOS as the scintillator, is used as a standard (a dose ratio B=1.0), the dose ratios B for other types of radiation detectors <b>30</b> are illustrated. For example, in this embodiment, dose ratio information <b>70</b> is stored in the storage unit <b>52</b> in advance.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0085">Meanwhile, in the above-described Expression (4), &#x201c;C&#x201d; is a parameter for adjusting the reference mAs value mAs_c and corresponds to the concentration of the AEC in the control of the radiation detector <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0086">As in the setting of the concentration of the AEC, for example, &#x201c;C&#x201d; is stored in advance in the storage unit <b>52</b> as a &#xb1;3-step adjustment value, such as 0.58, 0.69, 0.83, 1.0, 1.2, 1.4, and 1.7, for every &#xb1;20% (not illustrated).</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0087">In addition, the derivation unit <b>66</b> corrects the reference mAs value mAs_c according to the difference between the body thickness t of the subject W and the reference body thickness t_c to derive the set value of the mAs value corresponding to the body thickness t of the subject W. Specifically, the derivation unit <b>66</b> derives the set value of the mAs value corresponding to the body thickness t of the subject W using the following Expression (5).</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0000">
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?>mAs value=mAs_c&#xd7;exp(&#x3c1;&#xd7;(t&#x2212;t_c)) &#x2003;&#x2003;(5)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0088">In the above-described Expression (5), &#x201c;mAs_c&#x201d; is the reference mAs value and is derived by the above-described method. In addition, &#x201c;&#x3c1;&#x201d; is a linear attenuation coefficient and is derived by the above-described method.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0089">In a case in which the imaging condition set in the radiation emitting device <b>12</b> is the third condition, the derivation unit <b>66</b> derives the set value of the tube voltage kV corresponding to the body thickness t of the subject W in this way.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0090">On the other hand, in a case in which the imaging condition set in the radiation emitting device <b>12</b> is the first condition, the set value of the tube voltage kV is a fixed value regardless of the body thickness t of the subject W and is the reference tube voltage kV_c. Therefore, in the case of the third condition, the fluctuation range &#x394;kV may be set to zero (&#x394;kV=0) and can be derived by the same method as in the first condition.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0091">On the other hand, in a case in which the imaging condition set in the radiation emitting device <b>12</b> is the second condition, the set value of the mAs value is a fixed value regardless of the body thickness t of the subject W and is the reference mAs value mAs_c. Meanwhile, the set value of the tube voltage kV is derived according to at least one of the body thickness t of the subject W, the imaging part, the reference tube voltage kV_c, or the filter added to the radiation source <b>20</b> in order to make the dose of the radiation transmitted through the imaging part the same as the dose at the reference body thickness t_c. Specifically, the derivation unit <b>66</b> derives the set value of the tube voltage kV, using the imaging part, the body thickness t of the subject W, the reference tube voltage kV_c, and the filter added to the radiation source <b>20</b> as parameters, as defined in the following Expression (6).</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0000">
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?>kV=kV(imaging part, t, kV_c, conditions of filter) &#x2003;&#x2003;(6)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0092">For example, in this embodiment, a table (not illustrated), such as an LUT, showing the correspondence relationship among the set value of the tube voltage kV, the body thickness t, the reference tube voltage kV_c, and the conditions of the filter is stored for each imaging part in the storage unit <b>52</b> in advance. The derivation unit <b>66</b> derives the set value of the tube voltage kV corresponding to the body thickness t of the subject W and each parameter with reference to the table corresponding to the imaging part which is stored in the storage unit <b>52</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0093">Next, the operation of the console <b>10</b> according to this embodiment will be described with reference to the drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0094">In the console <b>10</b> according to this embodiment, the CPU <b>50</b>A of the control unit <b>50</b> executes the setting program <b>51</b> stored in the ROM <b>50</b>B to perform a setting process whose example is illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> is a flowchart illustrating an example of the flow of the setting process performed in the console <b>10</b> according to this embodiment. In addition, the timing when the CPU <b>50</b>A performs the setting process is not limited, and the CPU <b>50</b>A may perform the setting process at any timing. For example, the setting process may be performed at the timing when an instruction input from the user by the operation of the operation unit <b>56</b> after the positioning of the subject W ends is received or the timing when an instruction to emit the radiation R is received from the user.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0095">Then, in Step S<b>100</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref>, the second acquisition unit <b>62</b> acquires the body thickness information as described above. Specifically, the second acquisition unit <b>62</b> instructs the TOF camera <b>14</b> to capture a distance image and acquires the distance image captured by the TOF camera <b>14</b> on the basis of the instruction through the I/F unit <b>54</b>. The second acquisition unit <b>62</b> acquires the body thickness information from the acquired distance image using the above-described Expression (1) or (2).</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0096">Then, in Step S<b>102</b>, the first acquisition unit <b>60</b> acquires the imaging part information from the imaging menu as described above. Then, in Step S<b>104</b>, the third acquisition unit <b>64</b> acquires the condition information <b>53</b> from the storage unit <b>52</b> as described above.</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0097">Then, in Step S<b>106</b>, the derivation unit <b>66</b> determines whether or not the imaging condition indicated by the condition information acquired in Step S<b>104</b> is the second condition. In a case in which the imaging condition indicated by the acquired condition information is not the second condition, that is, in a case in which the imaging condition indicated by the acquired condition information is the first condition or the third condition, the determination result in Step S<b>106</b> is &#x201c;No&#x201d;, and the process proceeds to Step S<b>108</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0098">In Step S<b>108</b>, the derivation unit <b>66</b> acquires subject information related to the subject W. The subject information acquired in this step is information which is a parameter necessary for deriving the reference body thickness t_c and the standard deviation &#x3c3; of the body thickness t. For example, in this embodiment, as described above, the race, gender, and age of the subject W and the ratio of muscle to fat in the subject W are acquired. In addition, the method by which the derivation unit <b>66</b> acquires the subject information is not particularly limited.</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0099">As the method by which the derivation unit <b>66</b> acquires the gender and the age as the subject information, for example, the gender and the age may be acquired from the HIS, the RIS, or the like. In a case in which the subject information is included in the imaging order, the gender and the age may be acquired from the imaging order. In addition, for example, the derivation unit <b>66</b> may acquire information indicating the gender and the age input by the user using the operation unit <b>56</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0107" num="0100">Further, as the method by which the derivation unit <b>66</b> acquires the race as the subject information, for example, the race of the subject may be determined from a visible light image obtained by imaging the subject W with a visible light camera. In this case, a race determination trained model for determining the race of the subject W from the visible light image may be used. Specifically, a race determination trained model may be used which is generated using a plurality of learning information items in which racial information indicating the race of the object to be imaged is associated with visible light images obtained by imaging persons of various races, receives a visible light image obtained by imaging the subject W as an input, and outputs racial information indicating the race of the object to be imaged. A neural network model is given an example of the race determination trained model. For example, a back-propagation method can be applied as a learning algorithm. The derivation unit <b>66</b> can acquire the race as the subject information by inputting the visible light image obtained by imaging the subject W to the race determination trained model and obtaining racial information from the race determination trained model. In addition, for example, the derivation unit <b>66</b> may acquire information indicating the race input by the user using the operation unit <b>56</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0108" num="0101">Further, as the method by which the derivation unit <b>66</b> acquires the ratio of muscle to fat as the subject information, for example, the ratio of muscle to fat in the subject may be determined from a visible light image obtained by imaging the subject W with a visible light camera. In this case, a ratio determination trained model for determining the ratio of muscle to fat in the subject W from the visible light image may be used. Specifically, a ratio determination trained model may be used which is generated using a plurality of learning information items in which the ratios of muscle to fat in the objects to be imaged are associated with visible light images obtained by imaging persons having various ratios of muscle to fat, receives a visible light image obtained by imaging the subject W as an input, and outputs ratio information indicating the ratio of muscle to fat in the object to be imaged. A neural network model is given an example of the ratio determination trained model. For example, the back-propagation method can be applied as the learning algorithm. The derivation unit <b>66</b> can acquire the ratio of muscle to fat as the subject information by inputting the visible light image obtained by imaging the subject W to the ratio determination trained model and obtaining ratio information from the ratio determination trained model. Further, for example, the derivation unit <b>66</b> may derive an index, such as a body mass index (BMI), from the height and weight of the subject W and acquire the ratio of muscle to fat in the subject W from the derived index. In this case, the height and weight of the subject W may be acquired from, for example, the HIS or the RIS. In addition, for example, the derivation unit <b>66</b> may acquire information indicating the ratio of muscle to fat input by the user using the operation unit <b>56</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0109" num="0102">Then, in Step S<b>110</b>, the derivation unit <b>66</b> determines whether or not the imaging condition indicated by the condition information acquired in Step S<b>104</b> is the first condition. In a case in which the imaging condition indicated by the acquired condition information is the first condition, the determination result in Step S<b>110</b> is &#x201c;Yes&#x201d;, and the process proceeds to Step S<b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0110" num="0103">In Step S<b>112</b>, the derivation unit <b>66</b> sets the fluctuation range &#x394;kV of the tube voltage kV to zero (&#x394;kV=0) and then proceeds to Step S<b>114</b>. As described above, in a case in which the imaging condition set in the radiation emitting device <b>12</b> is the first condition, the fluctuation range &#x394;kV is set to zero since the tube voltage kV is a fixed value.</p>
<p id="p-0111" num="0104">On the other hand, in a case in which the imaging condition indicated by the condition information acquired in Step S<b>104</b> is not the first condition in Step S<b>110</b>, that is, in a case in which the imaging condition indicated by the acquired condition information is the third condition, the determination result in Step S<b>110</b> is &#x201c;No&#x201d;, and the process proceeds to Step S<b>114</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0112" num="0105">In Step S<b>114</b>, the derivation unit <b>66</b> specifies the reference body thickness t_c of the subject W. As described above, the reference body thickness t_c is a value that is determined on the basis of at least one of the imaging part, the race of the subject W, the gender of the subject W, the age of the subject W, or the ratio of muscle to fat in the subject W. Therefore, the derivation unit <b>66</b> specifies the reference body thickness t_c of the subject W, using the subject information acquired in Step S<b>108</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0113" num="0106">Then, in Step S<b>116</b>, the derivation unit <b>66</b> derives the set value of the tube voltage kV corresponding to the body thickness t of the subject W as described above. Specifically, the derivation unit <b>66</b> derives the set value of the tube voltage kV on the basis of the definition of the above-described Expression (3), using the subject information acquired in Step S<b>108</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0114" num="0107">Then, in Step S<b>118</b>, the derivation unit <b>66</b> derives the linear attenuation coefficient &#x3c1; corresponding to the set value of the tube voltage kV as described above. Specifically, the derivation unit <b>66</b> derives the linear attenuation coefficient &#x3c1; corresponding to the set value of the tube voltage kV, using the correspondence relationship between the set value of the tube voltage kV and the linear attenuation coefficient &#x3c1; stored in the storage unit <b>52</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0115" num="0108">Then, in Step S<b>120</b>, the derivation unit <b>66</b> derives the reference mAs value mAs_c as described above. Specifically, the derivation unit <b>66</b> derives the reference mAs value mAs_c on the basis of the definition of the above-described Expression (4).</p>
<p id="p-0116" num="0109">Then, in Step S<b>122</b>, the derivation unit <b>66</b> derives the set value of the mAs value as described above and then proceeds to Step S<b>128</b>. Specifically, the set value of the mAs value is derived on the basis of the definition of the above-described Expression (5), using the reference body thickness t_c specified in Step S<b>114</b>, the linear attenuation coefficient &#x3c1; derived in Step S<b>118</b>, and the reference mAs value mAs_c derived in Step S<b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0117" num="0110">On the other hand, in a case in which the imaging condition indicated by the condition information acquired in Step S<b>104</b> is the second condition in Step S<b>106</b>, the determination result in Step S<b>106</b> is &#x201c;Yes&#x201d;, and the process proceeds to Step S<b>124</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0118" num="0111">Then, in Step S<b>124</b>, the derivation unit <b>66</b> derives the set value of the mAs value as described above. Specifically, the reference mAs value mAs_c is derived as the set value of the mAs value.</p>
<p id="p-0119" num="0112">Then, in Step S<b>126</b>, the derivation unit <b>66</b> derives the set value of the tube voltage kV as described above and then proceeds to Step S<b>128</b>. Specifically, the derivation unit <b>66</b> derives the set value of the tube voltage kV corresponding to the body thickness t of the subject W and each parameter on the basis of the definition of the above-described Expression (6), with reference to the table corresponding to the imaging part stored in the storage unit <b>52</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0120" num="0113">In Step S<b>128</b>, the derivation unit <b>66</b> outputs the set value of the tube voltage kV and the set value of the mAs value to the radiation emitting device <b>12</b> through the I/F unit <b>54</b>. Then, in the radiation emitting device <b>12</b>, the tube voltage kV and the mAs value for emitting the radiation R are set. In a case in which the process in Step S<b>128</b> ends, the setting process illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> ends.</p>
<p id="p-0121" num="0114">As described above, the console <b>10</b> according to each of the above-described embodiments comprises the CPU <b>50</b>A as at least one processor. The CPU <b>50</b>A acquires the imaging part information indicating the imaging part of the subject W whose radiographic image is captured by the radiation R emitted from the radiation emitting device <b>12</b>. In addition, the CPU <b>50</b>A acquires the body thickness information indicating the body thickness t of the subject W in the direction in which the radiation R is transmitted. Further, the CPU <b>50</b>A acquires the condition information indicating whether the imaging condition set in the radiation emitting device <b>12</b> is the first condition in which the tube voltage value is a fixed value and the mAs value is a variable value, the second condition in which the tube voltage value is a variable value and the mAs value is a fixed value, or the third condition in which the tube voltage value is a variable value and the mAs value is a variable value. In addition, the CPU <b>50</b>A derives the set values of the tube voltage and the mAs value of the radiation emitting device <b>12</b> for emitting the radiation R such that the dose of the radiation transmitted through the imaging part is the same as the dose at the reference body thickness t_c, on the basis of the imaging part indicated by the imaging part information, the body thickness t indicated by the body thickness information, and the condition indicated by the condition information.</p>
<p id="p-0122" num="0115">As described above, the derivation unit <b>66</b> of the console <b>10</b> according to this embodiment derives the set values of the tube voltage and the mAs value of the radiation emitting device <b>12</b> for emitting the radiation R such that the dose of the radiation transmitted through the imaging part is the same as the dose at the reference body thickness t_c, on the basis of the imaging part indicated by the imaging part information, the body thickness t indicated by the body thickness information, and the condition indicated by the condition information.</p>
<p id="p-0123" num="0116">Therefore, according to the console <b>10</b> of this embodiment, it is possible to easily set appropriate tube voltage kV and mAs value corresponding to the imaging part and the body thickness t of the subject W for each imaging condition set in the radiation emitting device <b>12</b>. In addition, according to the console <b>10</b> of this embodiment, appropriate tube voltage kV and mAs value corresponding to the imaging part and the body thickness t of the subject W are automatically set. Therefore, it is possible to reduce the burden on the user for setting.</p>
<p id="p-0124" num="0117">In addition, in this embodiment, a method using the distance image captured by the TOF camera <b>14</b> has been described as the method by which the console <b>10</b> acquires the body thickness of the subject W. However, the present disclosure is not limited to this method. For example, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref>, the body thickness may be acquired by a body thickness measurement device <b>15</b> instead of the TOF camera <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0125" num="0118">For example, the body thickness measurement device <b>15</b> may be an imaging device that captures the distance image other than the TOF camera. For example, the following aspect may be used: a structured light method using an imaging device, which irradiates an object to be imaged with infrared light having a pattern and captures a distance image corresponding to reflected light from the object to be imaged, as the imaging device capturing the distance image is applied to capture the distance image. Further, for example, a depth-from-defocus (DFD) method that restores the distance on the basis of the degree of blurring of an edge region in the distance image may be applied. In the case of this aspect, for example, an aspect is known which uses a distance image captured by a monocular camera using a color aperture filter.</p>
<p id="p-0126" num="0119">In addition, for example, a measurement device that measures a distance to an object to be measured, using ultrasonic waves, laser light, or the like emitted to the object to be measured, is given as an example of the body thickness measurement device <b>15</b>. In this case, the second acquisition unit <b>62</b> acquires the measurement results of the STD and the SSD from the body thickness measurement device <b>15</b> and derives the body thickness t using the above-described Expression (1). Alternatively, the second acquisition unit <b>62</b> derives the body thickness t using the above-described Expression (2) on the basis of the SID, the TID, and the measurement result of the SSD acquired from the body thickness measurement device <b>15</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0127" num="0120">Further, for example, the body thickness measurement device <b>15</b> may be a caliper, a ruler, or the like. In this case, for example, an aspect may be used in which the user measures the body thickness of the subject W and inputs the measurement result using the operation unit <b>56</b> of the console <b>10</b>. Furthermore, in this aspect, in a case in which the caliper, the ruler, or the like has a transmission function of transmitting the measurement result wirelessly or in a wired manner, the measurement result measured by the user may be transmitted from the body thickness measurement device <b>15</b> to the console <b>10</b> by the transmission function.</p>
<p id="p-0128" num="0121">Moreover, for example, the body thickness measurement device <b>15</b> may be a visible light camera. The visible light camera is a so-called general camera and is a camera that captures a visible light image. Specifically, the visible light camera is a camera that receives visible light reflected by an object to be imaged using an imaging element and captures a visible light image on the basis of the received visible light. In this case, the visible light camera, which is the body thickness measurement device <b>15</b>, captures, for example, a visible light image of the subject W and the imaging table <b>32</b> from the side surface (the x direction in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>) of the subject W and the imaging table <b>32</b>. The second acquisition unit <b>62</b> may analyze the visible light image acquired from the body thickness measurement device <b>15</b> to derive the body thickness of the subject W.</p>
<p id="p-0129" num="0122">In addition, in each of the above-described embodiments, the aspect in which the console <b>10</b>, the radiation emitting device <b>12</b>, and the radiography apparatus <b>16</b> are stationary in the radiography system <b>1</b> has been described. However, the radiography system <b>1</b> is not limited to this aspect. For example, a mobile cart, that is, a nursing cart may be used as the radiography system <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0130" num="0123">Further, in each of the above-described embodiments, the aspect in which the console <b>10</b> is an example of the setting device according to the present disclosure has been described. However, devices other than the console <b>10</b> may have the functions of the setting device according to the present disclosure. In other words, for example, the radiation emitting device <b>12</b>, the radiography apparatus <b>16</b>, or an external device other than the console <b>10</b> may have some or all of the functions of the first acquisition unit <b>60</b>, the second acquisition unit <b>62</b>, the third acquisition unit <b>64</b>, and the derivation unit <b>66</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0131" num="0124">In addition, in each of the above-described embodiments, for example, the following various processors can be used as the hardware structure of processing units performing various processes such as the first acquisition unit <b>60</b>, the second acquisition unit <b>62</b>, the third acquisition unit <b>64</b>, and the derivation unit <b>66</b>. The various processors include, for example, a programmable logic device (PLD), such as a field programmable gate array (FPGA), that is a processor whose circuit configuration can be changed after manufacture and a dedicated electric circuit, such as an application specific integrated circuit (ASIC), that is a processor having a dedicated circuit configuration designed to perform a specific process, in addition to the CPU that is a general-purpose processor which executes software (programs) to function as various processing units as described above.</p>
<p id="p-0132" num="0125">One processing unit may be configured by one of the various processors or a combination of two or more processors of the same type or different types (for example, a combination of a plurality of FPGAs or a combination of a CPU and an FPGA). In addition, a plurality of processing units may be configured by one processor.</p>
<p id="p-0133" num="0126">A first example of the configuration in which a plurality of processing units are configured by one processor is an aspect in which one processor is configured by a combination of one or more CPUs and software and functions as a plurality of processing units. A representative example of this aspect is a client computer or a server computer. A second example of the configuration is an aspect in which a processor that implements the functions of the entire system including a plurality of processing units using one integrated circuit (IC) chip is used. A representative example of this aspect is a system-on-chip (SoC). As such, various processing units are configured by using one or more of the various processors as a hardware structure.</p>
<p id="p-0134" num="0127">In addition, specifically, an electric circuit (circuitry) obtained by combining circuit elements, such as semiconductor elements, can be used as the hardware structure of the various processors.</p>
<p id="p-0135" num="0128">Further, in each of the above-described embodiments, the aspect in which the setting program <b>51</b> is stored (installed) in the storage unit <b>52</b> in advance has been described. However, the present disclosure is not limited thereto. The setting program <b>51</b> may be recorded on a recording medium, such as a compact disc read only memory (CD-ROM), a digital versatile disc read only memory (DVD-ROM), or a universal serial bus (USB) memory, and then provided. In addition, the setting program <b>51</b> may be downloaded from an external device through the network.</p>
<p id="p-0136" num="0129">The disclosure of JP2020-161414 filed on Sep. 25, 2020 is incorporated herein by reference in its entirety.</p>
<p id="p-0137" num="0130">All of the documents, the patent applications, and the technical standards described in the specification are incorporated by reference herein to the same extent as it is specifically and individually stated that individual documents, patent applications, and technical standards are incorporated by reference.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A setting device comprising at least one processor, wherein the processor is configured to:
<claim-text>acquire imaging part information indicating an imaging part of a subject whose radiographic image is captured by radiation emitted from a radiation emitting device;</claim-text>
<claim-text>acquire body thickness information indicating a body thickness of the subject in a direction in which the radiation is transmitted;</claim-text>
<claim-text>acquire condition information indicating whether an imaging condition set in the radiation emitting device is a first condition in which a tube voltage value is a fixed value and a mAs value is a variable value, a second condition in which the tube voltage value is a variable value and the mAs value is a fixed value, or a third condition in which the tube voltage value is a variable value and the mAs value is a variable value; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>derive a set value of the tube voltage and a set value of the mAs value of the radiation emitting device for emitting the radiation such that a dose of the radiation transmitted through the imaging part is the same as a dose at a reference body thickness, on the basis of the imaging part indicated by the imaging part information, the body thickness indicated by the body thickness information, and the condition indicated by the condition information.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The setting device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the processor is configured to derive the set values using at least one of an SID, the imaging part, a filter added to a radiation source, a type of a radiation detector that detects the radiation, adjustment information related to adjustment of the tube voltage with respect to the body thickness, or a concentration in AEC.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The setting device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the reference body thickness is determined on the basis of at least one of the imaging part, a race, a gender, an age, or a ratio of muscle to fat in the subject, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the processor is configured to use a reference tube voltage corresponding to the reference body thickness as the adjustment information.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The setting device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein, in a case in which the condition indicated by the condition information is the first condition and the third condition, the processor is configured to derive the set value of the mAs value corresponding to the body thickness indicated by the body thickness information, using a linear attenuation coefficient for the tube voltage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The setting device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein, in a case in which the condition indicated by the condition information is the second condition, the processor is configured to derive the set value of the tube voltage on the basis of at least one of the imaging part indicated by the imaging part information, a reference tube voltage corresponding to the reference body thickness, or a filter added to a radiation source and the body thickness indicated by the body thickness information.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The setting device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the processor is configured to acquire the imaging part information from an imaging menu.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The setting device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the processor is configured to acquire the body thickness information by subtracting an SSD from an STD to derive the body thickness.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The setting device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the processor is configured to acquire the body thickness information by subtracting an SSD and a TID from an SID to derive the body thickness.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The setting device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the processor is configured to output the set value of the tube voltage and the set value of the mAs value to the radiation emitting device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. A setting method executed by a processor, the setting method comprising:
<claim-text>acquiring imaging part information indicating an imaging part of a subject whose radiographic image is captured by radiation emitted from a radiation emitting device;</claim-text>
<claim-text>acquiring body thickness information indicating a body thickness of the subject in a direction in which the radiation is transmitted;</claim-text>
<claim-text>acquiring condition information indicating whether an imaging condition set in the radiation emitting device is a first condition in which a tube voltage value is a fixed value and a mAs value is a variable value, a second condition in which the tube voltage value is a variable value and the mAs value is a fixed value, or a third condition in which the tube voltage value is a variable value and the mAs value is a variable value; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>deriving a set value of the tube voltage and a set value of the mAs value of the radiation emitting device for emitting the radiation such that a dose of the radiation transmitted through the imaging part is the same as a dose at a reference body thickness, on the basis of the imaging part indicated by the imaging part information, the body thickness indicated by the body thickness information, and the condition indicated by the condition information.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. A non-transitory computer-readable storage medium storing a setting program that causes a processor to execute a process comprising:
<claim-text>acquiring imaging part information indicating an imaging part of a subject whose radiographic image is captured by radiation emitted from a radiation emitting device;</claim-text>
<claim-text>acquiring body thickness information indicating a body thickness of the subject in a direction in which the radiation is transmitted;</claim-text>
<claim-text>acquiring condition information indicating whether an imaging condition set in the radiation emitting device is a first condition in which a tube voltage value is a fixed value and a mAs value is a variable value, a second condition in which the tube voltage value is a variable value and the mAs value is a fixed value, or a third condition in which the tube voltage value is a variable value and the mAs value is a variable value; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>deriving a set value of the tube voltage and a set value of the mAs value of the radiation emitting device for emitting the radiation such that a dose of the radiation transmitted through the imaging part is the same as a dose at a reference body thickness, on the basis of the imaging part indicated by the imaging part information, the body thickness indicated by the body thickness information, and the condition indicated by the condition information.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
