<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225249A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225249</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18155796</doc-number>
<date>20230118</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>45</main-group>
<subgroup>06</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>45</main-group>
<subgroup>065</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">CENTRIFUGAL ORBITAL FLOWER CUTTER WITH AN IRIS BLADE FOLLOWER</invention-title>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>63361730</doc-number>
<date>20220118</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Sullivan</last-name>
<first-name>John Timothy</first-name>
<address>
<city>Marriottsville</city>
<state>MD</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Sullivan</last-name>
<first-name>John Timothy</first-name>
<address>
<city>Marriottsville</city>
<state>MD</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A harvester for removing cannabis flower from stalks includes a blade follower iris that adjusts the size of the flower-stripping opening to correspond to the diameter of the stalk. The size of the opening may be controlled by centrifugal and spring forces that cause the iris to open and close. In addition, an improved stalk-pulling belt drive conveyor system utilizes two relatively floating, releasably coupled belt systems to pinch and pull the stalk through the blade follower iris.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="111.68mm" wi="151.55mm" file="US20230225249A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="225.64mm" wi="148.93mm" file="US20230225249A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="235.80mm" wi="172.64mm" file="US20230225249A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="224.28mm" wi="143.34mm" file="US20230225249A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="224.62mm" wi="171.70mm" file="US20230225249A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="201.93mm" wi="127.34mm" file="US20230225249A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="225.38mm" wi="138.26mm" file="US20230225249A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="230.46mm" wi="187.37mm" file="US20230225249A1-20230720-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="235.12mm" wi="176.53mm" file="US20230225249A1-20230720-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="225.81mm" wi="176.61mm" file="US20230225249A1-20230720-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="226.23mm" wi="172.55mm" file="US20230225249A1-20230720-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="223.10mm" wi="147.24mm" file="US20230225249A1-20230720-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00012" num="00012">
<img id="EMI-D00012" he="229.53mm" wi="128.52mm" file="US20230225249A1-20230720-D00012.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00013" num="00013">
<img id="EMI-D00013" he="232.66mm" wi="154.60mm" file="US20230225249A1-20230720-D00013.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims the benefit of U.S. Provisional Patent Appl. Ser. Nos. 63/361,730, filed Jan. 18, 2022, and 63/xxx,xxx, filed Nov. 20, 2022.</p>
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="tail"?>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">1. Field of the Invention</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">This invention relates to an apparatus removing for cannabis flowers from the stem, stalk, or branches (hereinafter referred to as the &#x201c;stalk&#x201d; of a cannabis plant. The apparatus of the invention eliminates disadvantages of a conventional bucking machine, including the need for an operator to match the stalk to select an appropriately sized hole in the bucking machine.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">2. Description of Related Art</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The process of removing cannabis flowers from the stalk is very labor-intensive. The flower removal process requires the operator to cut the flowers from the stem, stalk, or branch using hand labor scissors or something called a bucking machine.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The conventional bucking machine consists of a metal, wood, or plastic plate with several different holes in the plate. The operator must look at the stalk in their hand and try to match the diameter of the stalk to the hole size that is the closest match to the stalk diameter. The stalk is then pulled through the hole by two rubber drive wheels that frictionally engage the stalk, causing the flower to be stripped from the stalk as it pulled through the selected hole.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The need for hole size matching has the disadvantage that it is time-consuming and requires a great deal of skill and concentration on the part of the operator. If the hole is too small, the stalk will not fit in the hole and the flower cannot be removed, but If the operator places a small stalk in a large hole, the flower will be pulled through the hole with the stalk and be destroyed.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In addition, conventional bucking machines have the disadvantage that the use of two rubber drive wheels to pull the stalk through the fixed diameter holes destroys the natural shape of the flower, reducing the go-to-market value of the flower. Moreover, the biomass removed by pulling the stalk through the hole leaves a sticky residue on the rollers that is difficult to remove, exacerbating the problem that the pinch point where the rollers deform under compression exerts a drag on rotation that requires a lot of energy to overcome. If the stalk is too large in diameter, the gear that rotates the drive wheels will stall, so that the operator must put the motor in reverse to unclog the stalk jammed between the rollers, causing delays in the flower removal process.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The problems of compressing, snatching, ripping, and tearing the flower from the stalk with an improperly sized hole, damage to the shape of the flower even when the hole is properly sized, removal of sticky residue, and clogging of the machine dues to jamming of stalks during flower removal, have not been solved until now.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">It is accordingly a first objective of the invention to provide an apparatus that overcomes the disadvantages of conventional cannabis-flower-removing bucking machines or harvesters without the need for additional labor, by providing a bucking machine in which the stalk stripping opening by an iris blade follower mechanism that automatically matches hole size to stalk diameter, so that the stalk is pulled through the machine and the flower removed without destroying or affecting the natural shape of the flower.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Additional objectives of the invention include (i) provision of a cannabis flower removing apparatus that is convenient to operate and maintain, (ii) reduction in clogging and build-up of sticky residue on the stalk pulling mechanism to avoid the need for frequent reversals of the stalk pulling mechanism and delays in the flower removal process, (iii) provision for easy tool-free disassembly for cleaning, and/or (iv) enabling adjustments to compensate for wear and tear.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">These and other objectives of the invention are achieved by providing a harvester in which the stalk-stripping mechanism includes an iris consisting of centrifugal spring-loaded cutting blades that form an opening whose size increases in response to a spring force when the cutting blade assembly is rotated at a slow speed or when the rotation is stopped, and whose size decreases at high rotation speeds as centrifugal forces overcome the spring force. The centrifugal force that opens and closes the blades can be adjusted by adjusting the rotation speeds and depends on fixed or adjustable weights included in the cutting blade assembly. The size of the opening depends on the relative position of cutting or stripping edges of the two cutting blades, which in an exemplary embodiment of the invention are the edges of overlapping holes in the two plates, the degree of overlap changing with the centrifugal force on the plates to vary the size of the hole.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In the exemplary embodiment, each plate has a hole and the opening changes from round to oval as the plates are moved to a closed position in response to increasing rotation speed, although it will be appreciated that an iris effect can also be achieved with an arrangement in which one of the plates has a hole and the other plate has a corresponding curved edge that overlaps the hole. The hole(s) may optionally be serrated or undercut to increase a sharpness of the edges.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The plates are preferably coupled to a rotating, motor-driven hub by bearings that allow relative pivoting of the plates during rotation in response to the centrifugal forces caused the by rotation, which movement stops limiting the pivoting movement at high rotation speeds. The movement stops may be defined by guide slots in the plates and corresponding posts in the rotating hub.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">As the centrifugal forces resulting from rotation of the cutting mechanism overcome the spring tension, the pair of pivotal plates move outward in opposite directions to cause edges of the opening to move inwardly and form an ellipse of increasing eccentricity that pinches the stalk surface 180 degrees apart. The use of bearing followers to achieve the rotation and pivoting prevents the countersink rotation plate or cutting blades from cutting into the stalk, while achieving a chisel effect at the flower's apex where it is joined to the branch. As a result, the countersink rotating plate or cutting blades will only cut flowers and branches projecting outward from the surface of the stalk, in a manner similar to a razor blade trimming facial hair without cutting the skin. Pivoting of the countersink rotating plate or movement of the spring-loaded cutting blade holder in a reverse direction under either compression or extension spring forces returns the iris stem follower aperture formed by the overlapping holes to an open position when the rotational speed of the motor is lowered</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Because the countersink rotating plate or opposing branch followers are provided on a bearing follower to float as they pinch 180 degrees of the stalk in rotation, the ellipse shaped pinch hole is allowed to constantly adjust with the continually changing shape and thickness of the branch as it is being pulled through the cutter assembly. The amount of pinch friction applied to the stalk can be adjusted by adjusting motor rotation speeds, the weight of plate or blade mounting weight, or compression or extension spring loading.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In addition to the above described cutting mechanism, the exemplary embodiments of the invention provide for a timing belt or conveyor belt drive system that is used to pull the stalk through the stalk stripping opening and into the harvester. The drive system employs two or more adjustable turnbuckles to adjust the tension of individual drive belts and a third adjustable turnbuckle that applies a spring-loaded force tension between timing or conveyor belts and a drive pull belt. A floating bearing assembly moves up and down in linear slots of the belts while applying spring-loaded forces between the two belts with one of the belts being fixed in a position. The other drive belt floats between the two drive pull belts to pull a branch, or both belts float in a linear bearing track with spring tension on both sides to pinch a stalk and drag the biomass into the cutter assembly.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The stalk pulling conveyor belts have a bearing system with a male and female cavity to allow the top or bottom belt to move while one belt is fixed. A wiper is placed between the two belts to prevent debris from getting caught between the sidetracks of the belts to prevent a clog. The wiper can be a mating male and female cavity or a fixed strip of a plastic or metal strip. A toggle spring loaded tension on either side of the two belts to creates a force on the stalk being pulled by the two drive belts that are controlled by a speed controller. The cutting assembly is mounted on a door with a hinge that allows access to the belts that operate inside of the rotating cutting assembly.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The speed of the rotating blades can be controlled with an electrical input to control predetermined or variable speed controls by adjusting the belt or roller pull speeds relative to the rotating speeds of the cutter to optimized the cut of the flower without snatching the flower from the stem. The electrical input to control cutting blade rotation can be provided by a foot switch, optical sensor or mechanical sensor that communicates with the motor controller. The motor the drives the cutter can be a belt driven motor or hub-less motor with a hollow shaft. The conveyor pull belts are extended through the bearing assembly or hub-less motor to minimize the length of the stem needed to engage with the stem to pull it through the cutters. In addition, the rotation of the cutting plates or blades can be controlled by a loadcell on the bearing assembly, or an on/off timer that spins the cutting blades at a predetermined amount of time after the presence of a stalk is sensed, before the blades open again by stopping rotation or slowing the cutting mechanism rotation speed.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In order to compensate for stretching and position changes in the drive belt over time due to wear and abuse, the cutter rotating assembly may be mounted on a leadscrew stage to adjust the gap between the input of the cutter housing and the drive belts as they stretch and change position.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In addition, in order to facilitate cleaning and unclogging of the cutter assembly, the drive system of the exemplary embodiment may be taken apart without tools. The drive system is assembled using three adjustable toggle clamps, two of which take the slack adjustment out of the top and bottom motor driven belt pulleys. A third toggle clamp is used to apply a spring-loaded compression force between a fixed bottom belt drive assembly and the floating top belt drive assembly. The top belt floats on four roller bearings in a mating slot allowing the top spring-loaded to move up and down to accommodate the different stalk sizes. Each belt is driven by two different motors or a chain of pulley systems that uses one motor. One electrical resistive trip pot may be provided to synchronously control the exact motor speed of both motors. When all three toggle clamps are released, the two drive pull belts are easily removed for cleaning or replacement.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Cleaning and service may be further facilitated by arranging the system's front door on hinges to open the cabinet. Safety interlocks turn the motors off when any of the doors are opened.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Finally, in a second exemplary embodiment of the invention, the pivoting cutting blades of plates of the first exemplary embodiment may be replaced by a predetermined stacked weighted cutter having spring loaded return arms with wheels to reduce friction. In this embodiment, the stacked weights produce enough centrifugal forces to compress a return spring (not shown) when the cutting housing not shown is spinning.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is an isometric front view of cutting blade assembly according to a first exemplary embodiment of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is an isometric rear view of the cutting blade assembly of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> as a stalk is being pulled through the cutting assembly.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> Is n isometric front view of the cutting blade assembly of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> and <b>2</b></figref> as the stalk is pulled through the cutting assembly.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> Is a cut-way side view of flowers and stem <b>40</b> being inserted the cutting assembly of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>-<b>3</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> Is an isometric front view of a cutter and bearing housing that contains the cutting assembly of the first exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is an isometric front view of the housing of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> shown with the stationary guard and funnel illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> removed.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> is a second cut-way side view of the cutting blade assembly of the first exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> Is a cut away top view of a cutter assembly and drive belt system according to the first exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref> is a front view showing a funnel and closing top and blades <b>1</b>,<b>2</b> according to the first exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref> is a front view corresponding to the front view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref> in which the blades <b>1</b>,<b>2</b> have been moved to an open position.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b></figref> is an isometric view of a rotating cutting flower harvester that includes the cutting assembly and housing of the first exemplary embodiment of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>12</b></figref> is an isometric view of the flower cutter of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>12</b></figref> with the door <b>87</b> open.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>13</b></figref> is a cut away top view of an adjustable drive belt assembly with belt discharge wipers according to the first exemplary embodiment of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>14</b></figref> is a top view of a stem <b>113</b> and cut flower <b>114</b> being moved by the drive belt assembly of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>13</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>15</b></figref> is a cut away top view of the rotating cutting flower harvester of the exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>16</b></figref> is an isometric view of the rotating flower cutter and motors without the stationary guard and funnel of the first exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>17</b></figref> is an isometric rear view of the flower harvester of the first exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>18</b></figref> is another isometric side view of the flower harvester of the first exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>19</b></figref> is an isometric front view of top and bottom stalk pulling assemblies according to the first exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>20</b></figref> is an isometric front view further illustrating the stalk pulling assemblies of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>19</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>21</b></figref> is an isometric side view of the stalk pulling assemblies of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>19</b> and <b>20</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>22</b></figref> is an isometric side view of an opposite side of the stalk pulling assemblies shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>21</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>23</b></figref> is a front view of the stalk pulling assemblies of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>19</b>-<b>22</b></figref> after removal for cleaning.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>24</b></figref> is an isometric view of the removed stalk pulling assemblies of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>23</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>25</b></figref> is an isometric view of cutting assembly according to a second exemplary embodiment of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>26</b></figref> is a front view of a harvester that includes the cutting assembly of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>25</b></figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>-<b>7</b></figref> show the cutting assembly of a harvester for removing cannabis flowers and leaves from a stalk, stem, or branch in accordance with the principles of a first exemplary embodiment of the invention. The cutting assembly includes two centrifugal cutting plates or blades <b>1</b>,<b>2</b>, each including a respective weight <b>3</b>,<b>4</b> and circular cutting hole <b>19</b>,<b>20</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, the cutting holes are aligned to form a circular opening for receiving a stalk <b>21</b>, while <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> shows that the cutting blades <b>1</b>,<b>2</b> have moved apart as a result of centrifugal force, applied in the manner described below, so that the circular holes <b>19</b>,<b>20</b> in the respective cutting blades <b>1</b>,<b>2</b> are offset and their intersection forms a reduced-size elliptical opening or aperture whose minor axis corresponds to a diameter of the stalk <b>21</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Each cutting blade <b>1</b>,<b>2</b> includes bearings <b>16</b>,<b>18</b> for receiving bearing posts <b>15</b>,<b>17</b> fixed to a rotatable hub <b>52</b> such that rotational motion of the hub is transmitted to through the bearing posts <b>15</b>,<b>17</b> to the cutting blades <b>1</b>,<b>2</b> to enable the entire cutting assembly to rotate about a central axis of the cutting assembly. As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>, the rotating hub <b>52</b> is fixed to and rotated by a pulley <b>44</b> having a belt groove <b>54</b>. The centrifugal rotating cutting blades <b>1</b>,<b>2</b> are spring loaded by springs <b>13</b>,<b>14</b> attached at one end to the respective cutting blades <b>1</b>,<b>2</b> and at the other end to posts <b>11</b>,<b>12</b> that are fixed to the rotating hub assembly. Cutting blades <b>1</b>,<b>2</b> further include slots <b>7</b>,<b>8</b> through which posts <b>5</b>,<b>6</b> connected to the hub <b>52</b> extend to respectively guide pivoting of the cutting blades <b>1</b>,<b>2</b> relative to the hub in directions <b>5</b>,<b>6</b> as the entire cutting assembly is rotated. As explained below, pivoting of the cutting blades <b>1</b>,<b>2</b> relative to the rotating hub is the result of a spring force that causes the cutting blades <b>1</b>,<b>2</b> to pivot about the bearing posts <b>15</b>,<b>17</b> in a direction that increases the size of the stalk stripping opening or iris formed by the intersection of cutting holes <b>19</b>,<b>20</b>, and a centrifugal force the causes the cutting blades <b>1</b>,<b>2</b> to move in a direction that decreases the size of the stalk stripping opening.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>-<b>3</b></figref>, the stem <b>21</b> of flowers (and/or leaves) <b>22</b> being cut is inserted into an opening that is formed by overlapping holes <b>19</b>,<b>20</b> when cutting blade <b>1</b> is pivoted in a counterclockwise direction, as viewed in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> from the front of the cutting assembly, and cutting blade <b>2</b> is pivoted in a clockwise direction as viewed in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>. It will be appreciated that a corresponding iris effect could also be achieved by just pivoting one of the cutting blades <b>1</b>, <b>2</b>, while the other of the cutting blades <b>1</b>,<b>2</b> is fixed relative to the rotating hub. Pivoting to the open position results from the action of springs <b>13</b>,<b>14</b>, which overcome the reduced or zero centrifugal force at lower rotating speeds or when the motor that applies the centrifugal force is stopped. When the rotating speeds are increased, the centrifugal forces on weights <b>3</b>,<b>4</b> overcome the spring tension provided by springs <b>13</b>,<b>14</b>, causing the blades <b>1</b>,<b>2</b> to move in an opposite direction to reduce the size of the opening around the stem, so that the opening is closed on the stem <b>21</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> and the flowers or leaves <b>37</b> are cut off a section <b>37</b><i>a </i>of the stem <b>21</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, by the edges of respective holes <b>19</b>,<b>20</b> as the stem <b>21</b> is pushed into the opening by an operator (not shown). The edges of one or both of the respective holes <b>19</b>,<b>20</b> may optionally be countersunk to produce a sharper cutting edge. Irrespective of whether a sharper edge is provided, the cutting blades use a chisel effect to strip the flowers <b>22</b> from the stalk <b>21</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>-<b>7</b></figref> illustrate a housing for the blade assembly including the overlapping cutting blades <b>1</b>,<b>2</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>-<b>3</b></figref>. The stalk <b>21</b> with flowers is inserted into a stationary funnel <b>46</b> mounted on a stationary plate <b>41</b>, and into the stalk-stripping opening or iris formed by overlapping holes <b>19</b>,<b>20</b> in the cutting blades <b>1</b>,<b>2</b>. After being stripped by the stalk stripping opening or iris, the stripped stalk <b>21</b> passes through an opening in rotating mounting plate <b>52</b><i>a, </i>which is fixed to and rotatable with the hub <b>52</b>, and then passes into the hollow interior of hub <b>52</b>, into which a stalk-pulling dual belt system extends, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>8</b>, <b>13</b>, and <b>14</b></figref>. Bearing posts <b>15</b>,<b>17</b> extend from and rotate with the rotating mounting plate <b>52</b><i>a. </i>The hub <b>52</b> is rotatably mounted to a fixed housing <b>43</b> of the cutting assembly by bearings <b>45</b>. The entire assembly, including the rotating hub <b>52</b> is rotated by the drive pulley <b>44</b>, which includes a Vee cut slot <b>54</b> for a drive built <b>75</b>, illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref>. The pulley <b>44</b> has a pass-through hole <b>53</b> for the dual drive stalk-pulling belting, described below.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">The speed of the rotating cutting blades can be controlled with an electrical input to control predetermined or variable speed controls by adjusting the belt or roller pull speeds relative to the rotating speeds of the cutter to optimized the cut of the flower without snatching the flower from the stem. The electrical input to control cutting blade rotation can be provided by a foot switch, optical sensor or mechanical sensor (not shown) that communicates with the motor controller. The motor <b>78</b> that drives the cutter can be a belt driven motor, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>17</b></figref>, or optionally a hub-less motor with a hollow shaft. The conveyor pull belts are extended through the bearing assembly or hub-less motor to minimize the length of the stem needed to engage with the stem to pull it through the cutters. In addition, the rotation of the cutting plates or blades <b>1</b>,<b>2</b> can be controlled by a loadcell on the bearing assembly, or an on/off timer that spins the cutting blades <b>1</b>,<b>2</b> at a predetermined amount of time after the presence of a stalk <b>21</b> is sensed, before the cutting blades <b>1</b>,<b>2</b> open again by stopping rotation or slowing the cutting mechanism rotation speed.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">It will be appreciated by those skilled in the art that when the stalk <b>21</b> is pulled to a position <b>65</b><i>a </i>at which an apex flower <b>65</b> is attached to the stalk, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>5</b> and <b>6</b></figref>, the iris or opening formed by holes <b>19</b>,<b>20</b> in cutting blades <b>1</b>,<b>2</b> must pinch the stalk in such a way that the flowers will be cut at the apex where the flower stem meets the stalk. In addition, the edges of the iris or opening must be sufficiently sharp to cut through branches <b>66</b> at the point <b>66</b><i>a </i>wherein the branches <b>66</b> meet the stalk without cutting into the stalk itself. Appropriate pinching and cutting forces can be controlled by controlling the rotating speed of the cutting assembly and the speed at which the stalk <b>21</b> is pulled through the cutting assembly.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref>, a stalk-pulling conveyer belt system extends into the rotating hub <b>52</b> to pinch and pull the stalk through the iris opening in the cutting assembly. The stalk-pulling conveyor includes a conveyor drive belt assembly <b>73</b> inside of the rotating hub <b>74</b>. A toggle spring tensioner (described below) applies tension to the conveyor belt assembly <b>73</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref> shows the funnel <b>69</b> with the top cutting blade <b>20</b> closing in the direction of <b>81</b><i>a </i>and the bottom cutting blade <b>19</b> closing in the direction of <b>81</b><i>b </i>to create the closing iris scrape blade. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref> shows the iris in an open position after the blades <b>1</b>,<b>2</b> have been moved in the direction of arrows <b>83</b><i>a </i>and <b>83</b><i>b </i>by the spring force applied <b>13</b>,<b>14</b> after the rotational speed of motor <b>78</b> has been reduced to reduce the centrifugal force on the cutting blades <b>1</b>,<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>11</b> and <b>12</b></figref> show a complete assembly of the harvester of the exemplary embodiment, which includes the cutting assembly of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>-<b>10</b></figref>. The harvester includes a mounting frame <b>88</b>, discharge chute <b>89</b>, motor controllers <b>90</b><i>d, </i>and a door <b>87</b> door with a hinge <b>78</b><i>a. </i>The cutting assembly is collectively denoted by reference numeral <b>86</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">In the position shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>12</b></figref>, the door <b>87</b> is open. The cutter assembly drive motor <b>78</b> drives belt <b>75</b> to rotate the cutting assembly, as described above. The harvester also includes a discharge stem cutter motor <b>91</b> and upper and lower drive belt assemblies <b>99</b>,<b>100</b> including stalk pulling drive belts <b>95</b>,<b>96</b> and stalk pulling drive belt motors <b>97</b>,<b>98</b>. Each of the motors is controlled by a controller (not shown) in controller box <b>90</b>. A biomass waste cutter <b>92</b> is provided to cut biomass that has been pulled through the cutting assembly into smaller particles with a rotating blade for discharge through the chute <b>89</b> for storage or reduced volume and improved trash removal.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>13</b></figref> is a cut-way view of the elongated drive belt assembly <b>99</b>,<b>100</b> driven by belt drive motors <b>97</b>,<b>98</b> for pulling the stalk through the opening in the cutter assembly. The stalk pulling assembly further includes belt discharge wipers <b>105</b>,<b>106</b> for scraping sticky debris from respective belts <b>76</b>,<b>77</b>, and belt tension adjustors <b>101</b>,<b>102</b> for compensating for changes in belt tension due to wear. Also shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>13</b></figref> are a stationary plate <b>46</b> which forms the stalk input funnel <b>69</b>, the belt pinch position <b>109</b>, and idle pullies <b>107</b>,<b>108</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>14</b> and <b>15</b></figref> show a stem <b>21</b> and cut flower <b>37</b>, at a point where the stem <b>21</b> is being pinched between and pulled by the two independent belt assemblies <b>99</b>,<b>100</b> through the cutter opening formed by the overlapping blades <b>1</b>,<b>2</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>19</b>-<b>24</b></figref>, one of the belt pulling assemblies <b>100</b> is mounted on bearings <b>131</b> that slide in U-slots <b>130</b> fixed to the other belt pulling assembly <b>99</b>, as shown <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>19</b>,<b>20</b></figref>. The bearings <b>131</b> are held in U-shots <b>130</b> by springs <b>137</b> and toggle clamps <b>139</b>, shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>21</b></figref>, so that the belt pulling assembly <b>100</b> floats with respect to the belt-pulling assembly <b>99</b> and allows the pinch point between the respective belts to change shape in response to varying thickness of the stalk as it is pulled through the opening in the cutter assembly by the stalk pulling belt drive motors <b>97</b>,<b>98</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>18</b></figref> shows a door <b>126</b>, frame <b>127</b> and cover mount <b>127</b><i>a. </i>Toggle clamp <b>139</b> hooks onto spring <b>13</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>21</b></figref>, to releasably couple one side of the two stalk-pulling belt assemblies <b>99</b>,<b>100</b>. Release of the toggle clamp <b>139</b> allows the springs <b>137</b> to be unhooked from the toggle clamp to uncouple the stem pulling belt assemblies and allow bearings <b>131</b> to be disengaged from U-shaped slots <b>129</b>,<b>130</b> and allow the stalk-pulling belt drive assemblies to be separated for cleaning, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>23</b> and <b>24</b></figref>. Also shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>21</b> and <b>22</b></figref> are a belt slack adjustment idlers <b>140</b>,<b>141</b>, which can be used to compensate for stretching of the belts with age, and drive belt assembly <b>142</b>,<b>143</b> that extend into the rotating hub <b>52</b> to pinch and pull a stalk that has just been stripped.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>22</b></figref> shows a toggle clamp <b>145</b> for releasably coupling the opposite side of the stalk pulling belt assemblies via a tension spring <b>144</b> mounted to a post <b>144</b><i>a. </i>Additional male and female wipers <b>148</b>,<b>149</b> and <b>146</b>,<b>147</b> prevent debris from getting between the two drive assembles. In addition, a top and bottom belt puller with male protrusion <b>152</b> and mating female groove <b>150</b> is provided, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>23</b></figref>, to prevent debris from getting between the two top and bottom belt stem pullers during harvesting operation.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>25</b></figref> shows a second exemplary embodiment of the invention, in which the harvester includes a predetermined stacked weighted cutter with spring loaded return arms <b>157</b>,<b>159</b> with wheels <b>158</b> to reduce friction. The stacked weights <b>168</b> produce enough centrifugal forces to compress a return spring (not shown) when the cutting housing not shown is spinning.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>26</b></figref> is a front view of the harvester of the second exemplary embodiment, including a bearing housing <b>165</b> and hub <b>164</b>, with the two cutting blades <b>1</b>,<b>2</b> <b>162</b>,<b>164</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>25</b></figref>. The mechanical stops <b>160</b>,<b>161</b> stop against the inner hub <b>164</b> that is rotating within the bearing housing <b>165</b> that is stationary. The funnel <b>166</b> rotates with the blades <b>1</b>,<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">In both the first and second exemplary embodiments, the precise cutting ability can be adjusted mechanically from the offset of the blade to the edge of the blade follower that is touching the stalk. In each of the exemplary embodiments, the operator of the centrifugal flower cutter may trigger a sensor such as a foot pedal switch or optical switch to send a signal to the motor controller to slow down the blade assembly rotation speed or RPM to a preprogrammed rotation speed or stop. Once the two blade followers have assumed the shape of a hole, the operator or robot arm inserts the stalk into the follower hole. Once the tip of the most significant dimeter end of the branch is inserted, the operator or robot releases the foot pedal or the optical switch changes state to cause the motor controller to increase the rotation speed and capture the stalk between the two or more follower plates or cutting blades, which form the elliptical opening to pinch the stalk. The blade assembly increases the rotation speed that close the pinch follower and align the cutting blade within 0.01 to 0.250 inches from the stalk by the mounting hole spacing between the blade holder and the stalk.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">Although a number of embodiments of the invention have been described in detail in connection with the accompanying drawings, it will be appreciated that modifications of the illustrated embodiments may be made without departing from the scope of the invention. For example, the stalk-stripping iris assembly may include an iris follower that includes a fixed plate with a hole and countersink rotating plate rather that the illustrated pivotal top and bottom plates with cutting blades <b>1</b>,<b>2</b>, each having a circular hole and a bearing surface against which a force is applied to pivot the plates. In addition, the use of centrifugal force may be replaced by a system that using electromagnetic forces to pivot the cutting blades and change the size of the stalk-stripping opening. If the cutting assembly is electromagnetically actuated, the cutter assembly follower's electromagnetic coils can be placed around the spinning non-magnetic housing to activate a steel holder using magnetic forces at the while the cutter assemble is spinning to open or close the follower while the cutter assemblies are spinning. Still further, the belt drive for rotating the cutting assembly may be replaced by a hub-less motor with a hollow shaft.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">These and other variations or modifications are intended to be included within the scope of the invention and, as a result, the invention is not to be limited by the above description or the accompanying drawings, but rather is to be defined solely in accordance with the appended claims.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. Apparatus for stripping cannabis flower from a stem, branch, or stalk of a cannabis plant, comprising:
<claim-text>a cutting assembly that includes at least two movable plates that cooperate to form an opening through which the stem, branch, or stalk is pulled, wherein edges of the opening engage the stem, branch, or stalk to cut the cannabis flower from the stem, branch or stalk, wherein movement of the plates in response to a first force in first diametrically opposed direction increases a size of the opening, and wherein movement of the two movable plates in second diametrically opposed directions opposite the first diametrically opposed directions in response to a second force overcomes the first force to decrease the size of the opening until edges of the opening engage the stem, branch or stalk as it is pulled through the opening;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a stalk pulling assembly that includes at least two stalk pulling conveyor belt systems including conveyor belts configured to pinch the stalk, stem, or branch, wherein a first of the two conveyor belt systems floats relative to a second of the two conveyor belt systems to enable a spacing between the belts at a pinch point to vary with a diameter of the stalk, stem, or branch.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. Apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first force is a spring force and the second force is a centrifugal force caused by weights fixed to the plates and rotation of a hub to which the two movable plates are pivotally mounted, movement of the plates in response to the spring and centrifugal forces being limited by movement of posts in respective guide slots.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. Apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the opening through which the stalk, stem, or branch is pulled is formed by the intersection of overlapping circular holes in the two plates to form an elliptical opening that increases in eccentricity as the plates are moved in said second diametrically opposed directions.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. Apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein edges of said holes include undercuts to increase a sharpness of the edges that engage the stalk, stem, or branch to strip the cannabis flower.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. Apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the two movable plates are coupled to the rotating hub by bearings that serve to transmit the rotational motion of the hub to the plates, and that enable the plates to pivot about the bearings by an amount determined by the difference between opposing centrifugal and spring forces as the speed of rotation is varied.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. Apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the floating first conveyor belt system includes bearing posts that slide within U-shaped grooves extending transversely to the first conveyor belt, and wherein a steady pinching force is applied by at least one tension spring that couples the two conveyor belt systems.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. Apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the springs are releasably connected to one of the two conveyor belt systems by toggle clamps that enable the two conveyor belt systems to be separated from each other for cleaning.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. Apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising wipers that slidably engage the conveyor belts to remove debris from the belts.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. Apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the two conveyor belt systems include adjustable belt tensioning pulleys to compensate for stretching of the belts with age.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. Apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising two motors for driving the two conveyor belt systems.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. Apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a motor for driving a pulley coupled to the hub to rotate the cutting assembly including the two cutting plates.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. Apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the motor drives the hub-rotating pulley through a belt.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. Apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein rotation of the cutting assembly is initiated by a mechanical or optical sensor that senses entry of a stalk, stem, or branch into the opening, or by an operator-controlled switch.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. Apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the cutting assembly is mounted on a door that allows access to both the cutting assembly and the conveyor belts.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. Apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein a friction between the cutting edges on the plates and the stalk, stem, or branch is determined by a rotation speed of the cutting assembly and a pulling speed of the two conveyor belt systems.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. Apparatus for stripping cannabis flower from a stem, branch, or stalk of a cannabis plant, comprising:
<claim-text>a cutting assembly that includes an iris for adjusting a size of an opening through which the stem, branch, or stalk is pulled to strip the cannabis flower;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a stalk pulling assembly that includes at least two stalk pulling conveyor belt systems including conveyor belts configured to pinch the stalk, stem, or branch and pull it through the cutting assembly, wherein a first of the two conveyor belt systems floats relative to a second of the two conveyor belt systems to enable a spacing between the belts at a pinch point to vary with a diameter of the stalk, stem, or branch.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. Apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the floating first conveyor belt system includes bearing posts that slide within U-shaped grooves extending transversely to the first conveyor belt, and wherein a steady pinching force is applied by at least one tension spring that couples the two conveyor belt systems.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. Apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein the springs are releasably connected to one of the two conveyor belt systems by toggle clamps that enable the two conveyor belt systems to be separated from each other for cleaning.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. Apparatus for stripping cannabis flower from a stem, branch, or stalk of a cannabis plant, comprising:
<claim-text>a cutting assembly that includes at least two movable plates that cooperate to form an opening through which the stem, branch, or stalk is pulled, wherein edges of the opening engage the stem, branch, or stalk to cut the cannabis flower from the stem, branch or stalk, wherein movement of the plates in response to a first force in first diametrically opposed direction increases a size of the opening, and wherein movement of the two movable plates in second diametrically opposed directions opposite the first diametrically opposed directions in response to a second force overcomes the first force to decrease the size of the opening until edges of the opening engage the stem, branch or stalk as it is pulled through the opening.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. Apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein the first force is a spring force and the second force is a centrifugal force caused by weights fixed to the plates and rotation of a hub to which the two movable plates are pivotally mounted, movement of the plates in response to the spring and centrifugal forces being limited by movement of posts in respective guide slots.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
