<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225597A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225597</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17964962</doc-number>
<date>20221013</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>17</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2022-007122</doc-number>
<date>20220120</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>012</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>005</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>012</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>005</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>0008</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e61">ENDOSCOPIC IMAGING DEVICE AND ENDOSCOPE</invention-title>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>JAPAN LIFELINE CO., LTD.</orgname>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>KODAMA</last-name>
<first-name>Yuki</first-name>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A cholangioscope includes a catheter that is to be inserted into a body and has a curved shape, a camera shaft that can be inserted into the catheter and is formed in a curved shape, and a CMOS image sensor that is provided at a distal end portion of the camera shaft. The catheter further includes a forceps channel into which a medical instrument can be inserted, and a camera channel that is provided in an outer side portion of the catheter having the curved shape outer than the forceps channel and into which the camera shaft can be inserted. Curvature of the camera shaft is less than curvature of the catheter. The camera shaft is formed into a curved shape by using a shape memory alloy.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="32.94mm" wi="133.35mm" file="US20230225597A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="232.83mm" wi="96.77mm" file="US20230225597A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="172.80mm" wi="90.59mm" file="US20230225597A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="179.58mm" wi="129.12mm" file="US20230225597A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="237.15mm" wi="71.54mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225597A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="148.34mm" wi="152.82mm" file="US20230225597A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="161.37mm" wi="152.74mm" file="US20230225597A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="230.63mm" wi="95.67mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225597A1-20230720-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="194.14mm" wi="85.34mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225597A1-20230720-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="233.51mm" wi="151.30mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225597A1-20230720-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="208.36mm" wi="103.97mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225597A1-20230720-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention relates to an endoscopic imaging device and the like that is included in an endoscope.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND ART</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Patent Literature 1 discloses an endoscopic imaging device (camera) with an imaging element provided at the distal end portion of a camera shaft, which can be separated from a catheter (hereinafter also referred to as a sheath) into which the camera shaft can be inserted. An endoscope includes the catheter equipped with the endoscopic imaging device, and the imaging element exposed at the distal end portion of the camera shaft inserted into the body together with the catheter images an image of a diagnostic site or a treatment site in the body. After use, the endoscopic imaging device can be detached from the sheath, which is typically used once, and can be reused with other sheaths of the same type within a predetermined number of times of use. By reusing an expensive endoscopic imaging device (or an imaging element), the cost per procedure can be significantly reduced.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">CITATION LIST</heading>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">Patent Literature</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Patent Literature 1: WO 2021/191989</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">SUMMARY OF INVENTION</heading>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">Technical Problem</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In Patent Literature 1, an endoscopic imaging device inserted into a camera channel of a catheter may rotate in an unexpected direction within the camera channel.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The present invention has been made in view of such circumstances, and an object thereof is to provide an endoscopic imaging device and the like that can reduce rotation within a catheter. Alternatively, the present invention provides an endoscope and the like that can prevent misrecognition of the direction of an imaged image even when the endoscopic imaging device rotates within the catheter.</p>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">Solution to Problem</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">To solve the above-mentioned problems, an endoscopic imaging device according to an aspect of the present invention includes a curved camera shaft that can be inserted into a curved catheter that is to be inserted into a body, and an imaging element provided at a distal end portion of the camera shaft.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In this aspect, a curved camera shaft is guided by a similarly curved catheter, which can reduce rotation of the camera shaft within the catheter.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Another aspect of the present invention is an endoscope. This endoscope includes a curved catheter that is to be inserted into a body, a curved camera shaft that can be inserted into the catheter, and an imaging element that is provided at a distal end portion of the camera shaft.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Still another aspect of the present invention is also an endoscope. This endoscope includes a catheter that is to be inserted into a body, a camera shaft that can be inserted into the catheter, an imaging element that is provided at a distal end portion of the camera shaft, and a direction indicator that is located at a distal end portion of the catheter and can be imaged by the imaging element.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In this aspect, even if the camera shaft rotates within the catheter, misrecognition of the direction of the image imaged by the imaging element can be prevented based on the direction indicator imaged by the imaging element.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Still another aspect of the present invention is also an endoscope. This endoscope includes a catheter that is to be inserted into a body, a camera shaft that can be inserted into the catheter, and an imaging element that is provided at a distal end portion of the camera shaft. In the catheter, a cross-sectional shape of at least a part of the camera channel into which the camera shaft can be inserted and a cross-sectional shape of at least a part of the camera shaft are non-circular and substantially similar.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In this aspect, the camera channel and camera shaft having substantially similar cross-sectional shapes can reduce rotation of the camera shaft within the camera channel.</p>
<heading id="h-0008" level="1">Advantageous Effects of Invention</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">According to the present invention, the rotation of the endoscopic imaging device within the catheter can be reduced. Alternatively, according to the present invention, misrecognition of the direction of the imaged image can be prevented even when the endoscopic imaging device is rotated within the catheter.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0009" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> illustrates an entire cholangioscope.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a side view of a distal end portion of a catheter.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a plan view of a distal end surface of the distal end portion of the catheter.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>A and <b>4</b>B</figref> illustrate how a camera position switching unit switches a position of a camera head between a first position proximate to a proximal end and a second position proximate to a distal end.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> illustrates a camera removed from the cholangioscope.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b>A and <b>6</b>B</figref> illustrate a portion proximate to the distal end of the catheter and the camera in a cholangioscope according to a first embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>7</b>A and <b>7</b>B</figref> illustrate a portion proximate to the distal end of the catheter and the camera in the cholangioscope according to the first embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>8</b>A to <b>8</b>C</figref> illustrate details of a portion proximate to the distal end of the camera shaft before a curved shape is memorized in a shape memory alloy.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>9</b>A and <b>9</b>B</figref> illustrate one cross-section of the catheter and the camera in a cholangioscope according to a second embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref> illustrates a cholangioscope according to a third embodiment together with functional blocks implemented by a computer or the like outside the body connected to a connector provided at a proximal end portion of a camera.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>11</b>A and <b>11</b>B</figref> illustrate an example of image processing by an image processing unit.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0010" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Hereinafter, embodiments for carrying out the present invention will be described in detail with reference to the drawings. In the description or drawings, the same or equivalent constituent elements, members, and processing operations are denoted by the same reference numerals, and overlapping descriptions are omitted. The scales and shapes of the illustrated parts are set for convenience to facilitate the explanation and should not be construed as limiting unless otherwise specified. The embodiments are illustrative and do not limit the scope of the present invention in any way. Not all features or combinations of features described in the embodiments are essential to the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> illustrates an entire cholangioscope <b>100</b> to which an embodiment of the present invention is applied. The cholangioscope <b>100</b> is an endoscope that images the inside of the common bile duct and the pancreatic duct. The cholangioscope <b>100</b> includes a long tubular catheter <b>10</b> or sheath that is to be inserted into the body through the mouth or the like. At the distal end portion of the catheter <b>10</b> (lower end in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>), a camera head of a camera <b>30</b> as an endoscopic imaging device including an imaging element such as a CMOS image sensor is provided in an exposable state. The catheter <b>10</b> inserted into the duodenum through the mouth or the like is inserted into the common bile duct or the pancreatic duct through the papilla of Vater facing the duodenum. In this state, the camera head exposed at the distal end portion of the catheter <b>10</b> images an image such as a moving image or a still image of the interior of the common bile duct and the pancreatic duct for diagnosis or treatment.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">By inserting the catheter <b>10</b> of the cholangioscope <b>100</b> into the forceps channel or the like of a duodenoscope (not illustrated) inserted into the duodenum from the mouth or the like, the cholangioscope <b>100</b> can be reliably guided to the duodenum, and the cholangioscope <b>100</b> can be reliably inserted into the narrow papilla of Vater while confirming the images obtained from the duodenoscope. Before inserting the catheter <b>10</b> into the papilla of Vater, a guide wire having a smaller diameter than that of the catheter <b>10</b> may be inserted into the papilla of Vater through the wire lumen of the duodenoscope, and the papilla of Vater may be expanded in advance by a balloon catheter guided through the guide wire.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">A handle portion <b>20</b> for operating the cholangioscope <b>100</b> is provided in a portion proximate to the proximal end (upper end in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>) of the cholangioscope <b>100</b> or the catheter <b>10</b> or a portion of the cholangioscope <b>100</b> or the catheter <b>10</b> outside the body. The handle portion <b>20</b> has a grip portion <b>21</b> that is gripped by an operator such as a physician, and two rotary operating portions <b>25</b> and <b>26</b> that allow the operator to bend at least the distal end portion of the catheter <b>10</b> in any direction to adjust the position. Because the camera head of the camera <b>30</b> is disposed at the distal end portion of the catheter <b>10</b> as described above, the imaging portion and the imaging range of the camera <b>30</b> can be freely changed by rotating the two rotary operating portions <b>25</b> and <b>26</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">As will be described below, inside the catheter <b>10</b> or sheath, there are provided a camera channel <b>13</b> into which a small-diameter camera shaft with a camera head provided at the distal end portion thereof is inserted, and a forceps channel <b>17</b>, as a large-diameter instrument channel, into which various medical instruments for examination or treatment of the inside of the common bile duct or pancreatic duct are inserted. The handle portion <b>20</b> is provided with a camera port <b>23</b> communicating with the camera channel <b>13</b> of the catheter <b>10</b> and a forceps port <b>27</b> communicating with the forceps channel <b>17</b> of the catheter <b>10</b>. That is, the small-diameter camera shaft with the camera head provided at distal end portion thereof is inserted from the camera port <b>23</b> into the sheath <b>10</b> (camera channel <b>13</b>), and various medical instruments are inserted from the forceps port <b>27</b> into the sheath <b>10</b> (forceps channel <b>17</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a side view of the distal end portion of the catheter <b>10</b>, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a plan view of a distal end surface <b>15</b> of the distal end portion of the catheter <b>10</b>. As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, the cross-section of the catheter <b>10</b> is substantially circular and is provided with the camera channel <b>13</b>, the forceps channel <b>17</b> and two air/water channels <b>14</b>, each having a substantially circular cross-section. The camera channel <b>13</b>, the forceps channel <b>17</b>, and the air/water channels <b>14</b> communicate with the outside of the body through the sheath <b>10</b>. As described above, the camera channel <b>13</b> communicates with the camera port <b>23</b>, the forceps channel <b>17</b> communicates with the forceps port <b>27</b>, and the air/water channels <b>14</b> communicate with the air/water ports provided in the forceps port <b>27</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">A small-diameter long camera shaft with the camera head <b>31</b> provided at its distal end portion is inserted into the camera channel <b>13</b>. The camera head <b>31</b> constitutes the distal end portion of the camera <b>30</b> as an endoscopic imaging device and includes a CMOS image sensor <b>311</b> as an imaging element. The camera head <b>31</b> or the CMOS image sensor <b>311</b> is connected to a power source, a computer, and the like outside the body by lead wires passing through the camera shaft and a camera cable <b>35</b> extending from a camera connector <b>50</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> to the outside of the body. Through this lead wire, power is supplied from the power source outside the body to the CMOS image sensor <b>311</b>, control signals are transmitted from a control device such as a computer outside the body to the CMOS image sensor <b>311</b>, and image signals imaged by the CMOS image sensor <b>311</b> are transmitted to a computer, a monitor, and the like outside the body. It should be noted that transmission of control signals and image signals between a computer or the like outside the body and the CMOS image sensor <b>311</b> may be performed wirelessly by Bluetooth (trade name) or the like without using lead wires.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">While a light receiving surface of the CMOS image sensor <b>311</b> is rectangular (typically square), the distal end surface of the camera head <b>31</b> (which is also the distal end surface of the camera <b>30</b> or the camera shaft) circumscribing the light receiving surface is circular. A plurality of optical fibers (not illustrated) are provided in a region between the circular outer periphery of the camera head <b>31</b> and the rectangular outer periphery of the CMOS image sensor <b>311</b>, and thus the optical fibers surround the outer periphery of the CMOS image sensor <b>311</b>. These optical fibers extend out of the camera port <b>23</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> through the camera shaft in the same manner as the lead wires connected to the CMOS image sensor <b>311</b> and are connected to a light source outside the body. The light from this light source is emitted from the distal end surface of the optical fiber and illuminates the imaging range of the CMOS image sensor <b>311</b>, and thus a clear image of the diagnostic site or the treatment site can be obtained.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Various medical instruments with treatment tools such as forceps provided at their distal end portions are inserted into the forceps channel <b>17</b>. The air/water channels <b>14</b> supply air and water from air/water ports provided in the forceps port <b>27</b> to the diagnostic site or treatment site. The small-diameter camera channel <b>13</b> and the large-diameter forceps channel <b>17</b> are aligned, and thus their centers are disposed on the same straight line (on the vertical line in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>) as the center of the distal end surface <b>15</b> of the catheter <b>10</b>. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, the camera channel <b>13</b> and the forceps channel <b>17</b> are aligned vertically, and two air/water channels <b>14</b> are symmetrically disposed in the upper left and right regions (proximate to the small-diameter camera channel <b>13</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, the diameter of the catheter <b>10</b> or sheath is from 1.1 mm to 7.0 mm (for example, 3.6 mm), the diameter of the camera channel <b>13</b> is from 0.7 mm to 3.0 mm (for example, 1.1 mm), and the diameter of the forceps channel <b>17</b> is from 0.3 mm to 3.0 mm (for example, 2.0 mm). The diameter of the camera shaft and camera head <b>31</b> inserted into the camera channel <b>13</b> is slightly smaller than the diameter of the camera channel <b>13</b> and is from 0.6 mm to 2.9 mm (for example, 1.0 mm). If the forceps channel <b>17</b> has a diameter of 2.0 mm or more, it can be used with typical forceps or medical instruments having a diameter of 1.8 mm. On the other hand, the diameter of the camera channel <b>13</b> can be reduced according to the miniaturization of the CMOS image sensor <b>311</b>. Thus, according to the present embodiment, because the diameter of the camera channel <b>13</b> can be minimized (for example, 1.1 mm or less) while maintaining the minimum diameter (for example, 2.0 mm or more) of the forceps channel <b>17</b> compatible with typical forceps or medical instruments, it is possible to implement a sufficiently thin catheter <b>10</b> that can easily pass through the narrow papilla of Vater.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the camera head <b>31</b> constituting the distal end portion of the camera <b>30</b> as an endoscopic imaging device is provided in such a manner that the camera head <b>31</b> can further protrude and expose from the distal end surface <b>15</b> of the catheter <b>10</b> in a direction from the proximal end to the distal end of the catheter <b>10</b>. As described above, the position at which the camera head <b>31</b> or the CMOS image sensor <b>311</b> further protrudes from the distal end surface <b>15</b> of the catheter <b>10</b> in the direction from the proximal end to the distal end of the catheter <b>10</b> will be also referred to as a second position. On the other hand, the camera head <b>31</b> or the CMOS image sensor <b>311</b> can also take a position (hereinafter also referred to as a first position) retracted from the distal end surface <b>15</b> of the catheter <b>10</b> in a direction toward the proximal end of the catheter <b>10</b>. Switching between the first position and the second position can be performed by the operator using a camera position switching unit <b>53</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>) provided side by side with the camera connector <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b>A and <b>4</b>B</figref> illustrate how the camera position switching unit <b>53</b> switches the camera head <b>31</b> between a first position proximate to the proximal end and a second position proximate to the distal end. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>A</figref>, the camera head <b>31</b> is at a first position retracted from the distal end surface <b>15</b> of the catheter <b>10</b> toward the proximal end of the catheter <b>10</b>, and in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>B</figref>, the camera head <b>31</b> is at a second position projected from the distal end surface <b>15</b> of the catheter <b>10</b> in the direction from the proximal end to the distal end of the catheter <b>10</b>. The retraction distance between the distal end surface <b>15</b> of the catheter <b>10</b> and the first position is, for example, from 1.5 mm to 20 mm, and the protruding distance between the distal end surface <b>15</b> of the catheter <b>10</b> and the second position is, for example, from 0.5 mm to 80 mm.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">When the CMOS image sensor <b>311</b> of the camera head <b>31</b> images an image of a diagnostic site or a treatment site, the second position in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>B</figref> is taken. When the distal end portion of the catheter <b>10</b> is inserted into the common bile duct or pancreatic duct as an imaging portion, the first position of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>A</figref> in which the camera head <b>31</b> is housed in the catheter <b>10</b> or sheath is taken, and thus the camera head <b>31</b> does not come into contact with the inner wall of the duodenoscope that guides the catheter <b>10</b> to the duodenum, the inner wall of the papilla of Vater constricted by the sphincter of Oddi (or the sphincter of the biliary pancreatic ampulla), the common bile duct, or the pancreatic duct. The position switching mechanism of the camera head <b>31</b> by such a camera position switching unit <b>53</b> is disclosed in International Patent Application No. PCT/JP2020/012793 (WO 2021/191989) filed on Mar. 23, 2020, and the entire contents of which are incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The camera <b>30</b> as an endoscopic imaging device is detachable from the catheter <b>10</b> or the cholangioscope <b>100</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> illustrates the camera <b>30</b> detached from the cholangioscope <b>100</b>. The camera <b>30</b> includes the small-diameter (from 0.6 mm to 2.9 mm) and long tubular camera shaft <b>32</b> with the camera head <b>31</b> provided at its distal end portion (the left end portion in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>), the camera connector <b>50</b> connected to the proximal end portion (the right end portion in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>) of the camera shaft <b>32</b>, and the camera cable <b>35</b> electrically connecting the camera connector <b>50</b> and the connector <b>33</b> provided at the proximal end portion of the camera <b>30</b>. As described above, the lead wire connected to the CMOS image sensor <b>311</b> of the camera head <b>31</b> at the distal end portion of the camera <b>30</b> passes through the camera shaft <b>32</b> and the camera cable <b>35</b> and is connected to a power source, a computer, a monitor, and the like outside the body via the connector <b>33</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, the camera connector <b>50</b> is attachable/detachable to/from the camera port <b>23</b> of the cholangioscope <b>100</b>. However, as disclosed in International Patent Application No. PCT/JP2020/012793, an attachment restricting mechanism is provided to restrict the camera shaft <b>32</b> from being inserted into the catheter <b>10</b> (the camera channel <b>13</b>) in a state (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>B</figref>) in which the camera head <b>31</b> can protrude from the distal end surface <b>15</b> of the catheter <b>10</b>. As a result, the camera <b>30</b> (camera connector <b>50</b>) can be attached to the cholangioscope <b>100</b> (camera port <b>23</b>) only when the camera head <b>31</b> is in a position where the camera head <b>31</b> does not protrude from the distal end surface <b>15</b> of the catheter <b>10</b>, that is, when the camera head <b>31</b> is at the first position (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>A</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Switching between the first position and the second position of the camera head <b>31</b> is performed by rotating the camera position switching unit <b>53</b> provided side by side with the camera connector <b>50</b>. When the camera position switching unit <b>53</b> is rotated in a first direction, the camera head <b>31</b> moves to the first position (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>A</figref>) and a slide member <b>52</b> provided on the camera connector <b>50</b> moves in a direction toward the proximal end (the right side in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>). Further, when the camera position switching unit <b>53</b> is rotated in a second direction opposite to the first direction, the camera head <b>31</b> moves toward the second position (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>B</figref>), and the slide member <b>52</b> provided on the camera connector <b>50</b> moves in a direction toward the distal end (the left side in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>). Thus, it can be said that the camera <b>30</b> (camera connector <b>50</b>) can be attached to the cholangioscope <b>100</b> (camera port <b>23</b>) only when the slide member <b>52</b> is in a position proximate to the proximal end.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">As described above, the camera head <b>31</b> attached to the cholangioscope <b>100</b> at the first position (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>A</figref>) is moved to the second position (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>B</figref>) with the rotation of the camera position switching unit <b>53</b> in the second direction after reaching the imaging portion in the body to perform imaging. After completion of imaging, the camera head <b>31</b> is returned to the first position by the rotation of the camera position switching unit <b>53</b> in the first direction. By removing the catheter <b>10</b> from the body in this state, the camera head <b>31</b> retracted further than the distal end surface <b>15</b> of the catheter <b>10</b> in the direction toward the proximal end of the catheter <b>10</b> can be prevented from coming into contact with the body tissue or the inner wall of the main endoscope such as the duodenoscope. Furthermore, after use, the camera <b>30</b> is detached from the sheath <b>10</b>, which is typically used once (specifically, the camera <b>30</b> is detached from the camera port <b>23</b> of the cholangioscope <b>100</b>). This camera <b>30</b> can be reused for other sheaths <b>10</b> or cholangioscopes <b>100</b> of the same type within a range not exceeding a predetermined number of uses (for example, <b>10</b> times). By reusing the expensive camera <b>30</b> (or CMOS image sensor <b>311</b>), the cost per procedure can be greatly reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">As described above, in the cholangioscope <b>100</b> in which the camera <b>30</b> is detachable, there is a possibility that the camera shaft <b>32</b> inserted into the camera channel <b>13</b> of the catheter <b>10</b> rotates within the camera channel <b>13</b>. In the following embodiments, the camera <b>30</b> and the cholangioscope <b>100</b> that can reduce the rotation within the catheter <b>10</b>, and the cholangioscope <b>100</b> that can prevent misrecognition of the direction of the imaged image even when the camera <b>30</b> rotates within the catheter <b>10</b> are to be disclosed. A plurality of embodiments will be individually described below, but part or all of the embodiments can be combined freely unless there is a particular problem.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b> and <b>7</b></figref> illustrate portions proximate to the distal end of the catheter <b>10</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b>A and <b>7</b>A</figref>) and portions proximate to the distal end of the camera <b>30</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b>B and <b>7</b>B</figref>) in the cholangioscope <b>100</b> according to the first embodiment. The catheter <b>10</b> is formed in a curved shape, and thus the catheter <b>10</b> can be easily inserted into the common bile duct or pancreatic duct through the papilla of Vater on the side wall of the duodenum. As described above, the distal end portion <b>16</b> of the catheter <b>10</b> can be bent in any direction by the rotary operating portions <b>25</b> and <b>26</b>. However, the catheter <b>10</b> is formed in a curved shape while including also the catheter body <b>18</b> proximate to the proximal end of the catheter <b>10</b> from the distal end portion <b>16</b>. The catheter <b>10</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref> has a relatively large curvature, and the distal end surface <b>15</b> faces in a direction of the proximal end of the catheter <b>10</b> (right side in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>). The catheter <b>10</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>A</figref> has a relatively small curvature, and the distal end surface <b>15</b> does not face in the direction of the proximal end of the catheter <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">Here, the camera channel <b>13</b> into which the camera shaft <b>32</b> is inserted is provided in an outer side portion of the curved catheter <b>10</b>, and the forceps channel <b>17</b> into which various medical instruments for examination or treatment of the inside of the common bile duct or pancreatic duct are inserted is provided in an inner side portion of the curved catheter <b>10</b>. In the curved catheter <b>10</b> and the curved camera shaft <b>32</b>, which will be described below, &#x201c;outer side portion&#x201d; refers to a portion that protrudes in a convex shape and &#x201c;inner side&#x201d; refers to a portion that is depressed in a concave shape. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> illustrating the camera channel <b>13</b> and the forceps channel <b>17</b>, the upper side corresponds to the outer side portion of the curved catheter <b>10</b> and the lower side corresponds to the inside portion of the curved catheter <b>10</b>. Thus, the camera channel <b>13</b> is provided in the outer side portion of the curved catheter <b>10</b> outer than the forceps channel <b>17</b>. For this reason, the curvature of the camera channel <b>13</b> is slightly less than the curvature of the forceps channel <b>17</b>, and the camera shaft <b>32</b> can be easily inserted into the camera channel <b>13</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Similarly to a portion proximate to the distal end of the catheter <b>10</b>, a portion proximate to the distal end of the camera <b>30</b> or the camera shaft <b>32</b> is also formed in a curved shape. When the camera shaft <b>32</b> is inserted into the camera channel <b>13</b>, the curved camera shaft <b>32</b> is guided by the camera channel <b>13</b>, which is also curved, and thus the rotation of the camera shaft <b>32</b> within the camera channel <b>13</b> can be reduced. As described above, according to the present embodiment, the detachable camera <b>30</b> can be inserted into the catheter <b>10</b> or the cholangioscope <b>100</b> in a desired direction. Even if the camera shaft <b>32</b> does not bend greatly like the catheter <b>10</b> or the camera channel <b>13</b>, and if the camera shaft <b>32</b> bends enough to follow the curvature of the camera channel <b>13</b>, the camera shaft <b>32</b> can maintain a substantially constant direction within the camera channel <b>13</b>. Thus, the curvature of the camera shaft <b>32</b> may be smaller than the curvature of the catheter <b>10</b> or the camera channel <b>13</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Here, the curvature is the reciprocal of the radius (radius of curvature) of the curved portion. Although the curvature (and radius of curvature) can vary at each of the portions of the catheter <b>10</b> and each of the portions of the camera shaft <b>32</b>, when the curvature of each of the curved portions of the catheter <b>10</b> and the curvature of the corresponding one of curved portions of the camera shaft <b>32</b>, which are coming at the same position when the camera shaft <b>32</b> is inserted into the camera channel <b>13</b> of the catheter <b>10</b>, are compared, it is preferable that the former be generally or on average greater than the latter. Alternatively, it is preferable that the maximum curvature of the catheter <b>10</b> is greater than the maximum curvature of the camera shaft <b>32</b>. Moreover, when comparing the curvatures of each curved portion of the catheter <b>10</b> and the camera shaft <b>32</b>, it is preferable to compare the curvatures of the respective central shafts. Alternatively, the inner (innermost) curvatures of the catheter <b>10</b> and the camera shaft <b>32</b> may be compared, or the outer (outermost) curvatures of the catheter <b>10</b> and camera shaft <b>32</b> may be compared.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The camera shaft <b>32</b> is formed in a curved shape by using metal. Shape memory alloys such as NiTi (nickel titanium) alloys are suitable as metals. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> illustrates details of a portion proximate to the distal end of the camera shaft <b>32</b> before the curved shape is memorized in metal such as a shape memory alloy. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b>A</figref> illustrates the appearance of the camera shaft <b>32</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b>B</figref> is a transparent view of the cover and the like on the surface of the camera shaft <b>32</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b>A</figref>, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b>C</figref> is an enlarged view of a portion proximate to the distal end of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b>B</figref>. As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b>A</figref>, a cylindrical distal end cover <b>34</b> is provided at the distal end portion of the camera shaft <b>32</b> (the left end in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref>) to cover and protect the outer periphery or side surface of the camera head <b>31</b> or the CMOS image sensor <b>311</b>. The distal end cover <b>34</b> is made of hard resin or the like, and has a length of about 5 mm in the axial direction (the horizontal direction in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref>) of the distal end cover <b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">A cylindrical shaft cover <b>36</b> that covers the outer periphery of the shape memory alloy tube <b>37</b> and the like, which will be described below, is provided on a portion extending from the distal end portion of the camera shaft <b>32</b> toward the proximal end (the right side in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref>) of the camera shaft <b>32</b> so as to continue from the distal end cover <b>34</b>. At least a portion proximate to the distal end of the shaft cover <b>36</b> is located inside the distal end portion <b>16</b> of the catheter <b>10</b> (the camera channel <b>13</b>) in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b>A and <b>7</b>A</figref>. By forming the shaft cover <b>36</b> with a resin or the like that is softer than the hard distal end cover <b>34</b>, the camera shaft <b>32</b> (the shaft cover <b>36</b>) can be flexibly bent following the distal end portion <b>16</b> of the catheter <b>10</b>, which can be bent in any direction by the rotary operating portions <b>25</b> and <b>26</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">The shape memory alloy tube <b>37</b> as a tubular or cylindrical metal tube along the camera shaft <b>32</b> is provided on the inner periphery covered by the shaft cover <b>36</b>. The shape memory alloy tube <b>37</b> is a long circular tube made of a shape memory alloy such as a NiTi alloy and memorizes a desired curved shape of the camera shaft <b>32</b> as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b>B and <b>7</b>B</figref> by shape memory processing by temperature or magnetic field. The shape memory alloy tube <b>37</b> is not provided at the distal end portion (not intended to bend) of the camera shaft <b>32</b> where the hard distal end cover <b>34</b> is provided. A spiral cut <b>371</b> is provided in a portion proximate to the distal end of the shape memory alloy tube <b>37</b> by laser processing or the like. As a result, when the rotary operating portions <b>25</b> and <b>26</b> cause the distal end portion <b>16</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b>A and <b>7</b>A</figref>) of the catheter <b>10</b> to bend, the shape memory alloy tube <b>37</b> can also bend flexibly to follow the distal end portion <b>16</b>. The pitch of the spiral cut <b>371</b> is reduced gradually or in a stepwise manner as in a direction from a proximal end of the shape memory alloy tube <b>37</b> to a distal end of the shape memory alloy tube <b>37</b> at least in a part of the shape memory alloy tube <b>37</b>, and the closer to the distal end of the shape memory alloy tube <b>37</b> where the degree of bending caused by the rotary operating portions <b>25</b> and <b>26</b> is large, the easier the shape memory alloy tube <b>37</b> bends. On the other hand, the spiral cut <b>371</b> is not provided in a portion proximate to the proximal end of the shape memory alloy tube <b>37</b> where the degree of bending by the rotary operating portions <b>25</b> and <b>26</b> is very small (or absolutely zero). For example, the spiral cut <b>371</b> is formed in a range of about <b>25</b> mm from the distal end of the shape memory alloy tube <b>37</b> and is not formed in a portion extending therefrom to the proximal end of the shape memory alloy tube <b>37</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b>C</figref>, a plurality of lead wires <b>381</b> connected to the camera head <b>31</b> or the CMOS image sensor <b>311</b> and a plurality of optical fibers <b>382</b> disposed around the CMOS image sensor <b>311</b> pass through the distal end cover <b>34</b>, the shaft cover <b>36</b>, and the shape memory alloy tube <b>37</b> to extend to the outside of the camera port <b>23</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref> illustrates one cross-section of a catheter <b>10</b> and a camera <b>30</b> (a camera shaft <b>32</b>) in a cholangioscope <b>100</b> according to a second embodiment. The illustration of the air/water channels <b>14</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> illustrating the distal end surface of the catheter <b>10</b> and the camera <b>30</b> is omitted. In the present embodiment, a cross-sectional shape of at least a part of the camera channel <b>13</b> of the catheter <b>10</b> and a cross-sectional shape of at least a part of the camera shaft <b>32</b> of the camera <b>30</b> are non-circular and substantially similar.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">In the example of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b>A</figref>, a cross-sectional shape of at least a part of the camera channel <b>13</b> and a cross-sectional shape of at least a part of the camera shaft <b>32</b> are substantially similar elliptical. In the example of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b>B</figref>, a cross-sectional shape of at least a part of the camera channel <b>13</b> and a cross-sectional shape of at least a part of the camera shaft <b>32</b> are substantially similar polygonal (specifically, trapezoidal, for example). A guide groove extending in the length direction may be provided on one of the inner periphery of the camera channel <b>13</b> or the outer periphery of the camera shaft <b>32</b>, and a protruding portion that fits in the guide groove so as to be slidable or insertable in the length direction may be provided on the other of the inner periphery of the camera channel <b>13</b> or the outer periphery of the camera shaft <b>32</b> to achieve substantially similar shapes. The camera channel <b>13</b> and the camera shaft <b>32</b> having substantially similar cross-sectional shapes can reduce the rotation of the camera shaft <b>32</b> within the camera channel <b>13</b>, thus allowing the detachable camera <b>30</b> to be inserted into the catheter <b>10</b> or the cholangioscope <b>100</b> in a desired direction.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">Note that the substantially similar shape does not have to be a mathematically exact similar shape, as long as the shape is similar enough to effectively restrict the rotation of the camera shaft <b>32</b> within the camera channel <b>13</b>. For example, even if the camera shaft <b>32</b> with a rectangular cross-section is inserted into the camera channel <b>13</b> with an elliptical cross-section, the rotation of the camera shaft <b>32</b> within the camera channel <b>13</b> can be restricted, and thus the requirements for substantially similar shapes in this specification are satisfied. The non-circular cross-section as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>9</b>A and <b>9</b>B</figref> need not be formed along the entire length of the camera channel <b>13</b> and/or the camera shaft <b>32</b> but may be formed in at least one location along the length. When the cross-section of the camera channel <b>13</b> is formed in an elliptical or a polygonal shape over its entire length, the cross-section of the camera shaft <b>32</b> is a substantially circular shape included in the elliptical shape or the polygonal shape over its entire length. However, the rotation of the camera shaft <b>32</b> within the camera channel <b>13</b> may be restricted by attaching a rotation restricting portion having a shape substantially similar to the elliptical or polygonal shape to the outer circumference of at least one portion of the camera shaft <b>32</b> in the length direction.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref> illustrates a cholangioscope <b>100</b> according to a third embodiment together with functional blocks implemented by a computer or the like outside the body connected to a connector <b>33</b> provided at a proximal end portion of a camera <b>30</b>. An image acquisition unit <b>41</b> acquires an image imaged by a CMOS image sensor <b>311</b> in a camera head <b>31</b> and transmitted through lead wires passing through a camera shaft <b>32</b> and a camera cable <b>35</b> from the connector <b>33</b>. A camera direction detecting unit <b>42</b> detects a direction of the CMOS image sensor <b>311</b> relative to a catheter <b>10</b> (not illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref>, see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>) based on a direction indicator to be described below included in the image acquired by the image acquisition unit <b>41</b>. An image processing unit <b>43</b> processes the image acquired by the image acquisition unit <b>41</b> according to the direction of the CMOS image sensor <b>311</b> detected by the camera direction detecting unit <b>42</b> and displays the processed image on a monitor <b>40</b> or a display device.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">The direction indicator indicating the direction of the image acquired by the image acquisition unit <b>41</b> relative to the catheter <b>10</b> is located at a distal end portion of the catheter <b>10</b> and is imaged by the CMOS image sensor <b>311</b> before or during the procedure using the cholangioscope <b>100</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> illustrates an example of the direction indicator <b>44</b>. The direction indicator <b>44</b> is a linear mark extending in the length direction of the catheter <b>10</b> on the portion of the inner wall of the distal end portion of the camera channel <b>13</b> that is closest to the forceps channel <b>17</b>. As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>, the linear direction indicator <b>44</b> may extend from the lower end of the camera channel <b>13</b> to the upper end of the forceps channel <b>17</b> on the distal end surface <b>15</b> of the catheter <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The CMOS image sensor <b>311</b> positioned at the first position in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b>A</figref> by the camera position switching unit <b>53</b> can image the linear direction indicator <b>44</b> provided on the camera channel <b>13</b> and/or the forceps channel <b>17</b> or at the distal end portion of the catheter <b>10</b>. Then, the camera direction detecting unit <b>42</b> can detect the direction of the CMOS image sensor <b>311</b> relative to the catheter <b>10</b>, the camera channel <b>13</b> and the forceps channel <b>17</b> based on the direction indicator <b>44</b> included in the image acquired by the image acquisition unit <b>41</b>. In this manner, based on the direction indicator <b>44</b> imaged by the CMOS image sensor <b>311</b>, misrecognition of the direction of the image imaged by the CMOS image sensor <b>311</b> can be prevented even when the camera shaft <b>32</b> rotates within the catheter <b>10</b>. Note that the direction indicator <b>44</b> is not limited to the mark as described above and may be any object or structure that suggests the direction of the CMOS image sensor <b>311</b>. For example, the contour of the distal end portion of the camera channel <b>13</b>, the contour of the distal end portion of the forceps channel <b>17</b>, the contour of the distal end surface <b>15</b> of the catheter <b>10</b>, the medical instrument protruding from the distal end portion of the forceps channel <b>17</b>, or the like may be imaged by the CMOS image sensor <b>311</b> as the direction indicator <b>44</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">The image processing unit <b>43</b> processes the image acquired by the image acquisition unit <b>41</b> according to the direction of the CMOS image sensor <b>311</b> detected by the camera direction detecting unit <b>42</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b></figref> illustrates an example of image processing by the image processing unit <b>43</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b>A</figref> illustrates an example of an image imaged by the CMOS image sensor <b>311</b> and displayed on the monitor <b>40</b> in an ideal case where the CMOS image sensor <b>311</b> faces the desired direction relative to the forceps channel <b>17</b> and the like. A substantially circular common bile duct (BD or Bile Duct) is displayed in the center of the screen, and a medical instrument <b>171</b> led out from the forceps channel <b>17</b> emerges exactly below (vertically below) the center of the screen. In contrast, in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b>B</figref>, the camera shaft <b>32</b> rotates within the catheter <b>10</b>, which results in a rotation of the emerging position of the medical instrument <b>171</b> from a position illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b>A</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">As indicated by the first option OP<b>1</b>, the image processing unit <b>43</b> rotates the image imaged by the CMOS image sensor <b>311</b>, and thus the direction of the CMOS image sensor <b>311</b> detected by the camera direction detecting unit <b>42</b> matches the desired direction in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b>A</figref>. As a result, the monitor <b>40</b> displays an image similar to that illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b>A</figref>. At this time, as indicated by the second option OP<b>2</b>, the image processing unit <b>43</b> may cut out the image that is a target of rotation by the first option OP<b>1</b>, over a predetermined diameter range around the center of the rotation. When the image is rotated, a part of the originally rectangular image protrudes outside the screen and the outline of the image is lost. However, this influence can be eliminated by cutting the image in a circular shape. The predetermined diameter range cut out by the image processing unit <b>43</b> preferably includes at least the common bile duct BD as an imaging target.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">As indicated by the third option OP<b>3</b>, the image processing unit <b>43</b> displays the direction of the direction indicator <b>44</b> imaged by the CMOS image sensor <b>311</b> (the direction of the forceps channel <b>17</b> or the direction in which the medical instrument <b>171</b> emerges in the examples of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b> and <b>11</b></figref>) on the image imaged by the CMOS image sensor <b>311</b>. In the example of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b></figref>, the direction of the forceps channel <b>17</b> or the direction in which the medical instrument <b>171</b> emerges is indicated by an arrow-shaped directional mark. According to the present embodiment as described above, by the image processing based on the direction indicator <b>44</b> imaged by the CMOS image sensor <b>311</b>, even when the camera shaft <b>32</b> rotates within the catheter <b>10</b>, misrecognition of the direction of the image imaged by the CMOS image sensor <b>311</b> can be prevented.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">The present invention has been described above based on the embodiments. It should be understood by those skilled in the art that the embodiments are examples, that various modifications are possible in the combination of components and processing operations, and that such modifications are also within the scope of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">Note that the functional configuration of each device described in the embodiments can be implemented by hardware resources, software resources, or cooperation of hardware resources and software resources. Processors, ROMs, RAMs, and other LSIs can be used as the hardware resources. Programs such as operating systems and applications can be used as the software resources.</p>
<heading id="h-0011" level="1">REFERENCE SIGNS LIST</heading>
<p id="p-0063" num="0000">
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0001-0001" num="0062"><b>10</b> Catheter</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0002" num="0063"><b>13</b> Camera channel</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0003" num="0064"><b>17</b> Forceps channel</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0004" num="0065"><b>23</b> Camera port</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0005" num="0066"><b>27</b> Forceps port</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0006" num="0067"><b>30</b> Camera</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0007" num="0068"><b>31</b> Camera head</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0008" num="0069"><b>32</b> Camera shaft</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0009" num="0070"><b>34</b> Distal end cover</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0010" num="0071"><b>37</b> Shape memory alloy tube</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0011" num="0072"><b>41</b> Image acquisition unit</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0012" num="0073"><b>42</b> Camera direction detecting unit</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0013" num="0074"><b>43</b> Image processing unit</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0014" num="0075"><b>44</b> Direction indicator</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0015" num="0076"><b>53</b> Camera position switching unit</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0016" num="0077"><b>100</b> Cholangioscope</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0017" num="0078"><b>171</b> Medical instrument</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0018" num="0079"><b>311</b> CMOS image sensor</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0019" num="0080"><b>371</b> Cut</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0020" num="0081"><b>381</b> Lead wire</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0021" num="0082"><b>382</b> Optical fiber</li>
</ul>
</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. An endoscopic imaging device comprising:
<claim-text>a camera shaft configured to be inserted into a catheter and formed in a curved shape, the catheter being configured to be inserted into a body and having a curved shape; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an imaging element provided at a distal end portion of the camera shaft.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The endoscopic imaging device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein curvature of the camera shaft is less than curvature of the catheter.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The endoscopic imaging device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the camera shaft is formed into a curved shape by using a shape memory alloy.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The endoscopic imaging device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the shape memory alloy is not provided at the distal end portion of the camera shaft, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the distal end portion is provided with a distal end cover covering an outer periphery of the imaging element.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The endoscopic imaging device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the camera shaft is provided with a shape memory alloy tube made of the shape memory alloy, and a spiral cut is provided at least in a portion proximate to a distal end of the shape memory alloy tube.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The endoscopic imaging device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the spiral cut includes a portion where a pitch of the spiral cut decreases as in a direction from a proximal end of the shape memory alloy tube to a distal end of the shape memory alloy tube.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. An endoscope comprising:
<claim-text>a catheter configured to be inserted into a body and having a curved shape;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a camera shaft configured to be inserted into the catheter and formed in a curved shape; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an imaging element provided at a distal end portion of the camera shaft.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The endoscope according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the catheter further includes</claim-text>
<claim-text>an instrument channel into which a medical instrument is insertable, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a camera channel provided in an outer side portion of the catheter having the curved shape outer than the instrument channel and into which the camera shaft is insertable.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The endoscope according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, further comprising a direction indicator provided at a distal end portion of the catheter and configured to be imaged by the imaging element.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The endoscope according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>in the catheter, a cross-sectional shape of at least a part of the camera channel into which the camera shaft is insertable and a cross-sectional shape of at least a part of the camera shaft are non-circular and substantially similar.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. An endoscope comprising:
<claim-text>a catheter configured to be inserted into a body;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a camera shaft configured to be inserted into the catheter;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an imaging element provided at a distal end portion of the camera shaft; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a direction indicator located at a distal end portion of the catheter and configured to be imaged by the imaging element.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The endoscope according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the catheter further includes a camera channel into which the camera shaft is insertable and an instrument channel into which a medical instrument is insertable, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the direction indicator is at least one of a distal end portion of the camera channel, a distal end portion of the instrument channel, or the medical instrument protruding from the distal end portion of the instrument channel.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. The endoscope according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, further comprising
<claim-text>a camera position switching unit configured to switch a position of the imaging element relative to the distal end portion of the catheter between a first position proximate to a proximal end and a second position proximate to a distal end, wherein</claim-text>
<claim-text>the direction indicator is capable of being imaged at least by the imaging element at the first position.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The endoscope according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a camera direction detecting unit configured to detect a direction of the imaging element relative to the catheter based on the direction indicator imaged by the imaging element; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an image processing unit configured to process an image imaged by the imaging element according to the detected direction of the imaging element.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. The endoscope according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein the image processing unit rotates an image imaged by the imaging element, and thus the detected direction of the imaging element matches a predetermined direction.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. The endoscope according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the image processing unit cuts out the image that is a target of rotation, around the center of the rotation.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. The endoscope according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein the image processing unit displays a direction of the direction indicator imaged by the imaging element in an image imaged by the imaging element.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. An endoscope comprising:
<claim-text>a catheter configured to be inserted into a body;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a camera shaft configured to be inserted into the catheter; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an imaging element provided at a distal end portion of the camera shaft, wherein</claim-text>
<claim-text>in the catheter, a cross-sectional shape of at least a part of the camera channel into which the camera shaft is insertable and a cross-sectional shape of at least a part of the camera shaft are non-circular and substantially similar.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. The endoscope according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein a cross-sectional shape of at least a part of the camera channel and a cross-sectional shape of at least a part of the camera shaft are elliptical.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. The endoscope according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein a cross-sectional shape of at least a part of the camera channel and a cross-sectional shape of at least a part of the camera shaft are polygonal.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
