<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225497A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225497</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18067763</doc-number>
<date>20221219</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>46</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>11</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>46</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>11</main-group>
<subgroup>0006</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>46</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>11</main-group>
<subgroup>0072</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>46</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>2200</main-group>
<subgroup>104</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Liquid Dispensing Hairbrush Device</invention-title>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>63300846</doc-number>
<date>20220119</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Parris</last-name>
<first-name>James</first-name>
<address>
<city>Jacksonville</city>
<state>FL</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Parris</last-name>
<first-name>James</first-name>
<address>
<city>Jacksonville</city>
<state>FL</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The present invention relates generally to the field of hairbrushes. More specifically, the present invention relates to a liquid dispensing hairbrush device that allows a user to apply hair care product while simultaneously brushing their hair. The device is comprised of a body, further comprised of an interior container and at least one interchangeable brush head, further comprised of at least one nub with at least one continuous opening. Further the body and the brush head are in liquid communication through at least one continuous opening and are attached together via fasteners. The nubs are further comprised of at least one continuous opening that allow a liquid to flow through the openings and onto the user's hair while they brush their hair.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="162.98mm" wi="158.75mm" file="US20230225497A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="177.38mm" wi="153.92mm" file="US20230225497A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="187.71mm" wi="164.68mm" file="US20230225497A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="191.77mm" wi="144.27mm" file="US20230225497A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="157.14mm" wi="122.94mm" file="US20230225497A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present application claims priority to, and the benefit of, U.S. Provisional Application No. 63/300,846, which was filed on Jan. 19, 2022, and is incorporated herein by reference in its entirety.</p>
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="tail"?>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates generally to the field of hairbrushes. More specifically, the present invention relates to a liquid dispensing hairbrush device that allows a user to apply hair care product while simultaneously brushing their hair. The device is comprised of a body, further comprised of an interior container and at least one interchangeable brush head, further comprised of at least one nub with at least one continuous opening. Further, the body and the brush head are in liquid communication through at least one continuous opening and are attached together via fasteners. The nubs are further comprised of at least one continuous opening that allow a liquid to flow through the openings and onto the user's hair while they brush their hair. Accordingly, the present disclosure makes specific reference thereto. Nonetheless, it is to be appreciated that aspects of the present invention are also equally applicable to other like applications, devices and methods of manufacture.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">By way of background, individuals that have naturally curly hair often have difficulty maintaining and treating said hair. As a result, individuals must often apply essential oils and other hair products by hand and then brush their hair afterwards, which requires constant hand cleaning. This is very time consuming and can take up a large portion of an individual's time, which can negatively affect their daily routine.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Therefore, there exists a long-felt need in the art for a hairbrush that eliminates the need for people to apply hair care products by hand. Further, there exists a long-felt need in the art for a liquid dispensing hairbrush device that can simultaneously apply essential oils and hair products as the user brushes their hair. Further, there exists a long-felt need in the art for a liquid dispensing hairbrush device that allows a user to remove and apply different brush heads based of the need of the user, while still applying product through using the brush.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The subject matter disclosed and claimed herein, in one embodiment thereof, comprises a liquid dispensing hairbrush device. The device is primarily comprised of a body, further comprised of an interior container and at least one interchangeable brush head, further comprised of at least one nub with at least one continuous opening. In the preferred embodiment, the body of the device can be attached and detached from the brush head. The brush head and the body are in fluid communication, such that a user may place liquid hair care products in the interior container which then flows through the brush head and out of the nubs on the brush head. The fluid flows through the nubs onto the user's hair allowing for simultaneous application of liquid hair product and the brushing of hair.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In this manner, the liquid dispensing hairbrush device of the present invention accomplishes all of the foregoing objectives and provides a user with a convenient way to apply hair care products simultaneously while brushing their hair. The liquid dispensing hair care device further allows a user to save time and effort by providing a brush that dispenses the hair care directly to the hair while brushing through a series of openings.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The following presents a simplified summary in order to provide a basic understanding of some aspects of the disclosed innovation. This summary is not an extensive overview, and it is not intended to identify key/critical elements or to delineate the scope thereof. Its sole purpose is to present some general concepts in a simplified form as a prelude to the more detailed description that is presented later.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The subject matter disclosed and claimed herein, in one embodiment thereof, comprises a liquid dispensing hairbrush device. The device is primarily comprised of a body, further comprised of an interior container and at least one interchangeable brush head, further comprised of at least one nub with at least one continuous opening. The body and brush head are in fluid communication with each other, thereby allowing a liquid hair product to flow through the body into the brush head. Further, the brush head and the nubs are in fluid communication allowing the liquid hair product to flow through the nubs and out at least one opening at the bottom of the nubs. This allows the user to easily apply the liquid hair product directly to the hair while brushing.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Accordingly, the liquid dispensing hairbrush device of the present invention is particularly advantageous as it allows the user to effortlessly apply hair care products to the hair while simultaneously brushing. This allows the user to spend less time on their daily hair care routine, and more time elsewhere. In this manner, the liquid dispensing hairbrush device overcomes the limitations of existing hairbrushes known in the art.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Numerous benefits and advantages of this device will become apparent to those skilled in the art to which it pertains, upon reading and understanding the following detailed specification.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">To the accomplishment of the foregoing and related ends, certain illustrative aspects of the disclosed innovation are described herein in connection with the following description and the annexed drawings. These aspects are indicative, however, of but a few of the various ways in which the principles disclosed herein can be employed and are intended to include all such aspects and their equivalents. Other advantages and novel features will become apparent from the following detailed description when considered in conjunction with the drawings.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The description refers to provided drawings in which similar reference characters refer to similar parts throughout the different views, and in which:</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> illustrates a perspective view of one potential embodiment of a liquid dispensing hairbrush device of the present invention in accordance with the disclosed architecture;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> illustrates an enhanced perspective view of the interchangeable brush head of one potential embodiment of a liquid dispensing hairbrush device of the present invention in accordance with the disclosed architecture;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> illustrates an exploded view of one potential embodiment of the liquid dispensing hairbrush device of the present invention in accordance with the disclosed architecture; and</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> illustrates a flowchart chart of a method of using one potential embodiment of a liquid dispensing hairbrush device of the present invention in accordance with the disclosed architecture.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The innovation is now described with reference to the drawings, wherein like reference numerals are used to refer to like elements throughout. In the following description, for purposes of explanation, numerous specific details are set forth in order to provide a thorough understanding thereof. It may be evident, however, that the innovation can be practiced without these specific details. In other instances, well-known structures and devices are shown in block diagram form in order to facilitate a description thereof. Various embodiments are discussed hereinafter. It should be noted that the figures are described only to facilitate the description of the embodiments. They are not intended as an exhaustive description of the invention and do not limit the scope of the invention. Additionally, an illustrated embodiment need not have all the aspects or advantages shown. Thus, in other embodiments, any of the features described herein from different embodiments may be combined.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">As noted above, there is a long-felt need in the art for a hairbrush that eliminates the need for people to apply hair care products by hand. Further, there exists a long-felt need in the art for a hairbrush that can simultaneously apply essential oils and liquid hair products as the user brushes their hair. Further, there exists a long-felt need in the art for a hairbrush that allows a user to remove and apply different brush heads based of the need of the user, while still applying product through using the brush.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The present invention, in one exemplary embodiment, is comprised of a liquid dispensing hairbrush device primarily composed of a body, further comprised of an interior container and at least one interchangeable brush head, further comprised of at least one nub with at least one continuous opening. Further, the brush head and the body are attached via fasteners on both the brush head and the body. The brush head and the body are also in fluid communication via at least one continuous opening. The continuous openings on both the body and brush head are aligned in order to allow the liquid to flow through the body to the nubs of the brush head.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Further, the nubs are in fluid communication with the brush head through at least one continuous opening on the bottom of the nubs. This allows the liquid to flow through the device and onto the user's hair while simultaneously brushing the hair. As a result, a user saves ample amounts of time by not having to separately apply hair product and engage in brushing.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Accordingly, the liquid dispensing hairbrush of the present invention is particularly advantageous as it provides a device that allows a user to apply hair product while simultaneously brushing their hair. The device allows the user to save time and energy by providing a complete hair care tool that can easily and quickly apply product to the hair. In this manner, the liquid dispensing hairbrush device provides a novel means of hair care by allowing a user to simultaneously brush hair and apply hair care products.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Referring initially to the drawings, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> illustrates a perspective view of one potential embodiment of a liquid dispensing hairbrush device <b>100</b> of the present invention in accordance with the disclosed architecture. The device <b>100</b> is primarily comprised of a body <b>110</b>, further comprised of an interior container <b>112</b> and at least one interchangeable brush head <b>150</b>, further comprised of at least one nub <b>162</b> with at least one continuous opening <b>156</b>. In the preferred embodiment, the body <b>110</b> is ergonomic to the user's hand in shape, but may be any other shape without limitation such as, but not limited to: cylindrical, circular, rectangular, etc. In one embodiment, the body <b>110</b> (or any component of the device) may be manufactured from a ridged or semi-ridged (i.e., textured) plastic such as, but not limited to: acrylic, polycarbonate, polyethylene, thermoplastic, acrylonitrile butadiene styrene, low density polyethylene, medium density polyethylene, high density polyethylene, polyethylene terephthalate, polyvinyl chloride, polystyrene, polylactic acid, acetal, nylon, fiberglass, etc. The body <b>110</b> may have a grip area <b>132</b> located on the side surfaces <b>130</b> of the body <b>110</b> such as, but not limited to, a textured area, or a contoured area to fit to the user's hand. In another embodiment, the body <b>110</b> (or any component of the device <b>100</b>) may be made from a flexible plastic, silicone, rubber, or any other material known to one skilled in the art that allows the user to squeeze the body <b>110</b> to push the liquid <b>10</b> through the body <b>110</b> and out of the nubs <b>162</b>. In yet another embodiment, the grip area <b>132</b> of the body <b>110</b> may be comprised of a flexible rubber, plastic, or any other material known to one skilled in the art that allows the user to squeeze the grip area and push the liquid <b>10</b> through the body <b>110</b> and out of the openings in the nubs <b>162</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The body <b>110</b> also has a cap <b>122</b> located on the top surface <b>120</b> of the body <b>110</b> that allows a user to fill the interior container <b>112</b> with the liquid <b>10</b>. The cap <b>122</b> can be any fastener such as, but not limited to, a snap cap, a threaded cap, etc. The body <b>110</b> is further comprised of an interior container <b>112</b> that stores the liquid <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The body <b>110</b> also attaches to the brush head <b>150</b> via a fastener <b>142</b>, <b>154</b>. The brush head <b>150</b> can be made from a plurality of materials. In the preferred embodiment, the brush head <b>150</b> may be made from a plastic material such as, but not limited to: acrylic, polycarbonate, polyethylene, thermoplastic, acrylonitrile butadiene styrene, low density polyethylene, medium density polyethylene, high density polyethylene, polyethylene terephthalate, polyvinyl chloride, polystyrene, polylactic acid, acetal, nylon, fiberglass, etc. The brush head <b>150</b> has nubs <b>162</b> on the bottom surface <b>160</b> of the brush head <b>150</b>. In the preferred embodiment, the brush head <b>150</b> and the nubs <b>162</b> are made from the same plastic material.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> illustrates an enhanced perspective view of the interchangeable brush head <b>150</b> of one potential embodiment of a liquid dispensing hairbrush device <b>100</b>. In the preferred embodiment, the device <b>100</b> has at least one interchangeable brush head <b>150</b> that attaches to the bottom surface <b>140</b> of the body <b>110</b>. In differing embodiments, the brush head <b>150</b> may be any shape or style of brush head known in the art. The bottom surface <b>140</b> of the body <b>110</b> has at least one fastener <b>142</b> such as, but not limited to: hook and loop, snap button, tongue and groove, adhesive, magnetic, threaded fastener, etc. The bottom surface <b>140</b> also has at least one continuous opening <b>144</b> (of any shape, pattern, size, etc.) that is in fluid communication with at least one continuous opening <b>156</b> on the brush head <b>150</b>. The top surface <b>160</b> of the brush head <b>150</b> has a fastener <b>154</b> such as, but not limited to: hook and loop, snap button, tongue and groove, adhesive, magnetic, threaded fastener, etc., that engages the fastener <b>142</b> of the bottom surface <b>140</b> to allow the brush head <b>150</b> to removably attach to the bottom surface <b>140</b>. This allows the brush head <b>150</b> to be easily removed for cleaning purposes. The top surface <b>160</b> of the brush head <b>150</b> has at least one continuous opening that is in fluid communication with the continuous opening <b>144</b> on the bottom surface <b>140</b> of the body <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> illustrates an exploded view of one potential embodiment of the liquid dispensing hairbrush device <b>100</b>. In the preferred embodiment, the nubs <b>162</b> are located on the bottom surface <b>160</b> of the brush head <b>150</b>. The nubs <b>162</b> are comprised of at least one continuous opening <b>164</b> that allows the liquid <b>10</b> to be pushed out onto the user's hair, wherein said liquid flows from the interior container <b>112</b> to the brush head <b>150</b> and out the opening <b>164</b> of each nub <b>162</b> while the user uses the device <b>100</b> to brush their hair. The liquid <b>10</b> that may be used by the user can be any liquid that one skilled in the art would use on their hair and/or scalp.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">In one embodiment of the device <b>100</b> wherein the body <b>110</b> and brush head <b>150</b> are made from a rigid material, the liquid <b>10</b> naturally flows via gravity from the interior container <b>112</b> to the brush head <b>150</b> and out the opening <b>164</b> of each nub <b>162</b> while the user uses the device <b>100</b> to brush their hair. In an embodiment wherein the brush head <b>150</b> is made of a deformable material, the liquid <b>10</b> may flow via gravity from the interior container <b>112</b> to the brush head <b>150</b> and out the opening <b>164</b> of each nub <b>162</b> while the user uses the device <b>100</b> to brush their hair and pressing the brush head <b>150</b> down against their hair/scalp, which expels the liquid <b>10</b> from the nubs <b>162</b>. In a further embodiment wherein the body <b>110</b> is made of a deformable material, the liquid <b>10</b> may flow from the interior container <b>112</b> to the brush head <b>150</b> once the body <b>110</b> is squeezed by the hand of the user. After this occurs, the liquid <b>10</b> flows out the opening <b>164</b> of each nub <b>162</b> while the user uses the device <b>100</b> to brush their hair.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> illustrates a flowchart chart of a method of using one potential embodiment of a liquid dispensing hairbrush device <b>100</b>. The device <b>100</b> is also comprised of a method <b>200</b> of using the device <b>100</b>. First, the user opens the cap <b>122</b> on the top surface <b>120</b> of the body <b>110</b> [Step <b>202</b>]. Second, the user fills the interior container <b>112</b> with a liquid <b>10</b> [Step <b>204</b>]. Next, the user closes the cap <b>122</b> [Step <b>206</b>]. Then, the user places the device <b>100</b> on the user's hair and brushes over the hair, thereby allowing the liquid <b>10</b> to flow through the continuous openings <b>164</b> and onto the user's hair. [Step <b>208</b>]. In a different embodiment the user may squeeze the body <b>110</b> and/or press the brush head <b>150</b> against their hair/scalp to expel the liquid <b>10</b> through the nubs <b>162</b>, and onto the user's hair while brushing [Step <b>210</b>].</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Certain terms are used throughout the following description and claims to refer to particular features or components. As one skilled in the art will appreciate, different persons may refer to the same feature or component by different names. This document does not intend to distinguish between components or features that differ in name but not structure or function. As used herein &#x201c;liquid dispensing hairbrush device&#x201d; and &#x201c;device&#x201d; are interchangeable and refer to the liquid dispensing hairbrush device <b>100</b> of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Notwithstanding the foregoing, the liquid dispensing hairbrush device <b>100</b> of the present invention and its various components can be of any suitable size and configuration as is known in the art without affecting the overall concept of the invention, provided that they accomplish the above-stated objectives. One of ordinary skill in the art will appreciate that the size, configuration and material of the liquid dispensing hairbrush device <b>100</b> as shown in the FIGS. are for illustrative purposes only, and that many other sizes and shapes of the liquid dispensing hairbrush device <b>100</b> are well within the scope of the present disclosure. Although the dimensions of the liquid dispensing hairbrush device <b>100</b> are important design parameters for user convenience, the liquid dispensing hairbrush device <b>100</b> may be of any size, shape and/or configuration that ensures optimal performance during use and/or that suits the user's needs and/or preferences.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Various modifications and additions can be made to the exemplary embodiments discussed without departing from the scope of the present invention. While the embodiments described above refer to particular features, the scope of this invention also includes embodiments having different combinations of features and embodiments that do not include all of the described features. Accordingly, the scope of the present invention is intended to embrace all such alternatives, modifications, and variations as fall within the scope of the claims, together with all equivalents thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">What has been described above includes examples of the claimed subject matter. It is, of course, not possible to describe every conceivable combination of components or methodologies for purposes of describing the claimed subject matter, but one of ordinary skill in the art may recognize that many further combinations and permutations of the claimed subject matter are possible. Accordingly, the claimed subject matter is intended to embrace all such alterations, modifications and variations that fall within the spirit and scope of the appended claims. Furthermore, to the extent that the term &#x201c;includes&#x201d; is used in either the detailed description or the claims, such term is intended to be inclusive in a manner similar to the term &#x201c;comprising&#x201d; as &#x201c;comprising&#x201d; is interpreted when employed as a transitional word in a claim.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A liquid dispensing hairbrush device comprising:
<claim-text>a body comprised of a cap and an interior container; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a brush head comprised of a nub having an opening.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The liquid dispensing hairbrush device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the brush head is in fluid communication with the interior container.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The liquid dispensing hairbrush device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein a liquid stored within the interior container can be released via the opening in the nub.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The liquid dispensing hairbrush device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the body and the brush head are comprised of a rigid material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. A liquid dispensing hairbrush device comprising:
<claim-text>a body comprised of a cap, an interior container and a bottom surface having an opening;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a brush head comprised of a top surface having an opening;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a nub having an opening and positioned on the top surface; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fastener positioned on each of the top and bottom surfaces.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The liquid dispensing hairbrush device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the fastener of the top surface engages the fastener of the bottom surface to allow the brush head to removably attach to the body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The liquid dispensing hairbrush device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the fastener is a hook and loop fastener, a snap button fastener, a tongue and groove fastener, an adhesive fastener, a magnetic fastener or a threaded fastener.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The liquid dispensing hairbrush device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the opening of the bottom surface aligns with the opening of the brush head.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The liquid dispensing hairbrush device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the opening of the bottom surface and the opening of the brush head place the interior container of the body in fluid communication with the brush head.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The liquid dispensing hairbrush device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the body is textured.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The liquid dispensing hairbrush device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the body comprises a grip area.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The liquid dispensing hairbrush device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the cap is a snap cap or a threaded cap.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. The liquid dispensing hairbrush device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein at least one of the body and the brush head is comprised of a deformable material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The liquid dispensing hairbrush device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein a liquid is stored within the interior container.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. The liquid dispensing hairbrush device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein squeezing the body expels the liquid from the opening in the nub.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. The liquid dispensing hairbrush device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein pressing the brush head against a hair or scalp expels the liquid from the opening in the nub.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. A method of using a liquid dispensing hairbrush device to apply a liquid to a user's hair, the method comprising:
<claim-text>opening a cap of a body of the liquid dispensing hairbrush device to access an interior container;</claim-text>
<claim-text>filling the interior container with the liquid;</claim-text>
<claim-text>closing the cap; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>applying the liquid dispensing hairbrush device to the user's hair to allow the liquid to flow through an opening in a nub of the liquid dispensing hairbrush device and onto the user's hair.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. The method of using a liquid dispensing hairbrush device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein the body of the liquid dispensing hairbrush device is deformable.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. The method of using a liquid dispensing hairbrush device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein pressing the body against the user's hair expels the liquid from the opening in the nub.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. The method of using a liquid dispensing hairbrush device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein squeezing the body expels the liquid from the opening in the nub.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
