<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225537A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225537</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17897305</doc-number>
<date>20220829</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>17</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>33</main-group>
<subgroup>06</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>33</main-group>
<subgroup>06</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>2200</main-group>
<subgroup>08</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Decorative Artificial Tree with Interchangeable Scene</invention-title>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>63299443</doc-number>
<date>20220114</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Johnson</last-name>
<first-name>Julie</first-name>
<address>
<city>American Fork</city>
<state>UT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Johnson</last-name>
<first-name>Julie</first-name>
<address>
<city>American Fork</city>
<state>UT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The present invention relates to a multipurpose decorative artificial tree configured to be used in different holiday seasons for decoration. The artificial tree has detachable components and is easy to store. More specifically, the tree has a pole and a top branch having a portion therebetween which is devoid of artificial tree branches. A scene or a snow-globe like decoration is configured to be positioned between the pole and the top branch such that the tree having the scene represents a holiday season. In all embodiments, the scene is detachable and can be replaced with another scene representing another holiday season. In some exemplary embodiments, a motor powers the snow-globe like decoration for rotating the decoration and for providing power to a fan included in the snow-globe like decoration.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="151.05mm" wi="158.75mm" file="US20230225537A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="167.72mm" wi="163.75mm" file="US20230225537A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="187.20mm" wi="170.18mm" file="US20230225537A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="219.37mm" wi="165.86mm" file="US20230225537A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="162.05mm" wi="136.91mm" file="US20230225537A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="168.40mm" wi="125.90mm" file="US20230225537A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present application claims priority to, and the benefit of, U.S. Provisional Application No. 63/299,443, which was filed on Jan. 14, 2022 and is incorporated herein by reference in its entirety.</p>
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="tail"?>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates generally to the field of artificial trees for decoration. More specifically, the present invention relates to a novel artificial tree featuring an interchangeable scene or a snow globe-like decoration enabling the tree to be used and customized for different holiday seasons. The tree has a portion, void of artificial tree branches, where a scene is detachably positioned. The scene may have a design representing a holiday season and can be replaced with another scene representing, for example, another holiday season enabling use of the tree in different holiday seasons. Accordingly, the present disclosure makes specific reference thereto. Nonetheless, it is to be appreciated that aspects of the present invention are also equally applicable to other like applications, devices, and methods of manufacture.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">By way of background, holiday seasons are a time of great fun and happiness, and a great deal of the holiday cheer comes from the annual decorating traditions. Decorations, lighting, and celebrations are a part of celebrating holiday seasons and festivities like Easter, Halloween, Christmas, and more. Putting up and decorating artificial trees has long been practiced by people as a tradition and the most common of these is putting up the Christmas tree. The Christmas tree is an integral part of Christmas festivities and is often a pine or a fir, decorated with lights and ornaments. The act of putting the Christmas tree up and decorating it in one's home is a process that can be enjoyed by all members of the family. A decorated tree with all of the ornaments, the garland, and the tinsel is the centerpiece of a home's holiday decorations. People desire putting up and decorating similar artificial trees for other festivities, such as, Christmas, Halloween, Thanksgiving, and Easter; and may purchase holiday specific artificial trees. However, purchasing multiple trees for different occasions is expensive and multiple trees are difficult to store due to lack of space in urban homes.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Many people who do not want to spend money on buying multiple artificial trees try to build an artificial tree at home for decorations. However, this is not only time consuming and ineffective, but is also laborious. People desire artificial trees that can have interchangeable scenes and decorations thereby enabling a single tree to be customized for different holidays.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Standard artificial trees are non-collapsible and therefore, consume a lot of space for storage when not deployed. Further, the electronic components like lights, motors, and more can be damaged in storage. People desire an artificial tree that can be disassembled easily enabling easy and safe storage.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Therefore, there exists a long-felt need in the art for a decorative artificial tree that features interchangeable scenes and/or decorations. There is also a long-felt need in the art for a decorative artificial tree that can be customized and used for any festive or holiday season. Additionally, there is a long-felt need in the art for a decorative artificial tree that eliminates the requirement of purchasing multiple artificial trees for different occasions. Moreover, there is a long-felt need in the art for a decorative artificial tree that can accommodate snow globe mechanisms for decoration. Further, there is a long-felt need in the art for a decorative artificial tree that can be disassembled and is easy to store. Furthermore, there is a long-felt need in the art for a decorative artificial tree that provides a space to accommodate interchangeable scenes and decorations. Finally, there is a long-felt need in the art for a decorative artificial tree that enables users to choose from multiple scenes to display and accommodate any celebration or holiday easily and in a cost-effective manner.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The subject matter disclosed and claimed herein, in one embodiment thereof, comprises a multipurpose decorative artificial tree. The artificial tree is configured to be customized for decorations in various holiday seasons without requiring users to purchase separate trees for each holiday season. The tree features an elongated pole having a top end and a bottom end; a base detachably attached to the bottom end of the pole for supporting the tree; a decorative holiday scene positioned above the pole and detachably attached to the top end of the pole using a first fastening hole; the decorative scene having a design representing a holiday season; an elongated top branch positioned on top of the scene and detachably attached to a second fastening hole of the scene; a plurality of artificial tree branches and leaves that are removably attached to said pole and said top branch wherein the scene is void of artificial tree branches and leaves enabling the selected scene to be displayed, and the tree to be used in celebration of any holiday season. The scene can be replaced with a different scene having a design representing another holiday season.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In this manner, the multipurpose artificial tree of the present invention accomplishes all of the foregoing objectives and provides users with a unique artificial tree featuring an interchangeable scene or a snow globe-like decoration in the center. The tree enables users to choose from multiple scenes to display and accommodate any celebration or holiday. Interchangeable scenes and snow globes can be placed in a slot for proper display and for customization of the tree for a specific occasion.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The following presents a simplified summary in order to provide a basic understanding of some aspects of the disclosed innovation. This summary is not an extensive overview, and it is not intended to identify key/critical elements or to delineate the scope thereof. Its sole purpose is to present some general concepts in a simplified form as a prelude to the more detailed description that is presented later.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The subject matter disclosed and claimed herein, in one embodiment thereof, comprises a decorative artificial tree. The artificial tree further comprising an elongated pole having a top end and a bottom end; a base detachably attached to the bottom end of the pole for supporting the tree; a decorative scenery or display positioned above the pole and detachably attached to the top end of the pole using a first fastening hole; the decorative scenery or display having a design corresponding to the theme of a holiday season; an elongated top branch positioned on top of the scenery and detachably attached to a second fastening hole of the scenery; a plurality of artificial tree branches and leaves removably attached to said pole and said top branch wherein the scenery is void of artificial tree branches and leaves from a front view and a rear view, thereby enabling the selected scenery to be displayed and the tree to be used in celebration of any holiday season.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In yet another embodiment, the scenery is detachable from the artificial tree and is configured to be interchangeable with a scene having a design corresponding to a theme of another holiday season.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In yet another embodiment, the scenery corresponds to one of at least Christmas, Thanksgiving, Halloween, and Easter.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In yet another embodiment, the scenery has integrated LEDs for illumination.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In yet another embodiment, the scenery has a geometric 2-D or 3-D shape.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In yet another embodiment, a multipurpose decorative artificial tree is disclosed. The artificial tree has detachable components and includes an elongated pole having detachable artificial tree branches, an elongated top branch having detachable artificial tree branches, a portion devoid of detachable artificial tree branches positioned between said pole and said top branch; a decorative scene detachably positioned in said portion between the pole and the top branch for customizing the tree for a holiday season wherein the scene has a design indicating a holiday season; the scene is configured to be replaced with another selected scene, having a design indicating another holiday season, wherein the scene is fastened to the top end of the pole and the bottom end of the top branch for positioning in said portion.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In yet another embodiment, the pole is made of lightweight and durable plastic.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In yet another embodiment, the scene is a snow globe configured to be rotatable between said pole and said top branch.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In yet another embodiment, a decorative artificial bubble tree is disclosed. The bubble tree comprising a snow globe-like decoration positioned between two elongated poles; the snow globe-like decoration is fastened to the top end of a bottom pole and to the bottom end of a top pole; the snow globe-like decoration is coupled to a motor positioned at a base of the tree wherein the motor is configured to rotate the snow globe-like decoration using a pair of rotatable connectors, a power button for activating the rotation of the snow globe-like decoration and a fan integrated to the snow globe-like decoration.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Numerous benefits and advantages of this invention will become apparent to those skilled in the art to which it pertains upon reading and understanding of the following detailed specification.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">To the accomplishment of the foregoing and related ends, certain illustrative aspects of the disclosed innovation are described herein in connection with the following description and the annexed drawings. These aspects are indicative, however, of but a few of the various ways in which the principles disclosed herein can be employed and are intended to include all such aspects and their equivalents. Other advantages and novel features will become apparent from the following detailed description when considered in conjunction with the drawings.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The description refers to provided drawings in which similar reference characters refer to similar parts throughout the different views, and in which:</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> illustrates a front perspective view of one potential embodiment of a multipurpose decorative artificial tree of the present invention in accordance with the disclosed architecture;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> illustrates the artificial tree of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> mounted with the artificial tree branches in accordance with the disclosed architecture;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> illustrates a perspective view of another embodiment of a decorative artificial tree of the present invention in accordance with the disclosed architecture;</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> illustrates a front perspective view showing decorative artificial bubble tree of the present invention in accordance with the disclosed architecture; and</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> illustrates a disassembled view of the bubble tree of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> in accordance with the disclosed architecture.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PRESENT INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The innovation is now described with reference to the drawings, wherein like reference numerals are used to refer to like elements throughout. In the following description, for purposes of explanation, numerous specific details are set forth in order to provide a thorough understanding thereof. It may be evident, however, that the innovation can be practiced without these specific details. In other instances, well-known structures and devices are shown in block diagram form in order to facilitate a description thereof. Various embodiments are discussed hereinafter. It should be noted that the figures are described only to facilitate the description of the embodiments. They are not intended as an exhaustive description of the invention and do not limit the scope of the invention. Additionally, an illustrated embodiment need not have all the aspects or advantages shown. Thus, in other embodiments, any of the features described herein from different embodiments may be combined.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">As noted above, there exists a long-felt need in the art for a decorative artificial tree that features interchangeable scenes and/or decorations. There is also a long-felt need in the art for a decorative artificial tree that can be customized and used for any festive or holiday season. Additionally, there is a long-felt need in the art for a decorative artificial tree that eliminates the requirement of purchasing multiple artificial trees for different occasions. Moreover, there is a long-felt need in the art for a decorative artificial tree that can accommodate snow globe mechanisms for decoration. Further, there is a long-felt need in the art for a decorative artificial tree that can be disassembled and is easy for storage. Furthermore, there is a long-felt need in the art for a decorative artificial tree that provides a space to accommodate interchangeable scenes and decorations. Finally, there is a long-felt need in the art for a decorative artificial tree that enables users to choose from multiple scenes to display and accommodate any celebration or holiday easily and in a cost-effective manner.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The present invention, in one exemplary embodiment, is a decorative artificial bubble tree for celebratory or holiday seasons. The bubble tree comprising a snow globe-like decoration positioned between two elongated poles; the snow globe-like decoration is fastened to the top end of a bottom pole and to the bottom end of a top pole; the snow globe-like decoration is coupled to a motor positioned at base of the tree wherein the motor is configured to rotate the snow globe-like decoration using a pair of rotatable connectors, a power button for activating the rotation of the snow globe-like decoration and a fan integrated to the snow globe-like decoration.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Referring initially to the drawings, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> illustrates a front perspective view of one potential embodiment of the multipurpose decorative artificial tree <b>100</b> of the present invention in accordance with the disclosed architecture. The decorative artificial tree <b>100</b> is designed as a unique artificial tree in which scenes and decorations can be interchangeably placed to customize the tree for different festivities or seasons, such as, Easter, Halloween, Christmas, and more. More specifically, the tree <b>100</b> has a tree base <b>102</b> for supporting a tree pole or first lower portion <b>104</b>. The base <b>102</b> and the pole <b>104</b> are removably attached and the bottom end <b>1040</b> of the pole <b>104</b> is accommodated in the pole hole <b>1020</b>. The base <b>102</b> and the pole <b>104</b> can be detached to disassemble the artificial tree <b>100</b>. Both the base <b>102</b> and the pole <b>104</b> can be made from durable, lightweight, and insulated material like a suitable plastic material. The pole <b>104</b> is hollow and can accommodate one or more wires or circuits therein used for illumination of lights and for supplying power thereto for decorating the tree <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The pole <b>104</b> is longitudinal and extends from the bottom end <b>1040</b> to a top end <b>1042</b>. The pole <b>104</b> may have a plurality of detachable tree branches (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>) attached along the length of the pole <b>104</b>. A decorative scene <b>106</b>, preferably spherical in shape is configured to be fastened to the top end <b>1042</b> of the pole <b>104</b> such that the decorative scene <b>106</b> is positioned above the pole <b>104</b>. The decorative scene <b>106</b> has a bottom fastening hole <b>1060</b> at the bottom end <b>108</b> and a top fastening hole <b>1062</b> at the top end <b>110</b>. The fastening holes <b>1060</b>, <b>1062</b> are positioned diametrically opposed, such that the bottom fastening hole <b>1060</b> is fastened to the top end <b>1042</b> and the top fastening hole <b>1062</b> is fastened to a bottom end <b>1120</b> of the top branch or second upper portion <b>112</b>. The top branch <b>112</b> is configured as an independent longitudinal bar made of the same material as the pole <b>104</b> and has a closed top end <b>1122</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The detachable components of the base <b>102</b>, pole <b>104</b>, decorative scene <b>106</b>, and the top branch <b>112</b> together form the artificial tree <b>100</b> which is not only lightweight but can be disassembled for easy portability and storage. A plurality of artificial tree branches can also be extended sideways from the top branch <b>112</b> such that tree branches provide a look of a traditional real tree. The scene <b>106</b> can be interchangeable with different sceneries wherein the sceneries can be themed based upon different celebrations or holidays, such as, Christmas, Easter, Thanksgiving, Halloween, and much more. Based on the preference of a user, a scenery <b>106</b> based on any of the holidays can be selectively swapped/attached in order to customize the tree <b>100</b> for a holiday season.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The portion of the tree <b>100</b> between the top end <b>1042</b> of the pole <b>104</b> and the bottom end <b>1120</b> of the top branch <b>112</b> does not contain any tree branches wherein the scene <b>106</b> is visible, in one embodiment from at least a front view and a rear view. In another embodiment, the scene <b>106</b> is visible in a 360-degree range of view. As a result, the scenery <b>106</b> positioned between the pole <b>104</b> and the top branch <b>112</b> is properly displayed and adds to the celebration of a holiday season. The pole <b>104</b> is wide enough to easily accommodate the bottom fastening hole <b>1060</b> of the scenery <b>106</b> and similarly, the top branch <b>112</b> is wide enough to accommodate the top fastening hole <b>1062</b> of the scenery <b>106</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The multipurpose artificial tree <b>100</b> of the present invention is inexpensive, dependable, and fully effective in accomplishing its intended purpose of being used in different holiday seasons without requiring users to purchase multiple costly trees. Users can purchase the sceneries which can be accommodated between the pole and the top branch.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> illustrates the artificial tree <b>100</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> mounted with the artificial tree branches in accordance with the disclosed architecture. As illustrated, the artificial tree <b>100</b> has artificial tree branches <b>202</b> removably attached to the pole <b>104</b>. The pole <b>104</b> may have small holes (not shown) disposed along the length thereof for receiving artificial branches <b>202</b>. Alternatively, the artificial branches <b>202</b> can be tied to the pole <b>104</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Similarly, a second set of artificial branches <b>204</b> are removably attached to the top branch <b>112</b> for providing a complete conventional look to the tree <b>100</b>. The branches <b>202</b>, <b>204</b> may include decorations and illuminations <b>206</b> for providing an aesthetic appeal to the tree <b>100</b>. In one embodiment of the tree <b>100</b>, the base <b>102</b> may have wheels enabling the tree <b>100</b> to be easily moved between separate places. The wheels can be moved on any type of surface and terrain.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> illustrates a perspective view of another embodiment of the decorative artificial tree of the present invention in accordance with the disclosed architecture. In the present embodiment, the artificial tree <b>300</b> is designed for a Halloween festival or holiday. More specifically, the tree <b>300</b> has a base <b>302</b> having wheels <b>304</b> for movement of the tree <b>300</b>. An elongated pole <b>306</b> is removably attached to the base <b>302</b> at the bottom end <b>3060</b> of the pole <b>306</b>. At the top end <b>3062</b> of the pole <b>306</b>, a Halloween themed scenery or display <b>308</b> is removably attached by accommodating the bottom fastening hole <b>3080</b> of the scenery or display <b>308</b> into the top end <b>3062</b> of the pole <b>306</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The scenery or display <b>308</b> can be of any geometric shape in two dimension (2-D) or three dimension (3-D), and can be removably placed on the top of the pole <b>306</b>. The pole <b>306</b> has artificial leaves and branches <b>310</b> disposed thereon for providing the tree <b>300</b> with a look of a conventional decorative tree. The leaves and branches <b>310</b> may have illumination sources in the form of LED lights <b>312</b> that can provide electric power either using an external power source or an integrated battery (not shown). Based on the preferences of a user, the scenery or display <b>308</b> can be selectively replaced with another scenery to customize the tree <b>300</b> for any other holiday season.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> illustrates a front perspective view showing the decorative artificial bubble tree of the present invention in accordance with the disclosed architecture. In the present embodiment, the bubble tree <b>400</b> has a snow globe <b>402</b> as a decorative scenery or display. The snow globe <b>402</b> is connected to a motor <b>404</b> positioned at the base <b>406</b> of the tree <b>400</b> wherein the globe <b>402</b> and the motor <b>404</b> are connected through a wire <b>408</b> passing internally through the pole <b>410</b>. A motor <b>404</b> is configured to rotate the snow globe <b>360</b> degrees along the vertical axis formed by the pole <b>410</b> and a top branch <b>412</b>. The snow globe <b>402</b> positioned between the pole <b>410</b> and the top branch <b>412</b> comprises a 3-D scenery or display having any design <b>414</b> and a gel or air filled interior <b>416</b> therein for decoration. The interior <b>416</b> of the snow globe <b>402</b> can include snow particles therein (not illustrated).</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">A power button <b>418</b> is positioned on a control bar <b>420</b> enabling a user to activate rotation of the snow globe <b>402</b>. A snow globe speed adjuster and fan <b>422</b> enables a user to adjust the rotational speed of the snow globe <b>402</b> and the air flow therein to agitate the snow particles, and also adjusts the electric power received from the motor <b>404</b>. The snow globe <b>402</b> can be of any shape and size and can have any design or color as per preference of a user.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> illustrates a disassembled view of the bubble tree <b>400</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> in accordance with the disclosed architecture. The pole <b>410</b> is detachably attached to the base <b>406</b> by inserting the bottom end <b>502</b> of the pole <b>410</b> into the opening <b>504</b> of the base <b>406</b>. The base <b>406</b> is sturdy in order to support the weight of the pole <b>410</b> and the snow globe <b>402</b>. The top end <b>508</b> of the pole <b>410</b> is fastened to a rotatable connector <b>506</b> for rotatably fastening the snow globe <b>402</b> to the pole <b>410</b>. Similarly, the top branch (top pole) <b>412</b> is fastened to the second rotatable connector <b>510</b> for rotatably fastening the snow globe <b>402</b> to the top branch (top pole) <b>412</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The snow globe <b>402</b> is configured to rotate using the rotatable connectors <b>506</b>, <b>510</b> which are powered by the motor <b>404</b>. In one exemplary embodiment, the wire for driving the snow globe <b>402</b> passes through an interior hollow space of the pole <b>410</b>, however, in some embodiments, the wire can be exterior to the pole <b>410</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Other shapes, designs and configurations of the decorative artificial trees and the sceneries are contemplated and fall within the scope of the invention without affecting the utility of the device. Since the sceneries can be easily interchanged, a single tree can be used for different holidays, such as, Christmas, Easter, Thanksgiving, Halloween, and much more. Further, the scenery is visible from all directions and is void of artificial tree branches.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">Certain terms are used throughout the following description and claims to refer to particular features or components. As one skilled in the art will appreciate, different persons may refer to the same feature or component by different names. This document does not intend to distinguish between components or features that differ in name but not structure or function. As used herein &#x201c;artificial tree&#x201d;, &#x201c;decorative artificial bubble tree&#x201d;, &#x201c;decorative artificial tree&#x201d;, &#x201c;multipurpose decorative artificial tree&#x201d; and &#x201c;tree&#x201d; are interchangeable and refer to the multipurpose decorative artificial tree <b>100</b>, <b>300</b>, <b>400</b> of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Notwithstanding the foregoing, the multipurpose decorative artificial tree <b>100</b>, <b>300</b>, <b>400</b> of the present invention can be of any suitable size and configuration as is known in the art without affecting the overall concept of the invention, provided that it accomplishes the above-stated objectives. One of ordinary skill in the art will appreciate that the multipurpose decorative artificial tree <b>100</b>, <b>300</b>, <b>400</b> as shown in the FIGS. are for illustrative purposes only, and that many other sizes and shapes of the multipurpose decorative artificial tree <b>100</b>, <b>300</b>, <b>400</b> are well within the scope of the present disclosure. Although the dimensions of the multipurpose decorative artificial tree <b>100</b>, <b>300</b>, <b>400</b> are important design parameters for user convenience, the multipurpose decorative artificial tree <b>100</b>, <b>300</b>, <b>400</b> may be of any size that ensures optimal performance during use and/or that suits the user's needs and/or preferences.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Various modifications and additions can be made to the exemplary embodiments discussed without departing from the scope of the present invention. While the embodiments described above refer to particular features, the scope of this invention also includes embodiments having different combinations of features and embodiments that do not include all of the described features. Accordingly, the scope of the present invention is intended to embrace all such alternatives, modifications, and variations as fall within the scope of the claims, together with all equivalents thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">What has been described above includes examples of the claimed subject matter. It is, of course, not possible to describe every conceivable combination of components or methodologies for purposes of describing the claimed subject matter, but one of ordinary skill in the art may recognize that many further combinations and permutations of the claimed subject matter are possible. Accordingly, the claimed subject matter is intended to embrace all such alterations, modifications and variations that fall within the spirit and scope of the appended claims. Furthermore, to the extent that the term &#x201c;includes&#x201d; is used in either the detailed description or the claims, such term is intended to be inclusive in a manner similar to the term &#x201c;comprising&#x201d; as &#x201c;comprising&#x201d; is interpreted when employed as a transitional word in a claim.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A selectively decorative tree comprising:
<claim-text>a tree base, a tree pole, a selective scene, and a plurality of lights;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said tree base having a pole hole for supporting said tree pole and said selective scene thereabove;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said tree base and said tree pole are removably attached;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said tree pole having a first lower portion and a second upper portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said selective scene mounted between said first lower portion and said second upper portion; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>further wherein said selective scene is a holiday scene.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The selectively decorative tree of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said tree base and said tree pole comprising an insulated plastic material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The selectively decorative tree of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein said tree pole is hollow having an electrical cord therein for powering said selective scene and said plurality of lights.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The selectively decorative tree of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein said selective scene is 3-D.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The selectively decorative tree of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein said selective scene is spherical and fastened to a top end of said first lower portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The selectively decorative tree of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein said first lower portion and said second upper portion having a plurality of holes therethrough for receiving tree branches extending therefrom.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The selectively decorative tree of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein said tree branches having illuminations thereon.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The selectively decorative tree of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein said selective scene is visible in a 360 degree range of view.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. A selectively decorative tree comprising:
<claim-text>a tree base, a tree pole, and an illuminated selective scene;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said tree base having a pole hole for supporting said tree pole and said selective scene thereabove;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said tree base and said tree pole are removably attached;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said tree pole having a first lower portion and a second upper portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said illuminated selective scene mounted atop said second upper portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said illuminated selective scene is 3-D; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>further wherein said illuminated selective scene is visible in a 360-degree range of view.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The selectively decorative tree of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein said illuminated selective scene is rotatable about said second upper portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The selectively decorative tree of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein said tree pole is hollow having an electrical cord therein for powering said illuminated selective scene.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The selectively decorative tree of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein said illuminated selective scene is a holiday scene selected from a group consisting of Halloween, Thanksgiving, Christmas, and Easter.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. The selectively decorative tree of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein said illuminated selective scene is spherical.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The selectively decorative tree of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein said first lower portion and said second upper portion having a plurality of holes therethrough for receiving tree branches extending therefrom.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. The selectively decorative tree of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein said tree branches having a plurality of lights thereon.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. A selectively decorative tree comprising:
<claim-text>a tree base, a tree pole, and an illuminated selective scene;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said tree base having a pole hole for supporting said tree pole and said selective scene thereabove;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said tree base and said tree pole are removably attached;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said tree pole having a first lower portion and a second upper portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said illuminated selective scene mounted atop said second upper portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said illuminated selective scene is 3-D;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said illuminated selective scene is visible in a 360-degree range of view;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said tree pole is hollow having an electrical cord therein for powering said illuminated selective scene; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>further wherein said first lower portion and said second upper portion having a plurality of holes therethrough for receiving tree branches extending therefrom.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. The selectively decorative tree of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein said illuminated selective scene is rotatable about said second upper portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. The selectively decorative tree of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein said illuminated selective scene is a holiday scene selected from a group consisting of Halloween, Thanksgiving, Christmas, and Easter.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. The selectively decorative tree of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein said tree base having wheels thereunder.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. The selectively decorative tree of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein said illuminated selective scene is a snow-globe.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
