<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225394A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225394</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17579080</doc-number>
<date>20220119</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>17</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>24</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>30</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>24</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>28</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>24</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>24</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>30</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>24</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>28</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>24</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">WATER PIPE ADAPTER</invention-title>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Sherrett</last-name>
<first-name>Daniel Vincent</first-name>
<address>
<city>Upper Marlboro</city>
<state>MD</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Sherrett</last-name>
<first-name>Daniel Vincent</first-name>
<address>
<city>Upper Marlboro</city>
<state>MD</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A water pipe bowl adapter includes a body having an upper end surface, a lower end surface, an outer edge, and a flexible lip that extends downwardly from the body outer edge. There is a through opening extending through each of the upper and lower end surfaces. The lip and lower end recessed portion form a seal for connection with an upper end of a water pipe bowl. When the adapter is arranged on a water pipe bowl, the lip covers an outer surface of an upper portion of the bowl and is secured therewith via a frictional force and the lower end contacts an upper edge of the bowl to connect the adapter with the bowl and create an airtight seal therewith. A user can then place a cigarette in the through opening and smoke through a water pipe with an airtight, secure seal.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="61.30mm" wi="114.55mm" file="US20230225394A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="195.41mm" wi="118.62mm" file="US20230225394A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="235.80mm" wi="119.38mm" file="US20230225394A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="169.50mm" wi="104.65mm" file="US20230225394A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="228.60mm" wi="113.28mm" file="US20230225394A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="218.44mm" wi="168.74mm" file="US20230225394A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE DISCLOSURE</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present disclosure relates generally to water pipes, and more specifically to an adapter for water pipe bowls.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Water pipes are well known in the smoking apparatus field. A typical pipe includes a base, a removable bowl, a smoking chamber and a mouthpiece, among other elements. When the bowl, having cannabis, tobacco or another substance placed therein, is connected to the pipe and a substance is lit, a user inhales through the mouthpiece, and smoke travels through the chamber to the user. Water is often placed within the pipe to filter the smoke before it is inhaled.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">A &#x201c;joint bubbler&#x201d;, as shown in prior art <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> and <b>2</b></figref>, is similar to a water pipe but on a smaller scale and for a different purpose. This apparatus includes a bulbous body containing two openings, one having a tubular configuration through which a user inhales, and the other having a generally conical configuration for receiving a cigarette (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>). In practice, a user adds water to the bulbous portion through one of the two openings, inserts a marijuana or tobacco cigarette into the conical opening, lights the cigarette, and inhales through the tubular opening. As with the water pipe, the water filters the smoke as it passes through the bulbous portion.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Though these joint bubblers are useful and can be a good substitute to a water pipe when smoking a cigarette, they require a separate apparatus from the water pipe, they are expensive, they break easily, and they are complex for glass makers to construct. Rather than rely on these devices when one wishes to smoke a cigarette through a water pipe, a new apparatus is needed that is less expensive, simpler, and more durable.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE DISCLOSURE</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Accordingly, it is an object of the present disclosure to provide a water pipe bowl adapter that includes a body having an upper end surface, a lower end surface, an outer edge, and a flexible lip that extends downwardly from the body outer edge to create a lower end recessed portion. The lip and lower end recessed portion form a seal for connection with an upper end of a water pipe bowl. A through opening in the body extends through each of the upper and lower end surfaces, with which a cigarette can connect. When the adapter is connected with a water pipe bowl, the lip covers an outer surface of an upper portion of the bowl and is secured therewith via a frictional force, and the lower end contacts an upper edge of the bowl to connect the adapter with the bowl and create an airtight seal therewith. A user can then place a cigarette in the through opening and smoke through a water pipe with an airtight, secure seal. Preferably, the body has a cylindrical configuration and comprises silicone material.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In one embodiment, there is a tubular insert configured for an airtight connection with the body through opening. The insert includes an upper end having a flange connected therewith and a lower end. The tubular insert further contains a through opening extending through each of the upper end and lower end. When inserted into the adapter opening, the flange prevents the insert from passing through the adapter opening. A cigarette can then be placed in the insert for ease of smoking.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In another embodiment of the adapter, the body lower end surface further includes a convex portion extending therefrom which contains the body through opening and is configured for connection with an inner surface of a water pipe bowl. For this embodiment, the edge of the flexible lip extends inwardly toward a center point of the body, and a distance between the convex portion and the outer edge corresponds with a width between an inner surface and an outer surface of the water pipe bowl.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In a further embodiment, the body comprises an elastic material wherein the flexible lip is removably connectable with a water pipe bowl via a stretch force. Preferably, the body has a generally annular configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In yet another embodiment, the body through opening is located at a center of the body and has a circular configuration in a horizontal cross-section.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE FIGURES</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Other objects and advantages of the disclosure will become apparent from a study of the following specification when viewed in the light of the accompanying drawing, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a front perspective view of a water pipe adapter known in the art;</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a front perspective view of the adapter of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> with a cigarette therein;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is top perspective view of a first embodiment of water pipe adapter according to the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is a side view of the adapter of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is a bottom perspective view of the adapter of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is a side view of a water pipe adapter insert according to the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> is a perspective view of the insert of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>8</b> and <b>9</b></figref> are perspective views of a water pipe bowl with the adapter of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> connected therewith;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref> is a perspective view of the water pipe bowl with adapter of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>8</b> and <b>9</b></figref> with the insert included;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b></figref> is a top view second embodiment of a water pipe bowl adapter according to the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>12</b></figref> is a side view of the adapter of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>13</b></figref> is a top view of a third embodiment of a water pipe bowl adapter according to the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>14</b></figref> is a top perspective view of the adapter of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>13</b></figref>; and</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>15</b></figref> is a bottom perspective view of the adapter of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>13</b></figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The present disclosure includes a water pipe bowl adapter. Referring first to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>3</b>-<b>5</b></figref>, the adapter <b>2</b> includes a body <b>4</b> having an upper end surface <b>6</b>, a lower end surface <b>8</b>, an outer edge <b>10</b>, and a flexible lip <b>12</b> that extends downwardly from the body outer edge. There is a through opening <b>14</b> extending through each of the upper and lower end surfaces. The lip and lower end recessed portion form a seal for connection with an upper end of a water pipe bowl (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>8</b>-<b>10</b></figref>). Once connected with the bowl, the bowl is placed in a down stem of a water pipe, a cigarette is placed in the adapter, and a user can then light the cigarette and inhale smoke through a mouthpiece in the water pipe.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The body <b>2</b> of this embodiment has a cylindrical configuration and is comprised of silicone material. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, the body lower end surface <b>6</b> further includes a convex portion <b>16</b> extending therefrom which contains the through opening. This is configured for connection with an inner surface of a water pipe bowl. A distance D between the convex portion and the edge of the lip <b>12</b> corresponds with a width between an inner surface and an outer surface of the water pipe bowl. It will be understood by those with skill in the art that this distance D may vary based on the size of a corresponding bowl.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>8</b> and <b>9</b></figref>, when the adapter <b>2</b> is arranged on a water pipe bowl <b>18</b>, the lip <b>12</b> covers an outer surface of an upper portion <b>20</b> of the bowl and is secured therewith via a frictional force provided due to the flexibility of the adapter material. The lower end <b>8</b> of the body contacts an upper edge <b>22</b> of the bowl to connect the adapter with the bowl and create an airtight seal therewith. Once connected, a cigarette <b>24</b> is inserted into the adapter and smoked as detailed above.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b> and <b>7</b></figref>, the adapter further includes a tubular insert <b>26</b> configured for an airtight connection with the body through opening <b>14</b>. The insert includes an upper end <b>28</b> having a flange <b>30</b>, a central body <b>32</b> and a lower end <b>34</b>. The tubular insert contains a through opening <b>36</b> extending through each of the upper end and lower end. This adapter may be included to provide a more secure connection between a cigarette and the adapter to secure a cigarette therewith. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref> shows the water pipe bowl of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>8</b> and <b>9</b></figref> with the insert included between adapter <b>2</b> and cigarette <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>11</b> and <b>12</b></figref> show another embodiment of the adapter <b>102</b>. Similarly, this embodiment includes a body <b>104</b>, an upper end surface <b>106</b>, a lower end surface <b>108</b>, an outer edge <b>110</b>, a flexible lip <b>112</b>, and a central through opening <b>114</b>. Unlike with the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>3</b>-<b>5</b></figref>, the body has a flat, disc-like configuration. The body also comprises an elastic material, such as latex or a similar synthetic material, wherein the body is configured to stretch such that the flexible lip is pulled over the upper end of a bowl to removably connect the adapter with the bowl upper edge <b>22</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>9</b> and <b>10</b></figref>). The elasticity of the adapter and lip secure the adapter on the bowl upper edge.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>13</b>-<b>15</b></figref> show a third embodiment of the adapter <b>202</b>. In this embodiment, the body <b>204</b> also includes an upper end surface <b>206</b>, a lower end surface <b>208</b>, an outer edge <b>210</b>, and a flexible lip <b>212</b>. This embodiment comprises a more rigid material, though with sufficient flexure to allow for connection with a water pipe bowl that does not directly correspond to the configuration of the adapter. There is also a through opening <b>214</b> located at a center of the body with which a cigarette can be inserted. For this embodiment, the adapter is placed over a bowl such that the lower end surface <b>208</b> contacts the upper edge of the bowl. The lip <b>212</b> extends downwardly to secure the adapter to the bowl and prevent unwanted air from entering the bowl. Preferably, the lip has a width that generally corresponds to the width of the upper end of a bowl.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Although the above description references particular embodiments, it is to be understood that these embodiments are merely illustrative of the principles and applications of the present disclosure. It is therefore to be understood that numerous modifications may be made to the illustrative embodiments and that other arrangements may be devised and employed without departing from the spirit and scope of the present disclosure.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A water pipe bowl adapter, comprising:
<claim-text>(a) a body having an upper end surface, a lower end surface, and an outer edge, said body containing a through opening extending through each said upper and lower end surfaces; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) a flexible lip extending downwardly from said body outer edge to define a lower end recessed portion, said lip and lower end recessed portion forming a seal for connection with an upper end of a water pipe bowl, whereby when the adapter is arranged on a water pipe bowl, said lip covers an outer surface of an upper portion of the bowl and is secured therewith via a frictional force and said lower end contacts an upper edge of the bowl to connect the adapter with the bowl and create an airtight seal therewith.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. A water pipe bowl adapter as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, and further comprising a tubular insert configured for an airtight connection with said body through opening, said insert including an upper end and a lower end, said upper end having a flange, said tubular insert containing a through opening extending through each said upper end and lower end.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. A water pipe bowl adapter as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said body lower end surface further includes a convex portion extending therefrom, said convex portion containing said through opening and configured for connection with an inner surface of said water pipe bowl.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. A water pipe bowl adapter as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein a distance between said convex portion and said outer edge corresponds with a width between an inner surface and an outer surface of the water pipe bowl.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. A water pipe bowl adapter as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein said body has a cylindrical configuration.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. A water pipe bowl adapter as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein said body comprises a silicone material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. A water pipe bowl adapter as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said body comprises an elastic material, said flexible lip being removably connectable with a water pipe bowl via a stretch force.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. A water pipe bowl adapter as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein said body has a generally annular configuration.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. A water pipe bowl adapter as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said body through opening is located at a center of said body, said body through opening having a circular configuration in a horizontal cross-section.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. A water pipe bowl adapter as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein an edge of said flexible lip extends inwardly toward a center of said body.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
