<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225449A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225449</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18099098</doc-number>
<date>20230119</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>43</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>9</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>43</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>9</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">ARTICLE OF FOOTWEAR HAVING A FRAME</invention-title>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>63300934</doc-number>
<date>20220119</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="obligated-assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>PUMA SE</orgname>
<address>
<city>Herzogenaurach</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>DE</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>McKenzie</last-name>
<first-name>Carly</first-name>
<address>
<city>Herzogenaurach</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="01" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Fauconnier</last-name>
<first-name>Sidney</first-name>
<address>
<city>Nuremberg</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="02" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Girard</last-name>
<first-name>Romain</first-name>
<address>
<city>Lauf an der Pegnitz</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="03" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Donovan</last-name>
<first-name>Patrick</first-name>
<address>
<city>Fuerth</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="04" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Desens</last-name>
<first-name>Heiko Frank</first-name>
<address>
<city>Berlin</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="05" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Taylor</last-name>
<first-name>Daniel Simon</first-name>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An article of footwear includes an upper having a fastening mechanism, a sole, and a frame having an exterior surface and an interior surface. The sole includes a midsole structure and an outsole structure. The interior surface of the frame is adjacent portions of the midsole structure, the outsole structure, and the upper. The frame further has a lattice-work structure formed by a plurality of apertures extending through the interior and exterior surfaces of the frame such that at least some of the portions of the midsole structure, the outsole structure, and the upper adjacent the interior surface of the frame are exposed through the plurality of apertures. The fastening mechanism includes a fastening member extending through at least one aperture of the plurality of apertures of the frame.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="90.85mm" wi="158.75mm" file="US20230225449A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="228.09mm" wi="147.32mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225449A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="223.01mm" wi="175.94mm" file="US20230225449A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="229.11mm" wi="147.32mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225449A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="226.06mm" wi="140.89mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225449A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="225.98mm" wi="176.95mm" file="US20230225449A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="225.81mm" wi="176.02mm" file="US20230225449A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="220.13mm" wi="176.11mm" file="US20230225449A1-20230720-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="224.20mm" wi="147.83mm" file="US20230225449A1-20230720-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="241.38mm" wi="175.43mm" file="US20230225449A1-20230720-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="220.81mm" wi="171.87mm" file="US20230225449A1-20230720-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="222.00mm" wi="176.87mm" file="US20230225449A1-20230720-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00012" num="00012">
<img id="EMI-D00012" he="222.33mm" wi="173.23mm" file="US20230225449A1-20230720-D00012.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00013" num="00013">
<img id="EMI-D00013" he="210.14mm" wi="172.72mm" file="US20230225449A1-20230720-D00013.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00014" num="00014">
<img id="EMI-D00014" he="230.97mm" wi="174.16mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225449A1-20230720-D00014.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00015" num="00015">
<img id="EMI-D00015" he="229.02mm" wi="176.53mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225449A1-20230720-D00015.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00016" num="00016">
<img id="EMI-D00016" he="233.43mm" wi="150.11mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225449A1-20230720-D00016.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00017" num="00017">
<img id="EMI-D00017" he="240.20mm" wi="151.30mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225449A1-20230720-D00017.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00018" num="00018">
<img id="EMI-D00018" he="230.89mm" wi="174.67mm" file="US20230225449A1-20230720-D00018.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00019" num="00019">
<img id="EMI-D00019" he="226.91mm" wi="154.60mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225449A1-20230720-D00019.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00020" num="00020">
<img id="EMI-D00020" he="229.36mm" wi="144.36mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225449A1-20230720-D00020.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00021" num="00021">
<img id="EMI-D00021" he="229.62mm" wi="147.40mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225449A1-20230720-D00021.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00022" num="00022">
<img id="EMI-D00022" he="232.58mm" wi="152.48mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225449A1-20230720-D00022.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00023" num="00023">
<img id="EMI-D00023" he="226.06mm" wi="136.99mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225449A1-20230720-D00023.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00024" num="00024">
<img id="EMI-D00024" he="228.52mm" wi="151.30mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225449A1-20230720-D00024.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00025" num="00025">
<img id="EMI-D00025" he="229.70mm" wi="143.76mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225449A1-20230720-D00025.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims the benefit of priority from U.S. Provisional Application No. 63/300,934, filed Jan. 19, 2022, the contents of which are incorporated herein by reference in its entirety.</p>
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="tail"?>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">REFERENCE REGARDING FEDERALLY SPONSORED RESEARCH OR DEVELOPMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Not applicable</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SEQUENCE LISTING</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Not applicable</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">1. Field of the Invention</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The present disclosure relates generally to an article of footwear including a frame.</p>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">2. Description of the Background</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Many conventional shoes or other articles of footwear generally comprise an upper and a sole attached to a lower end of the upper. Conventional shoes further include an internal space, i.e., a void or cavity, which is created by interior surfaces of the upper and sole, that receives a foot of a user before securing the shoe to the foot. The sole is attached to a lower surface or boundary of the upper and is positioned between the upper and a ground surface. As a result, the sole typically provides stability and cushioning to the user when the shoe is being worn. In some instances, the sole may include multiple components, such as an outsole, a midsole, and a top portion. The outsole may provide traction to a bottom surface of the sole, and the midsole may be attached to an inner surface of the outsole and may provide cushioning or added stability to the sole. For example, a sole may include a particular foam material that may increase stability at one or more desired locations along the sole, or a foam material that may reduce stress or impact energy on the foot or leg when a user is running, walking, or engaged in another activity. The sole may also include additional components, such as plates, embedded with the sole to increase the overall stiffness of the sole and reduce energy loss during use.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The upper generally extends upward from the sole and defines an interior cavity that completely or partially encases a foot. In most cases, the upper extends over the instep and toe regions of the foot, and across medial and lateral sides thereof. Many articles of footwear may also include a tongue that extends across the instep region to bridge a gap between edges of medial and lateral sides of the upper, which collectively define an opening into the cavity. The tongue may also be disposed below a lacing system and between medial and lateral sides of the upper, to allow for adjustment of shoe tightness. The tongue may further be manipulatable by a user to permit entry or exit of a foot from the internal space or cavity. In addition, the lacing system may allow a user to adjust certain dimensions of the upper or the sole, thereby allowing the upper to accommodate a wide variety of foot types having varying sizes and shapes.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The upper of many shoes may comprise a wide variety of materials, which may be utilized to form the upper and chosen for use based on one or more intended uses of the shoe. The upper may also include portions comprising varying materials specific to a particular area of the upper. For example, added stability may be desirable at a front of the upper or adjacent a heel region so as to provide a higher degree of resistance or rigidity. In contrast, other portions of a shoe may include a soft woven textile to provide an area with stretch-resistance, flexibility, air-permeability, or moisture-wicking properties.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Sole assemblies generally extend between a ground surface and the upper. In some examples, the sole assembly includes an outsole that provides abrasion-resistance and traction with the ground surface. The outsole may be formed from rubber or other materials that impart durability and wear-resistance, and enhance traction with the ground surface.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">While many currently-available shoes have varying features related to the above-noted properties, many shoes, including athletic shoes, and even more so running shoes, have sole structures in which the outsole may wear faster than the rest of the sole structure and/or the upper of the shoe. This results in users needing to replace entire sets of shoes even though the upper and the sole structure, other than the outsole, have not yet worn to a condition requiring replacement. Further, some physical activities have differing support requirements at different locations of the sole structure and/or upper of shoes, including athletic shoes, to benefit the user of the shoe during such physical activities. For example, for traditional running activity, increased support in the heel region of the shoe may be beneficial to a user of the shoe, while for traditional cross training activity, increased support along the lateral and medial sides of the shoe may be beneficial to a user of the shoe.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Therefore, articles of footwear having features that permit the outsole of the sole structure to be replaced and/or that permit the sole structure to be customized by a user are desired. These and other deficiencies with the prior art are addressed by the following disclosure.</p>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">An article of footwear, as described herein, may have various configurations. The article of footwear may have an upper and a sole structure connected to the upper.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In some aspects, the present disclosure provides an article of footwear having an upper with a fastening mechanism, a sole structure including a midsole and an outsole, and a frame. The frame can have an exterior surface and an interior surface opposite the exterior surface. The interior surface of the frame can be adjacent portions of the midsole, the outsole, and the upper. The frame can further have a lattice-work structure formed by a plurality of apertures extending through the interior and exterior surfaces of the frame such that at least some of the portions of the midsole, the outsole, and the upper adjacent the interior surface of the frame are exposed through the plurality of apertures. The fastening mechanism of the upper can include a fastening member that extends through at least one aperture of the plurality of apertures of the frame.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In some embodiments, the frame can extend along a medial side and a lateral side of the article of footwear. In such embodiments, the lattice-work structure of the frame may extend along at least the lateral side of the article of footwear.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In some embodiments, the frame can extend along a medial side, a lateral side, and a heel region of the article of footwear. In such embodiments, the lattice-work structure of the frame may extend along at least the lateral side and the heel region of the article of footwear.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In some embodiments, the lattice work structure of the frame may extend along a percentage in a range of about 5% to about 60% of an exterior surface of the upper.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In some embodiments, the fastening member of the fastening mechanism can be a lace. In some embodiments, the fastening member of the fastening mechanism can be a hook and a loop that can be configured to removably engage the hook.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In some embodiments, a percentage in a range of about 30% to about 90% of the frame can include the lattice-work structure. In some embodiments, a percentage in a range of about 60% to about 90% of the frame includes the lattice-work structure.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In some embodiments, the lattice-work structure of the frame can be formed of a material that is configured to adapt to a wearer's foot. In some embodiments, the lattice-work structure of the frame may be formed of a material that can be configured to elastically deform under tension that can be exerted by the fastening member of the fastening mechanism. In some embodiments, portions of the lattice-work structure of the frame adjacent the outsole can have a greater stiffness than portions of the lattice-work structure of the frame adjacent the midsole.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In some embodiments, the frame of the article of footwear can further include an outsole member that may at least partially define the outsole of the sole structure. In some such embodiments, the outsole member may be disposed between the midsole and the interior surface of the frame along a bottom side of the frame. In other such embodiments, the outsole member can be disposed on the exterior surface of the frame along a bottom side of the frame.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">In other aspects, the present disclosure provides a frame for an article of footwear that includes an upper and a sole structure. The frame can have a lattice-work structure that can be formed by a plurality of apertures extending through an exterior surface and an interior surface of the frame. The interior surface of the frame may be configured for placement adjacent portions of a midsole and an outsole of the sole structure. The frame can be configured to be removably attachable to at least the sole structure of the article of footwear such that, when the frame is removably attached to the article of footwear, at least some of the portions of the midsole and the outsole adjacent the interior surface of the frame can be exposed through the plurality of apertures of the frame</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In some embodiments, the frame can further include a removable outsole member that may be disposed adjacent a bottom side of the frame.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In some embodiments, two or more apertures of the plurality of apertures of the frame can be configured to receive a portion of a lace of the upper to secure the frame to the sole structure of the article of footwear. In such embodiments, at least portions of the lattice-work structure of the frame can be configured to elastically deform under tension when the lace received within the two or more apertures of the plurality of apertures is in a tightened configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In some aspects, the present disclosure provides an article of footwear that may include an upper, a sole structure having a midsole and an outsole, and a frame. The frame can have an exterior surface and an interior surface. The interior surface of the frame can be adjacent portions of the midsole, the outsole, and the upper in a heel region of the article of footwear. The frame can have a lattice-work structure formed by a plurality of apertures extending through the interior and exterior surfaces of the frame such that at least some of the portions of the midsole, the outsole, and the upper adjacent the interior surface of the frame can be exposed through the plurality of apertures. The frame can be removably attached to at least the sole structure of the article of footwear.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">In some embodiments, the portion of the midsole in the heel region adjacent the interior surface of the frame can include a plurality of midsole members that may be removably attached to a bottom side of the upper. In such embodiments, the frame may extend over the plurality of midsole members of the sole structure. In such embodiments, the frame can further include an outsole member that can be disposed between the plurality of midsole members and the interior surface of the frame along a bottom side of the frame.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Other aspects of the article of footwear, including features and advantages thereof, will become apparent to one of ordinary skill in the art upon examination of the figures and detailed description herein. Therefore, all such aspects of the article of footwear are intended to be included in the detailed description and this summary.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0008" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a lateral side view of an article of footwear configured as a right shoe that includes an upper, a sole structure, and a frame, according to an embodiment of the disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a top view of the article of footwear of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, with a frame and a lacing mechanism of an upper removed;</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a top plan view of the article of footwear of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, with an upper removed and a user's skeletal foot structure overlaid thereon;</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is a bottom view of the article of footwear of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is a bottom view of the article of footwear of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, with the frame shown as translucent;</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is a lateral side view of another example of an article of footwear that is similar to the article of footwear of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> is a bottom view of the article of footwear of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> is a bottom view of the article of footwear of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>, with another example midsole member in a first compressed configuration;</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref> is a bottom view of the article of footwear of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref>, with the example midsole member in a second compressed configuration;</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref> is a bottom view of the article of footwear of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>, with an example outsole member included in the frame;</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b></figref> is a bottom view of the article of footwear of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>, with another example outsole member included in the frame;</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>12</b></figref> is a bottom-distal side partial detail view of the frame and the outsole member of the article of footwear of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>13</b></figref> is an exploded view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>12</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>14</b></figref> is a bottom view of the article of footwear of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>, with yet another example outsole member included in the frame:</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>15</b></figref> is a bottom-distal side partial detail view of the frame and the outsole member of the article of footwear of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>14</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>16</b></figref> is an exploded view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>15</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>17</b></figref> is a bottom view of the article footwear of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>, with another example frame;</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>18</b></figref> is a bottom view of the article of footwear of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>17</b></figref>, with an example outsole member included in the frame;</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>19</b></figref> is a bottom view of the article of footwear of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>17</b></figref>, with another example outsole member included in the frame;</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>20</b></figref> is a bottom view of the article of footwear of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>17</b></figref>, with yet another example outsole member included in the frame;</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>21</b></figref> is a bottom-lateral side perspective exploded view of another example sole structure and a frame of the article of footwear of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>, with an upper removed;</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>22</b></figref> is a top-medial side perspective exploded view of the frame and outsole members of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>21</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>23</b></figref> is a bottom view of the sole structure and the frame of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>21</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>24</b></figref> is a cross-sectional view taken along line <b>24</b>-<b>24</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>23</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>25</b></figref> is a top view of the sole structure and the frame of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>21</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>26</b></figref> is a cross-sectional view taken along line <b>26</b>-<b>26</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>25</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>27</b></figref> is a lateral side view of another example of an article of footwear that is similar to the article of footwear of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>28</b></figref> is a lateral side view of yet another example of an article of footwear that is similar to the article of footwear of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>29</b></figref> is a lateral side detail view of another example of a fastening mechanism of the article of footwear of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>28</b></figref>, with a second lace in a tightened configuration;</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>30</b></figref> is a lateral side detail view of the article of footwear of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>29</b></figref>, with the second lace in a loosened configuration;</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>31</b></figref> is a lateral side view of another example of an article of footwear that is similar to the article of footwear of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>32</b></figref> is a lateral side view of another example frame of the article of footwear of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>31</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>33</b></figref> is a lateral side view of another example of an article of footwear that is similar to the article of footwear of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>34</b></figref> is a lateral side view of yet another example of an article of footwear that is similar to the article of footwear of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>35</b></figref> is a lateral side view of another example of an article of footwear that is similar to the article of footwear of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>:</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>36</b></figref> is a lateral side view of yet another example of an article of footwear that is similar to the article of footwear of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>; and</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>37</b></figref> is a lateral side view of another example of an article of footwear that is similar to the article of footwear of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0009" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">The following discussion and accompanying figures disclose various embodiments or configurations of a shoe and a sole structure. Although embodiments of a shoe or sole structure are disclosed with reference to a sports shoe, such as a running shoe, tennis shoe, basketball shoe, etc., concepts associated with embodiments of the shoe or the sole structure may be applied to a wide range of footwear and footwear styles, such as, e.g., cross-training shoes, football shoes, golf shoes, hiking shoes, hiking boots, ski and snowboard boots, soccer shoes and cleats, walking shoes, and track cleats, for example. Concepts of the shoe or the sole structure may also be applied to articles of footwear that are considered non-athletic, including dress shoes, sandals, loafers, slippers, and heels. In addition to footwear, particular concepts described herein may also be applied and incorporated in other types of apparel or other athletic equipment, such as, e.g., helmets, padding or protective pads, shin guards, and gloves. Even further, particular concepts described herein may be incorporated in other consumer or industrial products, such as, e.g., cushions, backpack straps, and golf clubs. Accordingly, concepts described herein may be utilized in a variety of products.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">The term &#x201c;about,&#x201d; as used herein, refers to variation in the numerical quantity that may occur, for example, through typical measuring and manufacturing procedures used for articles of footwear or other articles of manufacture that may include embodiments of the disclosure herein; through inadvertent error in these procedures; through differences in the manufacture, source, or purity of the ingredients used to make the compositions or mixtures or carry out the methods; and the like. Throughout the disclosure, the terms &#x201c;about&#x201d; and &#x201c;approximately&#x201d; refer to a range of values&#xb1;5% of the numeric value that the term precedes.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">Further, as used herein, unless otherwise defined or limited, directional terms are used for convenience of reference for discussion of particular figures or examples. For example, references to &#x201c;downward,&#x201d; or other directions, or &#x201c;lower&#x201d; or other positions, may be used to discuss aspects of a particular example or figure, but do not necessarily require similar orientation or geometry in all installations or configurations.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">The terms &#x201c;first,&#x201d; &#x201c;second,&#x201d; &#x201c;third,&#x201d; etc. may be used herein to describe various elements, components, regions, layers, and/or sections. These elements, components, regions, layers, and/or sections should not be limited by these terms. These terms may be only used to distinguish one element, component, region, layer, or section from another region, layer, or section. Terms such as &#x201c;first,&#x201d; &#x201c;second,&#x201d; and other numerical terms do not imply a sequence or order unless clearly indicated by the context. Thus, a first element, component, region, layer, or section discussed below could be termed a second element, component, region, layer, or section without departing from the teachings of the example configurations.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">The present disclosure is directed to an article of footwear and/or specific components of the article of footwear, such as an upper and/or a sole or sole structure. The upper may comprise a knitted component, a woven textile, and/or a non-woven textile. The knitted component may be made by knitting of yarn, the woven textile by weaving of yarn, and the non-woven textile by manufacture of a unitary non-woven web. Knitted textiles include textiles formed by way of warp knitting, weft knitting, flat knitting, circular knitting, and/or other suitable knitting operations. The knit textile may have a plain knit structure, a mesh knit structure, and/or a rib knit structure, for example. Woven textiles include, but are not limited to, textiles formed by way of any of the numerous weave forms, such as plain weave, twill weave, satin weave, dobbin weave, jacquard weave, double weaves, and/or double cloth weaves, for example. Non-woven textiles include textiles made by air-laid and/or spun-laid methods, for example. The upper may comprise a variety of materials, such as a first yarn, a second yarn, and/or a third yarn, which may have varying properties or varying visual characteristics.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">In addition, the present disclosure relates to an article of footwear having a sole structure attached to an upper and a frame attached to the sole structure and/or the upper. The sole structure may include a midsole and an outsole. Each of the midsole and the outsole may be separate components coupled with one another, or one or more of these elements may be integrally formed with each other. The midsole may be made of a foam material and is disposed between and connects the upper with the outsole. The midsole may cushion the impact from a user's foot contacting the ground. The outsole may be attached to the midsole to define a bottom surface of the shoe. The outsole may be made from a rubber material and is configured to contact the ground and provide traction. The outsole may include one or more sections, for example, a heel section and a forefoot section, although the outsole may include more than two sections at different areas, or it may be a single component. The frame may be made of a rigid plastic, such as thermoplastic polyurethane (TPU), or from another type of plastic or composite, and is provided to increase structural support and/or contain components of the sole structure. In particular, the frame may wrap around the sole structure and has portions on both the lateral and medial sides of the article of footwear. Further, the frame can be configured to removably attach to the shoe, e.g., the sole structure and/or the upper. In some embodiments, the frame can be further configured to receive outsole members disposed between the frame and the midsole, in which the outsole members can function as the outsole of the shoe. Thus, the frame can provide customized support to the shoe while further providing a means to replace the outsole of the shoe.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">A frame is an elongate member that is coupled with and wraps around the sole structure and/or portions of the upper. The frame has an inner surface facing the article of footwear, which is configured to couple with the sole structure, and further, at least a portion of the upper when the sole structure is connected with the upper in some embodiments. The frame also has an outer surface, which, in some embodiments, may be smooth, contoured, or have other features such as apertures. The frame may be contoured, for example, to match adjacent portions of the sole structure and/or the upper. Such features can be used to tune the flexibility of the frame, making it stiffer in some portions, or along some directions, such as the length of the frame. Further, the frame may serve to add to the decorative nature of the shoe. Furthermore, the frame may have edges that are generally smooth and curvilinear, wavy, zig-zag, or otherwise undulate. Some portions of the frame, for example, those portions adjacent the bottom surface, may have one or more flanges extending therefrom. In such embodiments, the flanges of the frame may be disposed between the midsole, the outsole, and/or the upper to aid in securing the frame to the sole structure and/or the upper.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">As noted above, the frame wraps around the sole structure. In particular, the frame may define a first or distal end in a forefoot region proximate a medial side and a lateral side. The distal end may be located adjacent the bottom surface of the sole structure or it may extend partially onto the side of the midsole or the upper. The frame may extend rearward along the bottom surface of the sole structure proximate the medial side and the lateral side to a second or proximate end in a heel region. The frame may extend above the midsole near the forefoot region, the midfoot region, and/or the heel region, so that it connects with the upper. The frame may also wrap around the periphery of a heel region from the lateral side to the medial side, extending forward and ending at the distal end near or adjacent to the midfoot region or the forefoot region. The frame may be configured to connect with the sole structure and/or the upper on at least a portion of its length.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">The following discussion and accompanying figures disclose various embodiments or configurations of an article of footwear. The article of footwear can be provided as a pair of shoes including a first or left shoe and a second or right shoe. The left shoe and the right shoe may be similar in all material aspects, except that the left shoe and the right shoe are sized and shaped to receive a left foot and a right foot of a user, respectively. For ease of disclosure, a single shoe or article of footwear will be referenced to describe aspects of the disclosure. In some figures, the article of footwear is depicted as a right shoe, and in some figures the article of footwear is depicted as a left shoe. The disclosure below with reference to the article of footwear is applicable to both the left shoe and the right shoe. In some embodiments, there may be differences between the left shoe and the right shoe other than the left/right configuration. For example, in some embodiments, the left shoe may include a frame, while the right shoe may not include the frame, or vice versa. Further, in some embodiments, the left shoe may include one or more additional elements that the right shoe does not include, or vice versa.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>-<b>5</b></figref> depict an exemplary embodiment of an article of footwear <b>100</b> including an upper <b>102</b> and a sole structure <b>104</b>. Referring specifically to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, the upper <b>102</b> is attached to the sole structure <b>104</b>, which together define an interior cavity <b>106</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b> and <b>3</b></figref>) into which a foot of a user may be inserted. Many conventional footwear uppers are formed from multiple elements (such as, e.g., textiles, polymer foam, polymer sheets, leather, and synthetic leather) that are joined through bonding or stitching at a seam. In some embodiments, the upper <b>102</b> of the article of footwear <b>100</b> is formed from a knitted structure or knitted components. In various embodiments, a knitted component may incorporate various types of yarn that may provide different properties to an upper. For example, one area of the upper <b>102</b> may be formed from a first type of yarn that imparts a first set of properties, and another area of the upper <b>102</b> may be formed from a second type of yarn that imparts a second set of properties. Using this configuration, properties of the upper <b>102</b> may vary throughout the upper <b>102</b> by selecting specific yarns for different areas of the upper <b>102</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">With reference to the material(s) that comprise the upper <b>102</b>, the specific properties that a particular type of yarn will impart to an area of a knitted component may at least partially depend upon the materials that form the various filaments and fibers of the yarn. For example, cotton may provide a soft effect, biodegradability, or a natural aesthetic to a knitted material. Elastane and stretch polyester may each provide a knitted component with a desired elasticity and recovery. Rayon may provide a high luster and moisture absorbent material, wool may provide a material with an increased moisture absorbance, nylon may be a durable material that is abrasion-resistant, and polyester may provide a hydrophobic, durable material.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">Other aspects of a knitted component may also be varied to affect the properties of the knitted component and provide desired attributes. For example, a yarn forming a knitted component may include monofilament yarn or multifilament yarn, or the yarn may include filaments that are each formed of two or more different materials. In addition, a knitted component may be formed using a particular knitting process to impart an area of a knitted component with particular properties. Accordingly, both the materials forming the yarn and other aspects of the yarn may be selected to impart a variety of properties to particular areas of the upper <b>102</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">In some embodiments, an elasticity of a knit structure may be measured based on comparing a width or length of the knit structure in a first, non-stretched state to a width or length of the knit structure in a second, stretched state after the knit structure has a force applied to the knit structure in a lateral direction. In further embodiments, the upper <b>102</b> may also include additional structural elements. For example, in some embodiments, a heel plate or cover (not shown) may be provided on the heel region <b>112</b> to provide added support to a heel of a user. In some instances, other elements, e.g., plastic material, logos, trademarks, etc., may also be applied and fixed to an exterior surface using glue or a thermoforming process. In some embodiments, the properties associated with the upper <b>102</b>, e.g., a stitch type, a yarn type, or characteristics associated with different stitch types or yarn types, such as elasticity, aesthetic appearance, thickness, air permeability, or scuff-resistance, may be varied.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b> and <b>3</b></figref>, the article of footwear <b>100</b> defines a lateral side <b>116</b> and a medial side <b>118</b>. When a user is wearing the shoes, the lateral side <b>116</b> corresponds with an outside-facing portion of the article of footwear <b>100</b> while the medial side <b>118</b> corresponds with an inside-facing portion of the article of footwear <b>100</b>. As such, the article of footwear <b>100</b> has opposing lateral and medial sides <b>116</b>, <b>118</b>. The lateral side <b>116</b> and the medial side <b>118</b> adjoin one another along a longitudinal central plane or axis <b>120</b> of the article of footwear <b>100</b>, which is coplanar with a longitudinal axis L of the article of footwear <b>100</b>. As will be further discussed herein, the longitudinal central plane or axis <b>120</b> may demarcate a central, intermediate axis between the lateral side <b>116</b> and the medial side <b>118</b> of the article of footwear <b>100</b>. Put differently, the longitudinal plane or axis <b>120</b> may extend between a rear, proximal end <b>122</b> of the article of footwear <b>100</b> and a front, distal end <b>124</b> of the article of footwear <b>100</b> and may continuously define a middle of the sole structure <b>104</b> and/or the upper <b>102</b> of the article of footwear <b>100</b>, i.e., the longitudinal plane or axis <b>120</b> is a straight axis extending through the proximal end <b>122</b> to the distal end <b>124</b> of the article of footwear <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">Referring still to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b> and <b>3</b></figref>, the article of footwear <b>100</b> may be defined by a forefoot region <b>108</b>, a midfoot region <b>110</b>, and a heel region <b>112</b>, unless otherwise specified. The forefoot region <b>108</b> may generally correspond with portions of the article of footwear <b>100</b> that encase portions of a foot <b>128</b> that include the toes or phalanges <b>130</b>, the ball of the foot <b>132</b>, and one or more of the joints <b>134</b> that connect the metatarsals <b>136</b> of the foot <b>128</b> with the toes or phalanges <b>130</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>). The midfoot region <b>110</b> is proximate and adjoins the forefoot region <b>108</b>. The midfoot region <b>110</b> generally corresponds with portions of the article of footwear <b>100</b> that encase an arch of the foot <b>128</b>, along with a bridge of the foot <b>128</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>). The heel region <b>112</b> is proximate to the midfoot region <b>110</b> and adjoins the midfoot region <b>110</b>. The heel region <b>112</b> generally corresponds with portions of the article of footwear <b>100</b> that encase rear portions of the foot <b>128</b>, including the heel or calcaneus bone <b>138</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>), the ankle (not shown), and/or the Achilles tendon (not shown).</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">Still referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b> and <b>3</b></figref>, the forefoot region <b>108</b>, the midfoot region <b>110</b>, the heel region <b>112</b>, the lateral side <b>116</b>, and the medial side <b>118</b> are intended to define boundaries or areas of the article of footwear <b>100</b>. To that end, the forefoot region <b>108</b>, the midfoot region <b>110</b>, the heel region <b>112</b>, the lateral side <b>116</b>, and the medial side <b>118</b> generally characterize sections of the article of footwear <b>100</b>. Certain aspects of the disclosure may refer to portions or elements that are coextensive with one or more of the forefoot region <b>108</b>, the midfoot region <b>110</b>, the heel region <b>112</b>, the lateral side <b>116</b>, and/or the medial side <b>118</b>. Further, both the upper <b>102</b> and the sole structure <b>104</b> may be characterized as having portions within the forefoot region <b>108</b>, the midfoot region <b>110</b>, the heel region <b>112</b>, and/or along the lateral side <b>116</b> and/or the medial side <b>118</b>. Therefore, the upper <b>102</b> and the sole structure <b>104</b>, and/or individual portions of the upper <b>102</b> and the sole structure <b>104</b>, may include portions thereof that are disposed within the forefoot region <b>108</b>, the midfoot region <b>110</b>, the heel region <b>112</b>, and/or along the lateral side <b>116</b> and/or the medial side <b>118</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">With continued reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b> and <b>3</b></figref>, the forefoot region <b>108</b>, the midfoot region <b>110</b>, the heel region <b>112</b>, the lateral side <b>116</b>, and the medial side <b>118</b> are shown in detail. The forefoot region <b>108</b> extends from a toe end <b>140</b> to a widest portion <b>142</b> of the article of footwear <b>100</b>. The widest portion <b>142</b> is defined or measured along a first line <b>144</b> that is perpendicular with respect to the longitudinal axis <b>120</b> that extends from a distal portion of the toe end <b>140</b> to a distal portion of a heel end <b>146</b>, which is opposite the toe end <b>140</b>. The midfoot region <b>110</b> extends from the widest portion <b>142</b> to a thinnest portion <b>148</b> of the article of footwear <b>100</b>. The thinnest portion <b>148</b> of the article of footwear <b>100</b> is defined as the thinnest portion of the article of footwear <b>100</b> measured across a second line <b>150</b> that is perpendicular with respect to the longitudinal axis <b>120</b>. The heel region <b>112</b> extends from the thinnest portion <b>148</b> to the heel end <b>146</b> of the article of footwear <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">It should be understood that numerous modifications may be apparent to those skilled in the art in view of the foregoing description, and individual components thereof, may be incorporated into numerous articles of footwear. Accordingly, aspects of the article of footwear <b>100</b> and components thereof, may be described with reference to general areas or portions of the article of footwear <b>100</b>, with an understanding the boundaries of the forefoot region <b>108</b>, the midfoot region <b>110</b>, the heel region <b>112</b>, the lateral side <b>116</b>, and/or the medial side <b>118</b> as described herein may vary between articles of footwear. However, aspects of the article of footwear <b>100</b> and individual components thereof, may also be described with reference to exact areas or portions of the article of footwear <b>100</b> and the scope of the appended claims herein may incorporate the limitations associated with these boundaries of the forefoot region <b>108</b>, the midfoot region <b>110</b>, the heel region <b>112</b>, the lateral side <b>116</b>, and/or the medial side <b>118</b> discussed herein.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">Referring still to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b> and <b>3</b></figref>, the lateral side <b>116</b> begins at the distal, toe end <b>140</b> and bows outward along an outer side of the article of footwear <b>100</b> along the forefoot region <b>108</b> toward the midfoot region <b>110</b>. The lateral side <b>116</b> reaches the first line <b>144</b>, at which point the lateral side <b>116</b> bows inward, toward the longitudinal, central axis <b>120</b>. The lateral side <b>116</b> extends from the first line <b>144</b>, i.e., the widest portion <b>142</b>, toward the second line <b>150</b>, i.e., the thinnest portion <b>148</b>, at which point the lateral side <b>116</b> enters into the midfoot region <b>110</b>, i.e., upon crossing the first line <b>144</b>. Once reaching the second line <b>150</b>, the lateral side <b>116</b> bows outward, away from the longitudinal, central axis <b>120</b>, at which point the lateral side <b>116</b> extends into the heel region <b>112</b>, i.e., upon crossing the second line <b>150</b>. The lateral side <b>116</b> then bows outward and then inward toward the heel end <b>146</b>, and terminates at a point where the lateral side <b>116</b> meets the longitudinal, central axis <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">The medial side <b>118</b> also begins at the distal, toe end <b>140</b> and bows outward along an inner side of the article of footwear <b>100</b> along the forefoot region <b>108</b> toward the midfoot region <b>110</b>. The medial side <b>118</b> reaches the first line <b>144</b>, at which point the medial side <b>118</b> bows inward, toward the central, longitudinal axis <b>120</b>. The medial side <b>118</b> extends from the first line <b>144</b>, i.e., the widest portion <b>142</b>, toward the second line <b>150</b>, i.e., the thinnest portion <b>148</b>, at which point the medial side <b>118</b> enters into the midfoot region <b>110</b>, i.e., upon crossing the first line <b>144</b>. Once reaching the second line <b>150</b>, the medial side <b>118</b> bows outward, away from the longitudinal, central axis <b>120</b>, at which point the medial side <b>118</b> extends into the heel region <b>112</b>, i.e., upon crossing the second line <b>150</b>. The medial side <b>118</b> then bows outward and then inward toward the heel end <b>146</b>, and terminates at a point where the medial side <b>118</b> meets the longitudinal, central axis <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">With continued reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b> and <b>3</b></figref>, the upper <b>102</b> extends along the lateral and medial sides <b>116</b>, <b>118</b>, and across the forefoot, midfoot, and heel regions <b>108</b>, <b>110</b>, <b>112</b> to house and enclose the foot <b>128</b> of a user (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>). With specific reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, when fully assembled, the upper <b>102</b> also includes an interior surface <b>152</b> and an exterior surface <b>154</b>. The interior surface <b>152</b> faces inward and generally defines the interior cavity <b>106</b>, and the exterior surface <b>154</b> of the upper <b>102</b> faces outward and generally defines an outer perimeter or boundary of the upper <b>102</b>. The upper <b>102</b> also includes an opening <b>156</b> that is at least partially located in the heel region <b>112</b> of the article of footwear <b>100</b>, which provides access to the interior cavity <b>106</b> and through which the foot <b>128</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>) may be inserted and removed. In some embodiments, the upper <b>102</b> may also include an instep region <b>158</b> that extends from the opening <b>156</b> in the heel region <b>112</b> over an area corresponding to an instep of a foot to an area proximate the forefoot region <b>108</b>. The instep region <b>158</b> may comprise an area similar to where a tongue <b>160</b> of the present embodiment is disposed. In some embodiments, the upper <b>102</b> does not include the tongue <b>160</b>, i.e., the upper <b>102</b> is tongueless.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">Referring again to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, the sole structure <b>104</b> is connected or secured to the upper <b>102</b> and extends between the foot <b>128</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>) of a user and a ground surface (not shown) when the article of footwear <b>100</b> is worn by the user. In the illustrated embodiment, the sole structure <b>104</b> includes a midsole or midsole region <b>162</b> and an outsole or outsole region <b>164</b>. The outsole region <b>164</b> may define a bottom end or bottom surface <b>166</b> of the sole structure <b>104</b> across the heel region <b>112</b>, the midfoot region <b>110</b>, and the forefoot region <b>108</b>. Further, the outsole region <b>164</b> may be a ground-engaging portion or include a ground-engaging surface (e.g., the bottom surface <b>166</b>) of the sole structure <b>104</b>. The outsole region <b>164</b> may be formed from one or more materials to impart durability, wear-resistance, abrasion resistance, or traction to the sole structure <b>104</b>. In some embodiments, the outsole region <b>164</b> may be formed from any kind of elastomer material, e.g., rubber, including thermoset elastomers or thermoplastic elastomers, or a thermoplastic material, e.g., TPU. In some embodiments, the outsole region <b>164</b> may define a shore A hardness up to 95.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">Still referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, the midsole region <b>162</b> may be individually constructed from a thermoplastic material, such as polyurethane (PU), for example, and/or an ethylene-vinyl acetate (EVA), copolymers thereof, or a similar type of material. In other embodiments, the midsole region <b>162</b> may be an EVA-Solid-Sponge (&#x201c;ESS&#x201d;) material, an EVA foam (e.g., PUMA&#xae; ProFoam Lite&#x2122;, IGNITE Foam), polyurethane, polyether, an olefin block copolymer, organosheets, a thermoplastic material (e.g., a thermoplastic polyurethane, a thermoplastic elastomer, a thermoplastic polyolefin, etc.), or a supercritical foam. The midsole region <b>162</b> may be a single polymeric material or may be a blend of materials, such as an EVA copolymer, a thermoplastic polyurethane, a polyether block amide (PEBA) copolymer, and/or an olefin block copolymer. One example of a PEBA material is PEBAX&#xae;. In some embodiments, the midsole region <b>162</b> is manufactured by a process involving injection molding, vulcanization, printing layer by layer, i.e., additive manufacturing systems or methods, and the like.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">In embodiments where the midsole region <b>162</b> is formed from a supercritical foaming process, the supercritical foam may comprise micropore foams or particle foams, such as a TPU, EVA, PEBAX&#xae;, or mixtures thereof, manufactured using a process that is performed within an autoclave, an injection molding apparatus, or any sufficiently heated/pressurized container that can process the mixing of a supercritical fluid (e.g., CO<sub>2</sub>, N<sub>2</sub>, or mixtures thereof) with a material (e.g., TPU, EVA, polyolefin elastomer, or mixtures thereof) that is preferably molten. During an exemplary process, a solution of supercritical fluid and molten material is pumped into a pressurized container, after which the pressure within the container is released, such that the molecules of the supercritical fluid rapidly convert to gas to form small pockets within the material and cause the material to expand into a foam. In further embodiments, the midsole region <b>162</b> may be formed using alternative methods known in the art, including the use of an expansion press, an injection machine, a pellet expansion process, a cold foaming process, a compression molding technique, die cutting, or any combination thereof. For example, the midsole region <b>162</b> may be formed using a process that involves an initial foaming step in which supercritical gas is used to foam a material and then compression molded or die cut to a particular shape.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">Referring again to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the sole structure <b>104</b> may further include an insole <b>126</b> disposed above the midsole region <b>162</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>). The insole <b>126</b> may be a strobel board, a forefoot board, a lasting board, etc., or a combination thereof. In some embodiments, the insole <b>126</b> may be provided between the upper <b>102</b> and the sole structure <b>104</b>. In some embodiments, the insole <b>126</b> may be provided as part of the upper <b>102</b>. Furthermore, the insole <b>126</b> can be positioned within the interior cavity <b>106</b> of the upper <b>102</b>, which can be in direct contact with the user's foot <b>128</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>) while the article of footwear <b>100</b> is being worn. Moreover, the upper <b>102</b> may also include a liner (not shown) that can increase comfort, for example, by reducing friction between the foot <b>128</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>) of the user and the upper <b>102</b>, the insole <b>126</b>, and/or other components of the sole structure <b>104</b>, and/or by providing moisture wicking properties. The liner may line the entirety of the interior cavity <b>106</b> or only a portion thereof. In some embodiments, a binding (not shown) may surround the opening <b>156</b> of the interior cavity <b>106</b> to secure the liner to the upper <b>102</b> and/or to provide an aesthetic element to the article of footwear <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">Referring again to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, the upper <b>102</b> includes a fastening mechanism <b>172</b> that defines a plurality of first fastening members or lace retainers <b>174</b> disposed on the lateral side <b>116</b> and medial side <b>118</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>) of the article of footwear <b>100</b> adjacent to the tongue <b>160</b>. The lace retainers <b>174</b> are configured to receive a second fastening member or lace <b>176</b> that can extend in a crisscrossing manner across the tongue <b>160</b> and through the lace retainers <b>174</b>. In some embodiments, the lace <b>176</b> extends through the lace retainers <b>174</b> disposed on the lateral side <b>116</b> of the upper <b>102</b>, across the tongue <b>160</b> and the instep region <b>158</b>, and through the lace retainers <b>174</b> disposed on the medial side <b>118</b> of the upper <b>102</b>. In some embodiments, the lace <b>176</b> has free ends that can be tied together by the user. In some embodiments, the lace <b>176</b> comprises two laces each having a first end that is fixed to the upper <b>102</b> and a second end that is free, such that the second ends of the two laces can be tied together by the user. In some embodiments, the lace <b>176</b> may be a closed loop lace that is tightened manually and/or automatically by a tightening mechanism (not shown). In some embodiments, the fastening mechanism <b>172</b> includes more than one plurality of lace retainers <b>174</b> that are configured to receive one or more laces <b>176</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">Still referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, and as discussed above, the sole structure <b>104</b> includes the midsole or midsole region <b>162</b> and the outsole or outsole region <b>164</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, the midsole region <b>162</b> includes a plurality of midsole members <b>178</b> disposed along the forefoot region <b>108</b>, the midfoot region <b>110</b>, and the heel region <b>112</b>. The plurality of midsole members <b>178</b> may have varying properties, including different shapes, colors, thicknesses, and/or widths. In some embodiments, the midsole members <b>178</b> have other properties that vary between one or more midsole members <b>178</b>, such as the color. In some embodiments, and as discussed further below, one or more of the midsole members <b>178</b> can be comprised of different materials than the material comprising the other midsole members <b>178</b>. For example, in some embodiments, the midsole members <b>178</b> disposed in the heel region <b>112</b> are comprised of a different material than the midsole members <b>178</b> disposed in the forefoot region <b>108</b> and/or the midfoot region <b>110</b>. In some embodiments, the midsole members <b>178</b> can define both the midsole <b>162</b> and the outsole <b>164</b> of the sole structure <b>104</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">The plurality of midsole members <b>178</b> each have an upper portion <b>180</b> and a bottom portion <b>182</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, the bottom portions <b>182</b> of the plurality of midsole members <b>178</b> define the outsole <b>164</b> of the sole structure <b>104</b> and are configured to at least partially contact the ground while providing traction to a user wearing the article of footwear <b>100</b>. The upper <b>102</b> is connected to the upper portion <b>180</b> of the midsole members <b>178</b>. In some embodiments, the upper <b>102</b> may be attached to the upper portions <b>180</b> of the midsole members <b>178</b> by a glue or other adhesive. In some embodiments, the upper portions <b>180</b> of the plurality of midsole members <b>178</b> form a continuous surface. In such embodiments, the continuous surface of the upper portions <b>180</b> may function as the insole <b>126</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>) of the article of footwear <b>100</b>. In some embodiments, one or more gaps are present between the upper portions <b>180</b> of the plurality of midsole members <b>178</b>. In some embodiments, the insole <b>126</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>) is connected to the upper portions <b>180</b> of the plurality of midsole members <b>178</b>. In such embodiments, the upper <b>102</b> may be connected to the insole <b>126</b> of the sole structure <b>104</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">Referring specifically to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> and <b>4</b></figref>, the article of footwear <b>100</b> also includes a frame <b>170</b>. The frame <b>170</b> is an elongate member that wraps around the midsole region <b>162</b> and the outsole region <b>164</b> of the sole structure <b>104</b> (i.e., the plurality of midsole members <b>178</b> in the illustrated embodiment). In the illustrated embodiment, the frame <b>170</b> also wraps at least partially around lower portions of the upper <b>102</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>). Thus, in the illustrated embodiment, the frame <b>170</b> wraps around at least portions of the lateral side <b>116</b>, the medial side <b>118</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>), the proximal end <b>122</b>, the distal end <b>124</b>, the forefoot region <b>108</b>, the midfoot region <b>110</b>, and the heel region <b>112</b> of the article of footwear <b>100</b>. The frame <b>170</b> is a unitary body that can be made from a plastic material, such as TPU. In some embodiments, the frame <b>170</b> is made from a translucent TPU or another translucent material. Furthermore, two or more portions of the frame <b>170</b> may be comprised of two or more materials that have varying properties relative to each other. For example, in some embodiments, the frame <b>170</b> may have a portion comprising TPU and another portion comprising a composite.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">The frame <b>170</b> may be configured to be removably attached to the sole structure <b>104</b> and/or the upper <b>102</b>. In such embodiments, the frame <b>170</b> may be configured to include a plurality of frames having differing geometric and/or material properties that can each be removably attached to the sole structure <b>104</b> by the user to provide a specific support structure desired by the user for a particular physical activity. Further, as discussed below, the frame <b>170</b> may be configured such that a user can remove and replace the outsole <b>164</b> of the article of footwear <b>100</b>. In addition, as discussed below, the inclusion of the frame <b>170</b> can add to the visual appeal of the shoe by permitting the plurality of midsole members <b>178</b> to be visible from an outside of the article of footwear <b>100</b> through the frame <b>170</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">Still referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> and <b>4</b></figref>, the frame <b>170</b> is an elongate member that wraps around the midsole members <b>178</b> along with the lateral side <b>116</b> and the medial side <b>118</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>) of the upper <b>102</b>. The frame <b>170</b> has an exterior surface <b>184</b> that faces away from the article of footwear <b>100</b> and an interior surface <b>186</b> that faces toward the article of footwear <b>100</b>. In some embodiments, the frame <b>170</b> covers at least a portion of the sole structure <b>104</b> and does not cover any portion of the upper <b>102</b>. In some embodiments, the frame <b>170</b> covers a portion of the sole structure <b>104</b> and a portion of the upper <b>102</b>. In some embodiments, a percentage coverage of the upper <b>102</b> by the frame <b>170</b>, as defined as an absolute surface area without consideration of a plurality of apertures <b>188</b> of the frame <b>170</b>, is in a range of about 2% to about 90%, in a range of about 5% to about 95%, in a range of about 15% to about 80%, in a range of about 25% to about 75%, in a range of about 30% to about 70%, or in a range of about 50% to about 65%.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">The interior surface <b>186</b> of the frame <b>170</b> is configured to encase or cover one or more of the midsole members <b>178</b> of the sole structure <b>104</b> and/or portions of the upper <b>102</b>. In some embodiments, the frame <b>170</b> may be at least partially disposed within a plurality of channels or recesses (not shown) formed on one or more of the midsole members <b>178</b>. In some embodiments, the frame <b>170</b> is co-molded with the midsole members <b>178</b>. In some embodiments, the frame <b>170</b> is adhered to the midsole members <b>178</b> or the upper <b>102</b>. In some embodiments, the frame <b>170</b> is removably attached to the midsole members <b>178</b> by compression or other means. In some embodiments, the frame <b>170</b> can extend over, or cover, only a portion of the midsole members <b>178</b>. For example, in such embodiments, the frame <b>170</b> can extend over only those midsole members <b>178</b> disposed in the heel region <b>212</b>, such that the midsole members <b>178</b> disposed in the forefoot region <b>108</b> and the midfoot region <b>110</b> are not covered by the frame <b>170</b>. In some embodiments, the article of footwear <b>100</b> can include more than one frame <b>170</b>, for example, a first frame can extend over the midsole members <b>178</b> disposed in the heel region <b>112</b> and a second frame can extend over the midsole members <b>178</b> disposed in the forefoot region <b>108</b> and/or the midfoot region <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">Referring still to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> and <b>4</b></figref>, the frame <b>170</b> has a lattice-work structure formed by the plurality of apertures <b>188</b> that extend from the exterior surface <b>184</b> to the interior surface <b>186</b> of the frame <b>170</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, the apertures <b>188</b> are disposed along a lateral side <b>190</b>, a medial side <b>192</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>), a bottom side <b>194</b>, a distal side <b>196</b>, and/or a proximal side <b>198</b> of the frame <b>170</b>. Thus, the lattice-work structure of the frame <b>170</b> extends over the entire frame <b>170</b> such that the midsole members <b>178</b> covered by the frame <b>170</b> are visible from an outside (e.g., along the lateral side <b>116</b>, the medial side <b>118</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>), the proximal end <b>122</b>, the distal end <b>124</b>, and the outsole region <b>164</b>) of the article of footwear <b>100</b> through the lattice-work structure (i.e., the apertures <b>188</b>) of the frame <b>170</b>. In some embodiments, the apertures <b>188</b> are disposed entirely on the bottom side <b>194</b> of the frame <b>170</b> and thus the lattice-work structure of the frame <b>170</b> extends along only the outsole region <b>164</b> of the article of footwear <b>100</b> while the remainder of the frame <b>170</b> can extend along the lateral side <b>116</b>, the medial side <b>118</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>), the proximal end <b>122</b>, and the distal end <b>124</b> of the article of footwear <b>100</b>. In some embodiments, the apertures <b>188</b> are disposed only on the lateral and bottom sides <b>190</b>, <b>194</b> of the frame <b>170</b> and thus the lattice-work structure of the frame <b>170</b> extends along only the lateral side <b>116</b> and the outsole region <b>164</b> of the article of footwear <b>100</b> while the remainder of the frame can extend along the medial side <b>118</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>), the proximal end <b>122</b>, and the distal end <b>124</b> of the article of footwear <b>100</b>. In some embodiments, the apertures <b>188</b> are disposed only on the lateral and proximal sides <b>190</b>, <b>198</b> of the frame <b>170</b> and thus the lattice-work structure of the frame <b>170</b> extends along only the lateral side <b>116</b> and the heel region <b>112</b> of the article of footwear <b>100</b> while the remainder of the frame <b>170</b> can extend along the medial side <b>118</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>), the distal end <b>124</b>, and the outsole region <b>164</b> of the article of footwear <b>100</b>. In some embodiments, a percentage of the frame <b>170</b> including the plurality of apertures <b>188</b> (i.e., the lattice-work structure) is in a range of about 5% to about 30%, in a range of about 20% to about 60%, in a range of about 30% to about 80%, in a range of about 50% to about 90%, or in a range of about 10% to about 95%. In some embodiments, the lattice-work structure of the frame <b>170</b> can extend along a percentage of the exterior surface <b>154</b> of the upper <b>102</b> in a range of about 5% to about 60%, in a range of about 10% to about 50%, in a range of about 15% to about 45%, or in a range of about 20% to about 40%. In some embodiments, the frame <b>170</b>, or portions thereof, can have a continuous exterior surface <b>184</b> with no apertures <b>188</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">With continued reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> and <b>4</b></figref>, the plurality of apertures <b>188</b> can be of varying size and shape. For example, with specific reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>, the apertures <b>188</b> disposed on the bottom side <b>194</b> of the frame <b>170</b> toward the distal side <b>196</b> of the frame <b>170</b> have a smaller size and generally have a more circular shape in comparison to the apertures <b>188</b> disposed toward the proximal side <b>198</b> of the frame <b>170</b>. Likewise, with specific reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, the apertures <b>188</b> disposed on the lateral side <b>190</b> of the frame <b>170</b> have a generally oval shape, and the apertures <b>188</b> disposed toward the distal side <b>196</b> of the frame <b>170</b> have a smaller size and differently orientated oval shapes in comparison to the apertures <b>188</b> disposed toward the proximal side <b>198</b> of the frame <b>170</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">Referring specifically to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b> and <b>5</b></figref>, and as discussed above, with the apertures <b>188</b> included on the bottom side <b>194</b> of the frame <b>170</b>, the frame <b>170</b> and the bottom portions <b>182</b> of the midsole members <b>178</b> partially define the bottom surface <b>166</b> of the outsole <b>164</b> of the sole structure <b>104</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, the apertures <b>188</b> disposed on the bottom side <b>194</b> of the frame <b>170</b> are arranged such that at least two or more apertures <b>188</b> are at least partially disposed over each of the midsole members <b>178</b>. In some embodiments, the bottom side <b>194</b> of the frame <b>170</b> and the bottom portions <b>182</b> of the midsole members <b>178</b> form a substantially flat or continuous bottom surface <b>166</b> of the outsole <b>164</b>. In some embodiments, the midsole members <b>178</b> can include a plurality of protrusions (not shown) that align with two or more of the apertures <b>188</b> disposed on the bottom side of the frame <b>170</b>, such that the protrusions of the bottom portions <b>182</b> of the midsole members <b>178</b> extend at least partially through the apertures <b>188</b> of the frame <b>170</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0098">Referring again to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>, <b>4</b>, and <b>5</b></figref>, the midsole members <b>178</b> can be comprised of a compressible and/or deformable material that can provide cushioning or shock absorption benefits to a user when wearing the article of footwear <b>100</b>. In such embodiments, the frame <b>170</b> can be comprised of a material that is more rigid than a material comprising the midsole members <b>178</b> such that frame <b>170</b> provides support to the midsole members <b>178</b> when a user's foot exerts force on the sole structure <b>104</b>. In such embodiments, when a user wearing the article of footwear <b>100</b> exerts downward force on the sole structure <b>104</b> opposite a ground surface, the frame <b>170</b> can flex inward toward the midsole members <b>178</b> while the midsole members <b>178</b> compress between the user's foot and the ground surface. In some embodiments, the upper portions <b>180</b> of the midsole members <b>178</b> can be comprised of a different material than the bottom portions <b>182</b> of the midsole members <b>178</b>. In such embodiments, for example, the bottom portions <b>182</b> of the midsole members <b>178</b> can be comprised a first material that provides traction between the midsole members <b>178</b> and a ground surface while the upper portions <b>180</b> of the midsole members <b>178</b> are comprised of a second material that provides cushioning to a user wearing the article of footwear <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0099">Likewise, the frame <b>170</b> can be comprised of two or more materials having different properties. For example, the lateral side <b>190</b>, the medial side <b>192</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b> and <b>5</b></figref>), the distal side <b>196</b>, and/or the proximal side <b>198</b> of the frame <b>170</b> that are adjacent to the midsole region <b>162</b> can be comprised of a first material that is flexible while the bottom side <b>194</b> of the frame <b>170</b> adjacent to the outsole region <b>164</b> can be comprised of a second material that is more rigid than the first material. In such embodiments, portions of the lateral side <b>190</b> and the medial side <b>192</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b> and <b>5</b></figref>) of the frame <b>170</b> can be comprised of a third material that is more elastic than the first material. Such portions of the lateral side <b>190</b> and the medial side <b>192</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b> and <b>5</b></figref>) comprised of the third elastic material can be utilized as a fastening member of the fastening mechanism <b>172</b> in some embodiments. For example, the first fastening member or lace <b>176</b> can extend through the apertures <b>188</b> disposed on the lateral side <b>190</b> and the medial side <b>192</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b> and <b>5</b></figref>) of the frame <b>170</b> in addition to, or instead of, the second fastening members or lace retainers <b>174</b>. In such embodiments, the third material comprising the portions of the lateral side <b>190</b> and the medial side <b>192</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b> and <b>5</b></figref>) of the frame <b>170</b> can allow for elastic deformation of the frame <b>170</b> under tension by the lace <b>176</b>. In such embodiments, elastic deformation of the frame <b>170</b> may be defined as one or more portions of the lattice-work structure of the frame <b>170</b> being configured to sustain an elastic deformation when a force (e.g., the tensile force of the tightened lace <b>176</b>) is applied to the one or more portions of the frame <b>170</b> and to self-recover the original shape of the lattice-work structure of the frame <b>170</b> when the force is removed (e.g., when the lace <b>176</b> is loosened).</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0100">As discussed above, the frame <b>170</b> can extend along various portions of the upper <b>102</b>, which encases the user's foot <b>128</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>). Accordingly, in some embodiments, at least the lattice-work structure of the frame <b>170</b> defined by the plurality of apertures <b>188</b> can be formed of a material configured to adapt to a wearer's foot. For example, in such embodiments, the lattice-work structure of the frame <b>170</b> can be formed of an elastic material that is configured to adapt and elastically deform around contours of the wearer's foot, including expanding to a first length at some locations of the wearer's foot while expanding to a second length that is greater than the first length at other locations of the wearer's foot. In some such embodiments, the material forming the lattice-work structure of the frame <b>170</b> can be configured to maintain a shape corresponding to contours of a wearer's foot after the article of footwear <b>100</b> is worn by the user for some time. In other embodiments, the material forming the lattice-work structure of the frame <b>170</b> can be configured to adapt and elastically deform in response to bending of the sole structure <b>104</b> and/or upper <b>102</b> (e.g., when the forefoot region <b>108</b> of bottom surface <b>166</b> of the outsole <b>164</b> contacts a ground surface while the heel region <b>112</b> of the bottom surface <b>166</b> of the outsole <b>164</b> is raised from the ground surface during a particular phase of the wearer's stride) and then to self-recover to the non-bending shape of the lattice-work structure of the frame <b>170</b> when the sole structure <b>104</b> and/or upper <b>102</b> return to the original shape (e.g., when the forefoot and heel regions <b>108</b>, <b>112</b> of the bottom surface <b>166</b> of the outsole <b>164</b> simultaneously contact the ground surface during a different phase of the wearer's stride or when the wearer is standing stationary).</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0101">As discussed above, the frame <b>170</b> can be comprised of a translucent or partially transparent material. In this regard, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> illustrates an alternative embodiment of the frame <b>170</b> as being translucent, such that the entirety of the bottom portions <b>182</b> of the midsole members <b>178</b> are at least partially visible from the bottom surface <b>166</b> of the article of footwear <b>100</b> through the translucent frame <b>170</b>, in addition to portions of the midsole members <b>178</b> being visible through the apertures <b>188</b> disposed on the bottom side <b>194</b> of the frame <b>170</b>. In some embodiments, the upper portions <b>180</b> of the midsole members <b>178</b> and/or portions of the upper <b>102</b> covered by the frame <b>170</b> can be visible or partially visible from a side (such as, e.g., the lateral side <b>116</b>) of the article of footwear <b>100</b> through the frame <b>170</b>, in addition to portions thereof being visible through the apertures <b>188</b> disposed on the lateral side <b>190</b>, the medial side <b>192</b>, the distal side <b>196</b>, and/or the proximal side <b>198</b> of the frame <b>170</b>. In some embodiments, portions of the frame <b>170</b> can be translucent and other portions of the frame <b>170</b> can be opaque. For example, in some embodiments, the lateral side <b>190</b> of the frame <b>170</b> can be translucent while the medial side <b>192</b>, the bottom side <b>194</b>, the distal side <b>196</b>, and/or the proximal side <b>198</b> of the frame <b>170</b> can be opaque.</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0102">Referring again to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>, <b>4</b>, and <b>5</b></figref>, in some embodiments, one or more of the midsole members <b>178</b> and/or the frame <b>170</b> can be configured to be removably attached to the sole structure <b>104</b>. For example, in some embodiments, at least some portions of the frame <b>170</b> may be comprised of an elastic material and the frame <b>170</b> may be configured such that a user can remove the frame <b>170</b> from the fixedly attached midsole members <b>178</b> by inserting a finger into one or more of the apertures <b>188</b> and pulling the frame <b>170</b> outward and downward relative to the upper <b>102</b>. In another example, both the frame <b>170</b> and one or more midsole members <b>178</b> can be removably attached to the upper <b>102</b>, such that the frame <b>170</b> can be removed, one or more midsole members <b>178</b> can be replaced with a different midsole member <b>178</b> that can have different properties, and then the frame <b>170</b> can be reattached over the different midsole member <b>178</b>. In some embodiments, the midsole members <b>178</b> can be unattached to the upper <b>102</b> and the frame <b>170</b> can be configured to hold the midsole members <b>178</b> in contact with the upper <b>102</b> and/or contain the midsole members <b>178</b> in a particular arrangement with one another. In such embodiments, the frame <b>170</b> can further include one or more protrusions (not shown) extending from the interior surface <b>186</b> that can be configured to extend at least partially between the unattached midsole members <b>178</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0103">Referring still to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>, <b>4</b> and <b>5</b></figref>, the midsole members <b>178</b> and/or the frame <b>170</b> may be formed through additive manufacturing techniques, such as by 3D printing. To that end, a number of 3D printed techniques may be implemented to form the midsole members <b>178</b> and/or the frame <b>170</b>, such as vat photopolymerization, material jetting, binder jetting, powder bed fusion, material extrusion, directed energy deposition, and/or sheet lamination. In some embodiments, the frame <b>170</b>, or components thereof, may be 3D printed directly upon the midsole members <b>178</b> or along a portion of the upper <b>102</b>. In some embodiments, the frame <b>170</b>, or components thereof, may be 3D printed and then separately coupled with a portion of the article of footwear <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0104">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b>-<b>14</b></figref>, another exemplary embodiment of an article of footwear <b>200</b> is depicted, which includes an upper <b>202</b>, a sole structure <b>204</b> having a midsole or midsole region <b>262</b> and an outsole or outsole region <b>264</b>, and a frame <b>270</b>. The article of footwear <b>200</b> is similar to previous embodiments, with like elements being indicated by similar reference numerals under the &#x201c;2xx&#x201d; series of reference numerals. For example, the upper <b>202</b> of the article of footwear <b>200</b> has an interior surface <b>252</b>, an exterior surface <b>254</b>, and an instep region <b>258</b>, just as the upper <b>102</b> of the article of footwear <b>100</b> has the interior surface <b>152</b>, the exterior surface <b>154</b>, and the instep region <b>158</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>). While the article of footwear <b>200</b> is similar to the previous embodiment in many aspects, there are some aspects that differ. In particular, the fastening mechanism <b>272</b> further includes third fastening members or a second plurality of lace retainers <b>274</b><i>b </i>in addition to the second fastening members or the first plurality of lace retainers <b>274</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0105">Referring specifically to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b> and <b>7</b></figref>, the first fastening member or the lace <b>276</b> extends in a crisscrossing manner across the tongue <b>260</b> and through the first and second pluralities of lace retainers <b>274</b><i>a</i>, <b>274</b><i>b </i>in an alternating sequence or in series, i.e., through one of the first plurality of lace retainers <b>274</b><i>a</i>, across the tongue <b>260</b>, through one of the second plurality of lace retainers <b>274</b><i>b</i>, and so on. In the illustrated embodiment, the second plurality of lace retainers <b>274</b><i>b </i>are arranged between the first plurality of lace retainers <b>274</b><i>a </i>and the sole structure <b>204</b>. The first and second pluralities of lace retainers <b>274</b><i>a</i>, <b>274</b><i>b </i>can each be formed by a single lace or strip of material extending around and partially adhered to the lateral side <b>216</b> and the medial side <b>218</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref>) of the upper <b>102</b> and having one or more disconnected portions that can form the first and second pluralities of lace retainers <b>274</b><i>a</i>, <b>274</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0107" num="0106">Referring still to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b> and <b>7</b></figref>, the frame <b>270</b> extends along the lateral side <b>216</b>, the medial side <b>218</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref>), the proximal end <b>222</b>, and the distal end <b>224</b> of the sole structure <b>204</b> and along at least a lower portion of the upper <b>202</b>. Similar to the embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>-<b>5</b></figref>, the frame <b>270</b> has a lattice-work structure formed by a plurality of apertures <b>288</b>, including a first plurality of apertures <b>288</b><i>a </i>disposed at least partially along the lateral side <b>290</b>, the medial side <b>292</b>, the distal side <b>296</b>, and/or the proximal side <b>298</b> of the frame <b>270</b>. However, unlike the previous embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>-<b>5</b></figref>, the frame <b>270</b> includes a large central aperture <b>288</b><i>b </i>defined on the bottom side <b>294</b> of the frame <b>270</b> that extends partially along the forefoot, midfoot, and heel regions <b>208</b>, <b>210</b>, <b>212</b> between the lateral side <b>216</b> and the medial side <b>218</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref>) of the article of footwear <b>200</b>. The bottom side <b>294</b> of the frame <b>270</b> further includes a second plurality of apertures <b>288</b><i>c </i>(see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>) disposed around a perimeter of the large central aperture <b>288</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0108" num="0107">With continued reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b> and <b>7</b></figref>, in the illustrated embodiment, each of the midsole members <b>278</b> extend from the lateral side <b>216</b> to the medial side <b>218</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref>) of the sole structure <b>204</b>. The plurality of midsole members <b>278</b> includes a first or forefoot midsole member <b>278</b><i>a</i>, a second or midfoot midsole member <b>278</b><i>b</i>, a third or distal-heel midsole member <b>278</b><i>c</i>, and a fourth or proximal-heel midsole member <b>278</b><i>d</i>. The first midsole member <b>278</b><i>a </i>is disposed entirely within the forefoot region <b>208</b> of the article of footwear <b>200</b>, and the second midsole member <b>278</b><i>b </i>is disposed entirely within the midfoot region <b>210</b> of the article of footwear <b>200</b>. The third and fourth midsole members <b>278</b><i>c</i>, <b>278</b><i>d </i>are disposed entirely within distal and proximal portions of the heel region <b>212</b>, respectively, of the article of footwear <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0109" num="0108">In some embodiments, one or more of the midsole members <b>278</b> may be configured such that at least some portions of such midsole members <b>278</b> can expand through one or more of the first plurality of apertures <b>288</b><i>a </i>disposed on the lateral side <b>290</b>, the medial side <b>292</b>, and the proximal side <b>298</b> of the frame <b>270</b> when the sole structure <b>204</b> is compressed by a user's foot. For example, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>8</b> and <b>9</b></figref> illustrate the article of footwear <b>200</b> with various amounts of force applied downward on the insole <b>226</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>) of the sole structure <b>204</b>, such as downward force applied by a user's foot while in stride, and with the third and fourth midsole members <b>278</b><i>c</i>, <b>278</b><i>d </i>being configured to be expandable and the first and second midsole members <b>278</b><i>a</i>, <b>278</b><i>b </i>being configured to be non-expandable. Referring specifically to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref>, the article of footwear <b>200</b> is shown in a first compressed position when a first amount of force is applied downward on the insole <b>226</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>) of the sole structure <b>204</b>. In the first compressed position, the midsole members <b>278</b> of the sole structure <b>204</b> are compressed between the downward force on the insole <b>226</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>) and an opposing ground surface (not shown) contacting the bottom surface <b>266</b> of the outsole <b>264</b> of the sole structure <b>204</b>, causing the third and fourth midsole members <b>278</b><i>c</i>, <b>278</b><i>d </i>to expand partially outward through the first plurality of apertures <b>288</b><i>a </i>of the frame <b>270</b>. In such embodiments, the frame <b>270</b> may be configured to compress along at least the lateral and medial sides <b>290</b>, <b>292</b> of the frame <b>270</b> to a lesser or equal distance in which the midsole members <b>278</b> are compressed. In other embodiments, the frame <b>270</b> may be configured to be caused to move upward toward the opening <b>256</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>) of the upper <b>202</b> when the sole structure <b>204</b> is compressed.</p>
<p id="p-0110" num="0109">Referring specifically to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref>, the article of footwear <b>200</b> is shown in a second compressed configuration when a second amount of force, greater than the first amount of force, is applied downward on the insole <b>226</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>) of the sole structure <b>204</b>. In the second compressed position, the midsole members <b>278</b> of the sole structure <b>204</b> are compressed further between the greater downward force on the insole <b>226</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>) and the opposing ground surface (not shown) contacting the bottom surface <b>266</b> of the outsole <b>264</b> of the sole structure <b>204</b>, causing the third and fourth midsole members <b>278</b><i>c</i>, <b>278</b><i>d </i>to expand further outward through the first plurality of apertures <b>288</b><i>a </i>of the frame <b>270</b>. In some embodiments, the midsole members <b>278</b> may be configured to expand at least partially outward through the central aperture <b>288</b><i>b </i>and/or the second plurality of apertures <b>288</b><i>c </i>disposed on the bottom side <b>294</b> of the frame <b>270</b> when the sole structure <b>204</b> is compressed. In such embodiments, at least a bottom surface of the midsole members <b>278</b> may be comprised of a material that provides traction between the expanded portions of the midsole members <b>278</b> extending through the central aperture <b>288</b><i>b </i>and/or the second plurality of apertures <b>288</b><i>c </i>and the ground surface when the sole structure <b>204</b> is compressed.</p>
<p id="p-0111" num="0110">Referring still to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>8</b> and <b>9</b></figref>, and as noted above, the first and second midsole members <b>278</b><i>a</i>, <b>278</b><i>b </i>located in the forefoot and midfoot regions <b>208</b>, <b>210</b>, respectively, are configured to be non-expandable when the sole structure <b>204</b> is compressed, and the third and fourth midsole members <b>278</b><i>c</i>, <b>278</b><i>d </i>located in the heel region <b>212</b> are configured to be expandable when the sole structure <b>204</b> is compressed. Thus, when the sole structure <b>204</b> is compressed in the illustrated embodiment, the third and fourth midsole members <b>278</b><i>c</i>, <b>278</b><i>d </i>expand through the first plurality of apertures <b>288</b><i>a </i>while the first and second midsole members <b>278</b><i>a</i>, <b>278</b><i>b </i>do not expand through the first plurality of apertures <b>288</b><i>a</i>. In other embodiments, the midsole members <b>278</b> located in the forefoot, midfoot, and heel regions <b>208</b>, <b>210</b>, <b>212</b> can be configured to be expandable through the first plurality of apertures <b>288</b><i>a </i>when the sole structure <b>204</b> is compressed.</p>
<p id="p-0112" num="0111">Still referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>8</b> and <b>9</b></figref>, the midsole members <b>278</b> may be comprised of an outer casing <b>279</b> with a plurality of plastic bodies <b>281</b> disposed within the outer casing <b>279</b>. In some embodiments, the outer casing <b>279</b> of one or more of the midsole members <b>278</b> may be comprised of a translucent or partially translucent material such that the plastic bodies <b>281</b> disposed therein are visible therethrough and, thus, visible from an outside of the article of footwear <b>200</b> through the apertures <b>288</b>. In such embodiments, a fluid <b>283</b> may be contained within the outer casing <b>279</b> of the midsole members <b>278</b> such that the plastic bodies <b>281</b> are suspended in the fluid <b>283</b> and free to move relative to each other within the outer casing <b>279</b>. Thus, the fluid <b>283</b> may permit the plastic bodies <b>281</b> to move outwardly relative to an outer perimeter of the frame <b>270</b> into portions of the midsole members <b>278</b> that expand through the first plurality of apertures <b>288</b><i>a </i>of the frame <b>270</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref>. In other embodiments, the fluid <b>283</b> may be a binder such that movement of the plurality of plastic bodies <b>281</b> relative to each other is at least partially constrained.</p>
<p id="p-0113" num="0112">With continued reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>8</b> and <b>9</b></figref>, the plurality of plastic bodies <b>281</b> may be of a variety of shapes and sizes. For example, in the illustrated embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>8</b> and <b>9</b></figref>, a first plurality of plastic bodies <b>281</b><i>a </i>disposed within the fourth midsole member <b>278</b><i>d </i>have a different shape and size than a second plurality of plastic bodies <b>281</b><i>b </i>disposed within the third midsole member <b>278</b><i>c</i>. In some embodiments, the plurality of plastic bodies <b>281</b> are spherical and/or ellipsoidal shaped. In such embodiments, the spherical and/or ellipsoidal shaped plastic bodies <b>281</b> have dimensions, in the three spatial direction, in a range between about 1 millimeter (mm) and about 18 mm, in a range between about 2 mm and about 12 mm, or in a range between about 3 mm and about 10 mm. In some embodiments, the plurality of plastic bodies <b>281</b> has other varying properties within the same or different midsole members <b>278</b><i>a</i>, <b>278</b><i>b</i>, <b>278</b><i>c</i>, <b>278</b><i>d</i>. For example, in the illustrated embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>8</b> and <b>9</b></figref>, the first plurality of plastic bodies <b>281</b><i>a </i>may have varying colors within the fourth midsole member <b>278</b><i>d </i>or the first and second plurality of plastic bodies <b>281</b><i>a</i>, <b>281</b><i>b </i>may have differing colors within the third and fourth midsole members <b>278</b><i>c</i>, <b>278</b><i>d</i>, respectively. In some embodiments, the plastic bodies <b>281</b> may comprise between about 30% to about 95% of a weight of the midsole members <b>278</b>, and the fluid <b>283</b> may comprise between about 5% to about 70% of the weight of the midsole members <b>278</b>. In other embodiments, the plastic bodies <b>281</b> may comprise about 50% to about 60% of the weight of the midsole members <b>278</b>, and the fluid <b>283</b> may comprise about 40% to about 50% of the weight of the midsole members <b>278</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0114" num="0113">Referring specifically to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref>, the frame <b>270</b> of the article of footwear <b>200</b> may be configured to receive an outsole member <b>268</b> disposed between the bottom portions <b>282</b> of the midsole members <b>278</b> and the interior surface <b>286</b> along the bottom side <b>294</b> of the frame <b>270</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, the outsole member <b>268</b> is arranged such that portions of the outsole member <b>268</b> cover some of the second plurality of apertures <b>288</b><i>c </i>disposed on the bottom side <b>294</b> of the frame <b>270</b>. In some embodiments, the bottom side <b>294</b> of the frame <b>270</b> and the outsole member <b>268</b> can together define the bottom surface <b>266</b> of the outsole <b>264</b> of the article of footwear <b>200</b>. In some embodiments, the outsole member <b>268</b> can cover each of the apertures <b>288</b> disposed on the bottom side <b>294</b> of the frame <b>270</b>. In some embodiments, the outsole member <b>268</b> can be comprised of a material that is different than the frame <b>270</b> and/or the midsole members <b>278</b>. For example, in such embodiments, the outsole member <b>268</b> can be comprised of a first material that is configured to provide traction between the article of footwear <b>200</b> and a ground surface, the frame <b>270</b> can be comprised of a second material that is configured to provide structural support to the article of footwear <b>200</b>, and the midsole members <b>278</b> can be comprised of a third material that is configured to provide cushioning to a user wearing the article of footwear <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0115" num="0114">Referring specifically to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b></figref>, the outsole member <b>268</b> can include a first or distal outsole member <b>268</b><i>a </i>and a second or proximal outsole member <b>268</b><i>b</i>. Additionally, in such embodiments, the first and second outsole members <b>268</b><i>a</i>, <b>268</b><i>b </i>can be arranged such that some of the apertures <b>288</b> disposed on the bottom side <b>294</b> of the frame <b>270</b> open to the first or second outsole members <b>268</b><i>a</i>, <b>268</b><i>b </i>and some of the apertures <b>288</b> disposed on the bottom side of the frame <b>270</b> open to the bottom portions <b>282</b> of one or more of the midsole members <b>278</b><i>a</i>, <b>278</b><i>b</i>, <b>278</b><i>c</i>, <b>278</b><i>d</i>. In some embodiments, the first and second outsole members <b>268</b><i>a</i>, <b>268</b><i>b </i>and the bottom side <b>294</b> of the frame <b>270</b> can collectively define the bottom surface <b>266</b> of the outsole <b>264</b> of the sole structure <b>204</b>. More specifically, in such embodiments, the first outsole member <b>268</b><i>a </i>can define a first or distal bottom surface portion <b>266</b><i>a </i>of the bottom surface <b>266</b>, the second outsole member <b>268</b><i>b </i>can define a second or proximal bottom surface portion <b>266</b><i>b </i>of the bottom surface <b>266</b>, and the bottom side <b>294</b> of the frame <b>270</b> can define the remaining portion(s) of the bottom surface <b>266</b>. In some embodiments, the outsole member <b>268</b> can comprise three or more outsole members.</p>
<p id="p-0116" num="0115"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>12</b> and <b>13</b></figref> depict detail views of the outsole member <b>268</b> positioned on the interior surface <b>286</b> of the bottom side <b>294</b> of the frame <b>270</b>, with the lateral, medial, and distal sides <b>290</b>, <b>292</b>, <b>296</b> of the frame <b>270</b> including the first plurality of apertures <b>288</b><i>a </i>having been removed for illustration purposes. As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>12</b> and <b>13</b></figref>, the outsole member <b>268</b> can include a plurality of protrusions <b>214</b> that are configured to align with some of the apertures <b>288</b> along the bottom side <b>294</b> of the frame <b>270</b>, such as the second plurality of apertures <b>288</b><i>c</i>, when the outsole member <b>268</b> is included between the interior surface <b>286</b> of the frame <b>270</b> and the bottom portions <b>282</b> of midsole members <b>278</b>. More specifically, in the illustrated embodiment, the plurality of protrusions <b>214</b> extend downwardly from the outsole members <b>268</b> away from the midsole members <b>278</b> such that the plurality of protrusions <b>214</b> can be at least partially received within the second plurality of apertures <b>288</b><i>c </i>of the frame <b>270</b> and extend from the interior surface <b>286</b> toward the exterior surface <b>284</b> of the frame <b>270</b>. As discussed above, in some embodiments, the article of footwear <b>200</b> can be configured such that the frame <b>270</b> is removably attached to the sole structure <b>204</b>. In such embodiments, the outsole member <b>268</b> can be inserted into or removed from the interior surface <b>286</b> of the frame <b>270</b> when the frame <b>270</b> is removed from the sole structure <b>204</b> by a user. For example, if the protrusions <b>214</b> of the outsole member <b>268</b> wear down after repeated use of the article of footwear <b>200</b>, a user can remove the frame <b>270</b>, replace the worn-down outsole member <b>268</b> with a new outsole member <b>268</b> that is inserted into the interior surface <b>286</b> of the frame <b>270</b>, and then reattach the frame <b>270</b> to the sole structure <b>204</b> of the article of footwear <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0117" num="0116">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>14</b>-<b>16</b></figref>, in some embodiments, the outsole member <b>268</b> may be configured to be attached to the exterior surface <b>284</b> of the frame <b>270</b>. In this regard, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>15</b> and <b>16</b></figref> depict detail views of the outsole member <b>268</b> positioned on the exterior surface <b>284</b> along the bottom side <b>294</b> of the frame <b>270</b>, with the lateral, medial, and distal sides <b>290</b>, <b>292</b>, <b>296</b> of the frame <b>270</b> including the first plurality of apertures <b>288</b><i>a </i>having been removed for illustration purposes. In such embodiments, the outsole member <b>268</b> can include one or more protrusions <b>214</b> that are configured to align with, and be disposed within, one or more apertures <b>288</b> disposed on the bottom side <b>294</b> of the frame <b>270</b>, such as the second plurality of apertures <b>288</b><i>c</i>. More specifically, the plurality of protrusions <b>214</b> can extend upwardly from the outsole members <b>268</b> toward the midsole members <b>278</b> such that the plurality of protrusions <b>214</b> can be at least partially received within the second plurality of apertures <b>288</b><i>c </i>of the frame <b>270</b> and extend from the exterior surface <b>284</b> toward the interior surface <b>286</b> of the frame <b>270</b>. In such embodiments, a user can replace a worn-down outsole member <b>268</b> with a new outsole member <b>268</b> along the exterior surface <b>284</b> of the frame <b>270</b> without removing the frame <b>270</b> from the sole structure <b>204</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0118" num="0117">Referring in particular to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>14</b></figref>, the first outsole member <b>268</b><i>a </i>is attached to the exterior surface <b>284</b> of the frame <b>270</b> by engagement of one or more protrusions <b>214</b> with at least some of the second plurality of apertures <b>288</b><i>c </i>of the frame <b>270</b> located in the forefoot region <b>208</b> and the midfoot region <b>210</b>. Likewise, the second outsole member <b>268</b><i>b </i>is attached to the exterior surface <b>284</b> of the frame <b>270</b> by engagement of one or more protrusions of the second outsole member <b>268</b><i>b </i>with some of the second plurality of apertures <b>288</b><i>c </i>of the frame <b>270</b> located in the heel region <b>212</b>. As such, the first and second outsole members <b>268</b><i>a</i>, <b>268</b><i>b </i>each form distinct bottom surface portions <b>266</b><i>a</i>, <b>266</b><i>b </i>located below the exterior surface <b>284</b> of the frame <b>270</b> and that at least partially define the bottom surface <b>266</b> of the outsole <b>264</b> of the article of footwear <b>200</b>. In some embodiments, the first and second outsole members <b>268</b><i>a</i>, <b>268</b><i>b </i>can define the entire bottom surface <b>266</b> of the outsole <b>264</b> of the article of footwear <b>200</b>. In some embodiments, the protrusions <b>214</b> can be removably attached to surfaces defining the one or more apertures <b>288</b> and/or the exterior surface <b>284</b> along the bottom side <b>294</b> of the frame <b>270</b>. In some embodiments, the outsole member <b>268</b> is fixedly attached to the bottom side <b>294</b> of the frame <b>270</b> using an adhesive or other known fastening means. In some embodiments, one or more protrusions <b>214</b> of the outsole member <b>268</b> are attached to the bottom portion <b>282</b> of one or more midsole members <b>278</b> using an adhesive or other known fastening means.</p>
<p id="p-0119" num="0118">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>17</b>-<b>20</b></figref>, another exemplary embodiment frame <b>270</b>&#x2032; of the article of footwear <b>200</b> is depicted. The frame <b>270</b>&#x2032; of the article of footwear <b>200</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>17</b>-<b>20</b></figref> is similar to the previous embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b>-<b>16</b></figref>, with like elements being indicated by similar reference numerals. While the frame <b>270</b>&#x2032; of the article of footwear <b>200</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>17</b>-<b>20</b></figref> is similar to the previous embodiment in many aspects, there are some aspects that differ. In particular, the apertures <b>288</b> disposed on the bottom side <b>294</b> of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2032; have a generally circular shape. Further, two or more sets or pluralities of apertures <b>288</b> have varying diameters. For example, the second plurality of apertures <b>288</b><i>c </i>with a diameter D<b>1</b> is arranged adjacent to the large central aperture <b>288</b><i>b </i>that is disposed on the bottom side <b>294</b> of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2032;. A third plurality of apertures <b>288</b><i>d </i>having a diameter D<b>2</b>, which is larger than the diameter D<b>1</b> of the second plurality of apertures <b>288</b><i>c</i>, is arranged toward the periphery of the bottom side <b>294</b> of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2032;. A fourth plurality of apertures <b>288</b><i>e </i>having a diameter D<b>3</b>, which is smaller than the diameter D<b>2</b> of the third plurality of apertures <b>288</b><i>d </i>but larger than the diameter D<b>1</b> of the second plurality of apertures <b>288</b><i>c</i>, is arranged between the second and third pluralities of apertures <b>288</b><i>c</i>, <b>288</b><i>d </i>along the bottom side <b>294</b> of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2032;.</p>
<p id="p-0120" num="0119">In some embodiments, the outsole members <b>268</b> can be configured to attach to the exterior surface <b>284</b> of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2032; via one or more protrusions <b>214</b> that are configured to be received by apertures <b>288</b> disposed on the bottom side <b>294</b> of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2032;, similar to the exemplary outsole members <b>268</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>14</b>-<b>16</b></figref> described above, but can be further configured to be received by two or more apertures <b>288</b> of varying shapes and sizes. Referring specifically to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>18</b> and <b>19</b></figref>, in the illustrated embodiment, the protrusions <b>214</b> of the one or more outsole members <b>268</b> may be configured to be received by only one of the second, third, or fourth pluralities of apertures <b>288</b><i>c</i>, <b>288</b><i>d</i>, <b>288</b><i>e </i>(such as, e.g., the first outsole member <b>268</b><i>a </i>of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>18</b></figref>) disposed on the bottom side <b>294</b> of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2032; or by two or more of the second, third, and fourth pluralities of apertures <b>288</b><i>c</i>, <b>288</b><i>d</i>, <b>288</b><i>e </i>(such as, e.g., the second and third outsole members <b>268</b><i>b</i>, <b>268</b><i>c </i>of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>18</b></figref> and the first and second outsole members <b>268</b><i>a</i>, <b>268</b><i>b </i>of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>19</b></figref>). In some embodiments, the frame <b>270</b>&#x2032; and the outsole members <b>268</b> may be configured such that the outsole members <b>268</b> are removably attached to the exterior surface <b>284</b> of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2032; via an interference fit between the protrusions <b>214</b> and the corresponding apertures <b>288</b>. In some embodiments, the outsole members <b>268</b> can be adhered to the exterior surface <b>284</b> of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2032; and/or the protrusions <b>214</b> extending through the apertures <b>288</b> can be adhered to the bottom portions <b>282</b> of the midsole members <b>278</b>. In some embodiments, the protrusions <b>214</b> can include a flange (not shown) that can be configured to contact and engage the interior surface <b>286</b> of the bottom side <b>294</b> of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2032;. In such embodiments, the flanges of the protrusions <b>214</b> of the outsole members <b>268</b> may be adhered to the interior surface <b>286</b> of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2032;.</p>
<p id="p-0121" num="0120">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>18</b></figref>, the first outsole member <b>268</b><i>a </i>is configured to attach to only the third plurality of apertures <b>288</b><i>d </i>while the second outsole member <b>268</b><i>b </i>and the third outsole member <b>268</b><i>c </i>are configured to attach to both the third and fourth pluralities of apertures <b>288</b><i>d</i>, <b>288</b><i>e</i>. Similarly, in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>19</b></figref>, both the first and the second outsole members <b>268</b><i>a</i>, <b>268</b><i>b </i>are configured to attach to both the third and the fourth pluralities of apertures <b>288</b><i>d</i>, <b>288</b><i>e </i>disposed on the bottom side <b>294</b> of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2032;. In such embodiments, the outsole members <b>268</b> can be configured to attach proximate to the periphery of the bottom side <b>294</b> of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2032; via the third plurality of apertures <b>288</b><i>d </i>and proximate to the central aperture <b>288</b><i>b </i>via the second plurality of apertures <b>288</b><i>c</i>. Similar to the outsole members <b>268</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>14</b>-<b>16</b></figref>, the first, second, and third outsole members <b>268</b><i>a</i>, <b>268</b><i>b</i>, <b>268</b><i>c </i>of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>18</b></figref> and the first and second outsole members <b>268</b><i>a</i>, <b>268</b><i>b </i>of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>19</b></figref>, respectively, can each form distinct bottom surface portions <b>266</b><i>a</i>, <b>266</b><i>b</i>, <b>266</b><i>c </i>located below the exterior surface <b>284</b> of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2032; that can at least partially define the bottom surface <b>266</b> of the outsole <b>264</b> of the article of footwear <b>200</b>. In this configuration, the frame <b>270</b>&#x2032; can provide greater traction to the article of footwear <b>200</b> on the bottom side <b>294</b> of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2032; while providing greater flexibility to the frame <b>270</b>&#x2032; and greater support to the article of footwear <b>200</b> via the large central aperture <b>288</b><i>b </i>of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2032;.</p>
<p id="p-0122" num="0121">In some embodiments, the one or more outsole members <b>268</b> can be configured to attach to other parts of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2032;. For example, referring specifically to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>20</b></figref>, the outsole members <b>268</b> can be further configured to at least partially attach to each of the second, third, and fourth pluralities of apertures <b>288</b><i>c</i>, <b>288</b><i>d</i>, <b>288</b><i>e </i>as well as a portion of the large central aperture <b>288</b><i>b </i>of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2032;. In the illustrated embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>20</b></figref>, the first outsole member <b>268</b><i>a </i>is attached to the second, third, and fourth pluralities of apertures <b>288</b><i>c</i>, <b>288</b><i>d</i>, <b>288</b><i>e </i>disposed in the forefoot region <b>208</b> and is partially attached to a distal portion of the central aperture <b>288</b><i>b </i>in the forefoot region <b>208</b>. In such embodiments, the frame <b>270</b>&#x2032; and the outsole members <b>268</b> can provide even greater traction to the article of footwear <b>200</b> on the bottom side <b>294</b> of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2032; while providing greater flexibility to the frame <b>270</b>&#x2032; and support to the article of footwear <b>200</b> via the large central aperture <b>288</b><i>b </i>of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2032;, i.e., by providing a larger surface area of the bottom surface portion <b>266</b><i>a </i>for at least the first outsole member <b>268</b><i>a </i>to contact the ground surface.</p>
<p id="p-0123" num="0122">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b>-<b>20</b></figref>, various components of the article of footwear <b>200</b>, including the upper <b>202</b>, the midsole members <b>278</b>, the frames <b>270</b>, <b>270</b>&#x2032;, and/or the outsole members <b>268</b>, may be formed through additive manufacturing techniques, such as by one or more of the various 3D printing techniques mentioned above. For example, in some embodiments, the frame <b>270</b> may be 3D printed using a first material and the outsole members <b>268</b> may be simultaneously 3D printed within the frame <b>270</b> using a second material that is different than the first material. In some embodiments, the outsole members <b>268</b> may be 3D printed separate from the frame <b>270</b> and later attached to the frame <b>270</b>. In some embodiments, the outsole members <b>268</b> can be 3D printed such that the protrusions <b>214</b> are formed of a first material while the remainder of the outsole members <b>268</b> are formed of a second material that is different than the first material.</p>
<p id="p-0124" num="0123">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>21</b>-<b>26</b></figref>, another exemplary embodiment sole structure <b>204</b>&#x2032; and frame <b>270</b>&#x2033; of the article of footwear <b>200</b> is depicted. The sole structure <b>204</b>&#x2032; and the frame <b>270</b>&#x2033; of the article of footwear <b>200</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>21</b>-<b>26</b></figref> are similar to the previous embodiments shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b>-<b>20</b></figref>, with like elements being indicated by similar reference numerals. While the sole structure <b>204</b>&#x2032; and the frame <b>270</b>&#x2033; of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>21</b>-<b>26</b></figref> are similar to previous embodiments in many aspects, there are some aspects that differ. In particular, the midsole members <b>278</b> have an interconnected upper portion <b>280</b> with the bottom portions <b>282</b> extending downward from the upper portion <b>280</b> such that one or more gaps <b>234</b> extend between the bottom portions <b>282</b> of the midsole members <b>278</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0125" num="0124">Referring specifically to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>21</b></figref>, the sole structure <b>204</b>&#x2032; and the frame <b>270</b>&#x2033; of the article of footwear <b>200</b> are shown in an exploded view. The frame <b>270</b>&#x2033; has a lattice-work structure formed by a plurality of apertures <b>288</b> disposed on the lateral side <b>290</b>, medial side <b>292</b>, bottom side <b>294</b>, distal side <b>296</b>, and proximal side <b>298</b>. The frame <b>270</b>&#x2033; further includes a plurality of outsole members <b>268</b> including a first outsole member <b>268</b><i>a </i>and a second outsole member <b>268</b><i>b</i>, each having protrusions <b>214</b><i>a</i>, <b>214</b><i>b </i>and disposed between a first interior surface <b>286</b><i>a </i>of the bottom side <b>294</b> of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2033; and the bottom portions <b>282</b> of the midsole members <b>278</b>. Referring specifically to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>23</b></figref>, the first outsole member <b>268</b><i>a </i>is disposed in the forefoot region <b>208</b> and partially in the midfoot region <b>210</b> of the sole structure <b>204</b>&#x2032;, and the second outsole member <b>268</b><i>b </i>is disposed entirely in the heel region <b>212</b> of the sole structure <b>204</b>&#x2032;.</p>
<p id="p-0126" num="0125">Referring again to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>21</b></figref>, the bottom side <b>294</b> of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2033; can include a plurality of ribs <b>236</b> extending from the exterior surface <b>284</b> and arranged between the plurality of apertures <b>288</b>. In such embodiments, the plurality of ribs <b>236</b> on the bottom side <b>294</b> of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2033; can be configured to provide additional traction to the article of footwear <b>200</b> by at least partially defining the bottom surface <b>266</b> of the outsole <b>264</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>26</b></figref>). Further, in some embodiments, the plurality of ribs <b>236</b> can provide increased structural support to the bottom side <b>294</b> of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2033;. In some embodiments, the ribs <b>236</b> extend from the exterior surface <b>284</b> of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2033; to a distance that is equal to or less than a distance that the protrusions <b>214</b><i>a</i>, <b>214</b><i>b </i>of the outsole members <b>268</b> extend past the exterior surface <b>284</b> of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2033;. In some embodiments, the ribs <b>236</b> are comprised of a material having one or more properties that are different than a material that comprises at least the bottom side <b>294</b> of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2033;. For example, the bottom side <b>294</b> of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2033; can be comprised of a first material while the ribs <b>236</b> can be comprised of a second material that has a greater hardness or has greater frictional attributes than the first material.</p>
<p id="p-0127" num="0126">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>22</b></figref>, the first interior surface <b>286</b><i>a </i>of at least the bottom side <b>294</b> of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2033; can include one or more cavities <b>250</b> that are configured to receive one or more outsole members <b>268</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, the cavities <b>250</b> of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2033; have an outer shape that matches an outer perimeter <b>244</b> of one or more outsole members <b>268</b>. Similarly, with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>24</b></figref>, the cavities <b>250</b> may have a depth D that may correspond to a thickness T<sub>1 </sub>of the outsole members <b>268</b>. The depth D being measured from the first interior surface <b>286</b><i>a </i>of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2033; to a second interior surface <b>286</b><i>b </i>of the cavity <b>250</b>, and the thickness T<sub>1 </sub>being measured from an interior surface <b>242</b> to an exterior surface <b>248</b> of the outsole member <b>268</b> at a point on the outsole member <b>268</b> that does not include a protrusion <b>214</b><i>a</i>, <b>214</b><i>b</i>. In some embodiments, the outsole members <b>268</b> can have a thickness T<sub>1 </sub>in a range of about 0.3 mm to about 2 mm, in a range of about 0.5 mm to about 1.5 mm, or in a range of about 0.7 mm to about 1.3 mm. In some embodiments, the depth D of the cavities <b>250</b> of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2033; can be greater than or equal to the thickness T<sub>1 </sub>of the outsole members <b>268</b>. In some embodiments, the depth D of the cavities <b>250</b> of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2033; can be less than the thickness T<sub>1 </sub>of the outsole members <b>268</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0128" num="0127">Referring again to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>22</b></figref>, the outsole members <b>268</b> may include one or more recesses <b>238</b> corresponding to one or more of the protrusions <b>214</b><i>a</i>. The recesses <b>238</b> may be disposed on the interior surface <b>242</b> of the outsole members <b>268</b> such that each of the recesses <b>238</b> align with at least one of the protrusions <b>214</b><i>a</i>, <b>214</b><i>b </i>disposed on the exterior surface <b>248</b> of the outsole member <b>268</b>. Some of the protrusions <b>214</b><i>b </i>of the outsole members <b>268</b> may not have a corresponding recess <b>238</b>, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>22</b></figref>. In some embodiments, each of the protrusions <b>214</b><i>a</i>, <b>214</b><i>b </i>of the outsole members <b>268</b> may have a corresponding recess <b>238</b>. Referring again to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>24</b></figref>, the outsole members <b>268</b> have a thickness T<b>2</b> measured at a point on the outsole member <b>268</b> that includes a protrusion <b>214</b><i>a </i>with a corresponding recess <b>238</b> from the interior surface <b>242</b> (i.e., within the corresponding recess <b>238</b> of the protrusion <b>214</b>) to the exterior surface <b>248</b>. In some embodiments, the thickness T<b>2</b> can be equal to the thickness T<sub>1 </sub>of the outsole members <b>268</b>, such that the outsole members <b>268</b> have a uniform thickness from any point measured from the interior surface <b>242</b> to the exterior surface <b>248</b> of the outsole members <b>268</b>. In some embodiments, the thickness T<b>2</b> can be greater than or less than the thickness T<sub>1 </sub>of the outsole members <b>268</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0129" num="0128">With continued reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>24</b></figref>, the gaps <b>234</b> extending between the bottom portions <b>282</b> of the midsole members <b>278</b> extend from the upper portion <b>280</b> through the bottom portions <b>282</b> and can extend through the lateral side <b>216</b> and/or medial side <b>218</b> of the sole structure <b>204</b>&#x2032;. In some embodiments, the gaps <b>234</b> of the midsole members <b>278</b> can extend in a straight line from the lateral side <b>216</b> to the medial side <b>218</b> of the sole structure <b>204</b>&#x2032;. In some embodiments, the gaps <b>234</b> can extend through the proximal end <b>222</b> and/or the distal end <b>224</b> of the sole structure <b>204</b>&#x2032;. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>24</b> and <b>25</b></figref>, one or more channels <b>246</b> can be defined on an upper surface <b>234</b><i>b </i>of the upper portion <b>280</b> of the midsole members <b>278</b>. In some embodiments, the channels <b>246</b> may be disposed above one or more of the bottom portions <b>282</b> between the gaps <b>234</b>, such as, e.g., on a portion of the upper portion <b>280</b> that aligns with a bottom portion <b>282</b> disposed in the forefoot region <b>208</b> of the sole structure <b>204</b>&#x2032;. In some embodiments, the midsole member <b>278</b> may be comprised of an ethylene vinyl acetate (EVA) that may be formed via a compression molding process.</p>
<p id="p-0130" num="0129">Referring specifically to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>24</b></figref>, the frame <b>270</b>&#x2033; has a thickness T<b>3</b> measured from the exterior surface <b>284</b> to the first interior surface <b>286</b><i>a </i>of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2033;. In some embodiments, the thickness T<b>3</b> of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2033; can be in a range of about 0.5 mm to about 8 mm, in a range of about 0.8 mm to about 6 mm, in a range of about 1 mm to about 10 mm, in a range of about 1 mm to about 5 mm, or in a range of about 0.8 mm to about 4 mm. In the illustrated embodiment, the protrusions <b>214</b><i>b </i>of the outsole members <b>268</b> that do not have a corresponding recess <b>238</b> have a thickness T<b>4</b> measured from the interior surface <b>242</b> of the outsole member <b>268</b> that contacts the bottom portions <b>282</b> of the midsole members <b>278</b> to the exterior surface <b>248</b> of the protrusion <b>214</b><i>b</i>. In some embodiments, such protrusions <b>214</b><i>b </i>of the outsole members <b>268</b> can have a thickness T<b>4</b> in a range of about 0.3 mm to about 10 mm, in a range of about 0.5 mm to about 12 mm, in a range of about 0.8 to about 14 mm, in a range of about 1 mm to about 6 mm, or in a range of about 0.6 mm to about 5 mm. In some embodiments, the thickness T<b>4</b> of the protrusions <b>214</b><i>b </i>can be greater than the thickness T<b>3</b> of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2033; such that the exterior surface <b>248</b> of the protrusions <b>214</b><i>b </i>extend past the exterior surface <b>284</b> of the bottom side <b>294</b> of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2033;. In other embodiments, the thickness T<b>4</b> of the protrusions <b>214</b><i>b </i>can be equal to or less than the thickness T<b>3</b> of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2033; such that the exterior surface <b>248</b> of the protrusions <b>214</b><i>b </i>do not extend past the exterior surface <b>284</b> of the bottom side <b>294</b> of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2033;.</p>
<p id="p-0131" num="0130">With continued reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>24</b></figref>, the gaps <b>234</b> of the midsole members <b>278</b> have a width W measured between opposing surfaces of the bottom portions <b>282</b> of the midsole members <b>278</b>. In some embodiments, the gaps <b>234</b> of the midsole members <b>278</b> can have a width W in a range of about 0.1 mm to about 5 mm, in a range of about 0.2 mm to about 3 mm, in a range of about 0.3 mm to about 2 mm, or in a range of about 0.5 mm to about 1.5 mm. Referring still to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>24</b></figref>, the interconnected upper portion <b>280</b> of the midsole members <b>278</b> has a thickness T<b>5</b> measured from the upper end <b>234</b><i>a </i>of the gaps <b>234</b> to the upper surface <b>234</b><i>b </i>of the midsole members <b>278</b>. In some embodiments, the upper portion <b>280</b> of the midsole members <b>278</b> can have a thickness T<b>5</b> in a range of about 2.5 mm to about 10 mm, in a range of about 3 mm to about 8 mm, or in a range of about 3.5 mm to about 7 mm.</p>
<p id="p-0132" num="0131">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>26</b></figref>, the outsole members <b>268</b><i>a</i>, <b>268</b><i>b </i>can further include a second plurality of protrusions <b>214</b><i>c </i>extending from the interior surface <b>242</b> of the outsole members <b>268</b><i>a</i>, <b>268</b><i>b</i>. In some embodiments, the second plurality of protrusions <b>214</b><i>c </i>may be configured to be received within the gaps <b>234</b> of the midsole members <b>278</b> (as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>26</b></figref>) or to otherwise contact or engage the bottom portions <b>282</b> of the midsole members <b>278</b>. Similarly, the frame <b>270</b>&#x2033; can further include one or more protrusions <b>228</b> extending from the first interior surface <b>186</b><i>a </i>of the lateral side <b>290</b>, the medial side <b>292</b>, the bottom side <b>294</b>, the distal side <b>296</b>, and/or the proximal side <b>298</b>. In some embodiments, the protrusions <b>228</b> of the frame <b>270</b>&#x2033; may be configured to be received within the gaps <b>234</b> of the midsole members <b>278</b> (as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>26</b></figref>) or to otherwise contact or engage the bottom portions <b>282</b> of the midsole members <b>278</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0133" num="0132">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>27</b></figref>, another exemplary embodiment of an article of footwear <b>300</b> is depicted, which includes an upper <b>302</b>, a sole structure <b>304</b>, and a frame <b>370</b>. The article of footwear <b>300</b> is similar to previous embodiments, with like elements being indicated by similar reference numerals under the &#x201c;3xx&#x201d; series of reference numerals. In the article of footwear <b>300</b>, the fastening mechanism <b>372</b> includes a first fastening member or plurality of lace retainers <b>374</b> disposed along the lateral side <b>316</b> and the medial side <b>318</b> of the upper <b>302</b> adjacent to the tongue <b>360</b> and within the midfoot region <b>310</b> of the article of footwear <b>300</b>. A second fastening member or lace <b>376</b> extends through the plurality of lace retainers <b>374</b> in a crisscrossing manner across the tongue <b>360</b>. In some embodiments, the plurality of lace retainers <b>374</b> can extend adjacent to the tongue <b>360</b> within the forefoot and midfoot regions <b>308</b>, <b>310</b> of the article of footwear <b>300</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0134" num="0133">With continued reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>27</b></figref>, in the illustrated embodiment, at least the fourth midsole member <b>378</b><i>d </i>is not attached to the upper <b>302</b>. Instead, the fourth midsole member <b>378</b><i>d </i>is held in place adjacent to the upper <b>302</b> by the frame <b>370</b>. Thus, in such embodiments, the fourth midsole member <b>378</b><i>d </i>may be configured to provide support to a user only when the user's heel strikes a ground surface, such as, e.g., by causing at least a portion of the frame <b>370</b> to compress or move relative to the upper <b>302</b>. In some embodiments, two or more of the midsole members <b>378</b><i>a</i>, <b>378</b><i>b</i>, <b>378</b><i>c</i>, <b>378</b><i>d </i>may be not attached to the upper <b>302</b> and held adjacent to the upper <b>302</b> by the frame <b>370</b>. In some embodiments, the fourth midsole member <b>378</b><i>d </i>may be attached to the frame <b>370</b>. In some embodiments, two or more midsole members <b>378</b><i>a</i>, <b>378</b><i>b</i>, <b>378</b><i>c</i>, <b>378</b><i>d </i>may be attached to the frame <b>370</b> while two or more midsole members <b>378</b><i>a</i>, <b>378</b><i>b</i>, <b>378</b><i>c</i>, <b>378</b><i>d </i>may be attached to the upper <b>302</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0135" num="0134">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>28</b>-<b>30</b></figref>, yet another exemplary embodiment of an article of footwear <b>400</b> is depicted, which includes an upper <b>402</b>, a sole structure <b>404</b>, and a frame <b>470</b>. The article of footwear <b>400</b> is similar to previous embodiments, with like elements being indicated by similar reference numerals under the &#x201c;4xx&#x201d; series of reference numerals. In the article of footwear <b>400</b>, the fastening mechanism <b>472</b> includes a first fastening member or first plurality of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>a</i>, a second fastening member or second plurality of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>b</i>, a third fastening member or third plurality of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>c</i>, a fourth fastening member or fourth plurality of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>d</i>, a fifth fastening member or first lace <b>476</b><i>a</i>, and a fifth fastening member or second lace <b>476</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0136" num="0135">Referring specifically to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>28</b></figref>, in the illustrated embodiment, the first plurality of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>a </i>are pairs of apertures extending through the lateral side <b>416</b> and the medial side <b>418</b> of the upper <b>402</b> adjacent to the tongue <b>460</b>. The first lace <b>476</b><i>a </i>extends through the first plurality of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>a </i>in a crisscrossing manner across the tongue <b>460</b>. Free ends of the first lace <b>476</b><i>a </i>extend from the first plurality of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>a </i>adjacent to the opening <b>456</b> of the upper <b>402</b> such that a user can tighten and tie together the free ends of the first lace <b>476</b><i>a </i>along the tongue <b>460</b>. The second plurality of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>b </i>are disposed on the exterior surface <b>454</b> of the upper <b>402</b> on the lateral and medial sides <b>416</b>, <b>418</b> between the first plurality of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>a </i>and the sole structure <b>404</b>. In some embodiments, the second plurality of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>b </i>can be formed by one or more strips of material adhered to the exterior surface <b>454</b> of the upper <b>402</b> with one or more unconnected portions that form loops to receive the second lace <b>476</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0137" num="0136">Referring still to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>28</b></figref>, in the illustrated embodiment, the third plurality of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>c </i>are part of the lattice-work structure of the frame <b>470</b> that is formed by the plurality of apertures <b>488</b>. More specifically, one or more apertures <b>488</b> disposed on the lateral side <b>490</b> and the medial side (not shown) of the frame <b>470</b> and aligned with the second plurality of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>b </i>are configured to receive a portion of the second lace <b>476</b><i>b </i>extending along the exterior surface <b>484</b> to the interior surface <b>486</b> of the frame <b>470</b>, or vice versa. In the illustrated embodiment, the third plurality of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>c </i>includes three lace retainers on each of the lateral and medial sides <b>416</b>, <b>418</b> of the article of footwear <b>400</b>. In some embodiments, the third plurality of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>c </i>can include four or more lace retainers. In the illustrated embodiment, the fourth plurality of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>d </i>are one or more loops formed on the exterior surface <b>454</b> of the upper <b>402</b> adjacent to the proximal end <b>422</b> and the opening <b>456</b> of the upper <b>402</b> and on each of the lateral and medial sides <b>416</b>, <b>418</b> of the article of footwear <b>400</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0138" num="0137">With continued reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>28</b></figref>, the second lace <b>476</b><i>b </i>extends through the second plurality of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>b </i>and the third plurality of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>c </i>in a crisscrossing manner across the tongue <b>460</b> and through the fourth plurality of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>d </i>disposed near the proximal end <b>422</b> of the upper <b>402</b>. Free ends of the second lace <b>476</b><i>b </i>extend from the second, third, and fourth pluralities of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>b</i>, <b>474</b><i>c</i>, <b>474</b><i>d </i>along the lateral and medial sides <b>416</b>, <b>418</b> of the upper <b>402</b> adjacent to the proximal end <b>422</b> and the opening <b>456</b> of the upper <b>402</b> such that a user can tighten and tie together the free ends of the second lace <b>476</b><i>b </i>along the proximal end <b>422</b> of the upper <b>402</b> adjacent to the opening <b>456</b>. In some embodiments, the third plurality of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>c </i>can include four or more apertures <b>488</b> that can be disposed on the lateral side <b>490</b> and the medial side (not shown) of the frame <b>470</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0139" num="0138">Still referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>28</b></figref>, in the illustrated embodiment, the second and third pluralities of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>b</i>, <b>474</b><i>c </i>are disposed in each of the forefoot region <b>408</b>, the midfoot region <b>410</b>, and the heel region <b>412</b> of the article of footwear <b>400</b>, and the fourth plurality of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>d </i>are disposed along the upper <b>402</b> entirely in the heel region <b>412</b>. With the second lace <b>476</b><i>b </i>in a tightened configuration (as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>28</b></figref>), the second lace <b>476</b><i>b </i>pulls the lateral and medial sides <b>416</b>, <b>418</b> of the upper <b>402</b> inward toward the tongue <b>460</b> and the tongue <b>460</b> downward toward the sole structure <b>404</b> via the second plurality of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>b</i>. Further, with the second lace <b>476</b><i>b </i>in the tightened configuration, the second lace <b>476</b><i>b </i>also pulls the frame <b>470</b> upwards toward the upper <b>402</b> via the third plurality of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>c</i>. Thus, tightening of the second lace <b>476</b><i>b </i>may provide additional support to the lateral and medial sides <b>416</b>, <b>418</b> of the upper <b>402</b> and also provide tensioning force to further secure the frame <b>470</b> to the sole structure <b>404</b> of the article of footwear <b>400</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0140" num="0139">In some embodiments, the free ends of the second lace <b>476</b><i>b </i>can extend around the proximal end <b>422</b> of the upper <b>402</b> such that a user can tighten and tie together the free ends of the second lace <b>476</b><i>b </i>along the tongue <b>460</b> adjacent to the opening <b>456</b>. In some embodiments, the second lace <b>476</b><i>b </i>can comprise two laces each having a fixed end disposed toward the distal end <b>424</b> of the upper <b>402</b> and free ends that extend toward the proximal end <b>422</b> of the upper <b>402</b> through the second and third pluralities of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>b</i>, <b>474</b><i>c</i>. In some embodiments, the free ends of the second lace <b>476</b><i>b </i>can extend from the second plurality of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>b </i>adjacent to the distal end <b>424</b> of the upper <b>402</b> such that a user can tighten and tie together the free ends along the tongue <b>460</b> proximal to the distal end <b>424</b>. In some embodiments, the second lace <b>476</b><i>b </i>can be a closed loop lace. In such embodiments, the fastening mechanism <b>472</b> can further include a lacing mechanism (not shown) that can be disposed along the proximal end <b>422</b> of the upper <b>402</b> and that can be configured to manually and/or automatically tighten or loosen the second lace <b>476</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0141" num="0140">Referring specifically to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>29</b> and <b>30</b></figref>, another exemplary embodiment fourth plurality of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>d</i>&#x2032; of the fastening mechanism <b>472</b> of the article of footwear <b>400</b> is depicted. The fourth plurality of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>d</i>&#x2032; of the fastening mechanism <b>472</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>29</b> and <b>30</b></figref> is similar to the previous embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>28</b></figref>, however, in the illustrated embodiment, the fourth plurality of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>d</i>&#x2032; includes one or more hooks and the second lace <b>476</b><i>b </i>is a closed loop lace. More specifically, the one or more hooks of the fourth plurality of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>d</i>&#x2032; have an open end that is configured to removably receive the closed loop second lace <b>476</b><i>b</i>. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>29</b></figref>, the closed loop second lace <b>476</b><i>b </i>of the fastening mechanism <b>472</b> is shown in a tightened configuration. In the tightened configuration, a portion of the second lace <b>476</b><i>b </i>extending from an aperture <b>488</b> of the frame <b>470</b> to a lateral-proximal lace retainer of the second plurality of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>b </i>disposed near the proximal end <b>422</b> of the upper <b>402</b>, around the proximal end <b>422</b> of the upper <b>402</b>, and to the medial side <b>418</b> of the upper <b>402</b> (i.e., the &#x201c;proximal portion of the second lace <b>476</b><i>b</i>&#x201d;) is received within the hooks of the fourth plurality of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>d</i>&#x2032;. Further, in the tightened configuration (as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>28</b> and <b>29</b></figref>), the second lace <b>476</b><i>b </i>extends around the proximal end <b>422</b> of the upper <b>402</b> adjacent to the opening <b>456</b> of the upper <b>402</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0142" num="0141">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>30</b></figref>, the closed loop second lace <b>476</b><i>b </i>of the fastening mechanism <b>472</b> is shown in a loosened configuration. In the loosened configuration, the proximal portion of the second lace <b>476</b><i>b </i>extending around the proximal end <b>422</b> of the upper <b>402</b> is not disposed within the hooks of the fourth plurality of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>d</i>. Thus, in the loosened configuration, the proximal portion of the second lace <b>476</b><i>b </i>is free to move downward along the proximal end <b>422</b> and away from the opening <b>456</b> of the upper <b>402</b>. As the proximal portion of the second lace <b>476</b><i>b </i>moves downward toward the lateral-proximal lace retainer of the second plurality of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>b</i>, other portions of the second lace <b>476</b><i>b </i>are permitted to increase in length and thus, loosen around the corresponding portions of the upper <b>402</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0143" num="0142">Referring still to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>29</b> and <b>30</b></figref>, in some embodiments, the fourth plurality of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>d</i>&#x2032; can comprise a single hook disposed on the proximal end <b>422</b> of the upper <b>402</b> near a central or longitudinal axis <b>420</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>28</b></figref>) of the article of footwear <b>400</b>. In some embodiments, a plurality of hooks of the fourth plurality of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>d</i>&#x2032; can be disposed on the proximal end <b>422</b> of the upper <b>402</b> near the central axis <b>420</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>28</b></figref>) and arranged in series between the opening <b>456</b> of the upper <b>402</b> and the sole structure <b>404</b> such that the level of tightness of the closed loop second lace <b>476</b><i>b </i>can be adjusted based on which of the plurality of hooks of the fourth plurality of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>d</i>&#x2032; is utilized to secure the second lace <b>476</b><i>b</i>. For example, a first hook can be disposed adjacent to the opening <b>456</b> that is configured to provide a first tightness to the second lace <b>476</b><i>b </i>and a second hook can be disposed below the first hook toward the sole structure <b>404</b> that is configured to provide a second tightness to the second lace <b>476</b><i>b </i>that is less tight than the first tightness. In some embodiments, the fourth plurality of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>d</i>&#x2032; can include three or more hooks that can be disposed near the proximal end <b>422</b> of the upper <b>402</b>. For example, the lateral-proximal lace retainer (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>29</b> and <b>30</b></figref>) and the medial-proximal lace retainer (not shown) of the second plurality of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>b </i>can each be replaced with a hook of the fourth plurality of lace retainers <b>474</b><i>d</i>&#x2032;. In some embodiments, the closed loop second lace <b>476</b><i>b </i>can be comprised of an elastic material.</p>
<p id="p-0144" num="0143">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>31</b> and <b>32</b></figref>, yet another exemplary embodiment of an article of footwear <b>500</b> is depicted, which includes an upper <b>502</b>, a sole structure <b>504</b>, and a frame <b>570</b>. The article of footwear <b>500</b> is similar to previous embodiments, with like elements being indicated by similar reference numerals under the &#x201c;5xx&#x201d; series of reference numerals. In the article of footwear <b>500</b>, midsole members of the sole structure <b>504</b> include a first midsole member <b>578</b><i>a</i>, which comprises a plurality of members disposed entirely in the heel region <b>512</b> of the sole structure <b>504</b>, and a second midsole member <b>578</b><i>b</i>, which comprises a single member disposed in the forefoot region <b>508</b> and the midfoot region <b>510</b> of the sole structure <b>504</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0145" num="0144">Referring specifically to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>31</b></figref>, the frame <b>570</b> extends over the first plurality of midsole members <b>578</b><i>a </i>and along the lateral side <b>516</b>, the medial side <b>518</b>, and the proximal end <b>522</b> of the sole structure <b>504</b> and the upper <b>502</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, the frame <b>570</b> extends increasingly higher along portions of the upper <b>502</b> from the midfoot region <b>510</b> to the heel region <b>512</b> such that the frame <b>570</b> extends along a larger portion of the proximal end <b>522</b> of the upper <b>502</b> than the lateral and medial sides <b>516</b>, <b>518</b> of the upper <b>502</b>. A plurality of apertures <b>588</b> is disposed along the frame <b>570</b> that form a lattice-work structure of the frame <b>570</b>, which permits the first plurality of midsole members <b>578</b><i>a </i>and the covered portions of the upper <b>502</b> to be visible from an outside of the article of footwear <b>500</b> through the apertures <b>588</b> of the frame <b>570</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0146" num="0145">With continued reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>31</b></figref>, a first outsole member <b>568</b><i>a </i>is disposed on the bottom side <b>594</b> of the frame <b>570</b> and a second outsole member <b>568</b><i>b </i>is disposed on a bottom side of the second midsole member <b>578</b><i>b</i>. Similar to the first outsole member <b>268</b><i>a </i>of the article of footwear <b>200</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>10</b>-<b>13</b></figref>, the first outsole member <b>568</b><i>a </i>can be disposed between the interior surface <b>586</b> of the bottom side <b>594</b> of the frame <b>570</b> and the first midsole members <b>578</b><i>a </i>or can be disposed on the exterior surface <b>584</b> of the bottom side <b>594</b> of the frame <b>570</b>. In some embodiments, the second outsole member <b>568</b><i>b </i>can be removably attached or fixedly attached to the bottom of the second midsole member <b>578</b><i>b</i>. In the illustrated embodiment, the first and second outsole members <b>568</b><i>a</i>, <b>568</b><i>b </i>together form the bottom surface <b>566</b> of the outsole <b>564</b> of the sole structure <b>504</b>. In some embodiments, the second midsole member <b>578</b><i>b </i>can comprise a plurality of midsole members. In some embodiments, the frame <b>570</b><i>a </i>can comprise a first frame that extends over the first midsole members <b>578</b><i>a </i>and a second frame that extends over the second midsole member <b>578</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0147" num="0146">Referring specifically to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>32</b></figref>, another exemplary embodiment frame <b>570</b>&#x2032; of the article of footwear <b>500</b> is depicted. The frame <b>570</b>&#x2032; of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>32</b></figref> is similar to the frame <b>570</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>31</b></figref>, however, the frame <b>570</b>&#x2032; covers a smaller portion of the proximal end <b>522</b> of the upper <b>502</b> than the frame <b>570</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>31</b></figref>. Thus, the frame <b>570</b>&#x2032; also covers a smaller portion of the lateral and medial sides <b>516</b>, <b>518</b> of the upper <b>502</b> than the frame <b>570</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>31</b></figref>. In some embodiments, and as discussed above with reference to other embodiments, the article of footwear <b>500</b> may be configured such that the frames <b>570</b>, <b>570</b>&#x2032; of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>31</b> and <b>32</b></figref> are removably attachable to the sole structure <b>504</b>. Thus, in such embodiments, a user can interchangeably secure either of the frames <b>570</b>, <b>570</b>&#x2032; to the sole structure <b>504</b> of the article of footwear <b>500</b>. In some embodiments, the frames <b>570</b>, <b>570</b>&#x2032; can provide differing structural properties of the sole structure <b>504</b> to a user of the article of footwear <b>500</b>. For example, in such embodiments, at least a portion of the frame <b>570</b> can be formed of a first material while a similar portion of the frame <b>570</b>&#x2032; can be formed of a second material that is different than the first material.</p>
<p id="p-0148" num="0147">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>33</b></figref>, yet another exemplary embodiment of an article of footwear <b>600</b> is depicted, which includes an upper <b>602</b>, a sole structure <b>604</b>, and a frame <b>670</b>. The article of footwear <b>600</b> is similar to previous embodiments, with like elements being indicated by similar reference numerals under the &#x201c;6xx&#x201d; series of reference numerals. In the illustrated embodiment, the frame <b>670</b> of the article of footwear <b>600</b> has a lattice-work structure formed by a plurality of apertures that includes a first plurality of apertures <b>688</b><i>a</i>, which are disposed substantially on the lateral side <b>690</b> and the medial side (not shown) of the frame <b>670</b>, and a second plurality of apertures <b>688</b><i>b</i>, which are disposed substantially on the bottom side <b>694</b> of the frame <b>670</b>. Further, the frame <b>670</b> is configured such that it covers more of the lateral and medial sides <b>616</b>, <b>618</b> of the upper <b>602</b> than the lateral and medial sides <b>616</b>, <b>618</b> of the sole structure <b>604</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0149" num="0148">Referring still to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>33</b></figref>, a bottom side <b>694</b> of the frame <b>670</b> extends over the bottom portions <b>682</b> of the midsole members <b>678</b> while the lateral side <b>690</b> and the medial side (not shown) of the frame <b>670</b> extend over the upper portions <b>680</b> of the midsole members <b>678</b> and portions of the lateral and medial sides <b>616</b>, <b>618</b> of the upper <b>602</b>. The distal side <b>696</b> of the frame <b>670</b> extends over the upper <b>602</b> between the distal end <b>624</b> of the article of footwear <b>600</b> and the tongue <b>660</b> while the proximal side <b>698</b> of the frame <b>670</b> extends around the proximal end <b>622</b> of the upper <b>602</b>. The bottom side <b>694</b> of the frame <b>670</b> includes the second plurality of apertures <b>688</b><i>b</i>, which, in this embodiment, includes only two large apertures such that the lattice-work structure along the bottom side <b>694</b> of the frame <b>670</b> extends between gaps between each of the midsole members <b>678</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0150" num="0149">Still referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>33</b></figref>, the fastening mechanism <b>672</b> of the article of footwear <b>600</b> includes a first fastening member or first plurality of lace retainers <b>674</b><i>a </i>and a second fastening member or second plurality of lace retainers <b>674</b><i>b</i>. In the illustrated embodiment, the first plurality of lace retainers <b>674</b><i>a </i>are eyelets disposed on the lateral and medial sides <b>616</b>, <b>618</b> of the upper <b>602</b> adjacent to the tongue <b>660</b>, and the second plurality of lace retainers <b>674</b><i>b </i>are one or more of the first plurality of apertures <b>688</b><i>a </i>of the frame <b>670</b> disposed between the first plurality of lace retainers <b>674</b><i>a </i>and the sole structure <b>604</b>. A third fastening member or lace <b>676</b> extends through the first plurality of lace retainers <b>674</b><i>a </i>in a crisscrossing manner across the tongue <b>660</b> and through the first and second pluralities of lace retainers <b>674</b><i>a</i>, <b>674</b><i>b </i>in parallel, i.e., through one of the first plurality of lace retainers <b>674</b><i>a </i>to one of the second plurality of lace retainers <b>674</b><i>b</i>, and back through another one of the first plurality of lace retainers <b>674</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0151" num="0150">With continued reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>33</b></figref>, free ends of the lace <b>676</b> extend through the second plurality of lace retainers <b>674</b><i>b </i>adjacent to the opening <b>656</b> of the upper <b>602</b> such that a user can tighten and tie together the free ends of the lace <b>676</b> along the tongue <b>660</b> adjacent to the opening <b>656</b> of the upper <b>602</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, a user can tighten and tie together the free ends of the lace <b>676</b> to provide tension force on the frame <b>670</b>, which can further secure the frame <b>670</b> to the sole structure <b>604</b> and provide further support along the lateral and medial sides <b>616</b>, <b>618</b> of the upper <b>602</b> of the article of footwear <b>600</b> while pulling the tongue <b>660</b> downward toward the sole structure <b>604</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0152" num="0151">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>34</b></figref>, another exemplary embodiment of an article of footwear <b>700</b> is depicted, which includes an upper <b>702</b>, a sole structure <b>704</b>, and a frame <b>770</b>. The article of footwear <b>700</b> is similar to previous embodiments, with like elements being indicated by similar reference numerals under the &#x201c;7xx&#x201d; series of reference numerals. In contrast to previous embodiments, in the article of footwear <b>700</b>, neither a tongue nor a fastening mechanism is included along the instep region <b>758</b> of the upper <b>702</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0153" num="0152">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>34</b></figref>, the midsole members <b>778</b> are disposed only in the forefoot region <b>708</b> and the heel region <b>712</b> of the sole structure <b>704</b> of the article of footwear <b>700</b>. The frame <b>770</b> extends along the lateral side <b>716</b>, the medial side <b>718</b>, the proximal end <b>722</b>, and the distal end <b>724</b> of the sole structure <b>704</b> and along the lateral and medial sides <b>716</b>, <b>718</b> of a lower portion of the upper <b>702</b> in the heel region <b>712</b> of the article of footwear <b>700</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, the bottom side <b>794</b> of the frame <b>770</b> is shaped such that portions of the frame <b>770</b> are proximate to or contact a bottom side of the upper <b>702</b> while enlarged cavity sections are provided adjacent the midsole members <b>778</b>. Further, the frame <b>770</b> includes a plurality of apertures <b>788</b> having varying shapes and sizes. For example, the apertures <b>788</b> disposed in the heel region <b>712</b> have shapes with larger widths in comparison to the apertures <b>788</b> disposed in the forefoot and midfoot regions <b>708</b>, <b>710</b>. In some embodiments, the apertures <b>788</b> disposed in the midfoot region <b>710</b> can have shapes with larger widths in comparison to the apertures <b>788</b> disposed in the forefoot and heel regions <b>708</b>, <b>712</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0154" num="0153">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>35</b></figref>, yet another exemplary embodiment of an article of footwear <b>800</b> is depicted, which includes an upper <b>802</b>, a sole structure <b>804</b>, and a frame <b>870</b>. The article of footwear <b>800</b> is similar to previous embodiments, with like elements being indicated by similar reference numerals under the &#x201c;8xx&#x201d; series of reference numerals. In contrast to previous embodiments, in the article of footwear <b>800</b>, the frame <b>870</b> extends along the entire proximal end <b>822</b> of the upper <b>802</b> adjacent to the opening <b>856</b> of the upper <b>802</b> such that a substantial portion of the article of footwear <b>800</b>, including the upper <b>802</b> and the sole structure <b>804</b>, in the heel region <b>812</b> is covered by the frame <b>870</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0155" num="0154">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>35</b></figref>, the lateral and medial sides <b>890</b>, <b>892</b> of the frame <b>870</b> include the plurality of apertures <b>888</b> that increase in length in a direction extending from the distal side <b>896</b> to the proximal side <b>898</b>. As a result, upper portions of the frame <b>870</b> along the lateral, medial, and proximal sides <b>890</b>, <b>892</b>, <b>898</b> of the frame <b>870</b> increasingly cover larger portions of the upper <b>802</b> in the direction extending from the distal end <b>824</b> to the proximal end <b>822</b> such that a heel portion of the upper <b>802</b> within the heel region <b>812</b> is entirely covered by the proximal side <b>898</b> of the frame <b>870</b>. In some embodiments, the lateral and medial sides <b>816</b>, <b>818</b> of portions of the upper <b>802</b> within the forefoot region <b>808</b> and/or the midfoot region <b>810</b> can be entirely covered by the lateral and medial sides <b>890</b>, <b>892</b>, respectively, of the frame <b>870</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0156" num="0155">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>36</b></figref>, another exemplary embodiment of an article of footwear <b>900</b> is depicted, which includes an upper <b>902</b>, a sole structure <b>904</b>, and a frame <b>970</b>. The article of footwear <b>900</b> is similar to previous embodiments, with like elements being indicated by similar reference numerals under the &#x201c;9xx&#x201d; series of reference numerals. In contrast to previous embodiments, in the article of footwear <b>900</b>, the midsole members <b>978</b> comprise an interconnected upper portion <b>980</b> and a plurality of bottom portions <b>982</b> independently connected to parts of the interconnected upper portion <b>980</b> in one or more of the forefoot, midfoot, or heel regions <b>908</b>, <b>910</b>, <b>912</b>. Further, the frame <b>970</b> includes a plurality of first or bottom frames <b>970</b><i>a </i>attached to a respective one of the plurality of bottom portions <b>982</b> of the midsole members <b>978</b> and a plurality of upper frames <b>970</b><i>b </i>attached to the interconnected upper portion <b>980</b> of the midsole members <b>978</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0157" num="0156">Referring still to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>36</b></figref>, the interconnected upper portion <b>980</b> of the midsole members <b>978</b> extends along a bottom side of the upper <b>902</b> from the distal end <b>924</b> to the proximal end <b>922</b> and from the lateral side <b>916</b> to the medial side <b>918</b> of the upper <b>902</b>. A first or distal protruding member <b>980</b><i>a </i>protrudes from the distal end <b>924</b> of the sole structure <b>904</b>, and a second or proximal protruding member <b>980</b><i>b </i>protrudes from the proximal end <b>922</b> of the sole structure <b>904</b>. In addition, a plurality of connecting protrusions <b>980</b><i>c </i>extend downwardly from a corresponding one of a plurality of recesses <b>980</b><i>d </i>disposed along the interconnected upper portion <b>980</b> between the first and second protruding members <b>980</b><i>a</i>, <b>980</b><i>b </i>that connect the plurality of bottom portions <b>982</b> to the interconnected upper portion <b>980</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0158" num="0157">In the illustrated embodiment, the plurality of bottom portions <b>982</b> includes a first or distal bottom portion <b>982</b><i>a</i>, a second or distal-midfoot bottom portion <b>982</b><i>b</i>, a third or proximal-midfoot bottom portion <b>982</b><i>c</i>, and a fourth or proximal bottom portion <b>982</b><i>d</i>. Each of the first, second, third, and fourth bottom portions <b>982</b><i>a</i>, <b>982</b><i>b</i>, <b>982</b><i>c</i>, <b>982</b><i>d </i>of the midsole members <b>978</b> are connected to the interconnected upper portion <b>980</b> via a respective one of the plurality of connecting protrusions <b>980</b><i>c </i>extending downwardly from the upper portion <b>980</b>. In some embodiments, two or more of the first, second, third, and fourth bottom portions <b>982</b><i>a</i>, <b>982</b><i>b</i>, <b>982</b><i>c</i>, <b>982</b><i>d </i>may be connected to the upper portion <b>980</b> by a single connecting protrusion <b>980</b><i>c</i>. In some embodiments, two or more of the first, second, third, and fourth bottom portions <b>982</b><i>a</i>, <b>982</b><i>b</i>, <b>982</b><i>c</i>, <b>982</b><i>d </i>can be interconnected. In some embodiments, the plurality of bottom portions <b>982</b> can include three or less or five or more bottom portions.</p>
<p id="p-0159" num="0158">With continued reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>36</b></figref>, the plurality of bottom frames <b>970</b><i>a </i>wrap around a respective one of the bottom portions <b>982</b><i>a</i>, <b>982</b><i>b</i>, <b>982</b><i>c</i>, <b>982</b><i>d </i>of the midsole members <b>978</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, the bottom frames <b>970</b><i>a </i>and the first and second protruding members <b>980</b><i>a</i>, <b>980</b><i>b </i>of the upper portion <b>980</b> each include an outsole member <b>968</b> such that the plurality of bottom frames <b>970</b><i>a </i>and the first and second protruding members <b>980</b><i>a</i>, <b>980</b><i>b </i>collectively define the bottom surface <b>966</b> of the outsole <b>964</b> of the sole structure <b>904</b>. Similar to previous embodiments described herein, in some embodiments of the article of footwear <b>900</b>, the outsole members <b>968</b> may be removably attached or fixedly attached to the plurality of bottom frames <b>970</b><i>a </i>and/or the protruding members <b>980</b><i>a</i>, <b>980</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0160" num="0159">Still referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>36</b></figref>, the plurality of upper frames <b>970</b><i>b </i>extend within the recesses <b>980</b><i>d </i>and at least partially around the upper portion <b>980</b> and the connecting protrusions <b>980</b><i>c </i>of the midsole members <b>978</b>, and around lower portions of the upper <b>902</b>. A frame ring <b>914</b> extends along the lateral and medial sides <b>916</b>, <b>918</b> and the proximal and distal ends <b>922</b>, <b>924</b> of the sole structure <b>904</b> between the pluralities of bottom and upper frames <b>970</b><i>a</i>, <b>970</b><i>b</i>. In addition to providing aesthetic appeal, the frame ring <b>914</b> can be configured to provide structural support to the upper portion <b>980</b> of the midsole members <b>978</b> by structurally connecting the first and second protruding members <b>980</b><i>a</i>, <b>980</b><i>b</i>. In some embodiments, the frame ring <b>914</b> can extend through an aperture (not shown) that can be defined in the first protruding member <b>980</b><i>a </i>and/or the second protruding member <b>980</b><i>b</i>. In some embodiments, the frame ring <b>914</b> can be integrally formed with the first protruding member <b>980</b><i>a </i>and/or the second protruding member <b>980</b><i>b</i>. In some embodiments, the frame ring <b>914</b> is fixedly attached to the upper portion <b>980</b> of the midsole members <b>978</b>. In some embodiments, the frame ring <b>914</b> can be connected to each of the plurality of connecting protrusions <b>980</b><i>c </i>of the midsole members <b>978</b> in addition to the first and second protruding members <b>980</b><i>a</i>, <b>980</b><i>b</i>. In some embodiments, the frame ring <b>914</b> can be removably attached to the sole structure <b>904</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0161" num="0160">Referring still to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>36</b></figref>, the fastening mechanism <b>972</b> of the article of footwear <b>900</b> includes a first fastening member or plurality of lace retainers <b>974</b> and a second fastening member or lace <b>976</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, the plurality of lace retainers <b>974</b> are pairs of eyelets disposed on the lateral and medial sides <b>916</b>, <b>918</b> of the upper <b>902</b> adjacent to the instep region <b>958</b> between the distal end <b>924</b> and the opening <b>956</b> of the upper <b>902</b>. The lace <b>976</b> extends through the plurality of lace retainers <b>974</b> in a crisscrossing manner across the instep region <b>958</b>. Free ends of the lace <b>976</b> extend from the plurality of lace retainers <b>974</b> adjacent to the opening <b>956</b> of the upper <b>902</b> that can be tightened and tied together by a user. In some embodiments, a tongue (not shown) can be included on the upper <b>902</b> within the instep region <b>958</b>, and the plurality of lace retainers <b>974</b> can be arranged on the lateral and medial sides <b>916</b>, <b>918</b> of the upper <b>902</b> adjacent to sides of the tongue. In some embodiments, the fastening mechanism <b>972</b> can further include a third fastening member that can be defined by one or more of: the lattice-work structure formed by one or more apertures <b>988</b> of one or more of the plurality of lower frames <b>970</b><i>a</i>; the plurality of upper frames <b>970</b><i>b</i>; or the frame ring <b>914</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0162" num="0161">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>37</b></figref>, yet another exemplary embodiment of an article of footwear <b>1000</b> is depicted, which includes an upper <b>1002</b>, a sole structure <b>1004</b>, and a frame <b>1070</b>. The article of footwear <b>1000</b> is similar to previous embodiments, with like elements being indicated by similar reference numerals under the &#x201c;10xx&#x201d; series of reference numerals. In contrast to previous embodiments, in the article of footwear <b>1000</b>, a flap <b>1030</b> of the frame <b>1070</b> extends partially over the sole structure <b>1004</b> and over the instep region <b>1058</b> from the lateral side <b>1016</b> to the medial side <b>1018</b> of the upper <b>1002</b>, and then around the proximal end <b>1022</b> of the upper <b>1002</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0163" num="0162">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>37</b></figref>, the bottom side <b>1094</b> of the frame <b>1070</b> extends along bottom portions <b>1082</b> of the midsole members <b>1078</b> disposed in the forefoot and midfoot regions <b>1008</b>, <b>1010</b> of the sole structure <b>1004</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, the distal end <b>1096</b> of the frame <b>1070</b> does not extend to the distal end <b>1024</b> of the sole structure <b>1004</b>, and the proximal end <b>1098</b> of the frame <b>1070</b> extends through the midfoot region <b>1010</b> of the sole structure <b>1004</b>. The lateral and medial sides <b>1090</b>, <b>1092</b> of the frame <b>1070</b> extend over the upper portions <b>1080</b> of the midsole members <b>1078</b> within the midfoot and heel regions <b>1010</b>, <b>1012</b>. The flap <b>1030</b> of the frame <b>1070</b> extends from the lateral side <b>1090</b> of the frame <b>1070</b> and over the instep region <b>1058</b> to the medial side <b>1018</b> of the upper <b>1002</b>. The flap <b>1030</b> of the frame <b>1070</b> then extends along the medial side <b>1018</b> of the upper to a lower portion of the proximal end <b>1022</b> of the upper <b>1002</b> and along at least the upper portions <b>1080</b> of the midsole members <b>1078</b> disposed toward the proximal end <b>1022</b> of the sole structure <b>1004</b>. The flap <b>1030</b> of the frame <b>170</b> continues to extend around the proximal end <b>1022</b> of the upper <b>1002</b> and back to the lateral side <b>1016</b> of the upper <b>1002</b> where the flap <b>1030</b> terminates at a flap end <b>1032</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0164" num="0163">With continued reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>37</b></figref>, in some embodiments, the frame <b>1070</b> can be comprised of two or more materials, for example, at least a portion of the flap <b>1030</b> of the frame <b>1070</b> can be comprised of a first material that is flexible and the remainder of the frame <b>1070</b> can be comprised of a second material this is more rigid than the first material. In such embodiments, the flap <b>1030</b> of the frame <b>1070</b> can be configured to releasably attach to the upper <b>1002</b> and/or the sole structure <b>1004</b> such that the flap <b>1030</b> of the frame <b>1070</b> can be flexed away from the instep region <b>1058</b> by a user. In such embodiments, the flap <b>1030</b> of the frame <b>1070</b> can function as a fastening mechanism <b>1072</b> of the article of footwear <b>1000</b> by releasably securing the flap end <b>1032</b> of the flap <b>1030</b> of the frame <b>1070</b> to the upper <b>1002</b> and/or the sole structure <b>1004</b>. In such embodiments, the flap end <b>1032</b> of the flap <b>1030</b> can include a recess or a protrusion and the upper <b>1002</b> and/or the sole structure <b>1004</b> can include a corresponding recess or protrusion configured to receive the recess or protrusion of the flap end <b>1032</b>. In some embodiments, the flap <b>1030</b> extends from the medial side <b>1092</b> of the frame <b>1070</b> and then over the instep region <b>1058</b> to the lateral side <b>1016</b> of the upper <b>1002</b>. In some embodiments, a first flap extends from the lateral side <b>1090</b> of the frame <b>1070</b> over a first portion of the instep region <b>1058</b> and a second flap extends from the medial side <b>1092</b> of the frame <b>1070</b> over a second portion of the instep region <b>1058</b>. In such embodiments, the fastening mechanism <b>1072</b> of the article of footwear <b>1000</b> can comprise both the first flap on the lateral side <b>1090</b> and the second flap on the medial side <b>1092</b> of the frame <b>1070</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0165" num="0164">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>27</b>-<b>37</b></figref>, various components of the example articles of footwear <b>300</b>, <b>400</b>, <b>500</b>, <b>600</b>, <b>700</b>, <b>800</b>, <b>900</b>, <b>1000</b>, may be formed through additive manufacturing techniques, such as by one or more of the various 3D printing techniques mentioned above. For example, with reference to the article of footwear <b>900</b>, the interconnected upper portion <b>980</b> of the midsole members <b>978</b> of the article of footwear <b>900</b> may be 3D printed as a single unitary piece. Further, the plurality of lower frames <b>970</b><i>a</i>, the plurality of upper frames <b>970</b><i>b</i>, and/or the frame ring <b>914</b> of the article of footwear <b>900</b> may be 3D printed.</p>
<p id="p-0166" num="0165">In other embodiments, other configurations are possible. For example, certain features and combinations of features that are presented with respect to particular embodiments in the discussion above can be utilized in other embodiments and in other combinations, as appropriate. Further, any of the embodiments described herein may be modified to include any of the structures or methodologies disclosed in connection with other embodiments. Additionally, the present disclosure is not limited to articles of footwear of the type specifically shown. Still further, aspects of the articles of footwear of any of the embodiments disclosed herein may be modified to work with any type of footwear, apparel, or other athletic equipment.</p>
<p id="p-0167" num="0166">As noted previously, it will be appreciated by those skilled in the art that while the invention has been described above in connection with particular embodiments and examples, the invention is not necessarily so limited, and that numerous other embodiments, examples, uses, modifications and departures from the embodiments, examples and uses are intended to be encompassed by the claims attached hereto. The entire disclosure of each patent and publication cited herein is incorporated by reference, as if each such patent or publication were individually incorporated by reference herein. Various features and advantages of the invention are set forth in the following claims.</p>
<heading id="h-0010" level="1">INDUSTRIAL APPLICABILITY</heading>
<p id="p-0168" num="0167">Numerous modifications to the present invention will be apparent to those skilled in the art in view of the foregoing description. Accordingly, this description is to be construed as illustrative only and is presented for the purpose of enabling those skilled in the art to make and use the invention. The exclusive rights to all modifications which come within the scope of the appended claims are reserved.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>We claim:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. An article of footwear, comprising:
<claim-text>an upper including a fastening mechanism;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a sole including a midsole and an outsole; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a frame having an exterior surface and an interior surface opposite the exterior surface, the interior surface being adjacent portions of the midsole, the outsole, and the upper,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the frame has a lattice-work structure formed by a plurality of apertures extending through the interior and exterior surfaces of the frame such that at least some of the portions of the midsole, the outsole, and the upper adjacent the interior surface of the frame are exposed through the plurality of apertures, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the fastening mechanism includes a fastening member extending through at least one aperture of the plurality of apertures of the frame.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The article of footwear of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the frame extends along a medial side and a lateral side of the article of footwear, and
<claim-text>wherein the lattice-work structure of the frame extends along at least the lateral side of the article of footwear.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The article of footwear of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the frame extends along a medial side, a lateral side, and a heel region of the article of footwear, and
<claim-text>wherein the lattice-work structure of the frame extends along at least the lateral side and the heel region of the article of footwear.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The article of footwear of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the lattice-work structure of the frame extends along a percentage in a range of about 5% to about 60% of an exterior surface of the upper.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The article of footwear of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the fastening member of the fastening mechanism is a lace.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The article of footwear of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the fastening member of the fastening mechanism is a hook and a loop that is configured to removably engage the hook.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The article of footwear of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein a percentage in a range of about 30% to about 90% of the frame includes the lattice-work structure.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The article of footwear of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein a percentage in a range of about 60% to about 90% of the frame includes the lattice-work structure.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The article of footwear of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the lattice-work structure of the frame is comprised of a material that is configured to adapt to a wearer's foot.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The article of footwear of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the lattice-work structure of the frame is comprised of a material that is configured to elastically deform under tension exerted by the fastening member of the fastening mechanism.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The article of footwear of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein portions of the lattice-work structure of the frame adjacent the outsole have a greater stiffness than portions of the lattice-work structure of the frame adjacent the midsole.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The article of footwear of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the frame includes an outsole member that at least partially defines the outsole of the sole structure.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. The article of footwear of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the outsole member is disposed between the midsole and the interior surface of the frame along a bottom side of the frame.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The article of footwear of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the outsole member is disposed on the exterior surface of the frame along a bottom side of the frame.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. A frame for an article of footwear that includes an upper and a sole structure, the frame comprising:
<claim-text>a lattice-work structure formed by a plurality of apertures extending through an exterior surface and an interior surface of the frame,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the interior surface of the frame is configured for placement adjacent portions of a midsole and an outsole of the sole structure of the article of footwear, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the frame is configured to be removably attachable to at least the sole structure of the article of footwear such that, when the frame is removably attached to the article of footwear, at least some of the portions of the midsole and the outsole adjacent the interior surface of the frame are exposed through the plurality of apertures of the frame.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. The frame of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a removable outsole member disposed adjacent a bottom side of the frame.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. The frame of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein two or more apertures of the plurality of apertures of the frame are configured to receive a portion of a lace of the upper to secure the frame to the sole structure of the article of footwear, and
<claim-text>wherein at least portions of the lattice-work structure of the frame are configured to elastically deform under tension when the lace received within the two or more apertures of the plurality of apertures is in a tightened configuration.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. An article of footwear, comprising:
<claim-text>an upper;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a sole structure having a midsole and an outsole; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a frame having an exterior surface and an interior surface, the interior surface being adjacent portions of the midsole, the outsole, and the upper in a heel region of the article of footwear,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the frame has a lattice-work structure formed by a plurality of apertures extending through the interior and exterior surfaces of the frame such that at least some of the portions of the midsole, the outsole, and the upper adjacent the interior surface of the frame are exposed through the plurality of apertures, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the frame is removably attached to at least the sole structure of the article of footwear.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. The article of footwear of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein the portion of the midsole in the heel region adjacent the interior surface of the frame includes a plurality of midsole members that are removably attached to a bottom side of the upper, and
<claim-text>wherein the frame extends over the plurality of midsole members of the sole structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. The article of footwear of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein the frame further includes an outsole member disposed between the plurality of midsole members and the interior surface of the frame along a bottom side of the frame.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
