<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225544A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225544</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18123550</doc-number>
<date>20230320</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>27</main-group>
<subgroup>10</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>27</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>27</main-group>
<subgroup>10</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>27</main-group>
<subgroup>004</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">SOUS VIDE COOKER</invention-title>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17490580</doc-number>
<date>20210930</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11622644</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18123550</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation>
<division>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>16382534</doc-number>
<date>20190412</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11375843</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17490580</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</division>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Anova Applied Electronics, Inc.</orgname>
<address>
<city>San Francisco</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Messler</last-name>
<first-name>Carl H&#xe5;kan</first-name>
<address>
<city>San Francisco</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="01" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Yujie</last-name>
<first-name>Xia</first-name>
<address>
<city>San Francisco</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="02" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hu</last-name>
<first-name>Vivian Lee</first-name>
<address>
<city>San Francisco</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Anova Applied Electronics, Inc.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>San Francisco</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A sous vide cooker having a housing, a bulkhead attached to the housing to form a first cavity, a heat sink attached to the bulkhead to form a second cavity, and a skirt attached to the bulkhead to form a third cavity below the heat sink. A TRIAC is physically attached in conductive thermal communication to the heat sink in the second cavity. The cooker also has a motor, an impeller located in the third cavity, a drive shaft extending through at least the heat sink and into the third cavity and operatively connecting the motor to the impeller, and a heating element located within the third cavity.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="168.83mm" wi="81.87mm" file="US20230225544A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="232.66mm" wi="187.11mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225544A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="238.08mm" wi="140.63mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225544A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="242.99mm" wi="174.16mm" file="US20230225544A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="201.25mm" wi="103.46mm" file="US20230225544A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="244.77mm" wi="171.53mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225544A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="236.22mm" wi="148.25mm" file="US20230225544A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="151.13mm" wi="133.60mm" file="US20230225544A1-20230720-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a continuation of U.S. application Ser. No. 17/490,580, filed on Sep. 30, 2021, which is a divisional of U.S. application Ser. No. 16/382,534, filed on Apr. 12, 2019, which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="tail"?>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">This application relates to the field of sous vide immersion cooking systems in which a unitary housing is partially submerged into a liquid cooking medium.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Sous vide cooking devices are in popular use in commercial and home kitchens. A sous vide cooking device operates by heating water or another liquid medium to a predetermined temperature, and immersing a food item into the liquid to be cooked. Sous vide differs from simple boiling or the like in that the food item is isolated from the liquid (e.g., by a vacuum package or plastic bag), and the cooking temperature is typically relatively low (e.g., 125&#xb0; F.).</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">A typical professional sous vide cooker comprises a heating and circulation system and a separate bath structure. The bath holds the food items, and the heating and circulation system pumps heated liquid into and out of the bath. The heating and circulation system is isolated from the bath itself, and thus an operator is unlikely to come into contact with the heating elements or other heated components other than the liquid.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Sous vide cookers used on household kitchens are typically of the &#x201c;immersion&#x201d; type, in which the sous vide cooker is provided as a single unitary device having a heater and a pump. The immersion cooker is used by partially submerging it into a liquid bath provided in a container such as a pot or tub. Such immersion cookers usually are configured to work in a wide variety of different containers by having adjustable clamps and the like. While immersion cookers are more portable than the typical professional sous vide system, they also present more opportunities for the user to come into contact with the heated portions of the sous vide cooker. For example, a user could remove the sous vide cooker while the heating element is active (or shortly after deactivation) and touch the normally-submerged portion of the immersion cooker holding the heating element. This problem is exacerbated by the making the sous vide cooker smaller, as is typically desired in consumer appliances.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The inventors have determined that there is a need to provide better heat control in sous vide immersion cookers.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">This description of the background is provided to assist with an understanding of the following explanations of exemplary embodiments, and is not an admission that any or all of this background information is necessarily prior art.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In one aspect, there is provided a sous vide cooker having a housing extending along an longitudinal axis from an upper housing end to a lower housing end and comprising at least one display, a bulkhead having an upper bulkhead end extending along the longitudinal axis into the lower housing end, and a lower bulkhead end extending along the longitudinal axis below the housing, the bulkhead and housing forming a first cavity therebetween, and a heat sink comprising a metal material and having an upper heat sink end abutting the bulkhead and a lower heat sink end extending along the longitudinal axis below the bulkhead, the heat sink and bulkhead forming a second cavity therebetween. A skirt is attached at an upper skirt end to the bulkhead and extends to a lower skirt end located below the lower heat sink end to form a third cavity between the skirt and the heat sink. The skirt surrounds the heat sink in a direction perpendicular to the longitudinal axis, and has one or more one or more inlet openings and one or more outlet openings located below the lower heat sink end. A TRIAC is physically attached in conductive thermal communication to the heat sink in the second cavity. An impeller is located in the third cavity. A drive shaft extends through at least the heat sink and into the third cavity and is operatively connected to the impeller. A motor is operatively connected to the drive shaft. A heating element located within the third cavity.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In some embodiments, the bulkhead may have a circumferential rib positioned between the lower housing end and the upper skirt end, and the lower housing end, circumferential rib and upper skirt end may form a continuous wall profile along a predetermined distance along the longitudinal axis.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In some embodiments, the heat sink may be a monolithic piece of aluminum.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In some embodiments, the heating element may be mounted to the heat sink.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In some embodiments, the heating element may have a coil surrounding the drive shaft.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In some embodiments, the cooker may include at least one temperature sensor or water level sensor mounted to the heat sink and extending into the third cavity. The at least one temperature sensor or water level sensor may be mounted to the heat sink by an electrical insulator, and the cooker may further have a seal of insulating material covering the lower heat sink end and surrounding the at least one temperature sensor or water level sensor.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In some embodiments, the TRIAC may be attached to the heat sink by a layer of thermal grease.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In some embodiments, the second cavity may be formed at least in part by a recess in the heat sink, the recess extending from the upper heat sink end towards the lower heat sink end. The recess may have a cylindrical shape. The recess may have a sidewall extending from the upper heat sink end to a bottom wall at a lower end of the sidewall, and the TRIAC may be attached to the side wall. An axial bore may extend within the sidewall adjacent the TRIAC, and a temperature sensor may be located in the axial bore.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In some embodiments, the motor may be located in the second cavity.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In some embodiments, the skirt may be spaced in a direction perpendicular to the longitudinal axis from the heat sink by a gap so as to not directly contact the heat sink. An insulation sleeve may be located between and physically separate the skirt and the heat sink.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In some embodiments, the skirt may have one or more connector pins extending inward towards the bulkhead, and the bulkhead may have one or more connector slots configured to receive the one or more connector pins in an axial direction and a circumferential direction to secure the skirt to the bulkhead. The heating element may have one or more external slots extending from the one or more connector slots to slidingly receive the connector pins therein.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In some embodiments, the heat sink may have a motor shaft passage at the lower heat sink end through which the motor shaft passes, and a bearing in the motor shaft passage to support the motor shaft in a lateral direction perpendicular to the longitudinal axis.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">In some embodiments, at least a portion of the heating element may be located along the longitudinal axis between the one or more one or more inlet openings and the one or more outlet openings, and the impeller may be located between the heating element and the lower skirt end.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In another exemplary embodiment, there is provided a sous vide cooker having a housing extending along an longitudinal axis from an upper housing end to a lower housing end and comprising at least one display, a bulkhead having an upper bulkhead end extending along the longitudinal axis into the lower housing end, and a lower bulkhead end extending along the longitudinal axis below the housing, the bulkhead and housing forming a first cavity therebetween, and a skirt attached at an upper skirt end to the bulkhead and extending to a lower skirt end located below the lower bulkhead end to form a second cavity between the skirt and the bulkhead. The skirt has one or more one or more inlet openings and one or more outlet openings located below the lower bulkhead end. An impeller is located in the second cavity. A drive shaft extends through the bulkhead and into the second cavity and is operatively connected to the impeller. A motor is operatively connected to the drive shaft. A heating element is located within the second cavity. A ring-shaped metal heat sink is located in the first cavity. A TRIAC is physically attached in conductive thermal communication to the heat sink in the first cavity.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Embodiments of inventions will now be described, strictly by way of example, with reference to the accompanying drawings, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a front elevation view of a first exemplary sous vide cooker.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a right side elevation view of the first exemplary sous vide cooker, shown with the skirt removed.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a left side elevation view of the first exemplary sous vide cooker.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is an exploded view of the first exemplary sous vide cooker.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b>A</figref> is a cutaway front elevation view of the first exemplary sous vide cooker.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b>B</figref> is a magnified view of a portion of the view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b>A</figref></p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b>C</figref> is a cutaway side elevation view of a portion of the first exemplary sous vide cooker.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is a fragmented view showing portions of the first exemplary sous vide cooker</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> is a fragmented view showing portions of the first exemplary sous vide cooker</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> is a partially fragmented exploded view of a second exemplary sous vide cooker.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref> is a cutaway front elevation view of the second exemplary sous vide cooker.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref> is a cutaway side elevation view of the second exemplary sous vide cooker.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b></figref> is a fragmented view showing portions of the second exemplary sous vide cooker.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF EXEMPLARY EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a front elevation view of an example of an immersion type sous vide cooker <b>100</b>. In general terms, the cooker <b>100</b> has a housing <b>102</b> on which a display <b>104</b> is mounted, and a skirt <b>106</b> extending downwardly from the housing <b>102</b>. The display <b>104</b> illustrates information relevant to the operation of the cooker <b>100</b> or other information to a user. One or more controllers, such as dials, buttons, touchscreen interfaces, and the like, may be provided to control the device's operating settings. In the shown example, the display <b>104</b> includes integrated capacitive sensing buttons or the like. The cooker <b>100</b> preferably also may be controlled by wireless communication with an external controlling device, such as a dedicated remote control, or a smartphone or other multifunction computing device having software configured to communicate with and control the cooker <b>100</b>, as known in the art. The skirt <b>106</b> includes one or more inlet openings <b>108</b> to receive cooking liquid, and one or more outlet openings <b>110</b> to eject cooking liquid, as discussed in more detail below.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The cooker <b>100</b> and its various parts (e.g., the display <b>104</b>) may have any suitable shape, but preferably is elongated along a longitudinal axis <b>112</b>. The longitudinal axis <b>112</b> preferably is oriented vertically (i.e., in the gravitational vertical direction) during use of the cooker <b>100</b>. Terms of relative orientation, such as &#x201c;upper,&#x201d; &#x201c;lower,&#x201d; &#x201c;above,&#x201d; &#x201c;below,&#x201d; are used herein for convenience in describing the features, and in use it is expected that the longitudinal axis <b>112</b> generally will be oriented vertically. However, these relative terms are not intended to require a particular orientation of the cooker <b>100</b> in space, and it will be understood that the cooker <b>100</b> could exist and be operated with the longitudinal axis <b>112</b> in a non-vertical orientation (e.g., tilted), in which case the relative terms would still refer to orientation along the longitudinal axis <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b> and <b>3</b></figref>, a clamp <b>200</b>, clip or other structure may be provided to secure the cooker <b>100</b> to a pot or other container, with the skirt <b>106</b> immersed in a cooking liquid. In the shown example, the clamp <b>200</b> comprises an arm <b>214</b> that is slidably mounted by a ring-shaped collar <b>216</b> to the housing <b>102</b> and/or skirt <b>106</b>. The collar <b>216</b> has a bore with a cross-sectional shape that matches the shape of the housing <b>102</b> and skirt <b>106</b> (e.g., cylindrical) to allow sliding and/or rotational movement. A first threaded locking screw <b>218</b> is provided on the arm <b>214</b> to clamp onto a container, and a second threaded locking screw <b>220</b> is provided to tighten the collar <b>216</b> to prevent sliding.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The skirt <b>106</b> surrounds a heating element <b>202</b> and an impeller <b>204</b>, which are operative to heat and circulate the cooking liquid. In this case, the heating element <b>202</b> comprises a resistance heater that extends downward into the skirt <b>106</b> and is shaped into a number of coils <b>206</b> to concentrate heat generation towards the lower end of the cooker <b>100</b>. The impeller <b>204</b> is comprises a vaned disk located below the heating element coils <b>206</b>. The impeller <b>204</b> is mounted on a drive shaft <b>208</b> by any suitable connector (e.g., threaded engagement), and the drive shaft <b>208</b> may pass through the heating element coils <b>206</b> to a motor, as discussed in more detail below.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The skirt <b>106</b> also may contain a variety of sensors or other operative components. For example, one or more water level sensors <b>210</b> or temperature sensors <b>212</b> may be suspended within the skirt <b>106</b> adjacent the heating element <b>202</b> and drive shaft <b>208</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The cooker <b>100</b> also may include a power cord <b>222</b> to attach to a conventional <b>120</b> or <b>240</b> volt AC power supply, display lights located other than on the display <b>104</b>, audio speakers, handles, or other conventional features.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is an exploded view of the cooker <b>100</b> showing the internal components in more detail. Working downward from the upper end, the cooker <b>100</b> includes the display <b>104</b>, including a display cover <b>400</b> and display lighting and input element <b>402</b> comprising one or more light emitting diodes (LEDs), liquid crystal displays, or the like, as well as input sensors such as capacitive or pressure-sensitive switches. The display <b>104</b> is connected to the housing <b>102</b> at an upper housing end <b>404</b>. The housing <b>102</b> extends, along the longitudinal axis <b>112</b>, from the upper housing end <b>404</b> to a lower housing end <b>406</b>. Electrical controls, such as a printed circuit board (PCB) <b>408</b> are located inside the housing <b>102</b>. The electrical controls may comprise any suitable controller operatively connected to the other electrical components to operate the display <b>104</b>, the motor <b>428</b>, the heating element <b>202</b>, and so on.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">A bulkhead <b>410</b> is attached the housing <b>102</b> at the lower housing end <b>406</b>. The bulkhead <b>410</b> extends along the longitudinal axis <b>112</b> from an upper bulkhead end <b>412</b> to a lower bulkhead end <b>414</b>. The bulkhead <b>410</b> may be shaped such that the upper bulkhead end <b>412</b> extends upwards beyond the lower housing end <b>406</b> to be located inside the housing <b>102</b> (as shown), outside the housing <b>102</b>, or both. The upper bulkhead end <b>412</b> also may be flush with the lower housing end <b>406</b>. The lower bulkhead end <b>414</b> extends below the housing <b>102</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">A heat sink <b>416</b> is provided with an upper heat sink end <b>418</b> abutting the bulkhead <b>410</b> and a lower heat sink end <b>420</b> extending along the longitudinal axis <b>112</b> below the bulkhead <b>410</b>. The heat sink <b>416</b> preferably comprises a metal material having a high thermal conductivity, such as aluminum. The heat sink <b>416</b> also preferably is a monolithic piece of aluminum (i.e., formed from one single aluminum billet or casting), but this is not strictly required&#x2014;for example, the heat sink <b>416</b> may comprise two halves that are joined together by fasteners or interlocking shapes. The heat sink <b>416</b> may include one or more ribs or vanes to promote convection flows to enhance heat dissipation, but this is not required.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The skirt <b>106</b> extends from an upper skirt end <b>422</b> to a lower skirt end <b>424</b>. The upper skirt end <b>422</b> is attached to the bulkhead <b>410</b>, but alternatively may be attached to the housing <b>102</b> or the heat sink <b>416</b>. The lower skirt end <b>418</b> is located below the heating element <b>202</b>, and may be closed by a cover that is formed integrally with or attached to the remainder of the skirt <b>106</b>, or it may be open or have holes to allow liquid to pass therethrough.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">One or more electrical wires <b>426</b> are provided to connect the heating element <b>202</b>, water level sensors <b>210</b> and temperature sensor <b>212</b> to the PCB <b>408</b> and other electronic components located inside the housing <b>102</b>. Electrical wires <b>426</b> also connect to the impeller drive motor <b>428</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Other components, such as a motor mounting plate <b>430</b>, may be provided within the cooker <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>5</b>A-<b>5</b>C</figref> show the cooker <b>100</b> in cross section. Here, it is seen that the bulkhead <b>410</b> closes the lower housing end <b>406</b> to form a first cavity <b>500</b> between the bulkhead <b>410</b> and the housing <b>102</b>. The display <b>104</b> also may form part of the first cavity <b>500</b>, such as by forming a closure at the upper housing end <b>404</b>. The PCB <b>408</b> is located within the first cavity <b>500</b>. <b>0</b>-ring seals <b>502</b>, or other seals may be provided between the bulkhead <b>410</b> and the housing <b>102</b> to make the first cavity <b>500</b> fluid-resistant. To assure that the bulkhead <b>410</b> and housing <b>102</b> are properly connected during assembly the bulkhead <b>410</b> may include a circumferential rib <b>504</b> or similar stop structure, against which the lower housing end <b>406</b> sits when the parts are fully-assembled.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">The heat sink <b>416</b> is attached to the bulkhead <b>410</b> to form a second cavity <b>506</b>. The second cavity <b>506</b> may be formed, at least in part, by a sidewall <b>510</b> that forms a recess in the heat sink <b>416</b>. The recess extends from the upper heat sink end <b>418</b> towards the lower heat sink end <b>420</b>, and may have any suitable shape. For example, the recess may comprise a cylindrical inner wall (i.e., mostly or entirely cylindrical), which may be shaped to engage a similarly-shaped outer surface of the lower bulkhead end <b>414</b>. A seal, such as an O-ring seal <b>512</b> may be provided to make the second cavity <b>506</b> fluid-resistant at the junction of the bulkhead <b>410</b> and the heat sink <b>416</b>. In a preferred embodiment, the second cavity <b>506</b> is fluid impervious in satisfaction of the IPx7 level of water resistance, which requires that ingress of water in a harmful quantity (e.g., sufficient to cause an electrical hazard to a user or to cause the device to short circuit) is not possible when the enclosure is immersed in water under for 30 minutes with the lowest point of the enclosure at 1 meter below the water surface or the highest point of the enclosure at 150 mm below the water surface (whichever is deeper). It is also preferable that the first cavity <b>500</b> satisfies the IPx7 level of water resistance.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">In this example, the motor <b>428</b> is located in the second cavity <b>506</b>, and captured between an internal bulkhead wall <b>508</b> and the motor mounting plate <b>430</b>. In other examples, the motor <b>428</b> may be located in the first cavity <b>500</b>, or may be secured by alternative structures. The second cavity <b>506</b> may be sealed against the first cavity <b>500</b>, or it may have one or more openings passing to the first cavity <b>500</b>. For example, one or more openings may extend through the internal bulkhead wall <b>508</b> to permit the passage of electrical wires <b>426</b> or the like between the first cavity <b>500</b> and the second cavity <b>506</b>. Such openings may be sealed around the wires <b>426</b> if an air- or fluid-resistant seal is desired.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The drive shaft <b>208</b> extends from the motor <b>428</b> and passes through the lower heat sink end <b>420</b>. The heat sink <b>416</b> may include a bearing <b>514</b> to surround the drive shaft <b>208</b> and support it in the lateral direction (i.e., the direction perpendicular to the longitudinal axis <b>112</b>). The heat sink <b>416</b> also may include a shaft seal <b>516</b> to surround the drive shaft <b>208</b> and provide a fluid-resistant seal between the drive shaft <b>208</b> and the heat sink <b>416</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">As noted above, the skirt <b>106</b> may be attached at the upper skirt end <b>422</b> to the bulkhead <b>410</b>. For example, the skirt <b>106</b> may surround the outer surface of the bulkhead <b>410</b> and abut a lower side of the circumferential rib <b>504</b> to provide a positive stop during assembly. The lower housing end <b>406</b>, circumferential rib <b>504</b> and upper skirt end <b>422</b> may form a continuous wall profile along a predetermined distance along the longitudinal axis <b>112</b>, to allow the clamp <b>200</b> to slide vertically up and down across the connection between the parts. The skirt <b>106</b> may be connected to the bulkhead <b>410</b> using any suitable reversible or irreversible fastening mechanism, such as screws, rivets, adhesives, and so on. In the shown example the skirt <b>106</b> is attached to the bulkhead <b>410</b> by so-called bayonet connectors. The bayonet connectors comprise one or more pins <b>432</b> that extend radially-inward from the skirt <b>106</b> to engage corresponding slots <b>434</b> formed in the outer surface of the bulkhead <b>410</b>. The slots <b>434</b> extend from the lower bulkhead end <b>414</b> towards the upper bulkhead end <b>412</b>, preferably along the longitudinal axis <b>112</b>, and then turn to extend circumferentially around the central axis of the bulkhead <b>410</b>. The skirt <b>106</b> is secured to the bulkhead <b>410</b> by sliding the pins <b>432</b> axially and then circumferentially along the slots <b>434</b>. The ends of the slots <b>434</b> may include recesses into which the pins <b>432</b> snap fit to resiliently hold the pins <b>432</b> in place.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">The heat sink <b>416</b> may be recessed to allow also the pins <b>432</b> to be moved into the slots <b>434</b>. For example, the entire outer surface of the heat sink <b>416</b> may be narrow enough to pass between the pins <b>432</b>. As another example, the heat sink <b>416</b> may comprise slots <b>436</b> that extend from the lower heat sink end <b>420</b> to the upper heat sink end <b>418</b> and are shaped to guide the pins <b>432</b> to the slots <b>434</b> on the bulkhead <b>410</b>. The use of slots <b>436</b> on the heat sink <b>416</b> is expected to allow the heat sink <b>416</b> to be as large as possible in the radial direction, which can help increase its heat dissipation capacity. The outer wall of the heat sink <b>416</b> also may help support the skirt <b>106</b> if it is in direct or indirect contact with the skirt <b>106</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">Alternatively, the skirt <b>106</b> may be connected to heat sink <b>416</b> by one or more fastening mechanisms, such as those discussed above.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">A portion of the skirt <b>106</b> at the upper skirt end <b>422</b> surrounds some or all of the heat sink <b>416</b> in the lateral direction. An air gap <b>520</b> may be provided between the skirt <b>106</b> and the heat sink <b>416</b> to prevent or reduce direct physical contact therebetween. The skirt <b>106</b> also may be spaced from the heat sink <b>416</b> by an insulating sleeve <b>522</b> or other structure (e.g. high-temperature plastic or the like). The use of air gaps <b>520</b> and insulating sleeves <b>522</b> (or combinations thereof) is expected to provide greater thermal isolation between the skirt <b>106</b> and the heat sink <b>416</b>, to help maintain the skirt <b>106</b> at a temperature more suitable for contact by an operator. However, in alternative embodiment, the skirt <b>106</b> and heat sink <b>416</b> may contact one another directly or through a heat transfer medium to provide improve heat dissipation from the heat sink <b>416</b>. The choice of using an air gap <b>520</b> or insulating sleeve <b>522</b>, or alternatively using direct conductive contact, will be a matter of design choice based on considerations such as reducing the temperature to which a user might be exposed, and improving heat dissipation.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The lower skirt end <b>424</b> is located below the lower heat sink end <b>420</b> to form a third cavity <b>518</b> between the skirt <b>106</b> and the heat sink <b>416</b>. The heating element <b>202</b> is located in the third cavity <b>518</b>. The heating element <b>202</b> may be rigidly mounted to the heat sink <b>416</b> to hold the heating element <b>202</b> at the desired location within the third cavity <b>518</b>. For example, the upper end of the heating element <b>202</b> may be threaded, press-fit or adhesively bonded into a corresponding bore <b>524</b> through the lower heat sink end <b>420</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Also located in the third cavity <b>518</b> are the impeller <b>204</b> and a portion of the drive shaft <b>208</b> that operatively connects the motor <b>428</b> to the impeller <b>204</b>. The impeller <b>204</b> may be located at any suitable position to interact with the cooking liquid. In the shown embodiment, the impeller <b>204</b> is located between the lower skirt end <b>424</b> and the heating element <b>202</b>, and adjacent an outlet opening <b>110</b>. When the motor <b>428</b> is operated, it rotates the impeller <b>204</b> via the drive shaft <b>208</b>, and the impeller <b>204</b> thereby draws liquid into the inlet openings <b>108</b>, down past the heating element coils <b>206</b>, and out through the outlet opening <b>110</b>. Other embodiments may use other configurations for the various parts, such as an arrangement in which the liquid is passed upwards past the coils <b>206</b> or the like. Other alternatives and variations will be apparent to persons of ordinary skill in the art in view of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">The water level sensor(s) <b>210</b> and temperature sensor(s) <b>212</b> are also located in the third cavity <b>518</b>. As with the heating element <b>202</b>, the water level sensor(s) <b>210</b> and temperature sensor(s) <b>212</b> may be rigidly secured to the heat sink <b>416</b> to ensure their proper positioning within the third cavity <b>518</b>. To this end, the heat sink <b>416</b> may include additional bores to receive the upper ends of the sensors <b>210</b>, <b>212</b>, which may be secured by any suitable configuration of parts or type of connection. In some cases, it may be necessary to insulate one or more of the sensors <b>210</b>, <b>212</b> from electrically-conductive contact with other components via the metal heat sink <b>516</b>. In such cases, each potentially-affected sensor <b>210</b>, <b>212</b> may be connected to the heat sink <b>516</b> through a rigid insulators <b>526</b>, such as a nylon ring or the like. It also may be desirable to provide insulation to prevent inadvertent electrical contact between the sensors or other components by condensed steam or splashed water that might accumulate at the lower heat sink end <b>420</b>. To this end, a seal of insulating material <b>528</b> (e.g., rubber or the like) may the portion of the lower heat sink end <b>420</b> surrounding the potentially-affected sensors <b>210</b>, <b>212</b>. In the shown example, the insulating material <b>528</b> comprises a first portion <b>530</b> that lies against the heat sink <b>416</b>, and one or more additional portions <b>532</b> that extend downward along respective sensors <b>210</b>, <b>212</b>. The downward-extending portions <b>532</b> provide an additional measure of assurance that water will not create a potentially-harmful electrical path between the electrical components.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>5</b>B, <b>6</b> and <b>7</b></figref>, the purpose of the heat sink <b>416</b> and features of an exemplary heat sink structure are described in more detail. The heat sink <b>416</b> is provided to dissipate heat generated by electrical components, such as a TRIAC <b>438</b>. TRIACs are well-known devices, and are sometimes referred to as a bidirectional triode thyristor, bilateral triode thyristor, or the like. In general terms, a TRIAC is used as a switching device to control the output of power provided by a cyclical power source, such as a rectified or unrectified AC power supply. The details of TRIACs are known in the art and need not be described in detail herein.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">While TRIACs are in common use in various devices, they are known to generate a significant a significant amount of heat during use. For example, a TRIAC operating a 1200 watt heating element can generate its own heat load of about 9 watts (i.e., 9 joules of heat per second). Such heat loading is typically addressed by providing air ventilation to cool the TRIAC. However, in the context of a sealed appliance such as a modern sous vide cooker (early sous vide cookers typically were not water-tight), ventilated air cooling within the housing containing the TRIAC is not possible. It is also not feasible to simply move the TRIAC to a located where it is cooled by ambient air, because doing so would compromise the fluid-tight nature of the appliance. Still another problem can arise if the TRIAC is cooled by conductive heating to ambient air, such as by attaching the TRIAC to a heat sink located on the outer surface of the device, which is that the heat sink can attain temperatures that might be unacceptable to expose to the user of the device.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">To address these problems, the TRIAC <b>438</b> and heat sink <b>416</b> may be contained within the cooker <b>100</b>, where direct contact with the user is difficult or impossible. In addition, the TRIAC <b>438</b> preferably is sealed within the cooker against contact with liquid in the cooking bath, or water that might passed over the cooker <b>100</b> during cleaning the cooker <b>100</b> or filling the cooking bath.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">In the shown example, the heat sink <b>416</b> is contained within the skirt <b>106</b>, and has a sidewall <b>510</b> that forms a recess, such as described above. The sidewall <b>510</b> extends from the upper heat sink end <b>418</b> towards the lower heat sink end <b>420</b>, and terminates at a bottom wall <b>534</b> at the lower end of the sidewall <b>510</b>. The TRIAC <b>438</b> is physically attached, such as by a screw <b>440</b>, in conductive thermal communication with the heat sink <b>416</b> within the second cavity <b>506</b>. In the shown example, the TRIAC <b>438</b> is attached to the sidewall <b>510</b>, but alternatively it may be attached to the bottom wall <b>534</b> or other surfaces of the heat sink <b>416</b>. The TRIAC <b>438</b> may be attached directly against the heat sink <b>416</b> surface, or by a heat-conducting material such as a layer of thermal grease <b>600</b> or the like to provide a more uniform or distributed conduction heat path. Such conductive thermal communication provides a direct flow of heat from the TRIAC <b>428</b> to the heat sink <b>416</b>, but convective and radiation heat transfer from the TRIAC <b>438</b> to the heat sink <b>416</b> may also occur to some degree.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">The TRIAC <b>438</b> is operatively connected to the PCB <b>408</b> by wires <b>426</b>. In use, the PCB <b>408</b> controls the TRIAC <b>438</b>, motor <b>428</b> and heater <b>202</b> to heat and circulate liquid in the cooking bath, using input from the sensors <b>210</b>, <b>212</b> as feedback to evaluate the temperature and water level of the liquid. For example, the motor rotation speed and/or heater power output may be adjusted based on water level and/or temperature determinations, and the PCB <b>408</b> can display output on the display <b>104</b> and/or send signals wirelessly to a remote control (e.g., a smartphone operating an app) to provide instructions to add water, unplug or turn off the device, and so on. Such operations are known in the art and need not be described in detail herein.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">The temperature of the heat sink <b>416</b> and/or TRIAC <b>438</b> may be monitored by one or more temperature sensors. For example, an axial bore <b>700</b> may be provided in the heat sink <b>416</b> adjacent the TRIAC mounting location, and a temperature sensor <b>602</b> such as a thermocouple or the like may be secured in the bore by adhesives or a fastener. Such temperature monitoring at the location of the TRIAC <b>438</b> is expected to allow rapid evaluation of potential overheating situations. When an overheat is detected, a signal may be transmitted to terminate power, and, if the overheat is great enough, a message may be conveyed to the operator to refrain from handling the cooker <b>100</b> until the elevated temperature situation has subsided.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">As noted above, the heat sink <b>416</b> may include ribs or other structures to increase its surface are or to encourage convection cooling flows. However, it has been found that a heat sink <b>416</b> having a simply cylindrical shape can be sufficient to dissipate heat from the TRIAC <b>438</b> without unduly heating the skirt <b>106</b> or housing <b>102</b> to a temperature that might be unsuitable for contact by the user. In the shown example, the heat dissipating capacity of the heat sink <b>416</b> may be increased by extending the outer cylindrical wall downwards below the bottom wall <b>532</b> of the second cavity <b>506</b>, such as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>5</b>A-<b>5</b>C</figref>. In this way, heat may be conducted over a larger area to be further dissipated to the skirt <b>106</b> and surrounding air in the second and third cavities <b>506</b>, <b>518</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">The cylindrical shape of the sidewall <b>510</b> also may be helpful to locate the TRIAC <b>438</b> relatively far, in the lateral direction, from the motor <b>428</b> and other operating parts, and to maximize the volume of air within the heat sink recess to insulate the other components from heat generated by the TRIAC <b>428</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">The foregoing embodiment of a cooker <b>100</b> has a generally cylindrical outer shape, with the skirt <b>106</b> being cylindrical along most of its length, and the housing <b>102</b> being cylindrical along about half of its length. This shape allows the clamp <b>200</b> to slide up and down to position the skirt <b>106</b> at different locations within the liquid cooking bath, and allows the clamp <b>200</b> to rotate to orient the inlets <b>108</b> and outlets <b>110</b> into different orientations to direct the water flow in the container. Other embodiments may have other outer shapes. For example, the skirt <b>106</b> and/or housing <b>102</b> may have an oval, square or polyhedral profile. In such cases, the heat sink <b>416</b> optionally may be reconfigured to match the shape of the third cavity <b>518</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">It will be appreciated that the TRIAC <b>438</b> may be replaced with other electrical devices that generate a high thermal load while switching power, such as a metal-oxide-semiconductor field-effect transistor (MOSFET), insulated-gate bipolar transistor (IGBT), or the like, or with other electrical devices that generate a high thermal load while performing other functions (e.g., resistors or the like).</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>8</b>-<b>11</b></figref> show an alternative embodiment of a cooker <b>100</b>. In this case, the cooker <b>100</b> has many of the same features as the previous embodiment, including a housing <b>102</b>, skirt <b>106</b> and so on. For simplicity, the Figures are annotated to indicate similar features, and other similar features will be readily apparent from the illustrations. In this case, the bulkhead <b>410</b> is once again mounted to the lower housing end <b>406</b> to form a first cavity <b>500</b>, however, the motor <b>428</b> is positioned within the first cavity <b>500</b> with a lower end of the motor <b>428</b> being cradled in a motor mounting plate <b>430</b> and the upper end of the motor <b>428</b> being held by a motor cover <b>800</b>. The PCB <b>408</b> is located in the first cavity <b>500</b> adjacent to (and optionally attached to) the motor cover <b>800</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">The skirt <b>106</b> is removably attached to the bulkhead <b>410</b> by a bayonet fitting. In this case, the bayonet fitting slots <b>434</b> terminate at a cantilevered end to provide a snap engagement with the pins of the skirt <b>106</b>. The cantilevered end is formed by making a U-shaped slot <b>802</b> in the portion of the bulkhead <b>410</b> surround in the end of the slot <b>434</b>. The skirt <b>106</b> forms a second cavity <b>900</b> below the lower bulkhead end <b>414</b>. The heating element <b>202</b> and sensors <b>210</b>, <b>212</b> are attached to a mounting plate <b>804</b> to extend from the lower bulkhead end <b>414</b> into the second cavity <b>900</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">In this example, the heat sink <b>416</b> is located in the first cavity <b>500</b>, which preferably is sealed sufficiently to satisfy the IPx7 level of water resistance. Specifically, the heat sink <b>416</b> comprises a ring-shaped metal structure located inside the housing <b>102</b> at a location where it surrounds various components, such as the upper end of the motor <b>428</b> and the lower end of the PCB <b>408</b>. It is preferred for the heat sink <b>416</b> to extend entirely around as a complete ring, but this is not required. For example, the heat sink <b>416</b> may be a partial ring. The ring-shaped heat sink <b>416</b> preferably is positioned laterally outside the perimeter of the motor <b>428</b> and/or PCB <b>408</b>, and may be directly adjacent to an inner wall of the housing <b>102</b> so as to maximize the size of the heat sink <b>416</b> within the housing <b>102</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">As with the previous embodiment, the TRIAC <b>438</b> is mounted in direct conductive contact with the heat sink <b>416</b> (directly or via thermal grease or other heat distributing material or layer). In this example, the TRIAC is also connected directly and rigidly to the PCB <b>408</b>, such as by being soldered in place, rather than being connected remotely to the PCB <b>408</b> by wires <b>426</b>. This configuration provides a more compact arrangement of parts, while still providing sufficient heat dissipating capacity of the heat sink <b>416</b> to allow the use of a TRIAC <b>438</b> inside a sealed chamber formed by the housing <b>102</b> and bulkhead <b>410</b>. This configuration is also expected to simplify assembly in some instances.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">The present disclosure describes a number of inventive features and/or combinations of features that may be used alone or in combination with each other or in combination with other technologies. The embodiments described herein are all exemplary, and are not intended to limit the scope of the claims. It will also be appreciated that the inventions described herein can be modified and adapted in various ways, and all such modifications and adaptations are intended to be included in the scope of this disclosure and the appended claims.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A sous vide cooker comprising:
<claim-text>a housing extending along an longitudinal axis from an upper housing end to a lower housing end and comprising at least one display;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a bulkhead secured at the lower housing end and extending along the longitudinal axis from an upper bulkhead end to a lower bulkhead end, the bulkhead and housing forming a first cavity therebetween;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a skirt extending along the longitudinal axis from an upper skirt end to a lower skirt end located below the lower bulkhead end to form a second cavity between the skirt and the bulkhead, the skirt having one or more inlet openings and one or more outlet openings located below the lower bulkhead end;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an impeller located in the second cavity;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a motor operatively connected to the impeller;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a heating element located within the second cavity;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a metal heat sink located in the first cavity; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a TRIAC physically attached in conductive thermal communication to the heat sink in the first cavity.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The sous vide cooker of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the heat sink comprises a monolithic piece of aluminum.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The sous vide cooker of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the heat sink comprises a ring shape.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The sous vide cooker of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the TRIAC is attached to the heat sink by a layer of thermal grease.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The sous vide cooker of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a printed circuit board in the first cavity.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The sous vide cooker of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the TRIAC is connected directly to the printed circuit board.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The sous vide cooker of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the TRIAC is soldered to the printed circuit board and secured to the heat sink by a fastener.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The sous vide cooker of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the motor is located in the first cavity and connected to the impeller by a drive shaft extending through the bulkhead.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The sous vide cooker of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the heat sink surrounds at least a portion of the motor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The sous vide cooker of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, further comprising a motor cover located in the first cavity between the motor and the upper housing end.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The sous vide cooker of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, further comprising a printed circuit board located in the first cavity between the motor cover and the upper housing end.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The sous vide cooker of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the skirt and bulkhead collectively comprise a bayonet fitting configured to selectively hold the skirt to the bulkhead.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. The sous vide cooker of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the bayonet fitting comprises one or more connector pins extending inward from the skirt towards the bulkhead, and one or more connector slots in the bulkhead configured to receive the one or more connector pins in an axial direction and a circumferential direction to secure the skirt to the bulkhead.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The sous vide cooker of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the one or more connector slots each comprise a respective cantilevered end configured to snap engage with a respective connector pin.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. The sous vide cooker of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the heating element comprises a coil surrounding the drive shaft.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. The sous vide cooker of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, further comprising a water level sensor located in the second cavity and between the coil and the bulkhead.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. The sous vide cooker of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, further comprising a temperature sensor located in the second cavity and within a volume defined by the coil.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. The sous vide cooker of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein at least a portion of the heating element is located along the longitudinal axis between the one or more inlet openings and the one or more outlet openings, and the impeller is located between the heating element and the lower skirt end.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. The sous vide cooker of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first cavity is sealed to satisfy IPx7 water resistance standards.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. The sous vide cooker of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a clamp connected directly to an outer surface of the bulkhead, the clamp comprising an arm extending away from the outer surface of the bulkhead, and a screw extending from the arm towards the outer surface of the bulkhead.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
