<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225564A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225564</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18081908</doc-number>
<date>20221215</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>202210054112.X</doc-number>
<date>20220118</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>43</main-group>
<subgroup>08</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>43</main-group>
<subgroup>08</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e61">FOOD GRINDER</invention-title>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Tsann Kuen (Zhangzhou) Enterprise Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<address>
<city>Zhangzhou</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>ZHANG</last-name>
<first-name>Wenxia</first-name>
<address>
<city>Zhangzhou</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="01" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>CHEN</last-name>
<first-name>Mingli</first-name>
<address>
<city>Zhangzhou</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Tsann Kuen (Zhangzhou) Enterprise Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Zhangzhou</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A food grinder includes a grip mechanism having a flip cover body pivotally connected to a handle body, a cylindrical cutter set detachably mounted in the handle body, and a driving mechanism mounted in the grip mechanism. The grip mechanism includes first and second switch units electrically connected in series between a driving unit and a power supply unit. When the first switch unit is manually actuated to turn on while the second switch unit is actuated to turn on by the flip cover body as the flip cover body pivots toward a closing position, the driving unit operates with electric power supplied from the power supply unit to drive rotation of a cylindrical cutter of the cylindrical cutter set disposed in the handle body, such that a food ingredient in an inlet in the handle body is cut and grinded by the rotating cylindrical cutter.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="109.39mm" wi="158.75mm" file="US20230225564A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="193.46mm" wi="119.63mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225564A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="173.40mm" wi="127.85mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225564A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="199.98mm" wi="138.35mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225564A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="226.99mm" wi="140.12mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225564A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="193.21mm" wi="156.38mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225564A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="208.28mm" wi="90.09mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225564A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="109.98mm" wi="137.08mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225564A1-20230720-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="196.68mm" wi="129.12mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230225564A1-20230720-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims priority to Chinese Patent Application No. 202210054112.X, filed on Jan. 18, 2022.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The disclosure relates to a food processing apparatus, more particularly to a food grinder capable of grinding and cutting food ingredients.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">In order to produce cheese shreds from a block of cheese for convenience of use, an electric cheese grinder (or grater) has been developed, and generally includes a handle, a pressing plate pivoted to the handle, and a cylindrical cutter set disposed in the handle. After the block of cheese to be cut is placed into an inlet of the handle, the pressing plate is pivoted to move toward the handle, so that the block of cheese in the inlet is pressed against the cylindrical cutter set. When the electric cheese grinder is activated, the cylindrical cutter set is driven to rotate to cut and grind the block of cheese.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Although the electric cheese grinder is quite convenient to use, there are safety concerns with such electric cheese grinder. Since the cylindrical cutter set is driven to rotate after the power switch is turned on, if the pressing plate is pivoted to move away from the inlet, the block of cheese remaining in the inlet will be thrown out of the cylindrical cutter set and stain the surrounding environment or hurt someone, and the rotating cylindrical cutter set exposed through the inlet will also easily injure the user when the user accidentally touches it.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Therefore, an object of the disclosure is to provide a food grinder that can alleviate at least one of the drawbacks of the prior art.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">According to the disclosure, a food grinder is adapted for grinding and cutting a food ingredient, and includes a grip mechanism, a cylindrical cutter set, and a driving mechanism.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The grip mechanism includes a handle body that is formed with an inlet for receiving the food ingredient therein, and a flip cover body that is pivotally connected to the handle body in a manner that the flip cover body is pivotable relative to the handle body between a closing position and an open position. The flip cover body moving toward the closing position is capable of pushing the food ingredient into the inlet opening.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The cylindrical cutter set is detachably mounted in the handle body, and includes a cylindrical cutter that is rotatable to cut and grind the food ingredient in the inlet opening.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The driving mechanism is mounted in the grip mechanism, and includes a driving unit that is configured to drive rotation of the cylindrical cutter, a power supply unit, and first and second switch units that are electrically connected in series between the driving unit and the power supply unit and that are exposed outwardly of the handle body of the grip mechanism. The second switch unit is actuated to turn on by the flip cover body as the flip cover body pivots from the open position toward the closing position. The driving unit operates with electric power supplied from the power supply unit when the first and second switch units are turned on.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Other features and advantages of the disclosure will become apparent in the following detailed description of an embodiment with reference to the accompanying drawings. It is noted that various features may not be drawn to scale.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a perspective view of the embodiment of a food grinder according to the disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a partially exploded perspective view of the embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is an exploded perspective view of the embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is a schematic sectional view illustrating the embodiment when a flip cover body is in a closing position.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is a schematic sectional view illustrating the embodiment when the flip cover body is in an open position.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is an electrical block diagram of the embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> is a fragmentary schematic sectional view illustrating a cylindrical cutter of the embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> is a schematic sectional view schematically illustrating the embodiment in use.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Before the disclosure is described in greater detail, it should be noted that where considered appropriate, reference numerals or terminal portions of reference numerals have been repeated among the figures to indicate corresponding or analogous elements, which may optionally have similar characteristics.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> and <b>8</b></figref>, the embodiment of a food grinder <b>200</b> of the disclosure is adapted for cutting and grinding of a food ingredient, such as nuts, chocolate, cheese, etc. In the embodiment, the food is exemplarily a block of cheese <b>900</b>, and the food grinder <b>200</b> is exemplarily used to produce cheese shreds or cheese crumbs <b>901</b> from the block of cheese <b>900</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref>. The food grinder <b>200</b> includes a grip mechanism <b>3</b> for a user to hold, a cylindrical cutter set <b>4</b> detachably mounted in the grip mechanism <b>3</b>, and a driving mechanism <b>5</b> mounted to the grip mechanism <b>3</b>. For convenience of illustration, the left and right sides of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> are regarded as the front and rear of the food grinder <b>200</b>, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> to <b>5</b></figref>, the grip mechanism <b>3</b> includes a handle body <b>31</b>, an elongate flip cover body <b>32</b> located above the handle body <b>31</b>, and a lateral cover body <b>33</b> mounted removably to a lateral side (e.g., left side) of the handle body <b>31</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The handle body <b>31</b> has a mounting seat portion <b>311</b>, and an elongate handle portion <b>315</b> extending rearwardly from the mounting seat portion <b>311</b>. The mounting seat portion <b>311</b> is formed with an interior mounting space <b>312</b> for receiving the cylindrical cutter set <b>4</b> therein, an inlet <b>313</b> in the top thereof (i.e., an upper opening), and a mounting opening <b>314</b> in the lateral (e.g., left) side thereof. The interior mounting space <b>312</b>, the inlet <b>313</b> and the mounting opening <b>314</b> are communicated with each other. The inlet <b>313</b> allows the block of cheese <b>900</b> to be fed into the interior mounting space <b>312</b>. A pivot shaft <b>30</b>, which is provided on a rear end of the handle portion <b>315</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>), serves as a pivot for the flip cover body <b>32</b> to pivot relative to the handle body <b>31</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The lateral cover body <b>33</b> has an opening <b>331</b> communicated with the mounting opening <b>314</b> in the mounting seat portion <b>311</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The flip cover body <b>32</b> is pivotally connected to the handle portion <b>315</b> of the handle body <b>31</b> in a manner that the flip cover body <b>32</b> is pivotable relative to the handle portion <b>315</b> of the handle body <b>31</b> between a closing position (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>) and an open position (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>). In this embodiment, the flip cover body <b>32</b> has an elongate operating handle portion <b>321</b> having a rear end (distal from the mounting seat portion <b>311</b> of the handle body <b>31</b>) that is pivoted on the pivot shaft <b>30</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>), a pressing protrusion <b>322</b> downwardly extending from a front end of the operating handle portion <b>321</b> toward the mounting seat portion <b>311</b>, and a pushing portion <b>323</b> extending from the rear end of the operating handle portion <b>321</b> toward the rear end of the handle portion <b>315</b> of the handle body <b>31</b>. As the flip cover body <b>32</b> is pivoted from the open position toward the closing position, the flip cover body <b>32</b> is capable of pushing the block of cheese <b>900</b> into the inlet <b>313</b>, and more specifically, the operating handle portion <b>321</b> moves toward the handle body <b>31</b> such that the pressing protrusion <b>322</b> presses the block of cheese <b>900</b> to abut against the cylindrical cutter set <b>4</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref>), at which time the flip cover body <b>32</b> is said to be in a &#x201c;pressing state.&#x201d; When the pressing protrusion <b>322</b> is fully inserted into the inlet <b>313</b> and the operating handle portion <b>321</b> abuts against the handle body <b>31</b>, the flip cover body <b>32</b> is in the closing position (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>). Conversely, when the flip cover body <b>32</b> is pivoted (from the closing position) to the open position, the operating handle portion <b>321</b>, along with the pressing protrusion <b>322</b>, moves away from the handle body <b>31</b>. Furthermore, when the flip cover plate <b>32</b> is pivoted, the operating handle portion <b>321</b> rotates along with the pushing portion <b>323</b>. The function of the pushing portion <b>323</b> will be explained below.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>, <b>3</b>, <b>4</b>, and <b>7</b></figref>, the cylindrical cutter set <b>4</b> is disposed in the mounting seat portion <b>311</b> of the handle body <b>31</b>, and includes a cutter mounting seat <b>41</b>, a cylindrical cutter <b>42</b> and a cutter cap <b>43</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The cutter mounting seat <b>41</b> is detachably mounted in the interior mounting space <b>312</b> in the mounting seat portion <b>311</b>. Specifically, the cutter mounting seat <b>41</b> is mounted into the interior mounting space <b>312</b> through the mounting opening <b>314</b> in the mounting seat portion <b>311</b>, and can be removed from the interior mounting space <b>312</b> through the mounting opening <b>314</b>. In this embodiment, the cutter mounting seat <b>41</b> includes a laterally extending mounting tube portion <b>411</b>, and a feeding tube portion <b>412</b> upwardly extending from the mounting tube portion <b>411</b> and communicated with the mounting tube portion <b>411</b> and the inlet <b>313</b>. It is noted that the feeding tube portion <b>412</b> is downwardly tapered such that the block of cheese <b>900</b> in the inlet <b>313</b> can be guided by the feeding tube portion <b>412</b> into the mounting tube portion <b>411</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The cylindrical cutter <b>42</b> is detachably mounted in the mounting tube portion <b>411</b> of the cutter mounting seat <b>41</b>, and is detachably connected to and driven by a transmission module <b>511</b> of a driving unit <b>51</b> of the driving mechanism <b>5</b> disposed in the mounting space <b>312</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>) to rotate in the mounting tube portion <b>411</b> such that the block of cheese <b>900</b> guided into the mounting tube portion <b>411</b> can be cut and grinded by the rotating cylindrical cutter <b>42</b>. In this embodiment, the cylindrical cutter <b>42</b> has a hollow cylindrical body <b>421</b> that is formed with a plurality of outwardly projecting and spaced-apart blade parts <b>425</b> and a plurality of through holes <b>423</b> that respectively correspond to the blade parts <b>425</b>. The blade parts <b>425</b> and the through holes <b>423</b> can be simultaneously formed by punching. The hollow cylindrical body <b>421</b> has a connecting end portion <b>424</b> coaxially and detachably mounted on the transmission module <b>511</b>, and an outlet <b>422</b> opposite to the connecting end portion <b>424</b> and communicated with the mounting opening <b>314</b> of the mounting seat portion <b>311</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The cutter cap <b>43</b> openably closes the outlet <b>422</b> of the hollow cylindrical body <b>421</b>, and can be removed through the opening <b>331</b> in the lateral cover body <b>33</b> when the lateral cover body <b>33</b> is mounted to the handle body <b>31</b>, the cutter mounting seat <b>41</b> is mounted in the interior mounting space <b>312</b> in the mounting seat portion <b>311</b> and the cylindrical cutter <b>42</b> is mounted in the mounting tube portion <b>411</b> of the cutter mounting seat <b>41</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b> to <b>6</b> and <b>8</b></figref>, the driving mechanism <b>5</b> is mounted in the handle body <b>31</b>, and includes the driving unit <b>51</b>, which includes the transmission module <b>511</b>, a power supply unit <b>52</b>, a first switch unit <b>53</b>, and a second switch unit <b>54</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The driving unit <b>51</b> is configured to drive rotation of the cylindrical cutter <b>42</b> with the transmission module <b>511</b>, and is in the form of a motor and transmission assembly. Since the driving unit <b>51</b> is well-known and comes in a variety of modular types and structures, details thereof are not further described.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The power supply unit <b>52</b> is electrically connected to the driving unit <b>51</b>, and is configured to supply electric power for operation of the driving unit <b>51</b>, and includes a power source <b>522</b>, such as a rechargeable or non-rechargeable battery module, that supplies the electric power, and a power switch <b>521</b> that is electrically connected to the power source <b>522</b> and exposed from the bottom of the handle portion <b>315</b>. When the power switch <b>521</b> is turned on, the power supply unit <b>52</b> outputs the electric power supplied from the power source <b>522</b>. However, in other embodiments, the power source <b>522</b> may be an external power source, such as a commercial power source, that can be used with an adapter to supply the electric power for the driving unit <b>51</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The first and second switch units <b>53</b>, <b>54</b> are electrically connected in series between the power supply unit <b>52</b> and the driving unit <b>51</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>), and are exposed outwardly of the handle body <b>31</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>). The first switch unit <b>53</b> can be manually actuated to turn on, and the second switch unit <b>54</b> can be actuated to turn on by the flip cover body <b>32</b> when the flip cover body <b>32</b> is transitioning from the open position to the closing position. When the first and second switch units <b>53</b>, <b>54</b> are turned on, the driving unit <b>51</b> operates with the electric power supplied from the power supply unit <b>52</b> (by this time, the power switch <b>521</b> should have been turned on).</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">In this embodiment, the first switch unit <b>53</b> includes a first switch member <b>531</b>, a first actuating member <b>532</b>, and a first biasing member <b>533</b>, such as a coil spring. The first switch member <b>531</b>, such as a micro switch, is disposed in the handle body <b>31</b> and is electrically connected between the driving unit <b>51</b> and the second switch unit <b>54</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>). The first actuating member <b>532</b> is connected pivotally (or movably) to the handle body <b>31</b> and is exposed from the bottom of the handle body <b>31</b>. The first actuating member <b>532</b>, serving as a manually operable actuator, is operable to actuate the first switch member <b>531</b> to an ON-state by applying a pressing force thereto. The first biasing member <b>533</b> is disposed in the handle portion <b>315</b> and abuts against the first actuating member <b>532</b> for biasing the first actuating member <b>532</b> to move away from the first switch member <b>531</b>. When the first actuating member <b>532</b> is pressed to actuate the first switch member <b>531</b> to the ON-state, the first biasing member <b>533</b> deforms and accumulates a biasing force.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">In this embodiment, the second switch unit <b>54</b> includes a second switch member <b>541</b>, a second actuating member <b>542</b> and a second biasing member <b>543</b>. The second switch member <b>541</b>, such as a micro switch, is disposed in the rear end of the handle portion <b>315</b> of the handle body <b>31</b>, and is electrically connected between the first switch member <b>531</b> and the power switch <b>521</b> of the power supply unit <b>52</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>). The second actuating member <b>542</b> is disposed movably in the handle portion <b>315</b>, and extends outwardly of the rear end of the handle portion <b>315</b> to contact the pushing portion <b>323</b> of the flip cover body <b>32</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>). The second actuating member <b>542</b> is operable to actuate the second switch member <b>541</b> to an ON-state by applying a pushing force thereto. The second biasing member <b>543</b>, such as a coil spring, is restricted in the handle portion <b>315</b> and abuts against the second actuating member <b>542</b> for biasing the second actuating member <b>542</b> to move away from the second switch member <b>541</b>. However, in other embodiments, the second switch unit <b>54</b> may also be designed to include one of a photoelectric switch, a mechanical switch and a magnetic sensing switch that is actuated by the flip cover body <b>32</b> as the flip cover body <b>32</b> transitions from the open position to the closing position.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">It is noted that, when the flip cover body <b>32</b> is being pivoted toward the closing position, the operating handle portion <b>321</b> moves toward said handle body <b>31</b> such that the pushing portion <b>323</b> of the flip cover body <b>32</b> moves toward the rear end of the handle portion <b>315</b> and pushes the second actuating member <b>542</b> to actuate the second switch member <b>541</b> to the ON-state (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref>). When the second actuating member <b>542</b> is pushed to actuate the second switch member <b>541</b> to the ON-state, the second biasing member <b>543</b> deforms to accumulate a biasing force.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In use, after the flip cover body <b>32</b> is first pivoted to the open position to expose the inlet <b>313</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>), the block of cheese <b>900</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref>) is put into the inlet <b>313</b> (specifically, the feeding tube portion <b>412</b> at the inlet <b>313</b>), and the power switch <b>521</b> of the power supply unit <b>52</b> is then turned on. At this time, since the second actuating member <b>542</b> of the second switch unit <b>54</b> extends outwardly of the rear end of the handle portion <b>315</b> to the fullest extent, the second switch member <b>541</b> of the second switch unit <b>54</b> is not actuated and remains in an OFF-state. Therefore, even if the first actuating member <b>532</b> of the first switch unit <b>53</b> is accidentally pressed to actuate the first switch member <b>531</b> of the first switch unit <b>53</b> to the ON-state, the driving unit <b>51</b> would not operate since the electric power from the power supply unit <b>52</b> is not supplied thereto, thereby avoiding accidental rotation of the cylindrical cutter <b>42</b>, which would have occurred in the aforesaid prior art. Next, the flip cover body <b>32</b> is pivoted from the open position toward the closing position to be in the pressing state (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref>) where the block of cheese <b>900</b> is pushed downwardly toward the cutter mounting seat <b>41</b> to abut against the cylindrical cutter <b>42</b>. When the first actuating member <b>532</b> of the first switch unit <b>53</b> is pressed by a user's hand holding the handle body <b>31</b> to actuate the first switch member <b>531</b> of the first switch unit <b>53</b> to the ON-state while the second actuating member <b>542</b> of the second switch unit <b>54</b> is pushed by the pushing portion <b>323</b> to actuate the second switch member <b>541</b> of the second switch unit <b>54</b> to the ON-state, the electric power supplied from the power source <b>522</b> is transmitted to the driving unit <b>51</b> via the power switch <b>521</b> and the second and first switch members <b>541</b>, <b>531</b> that are in the ON-state, such that the driving unit <b>51</b> operates with the electric power to drive the cylindrical cutter <b>42</b> to cut and grind the block of cheese <b>900</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">During operation of the driving unit <b>51</b>, cheese shreds/crumbs <b>901</b> cut/grinded from the block of cheese <b>900</b> by the blade parts <b>425</b> of the cylindrical cutter <b>42</b> would fall into the hollow cylindrical body <b>421</b> through the through holes <b>423</b>. It is noted that, during operation of the driving unit <b>51</b>, once the user's hand releases the first actuating member <b>532</b> of the first switch unit <b>53</b>, the first biasing member <b>533</b> would bias the first actuating member <b>532</b> to move away from the first switch member <b>531</b>, and the first switch member <b>531</b> would thus be turned off, i.e., be in an OFF-state, so that operation of the driving unit <b>51</b> would stop due to lack of electric power from the power supply unit <b>52</b> to thereby terminate driving of the cylindrical cutter <b>42</b>. As the operating handle portion <b>321</b> of the flip cover body <b>32</b> continues to be moved downwardly, it will eventually come into abutment against the mounting seat portion <b>311</b> of the handle body <b>31</b>, and at this time, the flip cover body <b>32</b> is in the closing position, where the block of cheese <b>900</b> would have been fully processed (cut/grinded into cheese shreds or crumbs <b>901</b>). At this time, the user's hand may release the first actuating member <b>532</b> of the first switch unit <b>53</b> so as to turn the first switch member <b>531</b> to the OFF-state, such that operation of the driving unit <b>51</b> would stop. Then, after the cutter cap <b>43</b> is opened, the cheese shreds/crumbs <b>901</b> received in the hollow cylindrical body <b>421</b> can be poured out through the outlet <b>422</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">When processing of the block of cheese <b>900</b> is finished, the lateral cover body <b>33</b>, the cutter mounting seat <b>41</b> and the cylindrical cutter <b>42</b> can be easily detached from the handle body <b>31</b> for cleaning.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">In this embodiment, the second switch unit <b>54</b> and the first switch unit <b>53</b> are designed to be micro switch modules, but in other embodiments of the present disclosure, the second switch unit <b>54</b> may alternatively have a photo-electric switch module design, a mechanical tact switch module design, or a magnetic sensor switch module design, in which case the second switch unit <b>54</b> would be actuated by the flip cover body <b>32</b> to switch to the ON state when the angle between the flip cover body <b>32</b> and the handle body <b>31</b> is less than a predetermined angle.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">In summary, in view of the presence of the first and second switch units <b>53</b>, <b>54</b> that are electrically connected in series between the driving unit <b>51</b> and the power supply unit <b>52</b>, the driving unit <b>51</b> operates with the electric power from the power supply unit <b>52</b> only when the first and second switch units <b>53</b>, <b>54</b> are turned on. In other words, when any one of the first and second switch units <b>53</b>, <b>54</b> is turned off, operation of the driving unit <b>51</b> stops. Therefore, safety during use of the food grinder <b>200</b> is enhanced. Furthermore, the structure of the cylindrical cutter set <b>4</b> is designed to be easily detachable from the handle body <b>31</b>, making cleaning the cutter mounting seat <b>41</b>, the cylindrical cutter <b>42</b> and the cutter cap <b>43</b> convenient. Therefore, the object of this disclosure can indeed be achieved.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">In the description above, for the purposes of explanation, numerous specific details have been set forth in order to provide a thorough understanding of the embodiment. It will be apparent, however, to one skilled in the art, that one or more other embodiments may be practiced without some of these specific details. It should also be appreciated that reference throughout this specification to &#x201c;one embodiment,&#x201d; &#x201c;an embodiment,&#x201d; an embodiment with an indication of an ordinal number and so forth means that a particular feature, structure, or characteristic may be included in the practice of the disclosure. It should be further appreciated that in the description, various features are sometimes grouped together in a single embodiment, figure, or description thereof for the purpose of streamlining the disclosure and aiding in the understanding of various inventive aspects; such does not mean that every one of these features needs to be practiced with the presence of all the other features. In other words, in any described embodiment, when implementation of one or more features or specific details does not affect implementation of another one or more features or specific details, said one or more features may be singled out and practiced alone without said another one or more features or specific details. It should be further noted that one or more features or specific details from one embodiment may be practiced together with one or more features or specific details from another embodiment, where appropriate, in the practice of the disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">While the disclosure has been described in connection with what is considered the exemplary embodiment, it is understood that this disclosure is not limited to the disclosed embodiment but is intended to cover various arrangements included within the spirit and scope of the broadest interpretation so as to encompass all such modifications and equivalent arrangements.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A food grinder adapted for grinding and cutting a food ingredient, and comprising:
<claim-text>a grip mechanism including a handle body that is formed with an inlet for receiving the food ingredient therein, and a flip cover body that is pivotally connected to said handle body that said flip cover body is pivotable relative to said handle body between a closing position, and an open position, said flip cover body moving toward the closing position being capable of pushing the food ingredient into said inlet;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a cylindrical cutter set detachably mounted in said handle body and including a cylindrical cutter that is rotatable to cut and grind the food ingredient in said inlet; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a driving mechanism mounted in said grip mechanism and including a driving unit that is configured to drive rotation of said cylindrical cutter, a power supply unit, and first and second switch units that are electrically connected in series between said driving unit and said power supply unit and that are exposed outwardly of said handle body of said grip mechanism, said second switch unit being actuated to turn on by said flip cover body as said flip cover body pivots from the open position to the closing position, said driving unit operating with electric power supplied from said power supply unit when said first and second switch units are turned on.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The food grinder of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said first switch unit includes a first switch member disposed in said handle body, and a first actuating member connected movably to and exposed from said handle body and operable to actuate said first switch member.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The food grinder of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said first switch unit further includes a first biasing member limited in said handle body to abut against said first actuating member for biasing said first actuating member to move away from said first switch member; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>when said first actuating member is pressed to actuate said first switch member to an ON-state, said first biasing member deforms to accumulate a biasing force.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The food grinder of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said second switch unit includes a second switch member disposed in said handle body, a second actuating member disposed movably in and extending outwardly of said handle body and operable to actuate said second switch member, and a second biasing member restricted in said handle body to abut against said second actuating member for biasing said second actuating member to move away from said second switch member; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>said second actuating member is pushed by said flip cover body to actuate said second switch member to an ON-state as said flip cover body pivots from the open position to the closing position.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The food grinder of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said second switch unit includes one of a micro switch, a photoelectric switch, a mechanical switch and a magnetic sensing switch that is actuated by said flip cover body as said flip cover body pivots from the open position to the closing position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The food grinder of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said power supply unit includes a power switch exposed from said handle body; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>said driving unit operates with the electric power supplied from said power supply unit when said power switch and said first and second switch units are turned on.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The food grinder of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said handle body includes a mounting seat portion formed with said inlet and mounted with said cylindrical cutter set therein, and a handle portion connected to said mounting seat portion and mounted with said first and second switch units therein;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said flip cover body has an operating handle portion with one end distal from said mounting seat portion and connected pivotally to said handle portion, a pressing protrusion extending from said operating handle portion toward said mounting seat portion, and a pushing portion extending from said operating handle portion toward said second switch unit; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>as said flip cover body pivots from the open position to the closing position, said operating handle portion moves toward said handle body such that said pressing protrusion presses the food ingredient in said inlet to abut against said cylindrical cutter set and that said pushing portion moves to actuate said second switch unit to an ON-state.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The food grinder of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said inlet of said mounting seat portion is in the form of an upper opening;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said cylindrical cutter set further includes a cutter mounting seat that is mounted in said mounting seat portion and that includes a mounting tube portion mounted with said cylindrical cutter therein, and a feeding tube portion extending from said mounting tube portion and communicated with said mounting tube portion and said inlet;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the food ingredient in said inlet is guided by said feeding tube portion into said mounting tube portion; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>said cylindrical cutter is detachably connected to and driven by said driving unit to rotate in said mounting tube portion such that the food ingredient guided into said mounting tube portion is cut and grinded by said rotating cylindrical cutter.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The food grinder of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said mounting seat portion further has a mounting opening that allows said cutter mounting seat to be detachably mounted in said mounting seat portion therethrough; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>said driving unit includes a transmission module coaxially and detachably connected to said cylindrical cutter in said cutter tube portion of said cutter mounting seat.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The food grinder of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein said cylindrical cutter has a hollow cylindrical body that is formed with a plurality of outwardly projecting and spaced-apart blade parts and a plurality of through holes and that has an outlet communicated with said mounting opening of said mounting seat portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The food grinder of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein said cylindrical cutter set further includes a cutter cap openably closing said outlet of said hollow cylindrical body.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
