<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225604A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225604</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17750798</doc-number>
<date>20220523</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>17</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>10-2022-0006186</doc-number>
<date>20220114</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>12</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>126</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>3132</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e61">OPENING AND CLOSING UNIT AND ENDOSCOPE AND ENDOSCOPE SYSTEM INCLUDING THE SAME</invention-title>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>TAEWOONG MEDICAL CO., LTD.</orgname>
<address>
<city>Gimpo-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>JI</last-name>
<first-name>Hyun Soo</first-name>
<address>
<city>Seoul</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An opening and closing unit includes a body that has a first hollow part penetrating through both ends thereof and an opening part communicating the first hollow part with an outside, and an opening and closing part that is inserted into the first hollow part to selectively open and close the opening part, has second hollow part formed therein, and has a through hole communicating with the second hollow part on one side thereof.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="103.63mm" wi="152.48mm" file="US20230225604A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="110.57mm" wi="159.26mm" file="US20230225604A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="118.28mm" wi="154.52mm" file="US20230225604A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="163.49mm" wi="87.21mm" file="US20230225604A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="136.06mm" wi="83.99mm" file="US20230225604A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="209.63mm" wi="112.69mm" file="US20230225604A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="208.79mm" wi="105.75mm" file="US20230225604A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">1. Field of the Invention</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present disclosure relates to an apparatus and a system, and more particularly, to an opening and closing unit and an endoscope and an endoscope system including the same.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">2. Discussion of Related Art</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">In general, surgery using an endoscope is conducted by inserting an endoscope equipped with a camera and a surgical tool through a small hole without making a large incision in a human body and then examining a patient's affected area through an image taken by the endoscope in the body. In particular, since endoscopic surgery originating from laparoscopic surgery has a smaller incision compared to abdominal surgery, the endoscopic surgery has the advantage of having a smaller scar area and less bleeding, resulting in speeding up a patient's recovery time after the surgery.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Since the conventional endoscope has a structure in which an insertion part inserted into a body and an operation part for controlling the insertion part are integrated, a plurality of conduits and guides penetrating through the inside of each part are built into the endoscope, and in particular, a tip of the insertion part inserted into the body is equipped with an imaging device such as an expensive CCD, the conventional endoscope has a problem in that it is difficult to separate only the insertion part from the operation part and replace the insertion part with a new insertion part. As a result, with the trend of strengthening the hygiene of medical endoscopes, various types of detachable endoscopes, which may connect and use the insertion part inserted into the body and the operation part operating the insertion part with each other or may separate and store the insertion part and the operation part from each other, are being used.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Meanwhile, in the case of discharging contaminants (e.g., blood) generated inside a patient's body during the endoscopic surgery to the outside, the contaminants are sucked and discharged by using a suction force generated from a suction device connected to the endoscope. In this case, the contaminants move to the outside of the endoscope through a discharge passage formed inside the endoscope, and the discharge passage is generally formed to pass through the inside of the operation part.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Accordingly, there may be a problem in that the inside of the operation part is contaminated due to the contaminants passing through the inside of the operation part through the discharge passage. However, since the inside of the operation part has a complicated structure in which various parts for flexural movement of the insertion part are coupled, it is difficult to clean the operation part when the inside of the operation part is contaminated, so, after the endoscopic surgery is finished, the operation part as well as the insertion part is being interchangeably used for the subsequent surgery. In addition, since the manufacturing and selling cost of the operation part is high due to its complicated internal structure, there is also a cost problem involved in replacing the operation part with a new operation part every time the endoscopic surgery is performed.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The present disclosure provides an opening and closing unit capable of preventing contaminants generated during an endoscopic surgery from flowing into an operation part of an endoscope to prevent the operation part from being contaminated, and an endoscope and an endoscope system including the same.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The technical problems to be achieved by the present disclosure are not limited to the technical problems described above, and other technical problems that are not described may be clearly understood by those with ordinary knowledge in the technical field to which the present disclosure belongs from the following description.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">According to an embodiment of the present disclosure, an opening and closing unit may include a body that has a first hollow part penetrating through both end portions thereof and an opening part communicating the first hollow part with an outside, and an opening and closing part that is inserted into the first hollow part to selectively open and close the opening part, has second hollow part formed therein, and has a through hole communicating with the second hollow part on one side thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The opening and closing part may be disposed inside the first hollow part to enable reciprocating linear movement along a longitudinal direction.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The through hole may selectively communicate with the opening part by the reciprocating linear movement of the opening and closing part.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The opening and closing part may move in one direction when the opening part is opened to dispose the through hole on the same line as the opening part so that the operation part and the through hole communicate with each other, and move in an opposite direction to the one direction when the opening part is closed to alternately dispose the through hole and the opening part so that the communication of the through hole and the opening part is released.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">According to another embodiment of the present disclosure, an endoscope may include an insertion unit having one end inserted into a body, an operation unit that is coupled to the other end of the insertion unit, and operates the one end of the insertion unit to perform flexural movement using an operation module, a joint unit connected to one end portion of the operation unit, and the opening and closing unit described above which is disposed on the operation unit and selectively communicates the insertion unit and the joint unit.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">According to a still another embodiment of the present disclosure, an endoscope system may include an endoscope, a suction unit that sucks and moves a contaminant generated during an endoscopic surgery, and a receiving unit that receives the contaminant moved by the suction unit and discharged to the outside.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The insertion unit may communicate with the suction unit by using a bypass formed to bypass the operation unit.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a diagram illustrating a conventional endoscope system.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a diagram illustrating an endoscope system according to an embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a perspective view illustrating a portion of an opened opening and closing unit which is provided in an endoscope according to an embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is a perspective view illustrating a portion of the closed opening and closing unit which is provided in the endoscope according to the embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is a traverse cross-sectional view illustrating the opened opening and closing unit which is provided in the endoscope according to the embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is a traverse cross-sectional view illustrating the closed opening and closing unit which is provided in the endoscope according to the embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF EXEMPLARY EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Hereinafter, the present disclosure will be described with reference to the accompanying drawings. However, the present disclosure may be implemented in various different forms, and is not limited to exemplary embodiments described herein. In addition, in the drawings, portions unrelated to the description will be omitted to obviously describe the present disclosure, and similar reference numerals are attached to similar portions throughout the specification.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Throughout the present specification, when any one part is referred to as being &#x201c;connected (joined, contacted, and coupled) to&#x201d; another part, it means that any one part and another part are &#x201c;directly connected to&#x201d; each other or are &#x201c;indirectly connected to&#x201d; each other with the other part interposed therebetween. In addition, unless explicitly described to the contrary, &#x201c;including&#x201d; any component will be understood to imply the inclusion of other components rather than the exclusion of other components.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The terms used in the present specification are only used to describe specific embodiments, and are not intended to limit the present disclosure. Singular forms are intended to include plural forms unless the context clearly indicates otherwise. It should be further understood that terms &#x201c;include&#x201d; or &#x201c;have&#x201d; used in the present specification specify the presence of features, numerals, steps, operations, components, parts mentioned in the present specification, or combinations thereof, but do not preclude the presence or addition of one or more other features, numerals, steps, operations, components, parts, or combinations thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Hereinafter, embodiments of the present disclosure will be described in detail with reference to the accompanying drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> illustrates a conventional endoscope system.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, a conventional endoscope system <b>1</b>&#x2032; may include an endoscope <b>10</b>&#x2032;, and a supply and suction unit <b>40</b>. The endoscope <b>10</b>&#x2032; may include an endoscope operation part <b>100</b>&#x2032;, an insertion part <b>200</b>&#x2032;, a joint part <b>300</b>&#x2032;, and an operation control part <b>400</b>&#x2032;. In this case, the insertion part <b>200</b>&#x2032; may be a part inserted into a patient's body during an endoscopic surgery, and the endoscope operation part <b>100</b>&#x2032; may be a part for operating flexural movement of the insertion part <b>200</b>&#x2032;. The joint part <b>300</b>&#x2032; is connected to an endoscope control and management system, and the operation control part <b>400</b>&#x2032; may be an operation part for selectively opening or closing a second pipe P<b>2</b> to be described later.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The supply and suction unit <b>40</b> may include a pressure part <b>41</b> that generates a suction force for discharging saliva or foreign substances generated from an endoscopic surgery or generates a pressure required to supply liquid or gas, and a storage part <b>42</b> in which the liquid used for the endoscopic surgery is stored.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">When contaminants (e.g., patient's blood) generated during the endoscopic surgery are sucked and discharged, the conventional endoscope system <b>1</b>&#x2032; uses the suction force generated from the pressure unit <b>41</b> to suck and move the contaminants, thereby discharging the contaminants to the outside of the patient's body and the endoscope <b>10</b>&#x2032;.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The sucked contaminants are discharged by moving along pipe parts P<b>1</b>, P<b>2</b>, P<b>3</b>, and P<b>4</b> provided in the endoscope <b>10</b>&#x2032;. In this case, the pipe parts P<b>1</b>, P<b>2</b>, P<b>3</b>, and P<b>4</b> may be formed by sequentially and continuously connecting a &#x201c;first pipe P<b>1</b>&#x201d; extending into the insertion part <b>200</b>&#x2032; from an opening part of an insertion end portion <b>210</b>, a &#x201c;second pipe P<b>2</b>&#x201d; extending into the endoscope operation part <b>100</b>&#x2032; and connected to one side of the operation control part <b>400</b>&#x2032;, a &#x201c;third pipe P<b>3</b>&#x201d; connected to the other side of the operation control part <b>400</b>&#x2032; and extending toward the joint part <b>300</b>&#x2032;, and a &#x201c;fourth pipe P<b>4</b>&#x201d; extending into the joint part <b>300</b>&#x2032; and connected to a discharge part.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">In this case, when the contaminants sucked through the opening part pass through the first pipe P<b>1</b> and pass through the second pipe P<b>2</b>, as the second pipe P<b>2</b> extends through the inside of the endoscope operation part <b>100</b>&#x2032;, the contaminants may flow into the inside of the endoscope operation part <b>100</b>&#x2032;, thereby causing a problem in that the inside of the endoscope operation part <b>100</b>&#x2032; is contaminated. In this case, since the endoscope operation part <b>100</b>&#x2032; is configured to have a complicated internal structure for the flexural movement of the insertion part <b>200</b>&#x2032;, there is a problem that it is difficult to clean the endoscope operation part <b>100</b>&#x2032; when the inside of the endoscope operation part <b>100</b>&#x2032; is contaminated.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> illustrates an endoscope system according to an embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the endoscope system <b>1</b> according to the present disclosure may be a system for performing an endoscopic surgery on a patient and discharging contaminants (e.g., blood) generated during the surgery to the outside of the body. In this case, the endoscope system <b>1</b> may include an endoscope <b>10</b>, a receiving unit <b>20</b>, and a suction unit <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The endoscope <b>10</b> may include an operation unit <b>100</b>, an insertion unit <b>200</b>, and a joint unit <b>300</b>, and an opening and closing unit <b>400</b>. In the present specification, an embodiment of a &#x201c;detachable endoscope&#x201d; in which the insertion unit <b>200</b> is detachably coupled to the operation unit <b>100</b> will be mainly described, but is not limited thereto.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The operation unit <b>100</b> is a part operated by a user to control the operation of the insertion unit <b>200</b>, and may include an operation module H. In this case, the operation module H may include a first operation part H<b>10</b> and a second operation part H<b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The detachable insertion unit <b>200</b> may be selectively connected to one end of the operation unit <b>100</b>. In the state in which the insertion unit <b>200</b> is coupled to the operation unit <b>100</b>, a user may rotate the first operation part H<b>10</b> in left and right directions to flex a tip (hereinafter, insertion end portion) of the insertion unit <b>200</b> in upward and downward directions, or rotate the operation part H<b>20</b> in the left and right directions to flex the above-described insertion end portion in the left and right directions.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The operation unit <b>100</b> may include intermediate pipe parts M<b>1</b> and M<b>2</b>. As an embodiment, a pair of intermediate pipe parts M<b>1</b> and M<b>2</b> may be provided and disposed inside the operation unit <b>100</b>. In this case, the pair of intermediate pipe parts will be referred to as a first intermediate pipe part M<b>1</b> and a second intermediate pipe part M<b>2</b> for convenience of description. The first intermediate pipe part M<b>1</b> and the second intermediate pipe part M<b>2</b> are disposed between the opening and closing unit <b>400</b> and the joint unit <b>300</b> to communicate the opening and closing unit <b>400</b> and the joint unit <b>300</b> each other, which will be described later.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">A portion (i.e., insertion end portion) of the insertion unit <b>200</b> may be inserted into a body during the endoscopic surgery. In this case, the insertion end portion may be an end portion opposite to an end portion coupled to the operation unit <b>100</b> among both end portions of the insertion unit <b>200</b>. The insertion end portion may be provided with an illumination imaging part that includes a light source illuminating a body and an image sensor capturing the body.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The insertion unit <b>200</b> may include an auxiliary connection unit <b>220</b> that provides a passage through which surgical equipment and a suction nozzle used for the endoscopic surgery are inserted into the endoscope <b>10</b>. In this case, the insertion unit <b>200</b> may include a first pipe part I<b>1</b>. The first pipe part I<b>1</b> may be disposed inside the insertion unit <b>200</b>. One end of the first pipe part I<b>1</b> may communicate with the outside of the endoscope <b>10</b> through the insertion end portion of the insertion unit <b>200</b>, and the other end of the first pipe part I<b>1</b> may extend toward the other end (e.g., the opposite end portion of the insertion end portion) of the insertion unit <b>200</b> to be connected to the auxiliary connection unit <b>220</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">As an embodiment, the auxiliary connection unit <b>220</b> may include a pair of auxiliary insertion parts <b>221</b> and <b>222</b>. In this case, the pair of auxiliary insertion parts <b>221</b> and <b>222</b> is each provided with a hollow part communicating with an inner space of the insertion unit <b>200</b>, and these hollow parts may be connected to the first pipe part I<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">In this case, a tip of equipment for the endoscopic surgery may be inserted into the insertion unit <b>200</b> through a &#x201c;first auxiliary insertion part <b>221</b>&#x201d; which is one of the pair of auxiliary insertion parts. In this case, a user may operate the operation module H before or after inserting the surgical equipment to move the insertion end portion <b>210</b> of the insertion unit <b>200</b> to a surgical target part located inside a patient's body. Accordingly, the tip of the surgical equipment inserted into the insertion unit <b>200</b> may move along the first pipe part I<b>1</b> and move toward the insertion end portion <b>210</b>, and may be drawn out to the outside of the endoscope <b>10</b> through the opening part formed in the insertion end portion <b>210</b>. As a result, the surgical equipment may be guided to a surgical target location inside a patient's body to perform surgery.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">In addition, a tip of a first tube T<b>1</b> to be described later may be inserted into the insertion unit <b>200</b> through a &#x201c;second auxiliary insertion part <b>222</b>&#x201d; which is the other one of the pair of auxiliary insertion parts. In this case, the other end of the first tube T<b>1</b> may be connected to the receiving unit <b>20</b>. In this case, the contaminants generated during the endoscopic surgery may move to the receiving unit <b>20</b> through the first pipe part I<b>1</b> and the first tube T<b>1</b> communicating with the first pipe part I<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The joint unit <b>300</b> may be connected to the endoscope management and control part of the detachable endoscope <b>10</b>. Here, the endoscope management and control part may include the receiving unit <b>20</b> and the suction unit <b>30</b> as described above, which will be described in detail below.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The joint unit <b>300</b> may be disposed between the operation unit <b>100</b> and the endoscope control unit to connect the operation unit <b>100</b> and the endoscope control part. As an embodiment, a tip <b>310</b> of the joint unit <b>300</b> may be connected to the operation unit <b>100</b>, and a rear end portion <b>320</b> of the joint unit <b>300</b> may be connected to the endoscope control part.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The joint unit <b>300</b> may be provided with second pipe parts I<b>2</b> and <b>13</b> penetrating from the tip <b>310</b> to the rear end portion <b>320</b> therein.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">In one embodiment, the second pipe parts I<b>2</b> and I<b>3</b> may be provided in a pair. In this case, when the joint unit <b>300</b> is coupled to the operation unit <b>100</b>, one end of the &#x201c;2-1th pipe part I<b>2</b>,&#x201d; which is any one of the pair of second pipe parts, may be connected to the second intermediate pipe part M<b>2</b>. In addition, one end portion of the &#x201c;2-2th pipe part I<b>3</b>,&#x201d; which is the other one of the pair of second pipe parts, may be connected to the first intermediate pipe part M<b>1</b>. In this case, the other end of &#x201c;the 2-1th pipe part <b>12</b>&#x201d; may communicate with the receiving unit <b>20</b> via a second tube T<b>2</b>. The other end of the &#x201c;2-2 pipe part I<b>3</b>&#x201d; may be connected to the suction unit <b>30</b> via a third tube T<b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The opening and closing unit <b>400</b> may selectively communicate the insertion unit <b>200</b> and the joint unit <b>300</b> with each other when the insertion unit <b>200</b> and the joint unit <b>300</b> are coupled to the operation unit <b>100</b>, which will be described in detail below.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a perspective view illustrating a portion of the opened opening and closing unit provided which is provided in the endoscope according to an embodiment of the present disclosure, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is a perspective view illustrating a portion of the closed opening and closing unit which is provided in the endoscope according to an embodiment of the present disclosure. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is a transverse cross-sectional view illustrating the opened opening and closing unit which is provided in the endoscope according to the embodiment of the present disclosure, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is a transverse cross-sectional view illustrating the closed opening and closing unit which is provided in the endoscope according to the embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>3</b> to <b>6</b></figref>, the opening and closing unit <b>400</b> according to the embodiment of the present disclosure may include a body <b>410</b>, an opening and closing part <b>420</b>, and an operation part <b>430</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">The body <b>410</b> is a part in which the opening and closing part <b>420</b> is disposed, and may guide the opening and closing movement of the opening and closing part <b>420</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The body <b>410</b> may include an upper end portion <b>411</b> and a lower end portion <b>412</b>. In this case, the upper end portion <b>411</b> may be a portion including an end portion disposed on the upper side with respect to the vertical direction of the drawing, and the lower end portion <b>412</b> may be a portion including an end portion disposed at the lower side. In an embodiment, the upper end portion <b>411</b> and the lower end portion <b>412</b> may be configured as separate structures from each other. In this case, the body <b>410</b> may be formed by coupling the upper end portion <b>411</b> and the lower end portion <b>412</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The body <b>410</b> may have a first hollow part <b>411</b><i>a </i>therein. The first hollow part <b>411</b><i>a </i>may be formed to penetrate from the upper end portion <b>411</b> to the lower end portion <b>412</b> along the vertical direction.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">In this case, the body <b>410</b> may include an opening part <b>412</b><i>a </i>for communicating the first hollow part <b>411</b><i>a </i>with the outside. In an embodiment, the opening part <b>412</b><i>a </i>may be disposed on the side of the lower end portion <b>412</b>. In this case, the opening part <b>412</b><i>a </i>may be formed by penetrating through the side surface of the lower end portion <b>412</b> along a direction (e.g., radial direction) perpendicular to a longitudinal direction (or vertical direction in the drawing) of the body <b>410</b>. Through the opening part <b>412</b><i>a, </i>the first hollow part <b>411</b><i>a </i>may be in communication with the outside of the body <b>410</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">The first hollow part <b>411</b><i>a </i>may have a stepped portion <b>411</b><i>b. </i>The step portion <b>411</b><i>b </i>may be disposed on the inner side of the upper end portion <b>411</b> to define the opening/closing movement range of the operation part <b>430</b>, which will be described below.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">The opening and closing part <b>420</b> may selectively open and close the above-described opening part <b>412</b><i>a </i>to control the communication state with the outside of the first hollow part <b>411</b><i>a. </i>The opening and closing part <b>420</b> may be, for example, a cylindrical bar. In this case, the opening and closing part <b>420</b> may be formed to have a diameter equal to or similar to an inner diameter of the first hollow part <b>411</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">The opening and closing part <b>420</b> may be inserted into and disposed in the first hollow part <b>411</b><i>a. </i>In this case, the opening and closing part <b>420</b> may be disposed to enable reciprocating linear movement (hereinafter, opening and closing movement) along a downward direction B<b>1</b> and an upward direction B<b>2</b> while being inserted into the first hollow part <b>411</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The opening and closing part <b>420</b> may have a second hollow part <b>420</b><i>a </i>therein. The second hollow part <b>420</b><i>a </i>may be formed to extend upward from the lower end portion of the opening and closing part <b>420</b>. In this case, the opening and closing part <b>420</b> may have a through hole <b>420</b><i>b </i>for communicating the second hollow part <b>420</b><i>a </i>with the outside.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">In an embodiment, the through hole <b>420</b><i>b </i>may be formed to penetrate through the side surface of the opening and closing part <b>420</b>. More specifically, the through hole <b>420</b><i>b </i>may be formed to penetrate through the side surface of the opening and closing part <b>420</b> along the direction (e.g., radial direction) perpendicular to the longitudinal direction (or vertical direction in the drawing) of the opening and closing part <b>420</b><i>b. </i>Accordingly, the through hole <b>420</b><i>b </i>may be in a state in which both end portions (hereinafter, opened end portion) are opened along a width direction (or the longitudinal direction of the through hole <b>420</b><i>b</i>) of the opening and closing part <b>420</b>. Through the through hole <b>420</b><i>b, </i>the second hollow part <b>420</b><i>a </i>may selectively communicate with the first hollow part <b>411</b><i>a </i>or the opening part <b>412</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">The operation part <b>430</b> may be a part for operating the opening and closing movement of the opening and closing part <b>420</b>. In an embodiment, the operation part <b>430</b> may be connected to the opening and closing part <b>420</b>. Specifically, the upper end portion of the operation part <b>430</b> may be exposed to the outside through the upper opening part of the first hollow part <b>411</b><i>a, </i>and the lower end portion of the operation part <b>430</b> may be connected with the upper end portion of the opening and closing part <b>420</b> to reciprocate in the upward and downward directions B<b>1</b> and B<b>2</b> together with the opening and closing part <b>420</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">As exemplarily illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>3</b> and <b>5</b></figref>, a user may move the opening and closing part <b>420</b> in the downward direction B<b>1</b> by pressing the upper surface of the operation part <b>430</b>. As such, the opening and closing part <b>420</b> may move in the downward direction B<b>1</b> so that the through hole <b>420</b><i>b </i>is disposed on the same line as the opening part <b>412</b><i>a, </i>thereby communicating the through hole <b>420</b><i>b </i>and the opening part <b>412</b><i>a </i>with each other. In this case, among both opened end portions of the through hole <b>420</b><i>b, </i>the opened end portion facing the opening part <b>412</b><i>a </i>may communicate with the opening part <b>412</b><i>a. </i>As a result, the second hollow part <b>420</b><i>a </i>may communicate with the second intermediate pipe part M<b>2</b> through the through hole <b>420</b><i>b </i>and the opening part <b>412</b><i>a, </i>and thus, may be in a state (hereinafter, an opened state) in which a fluid may move into the second hollow part <b>420</b><i>a </i>through the second intermediate pipe part M<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">In an embodiment, the first hollow part <b>411</b><i>a </i>may have an inner groove part <b>411</b><i>c </i>depressed outwardly in a radial direction from its inner surface. In this case, the inner groove part <b>411</b><i>c </i>may be disposed on an inner surface opposite to the opening part <b>412</b><i>a. </i>The inner groove part <b>411</b><i>c </i>may at least partially communicate with an opened end portion located on the opposite side of the opening part <b>412</b><i>a </i>among both opened end portions of the through hole <b>420</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">Meanwhile, the operation part <b>430</b> may have a larger diameter than the opening and closing part <b>420</b>. The operation part <b>430</b> may be in contact with the stepped portion <b>411</b><i>b </i>when the operation part <b>430</b> moves by a predetermined distance in the downward direction B<b>1</b> by the user's pressure. In this case, the operation part <b>430</b> is blocked by the stepped portion <b>411</b><i>b, </i>and thus, may not be able to move further in the downward direction B<b>1</b>. As such, the stepped part <b>411</b><i>b </i>may define the opening/closing movement range of the operation part <b>430</b> by limiting the movement distance in the downward direction B<b>1</b> of the operation part <b>430</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">As exemplarily illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b> and <b>6</b></figref>, a user may release the above-described &#x201c;opened state&#x201d; by removing a force applied to the operation part <b>430</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">For example, when stopping the fluid from flowing into the second hollow part <b>420</b><i>a, </i>the user may remove the force applied to the upper surface of the operation part <b>430</b> to move the operation part <b>430</b> back in the upward direction B<b>2</b>. Accordingly, the through hole <b>420</b><i>b </i>may move in the upward direction B<b>2</b> to be positioned above the opening part <b>412</b><i>a, </i>so the through hole <b>420</b><i>b </i>and the opening part <b>412</b><i>a </i>may be disposed in a &#x201c;alternate state.&#x201d;</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">In this case, the open end disposed on the opening part <b>412</b><i>a </i>side among both opened end portions of the through hole <b>420</b><i>b, </i>which is in the &#x201c;alternate state&#x201d;, may be closed by the inner surface of the lower end portion <b>412</b> of the body <b>410</b>, and the opening part <b>412</b><i>a </i>may be closed by the outer surface of the opening and closing part <b>420</b>. As a result, the through hole <b>420</b><i>b </i>is isolated from the opening part <b>412</b><i>a, </i>and thus, may be in a state (hereinafter, a closed state) in which the fluid may not move into the second hollow part <b>420</b><i>a </i>through the second intermediate pipe part M<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">In an embodiment, the operation part <b>430</b> may include an elastic member (not illustrated). The elastic member may be disposed between the lower surface of the operation part <b>430</b> and the stepped portion <b>411</b><i>b </i>of the body <b>410</b>. The elastic member may be compressively deformed when the operation part <b>430</b> is pressed in the downward direction B<b>1</b>, and when the force applied to the operation part <b>430</b> is removed, may supply an elastic restoring force in the upward direction B<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">In this case, as the pressure by the user is removed, the elastic member may apply the elastic restoring force in the upward direction B<b>2</b> to move the operation part <b>430</b> in the upward direction B<b>2</b>. In this case, after the pressure by the user is removed, when a predetermined time elapses, the operation part <b>430</b> may return to its original position.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">The opening and closing unit <b>400</b> may be disposed in the operation unit <b>100</b>. In an embodiment, the opening and closing unit <b>400</b> may be disposed on one side of the operation unit <b>100</b>. In this case, the one side of the operation unit <b>100</b> may be a side adjacent to the operation module H. In this way, by disposing the opening and closing unit <b>400</b> in a position adjacent to the operation module H, the user of the endoscope <b>10</b> may simultaneously or separately perform the flexural movement of the insertion unit <b>200</b> and the opening and closing movement of the opening and closing unit <b>400</b> by using only one hand.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">More specifically, in the opening and closing unit <b>400</b>, the upper end <b>411</b> of the body <b>410</b> and the operation unit <b>430</b> may protrude to the outside of the operation unit <b>100</b>, and the lower end portion <b>412</b> of the body <b>410</b> may be inserted into the operation unit <b>100</b>. In this case, while being disposed inside the operation unit <b>100</b>, the opening part <b>412</b><i>a </i>may be connected to the second intermediate pipe part M<b>2</b>, and the first hollow part <b>411</b><i>a </i>may be connected to the first intermediate pipe part M<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">Referring back to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the receiving unit <b>20</b> may be a part in which the contaminants generated during the endoscopic surgery are discharged and received. In this case, the contaminants may be, for example, blood generated during the endoscopic surgery. In an embodiment, the receiving unit <b>20</b> may be a cylindrical tank having an inner space <b>21</b> therein, but the present disclosure is not limited thereto, and the receiving unit <b>20</b> may have a shape different from the cylindrical shape.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">The receiving unit <b>20</b> may have a connection part CF. In an embodiment, a pair of connection parts CF may be provided. In this case, the pair of connection parts CF may be disposed to communicate with the inner space <b>21</b> of the receiving unit <b>20</b>. In this case, a first tube T<b>1</b> may be connected to any one CF<b>1</b> of the pair of connection parts CF, and a second tube T<b>2</b> may be connected to the other one CF<b>2</b> of the pair of connection parts CF.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">The suction unit <b>30</b> may suck the contaminants generated during the endoscopic surgery and discharge the sucked contaminants to the outside of the patient's body and the endoscope <b>10</b>. The suction unit <b>30</b> may be, for example, a suction machine that generates a suction force through a pump and sucks saliva or foreign substances through an inlet and discharges the saliva or foreign substances.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">The suction unit <b>30</b> may be connected to the endoscope <b>10</b> via a third tube T<b>3</b>. Specifically, one end of the third tube T<b>3</b> may be connected to the suction unit <b>30</b>. The other end of the third tube T<b>3</b> may communicate with the 2-2th pipe part I<b>3</b> through the suction connection part SF of the joint unit <b>300</b>. In this case, the 2-2th pipe part I<b>3</b> may be connected to the first intermediate pipe part M<b>1</b> by extending through the inside of the joint unit <b>300</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">Using the above-described endoscope system <b>1</b>, a method of sucking and removing contaminants during endoscopic surgery may be as follows.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">First, the endoscope <b>10</b> in the state in which the insertion unit <b>200</b> and the joint unit <b>300</b> are connected to the operation unit <b>100</b> may be connected to the receiving unit <b>20</b> and the suction unit <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">In this case, the first pipe part I<b>1</b> may be connected to the inner space <b>21</b> of the receiving unit <b>20</b> via the first tube T<b>1</b>. Specifically, one end of the first tube T<b>1</b> may be inserted into the second auxiliary insertion part <b>222</b> provided in the insertion unit <b>200</b> to be connected to the first pipe part I<b>1</b>. In this case, the other end of the first tube T<b>1</b> may be drawn out of the second auxiliary insertion part <b>222</b> and may extend toward the receiving unit <b>20</b> while forming a &#x201c;bypass&#x201d; bypassing the operation unit <b>100</b>. The other end of the first tube T<b>1</b> may be connected to any one CF<b>1</b> of the pair of connection parts to communicate with the inner space <b>21</b> of the receiving unit <b>20</b>. Accordingly, the first tube Ti may communicate with the insertion unit <b>200</b> and the receiving unit <b>20</b> through the &#x201c;bypass&#x201d; formed outside the operation unit <b>100</b> without passing through the inner space <b>21</b> of the operation unit <b>100</b>. At the same time, the first tube T<b>1</b> may be connected to the first intermediate pipe part M<b>1</b> to communicate with the first hollow part <b>411</b><i>a </i>of the opening and closing unit <b>400</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">In addition, one end of the second intermediate pipe part M<b>2</b> may be connected to the opening part <b>412</b><i>a </i>provided in the opening and closing unit <b>400</b>, and the other end of the second intermediate pipe part M<b>2</b> may be connected to one end of the 2-1th pipe part <b>12</b> provided inside the joint unit <b>300</b>. In this case, the other end of the 2-1th pipe part <b>12</b> may be connected to the second tube T<b>2</b> through any one of the pair of suction connection parts SF, and the second tube T<b>2</b> may be connected to the other oneCF<b>2</b> of the pair of connection parts. As such, the opening part <b>412</b><i>a </i>of the opening and closing unit <b>400</b> may communicate with the inner space <b>21</b> of the receiving unit <b>20</b> through the second intermediate pipe part M<b>2</b>, the 2-1th pipe part <b>12</b>, and the second tube T<b>2</b> sequentially connected thereto. The first pipe partI<b>1</b> connected to the first tube T<b>1</b> may extend past the inside of the insertion unit <b>200</b> and communicate with the outside of the endoscope <b>10</b> through the opening part of the insertion end portion <b>210</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">Accordingly, in the opening part of the insertion end portion <b>210</b>, a &#x201c;first flow path part <b>210</b>-I<b>1</b>-T<b>1</b>-CF<b>1</b>-<b>21</b>&#x201d; leading to the space <b>21</b> through the first tube T<b>1</b> forming a circuit outside the operation unit <b>100</b> past the first pipe partI<b>1</b> inside the insertion unit <b>200</b> may be formed. In the inner space <b>21</b> of the receiving unit <b>20</b>, a &#x201c;second flow path part <b>21</b>-CF<b>2</b>-T<b>2</b>-SF<b>142</b>-H<b>2</b>-<b>412</b>&#x201d; leading to the opening part <b>412</b><i>a </i>of the opening and closing unit <b>400</b> through the second intermediate pipe part M<b>2</b> past the second tube T<b>2</b> and the 2-1th pipe part <b>12</b> sequentially connected thereto may be formed. In the second hollow part <b>420</b><i>a </i>of the opening and closing unit <b>400</b>, a &#x201c;third flow path part <b>420</b><i>a</i>-H<b>1</b>-I<b>3</b>-SF<b>2</b>-T<b>3</b>&#x201d; leading to the suction unit <b>30</b> through the third tube T<b>3</b> past the first intermediate pipe part M<b>1</b> and the 2-2th pipe part I<b>3</b> connected thereto may be formed.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">Next, a user may insert at least a portion (e.g., insertion end portion <b>210</b> and its peripheral portion) of the insertion unit <b>200</b> into the patient's body. In this case, by using the operation module H, the user flexes the insertion end portion <b>210</b> in the up-down and/or left-right directions, so that the insertion end portion may be positioned in a surgical target part inside the patient's body. Thereafter, the user may perform endoscopic surgery by moving the surgical equipment to the surgical target part through the first auxiliary insertion part <b>221</b> and the first pipe part I<b>1</b> communicating therewith. During this surgery, contaminants such as blood may occur in the surgical target part and its peripheral portion.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">Next, the suction unit <b>30</b> may generate a suction force by performing a suction operation. In this case, the user may selectively press the operation part <b>430</b> of the opening and closing unit <b>400</b> to transmit the suction force to the insertion end portion <b>210</b>. Meanwhile, the user may draw out the surgical equipment from the insertion unit <b>200</b> prior to the suction of the contaminants, and then may seal the first auxiliary insertion unit <b>221</b> by using a cap <b>211</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">In the case of discharging the contaminants generated during the endoscopic surgery to the outside of the body, the user may press the operation part <b>430</b> to move the opening and closing part <b>420</b> in the downward direction B<b>1</b>. As a result, the through hole <b>420</b><i>b </i>may communicate with the opening part <b>412</b><i>a </i>and may be in the &#x201c;opened state,&#x201d; and thus, the third flow path part <b>420</b><i>a</i>-H<b>1</b>-I<b>3</b>-SF<b>2</b>-T<b>3</b> may be connected to the second flow path part <b>21</b>-CF<b>2</b>-T<b>2</b>-SF<b>142</b>-H<b>2</b>-<b>412</b> and the inner space <b>21</b> of the receiving unit <b>20</b>. Accordingly, the third flow path part <b>420</b><i>a</i>-H<b>1</b>-I<b>3</b>-SF<b>2</b>-T<b>3</b> may also communicate with the first flow path part <b>21041</b>-T<b>1</b>-CF<b>1</b>-<b>21</b> forming the &#x201c;bypass,&#x201d; and as a result, may communicate with the surgical target part inside the patient's body and its peripheral portion through the opening part of the insertion end portion <b>210</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">In this case, by the suction action of the suction unit <b>30</b>, the contaminants may be sucked through the opening part of the insertion end portion <b>210</b>, pass through the first flow path part <b>210</b>-I<b>1</b>-T<b>1</b>-CF<b>1</b>-<b>21</b>, and may be sucked and moved towards the receiving unit <b>20</b>. The contaminants that move in this way may be discharged into the inner space <b>21</b> of the receiving unit <b>20</b>. As such, by the user's operation, the contaminants that are sucked and moved may pass through the &#x201c;bypass&#x201d; formed outside the operation unit <b>100</b> and may be received in the receiving unit <b>20</b>, thereby preventing the contaminants from flowing into the operation unit <b>100</b> during the endoscopic surgery and preventing the inside of the operation unit <b>100</b> from being contaminated due to the contaminants.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">As another example, when the discharge of the contaminants is completed or it is no longer necessary to discharge the contaminants, the user stops pressing the operation part <b>430</b> to move the opening and closing part <b>420</b> in the upward direction B<b>2</b> and make the opening and closing part <b>420</b> return to its original position. Thereby, the state in which the through hole <b>420</b><i>b </i>communicates with the opening part <b>412</b><i>a </i>is released, and thus, the through hole may be in the &#x201c;closed state.&#x201d; As a result, the second flow path part <b>21</b>-CF<b>2</b>-T<b>2</b>-SF<b>1</b>-I<b>2</b>-H<b>2</b>-<b>412</b> is closed, so the suction force generated from the suction unit <b>30</b> is not transmitted to the first flow path part <b>210</b>-I<b>1</b>-T<b>1</b>-CF<b>1</b>-<b>21</b> and the insertion end portion <b>210</b>, thereby stopping the suction action of the contaminants through the opening part of the insertion end portion <b>210</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">In this case, as the operation part <b>430</b> moves in the upward direction B<b>2</b>, the first hollow part <b>411</b><i>a </i>may communicate with the outside through a &#x201c;separation space between the operation part <b>430</b> and the upper end portion <b>411</b> of the body <b>410</b>.&#x201d; As a result, when the suction operation of the suction unit <b>30</b> continues, air may be sucked through the &#x201c;separation space&#x201d; instead of the closed opening part <b>412</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">As described above, according to the opening and closing unit <b>400</b> and the endoscope <b>10</b> and the endoscope system <b>1</b> including the same in accordance with the embodiments of the present disclosure, by pressurizing or depressurizing an operation part of the opening and closing unit, it is possible to simply and easily control suction of contaminants or interruption of suction of the contaminants. In addition, by connecting the insertion unit <b>200</b> and the receiving unit <b>20</b> through the bypass formed by bypassing the operation unit <b>100</b>, it is possible to prevent the sucked contaminants from flowing into the operation unit <b>100</b>, and as a result, to solve the cleaning problem of the operation unit <b>100</b> and reuse the operation unit <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">According to an opening and closing unit and an endoscope and an endoscope system including the same in accordance with embodiments of the present disclosure, by pressurizing or depressurizing an operation part of the opening and closing unit, it is possible to simply and easily control suction of contaminants or interruption of suction of the contaminants. In addition, by connecting an insertion unit and a receiving unit through a bypass formed by bypassing the operation unit, it is possible to prevent sucked contaminants from flowing into the operation unit, and as a result, solve a cleaning problem of the operation unit and reuse the operation unit.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">The effect of the present disclosure is not limited to the above effects, and should be understood to include all effects that can be inferred from the detailed description of the present disclosure or the composition of the disclosure described in the claims.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">It can be understood that the above description of the disclosure is for illustrative purposes only, and those skilled in the art to which the disclosure belongs can easily convert the disclosure into another specific form without changing the technical ideas or essential features of the disclosure. Therefore, it should be understood that the above-mentioned embodiments are exemplary in all aspects but are not limited thereto. For example, each component described as a single type may be implemented in a distributed manner, and similarly, components described as distributed may be implemented in a combined form.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">It is to be understood that the scope of the present disclosure will be defined by the claims rather than the above-mentioned description and all modifications and alternations derived from the claims and their equivalents are included in the scope of the present disclosure.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. An opening and closing unit, comprising:
<claim-text>a body that has a first hollow part penetrating through both end portions thereof and an opening part communicating the first hollow part with an outside; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an opening and closing part that is inserted into the first hollow part to selectively open and close the opening part, has a second hollow part formed therein, and has a through hole communicating with the second hollow part on one side thereof.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The opening and closing unit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the opening and closing part is disposed inside the first hollow part to enable reciprocating linear movement along a longitudinal direction.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The opening and closing unit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the through hole selectively communicates with the opening part by the reciprocating linear movement of the opening and closing part.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The opening and closing unit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the opening and closing part moves in one direction when the opening part is opened to dispose the through hole on the same line as the opening part so that the operation part and the through hole communicate with each other, and moves in an opposite direction to the one direction when the opening part is closed to alternately dispose the through hole and the opening part so that the communication of the through hole and the opening part is released.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. An endoscope, comprising:
<claim-text>an insertion unit having one end portion inserted into a body;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an operation unit that is coupled to the other end of the insertion unit, and operates the one end of the insertion unit to perform flexural movement by using an operation module;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a joint unit connected to one end of the operation unit; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the opening and closing unit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> which is disposed on the operation unit and selectively communicates the insertion unit and the joint unit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. An endoscope system, comprising:
<claim-text>the endoscope of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a suction unit that sucks and moves a contaminant generated during an endoscopic surgery; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a receiving unit that receives the contaminant moved by the suction unit and discharged to the outside.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The endoscope system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the insertion unit communicates with the suction unit by using a bypass formed to bypass the operation unit.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
