<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225462A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230710" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225462</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18084774</doc-number>
<date>20221220</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>44</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>13</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>44</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>13</main-group>
<subgroup>0029</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="iopxlaiqlxp5i">Novel Fabric Mending Device And Methods Of Use Thereof</invention-title>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>63300754</doc-number>
<date>20220119</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Bahareh Banisadr, LLC</orgname>
<address>
<city>Miami</city>
<state>FL</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Banisadr</last-name>
<first-name>Bahareh</first-name>
<address>
<city>Miami</city>
<state>FL</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The present invention relates to a device for mending an article of fabric by placement of a barbed thread across an area to be mended, such that the barbs engage the fibers of the fabric forming a secure closure.#</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="114.72mm" wi="165.69mm" file="US20230225462A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="201.08mm" wi="174.75mm" file="US20230225462A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="207.69mm" wi="169.76mm" file="US20230225462A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="192.19mm" wi="145.20mm" file="US20230225462A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="152.99mm" wi="121.16mm" file="US20230225462A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="lead"?>
<heading level="1" id="h-0001">CROSS REFERENCES TO RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims the benefit of and priority to U.S. Provisional Application No. 63/300,754, filed Jan. 19, 2022. The entire specification and figures of the above-referenced application is hereby incorporated in its entirety by reference.</p>
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="tail"?>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading level="1" id="h-0002">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates generally to systems, methods, and devices for repairing or mending articles of fabric. In particular, the invention relates to a device for mending an article of fabric by placement of a barbed thread across an area to be mended, such that the barbs engage the fibers of the fabric forming a secure closure.</p>
<heading level="1" id="h-0003">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Articles of fabric, such as clothing and other personal garments are susceptible to excessive wear and tearing during use. In particular, items of clothing used for outdoor activities are exposed to rugged environments that can result in worn openings and/or tears in the clothing or gear fabric. In addition, articles of clothing, such as socks and other undergarments are subject to increased friction and pressure. As a result, torn fabric must then be repaired in order to preserve the garment or other article constructed from a mendable fabric.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Ordinarily, repairing the fabric is accomplished by stitching the tear closed with a needle and thread, preferably with the use of a sewing machine. Alternatively, the worn opening or tear can be repaired with a patch that attaches to the clothing fabric and covers the damaged area. However, many individuals do not, or may not have easy access to a sewing machine or are not proficient in sewing techniques to be able to repair their own articles of clothing or other fabric items. Moreover, patches often do not match the color and pattern of the fabric to reduce visibility of the patch when attached to the damaged portion.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Presently, the attachment of a repair patch to a garment or other fabric article is accomplished by either stitching with a needle and thread or by hot melt adhesion using an electric iron. Stitching the patch to the fabric is labor intensive and is best accomplished with the use of an electric sewing machine as noted above. Due to the need for special skills and electric equipment, neither the stitching method nor the hot melt adhesion method is suited for repairs performed in remote locations, or by an untrained user. Instead, the torn garment or gear must be taken to a tailor, seamstress or other skilled professional for repair. The inability to repair the damaged garment or other article of fabric using a simple compact device is inconvenient, potentially costly, and may result in further damage to the garment.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Accordingly, there remains a need for a simple device that can repair tears and openings in the fabric of a garment or other articles of fabric, or alternatively mend two or more articles of fabric together forming a secure attachment without the need for special equipment, electric power, or unique skills.</p>
<heading level="1" id="h-0004">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">One object of the present invention is to provide a simple, compact, and easy-to-carry fabric mending device that can quickly repair tears in articles of fabric, such as clothing and other garments.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Another object of the present invention is to provide a simple, compact, and easy-to-carry fabric mending device that can quickly mend two or more article of fabric together. As used herein, the term &#x201c;fabric&#x201d; generally refer to cloth or other material produced by weaving together natural or synthetic fibers such as cotton, nylon, wool, silk, or other threads. As used herein, the term &#x201c;article of fabric,&#x201d; refers to any article, or thing that includes at least some portion of fabric, such as clothes, bags, curtains, sheets and the like.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In a preferred aspect, the invention may include a fabric mending device configured to position a flexible thread having a plurality of barbs across an area to be mended, such as a rip or tear in a garment, such that the barbs of the thread engage with the fabric and generate a secure closure of the area.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In another preferred aspect, the invention may include a fabric mending device configured to position a flexible thread having a plurality of barbs across an area to be mended, such as a rip or tear in a garment, using a needle having a hollow channel. In this aspect, the barded thread may be positioned within the hollow channel of the needle which can be used to penetrate the area to be mended on the article of fabric while protecting the barbs from prematurely engaging the fibers of the fabric until it had been adequately positioned.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In another preferred aspect, the invention may include a fabric mending device having a cap configured to secure a needle and barbed thread. In this aspect, the barded thread may be positioned within the hollow channel of the needle with a portion extending beyond the proximal end of the needle such that when secured to the cap the thread is independently secured in place such that it cannot be displaced from the hollow chamber of the needle until the cap is disengaged.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In another preferred aspect, the invention may include a fabric mending device configured to position a flexible thread having a plurality of barbs across an area to be mended, such as a rip or tear in a garment, using a flexible tube having a hollow channel. In this aspect, the barded thread may be positioned within the hollow channel of the flexible tube which can be used to penetrate the area to be mended on the article of fabric while protecting the barbs from prematurely engaging the fibers of the fabric until it had been adequately positioned.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In another preferred aspect, the invention may include a fabric mending device having a cap configured to secure the flexible tube and barbed thread. In this aspect, the barded thread may be positioned within the hollow channel of the flexible tube with a portion extending beyond the proximal end of the flexible tube such that when secured to the cap the thread is independently secured in place such that it cannot be displaced from the hollow chamber of the flexible tube until the cap is disengaged.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Additional aspects of the invention will become apparent to those of ordinary skill in the art based on the description, figures, and claims provided below.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading level="1" id="h-0005">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>: shows a disarticulated fabric repair device of the invention having a length of barbed thread, a needle having a hollow channel, and a cap in one embodiment thereof;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>: shows a cross-sectional view fabric repair device of the invention having a length of barbed thread positioned within the hollow channel of a needle, the proximal ends of both being secured by a cap in one embodiment thereof;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref>: shows a length of thread having a plurality of circumferentially arranged barbs in one embodiment thereof;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>B</figref>: shows an alternative length of thread having a midline separating proximal and distal barbed sections having opposing bilateral barbs as well as unbarbed proximal and distal ends in one embodiment thereof;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>C</figref>: shows a horizontal cross sectional view of a length of thread having a plurality of circumferentially arranged barbs in one embodiment thereof;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>: shows a disarticulated fabric repair device of the invention having a length of barbed thread, a needle having a hollow channel, and a cap in one embodiment thereof;</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>: shows a disarticulated fabric repair device of the invention having a length of barbed thread, a flexible tube having a hollow channel, and a cap in one embodiment thereof; and</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b>A-C</figref>: show the multi-step operation of the fabric mending device of the invention repairing an exemplary tear in an article of fabric in one embodiment thereof.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading level="1" id="h-0006">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The invention includes a fabric mending device (<b>1</b>) configured to position a flexible thread (<b>9</b>) having a plurality of barbs (<b>11</b>) across an area to be mended, such as a rip or tear in a garment or other article of fabric (<b>14</b>), such that the barbs (<b>11</b>) of the thread (<b>9</b>) engage with the fabric (<b>14</b>) and generate a secure closure of the area. It should be noted that the terms &#x201c;mending&#x201d; and &#x201c;repair&#x201d; may be used interchangeable and may include the mending or repairing a damaged portion of an article of fabric (<b>14</b>), such as a tear or hole generated from use, as well as attaching two or more articles of fabric together using the fabric mending device (<b>1</b>) of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The fabric mending device (<b>1</b>) of the invention may include a needle (<b>5</b>) configured to secure and position a thread (<b>9</b>) having a plurality of barbs (<b>11</b>) within an article of fabric (<b>14</b>) at area to be mended generating a secure closure. In the preferred embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, the needle (<b>5</b>) of the invention may include a hollow channel (<b>6</b>) having an opening on the proximal end (<b>8</b><i>a</i>). In this embodiment, the distal end (<b>8</b><i>b</i>) of the needle may preferably be closed to prevent the egress of the barbed thread (<b>9</b>) during use of the device, as well as to better facilitate penetration of the fabric (<b>14</b>) to be mended as further described below.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The length of the needle (<b>5</b>) of the invention can be variable. For example, the needle (<b>5</b>) may partially or fully span at least the area to be mended on the article of fabric (<b>14</b>). Moreover, the gauge of the needle (<b>5</b>) may be different depending on the type of fabric or other material to be mended or repaired, with a larger gauge being used to penetrate articles of fabric (<b>14</b>) that are substantially permeable, while smaller gauge needles may be implemented for articles of fabric (<b>14</b>) that are resistant to penetration by the needle (<b>5</b>). Notably, while the embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>-<b>2</b></figref> shows the use of a metal needle (<b>5</b>), a variety of suitable materials may be implemented with the current invention. For example, the needle (<b>5</b>) of the invention may be made from a rigid plastic, while in alternative embodiments, the needle (<b>5</b>) may be made from a substantially pliable material forming a flexible tube (<b>13</b>) having a hollow channel (<b>6</b>) configured to secure and position a thread (<b>9</b>) having a plurality of barbs (<b>11</b>) within an article of fabric (<b>14</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Referring again to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>-<b>2</b></figref>, a needle (<b>5</b>) of the invention may further include a proximal end (<b>8</b><i>a</i>) and a distal end (<b>8</b><i>b</i>). In this preferred embodiment, the proximal end (<b>8</b><i>a</i>) of the needle (<b>5</b>) may include a planar surface forming an opening to a hollow channel (<b>6</b>). As further described below, the proximal end (<b>8</b><i>a</i>) of the needle (<b>5</b>) may include a slot (not shown) configured to secure the barbed thread (<b>9</b>) and facilitate its securement in the cap (<b>2</b>) of the invention. Again, in this preferred embodiment, the distal end (<b>8</b><i>b</i>) of the needle (<b>5</b>) may include a tapered end (<b>7</b>), having a closed configuration, configured to allow easier penetration of fabric (<b>14</b>) and other materials by the needle (<b>5</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The fabric mending device (<b>1</b>) of the invention may include a thread (<b>9</b>), which may further include a plurality of barbs (<b>11</b>) configured to grasp and engage the fibers of an article of fabric (<b>14</b>), or other material and secure the portions of the article to be mended together forming a secure closure. In the preferred embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>3</b>A-C</figref>, the thread (<b>9</b>) of the invention may include a plurality of barbs (<b>11</b>) that may be further positioned in an aligned, or offset position around the circumference of the thread (<b>9</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The thread (<b>9</b>) of the invention may include a plurality of distinct regions that enhance the engagement of the barbs (<b>3</b>) with the subject fabric (<b>14</b>). For example, in one preferred embodiment, the thread (<b>9</b>) of the invention may include a proximal barbed section (<b>10</b><i>a</i>) and a distal barbed section (<b>10</b><i>b</i>) separated at a mid-line (<b>12</b>). As specifically shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref>, the barbs of the barbs of the proximal barbed section (<b>10</b><i>a</i>) and a distal barbed section (<b>10</b><i>b</i>) are oriented in an opposing bilateral configuration. When positioned within an article of fabric (<b>14</b>) to be mended as detailed below, the movement of the fabric (<b>14</b>), such as by stretching, allows the opposing barbs (<b>11</b>) to engage the fibers of the fabric (<b>14</b>) generating an opposing force against one another. As a result, movement of fabric (<b>14</b>), such as when worn by a user, causes the barbs (<b>9</b>) of the thread (<b>9</b>) to engage even more securely with the fabric thereby strengthening the closure of the mended area.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The thread (<b>9</b>) of the invention may further include one or more unbarbed regions. Again, in the preferred embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref>, the proximal end and distal ends (<b>15</b>, <b>16</b>) may lack barbs such that the thread (<b>9</b>) does not engage with the fibers of the article of fabric (<b>14</b>) to be mended. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref>, the unbarbed sections may include different lengths, such that in a preferred embodiment, the distal end of the thread (<b>16</b>) may include a shorter unbarbed region than that of the proximal end (<b>15</b>). As detailed below, in this configuration, the unbarbed regions may allow for a user to grasp the proximal or distal ends (<b>15</b>, <b>16</b>) of the thread (<b>9</b>) more easily once it has been positioned within an area to be mended on fabric (<b>14</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The thread (<b>9</b>) of the invention may be variable in length, width, as well as number and placement of barbs (<b>11</b>) and barbed sections (<b>10</b><i>a</i>, <b>10</b><i>b</i>). For example, the thread (<b>9</b>) may partially or fully span at least the area to be mended on the article of fabric (<b>14</b>), and more preferably the barbed sections (<b>10</b><i>a</i>, <b>10</b><i>b</i>) of the thread (<b>9</b>) may partially or fully span at least the area to be mended in the article of fabric (<b>14</b>) such that the barbed section (<b>10</b><i>a</i>, <b>10</b><i>b</i>) are fully-engaged with the fabric (<b>14</b>) across the entire span of the tear or gap to be mended in the fabric (<b>14</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Moreover, the gauge of the thread (<b>9</b>) may be different depending on the type of fabric or other materials to be mended or repaired, with a larger gauge being used to penetrate and secure articles of fabric (<b>14</b>) that are resistant to engagement with the barbs (<b>11</b>), or are heavier and less playable, while smaller gauge thread (<b>9</b>) may be implemented for articles of fabric (<b>14</b>) that are fibrous such that individual barbs (<b>11</b>) may more readily engage with the individual fibers of the fabric (<b>14</b>). Moreover, the length, gauge, and size of the barbs (<b>11</b>) can be adjusted to account for different applications and materials, such that a user&#x2019;s skin does not come into repetitive contact with the barbed thread (<b>9</b>). A variety of suitable materials may be implemented with the barbed thread (<b>9</b>) of the current invention. In a preferred example, the thread (<b>9</b>) of the invention may be made from a flexible monofilament material having a plurality of barbs (<b>11</b>) as described above.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The fabric mending device (<b>1</b>) of the invention may include a cap (<b>2</b>) configured to secure a needle (<b>5</b>) and thread (<b>9</b>). In the preferred embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the cap (<b>2</b>) of the invention may include an aperture (<b>4</b>) to receive and secure the proximal end of the needle (<b>5</b>). In this embodiment, the aperture (<b>4</b>) may be smaller than the diameter of the needle (<b>5</b>) and may further be made from a pliable material such as, plastic, rubber, or form. In this configuration, the aperture (<b>4</b>) generates a compressive force to secure the needle (<b>5</b>) to the cap (<b>2</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">As further shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the thread of the invention may be positioned inside the hollow channel (<b>6</b>) of the needle (<b>5</b>) while a portion of the proximal end of the thread (<b>15</b>) extends beyond the proximal end (<b>8</b><i>a</i>) of the needle (<b>5</b>). When positioned within the aperture as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the compressive force of the aperture (<b>4</b>) of the cap (<b>2</b>) independently secures the thread (<b>9</b>) such that it remains within the hollow channel (<b>6</b>) of the needle (<b>5</b>) during use. As detailed below, the needle (<b>5</b>) may be independently removed from the cap (<b>2</b>) and withdrawn exposing the length of the barbed thread (<b>9</b>), while the compressive force of the cap (<b>2</b>) retains the thread (<b>9</b>), and preferably the unbarbed regions of the proximal end of the thread (<b>15</b>) secured in the aperture (<b>4</b>). In this manner, the cap (<b>2</b>) of the invention may be disengaged from the thread (<b>9</b>) without engagement of the barbs (<b>11</b>) with the cap (<b>2</b>) in one embodiment. In alternative embodiments, the cap (<b>2</b>) of the invention may secure a needle (<b>5</b>) and barbed thread (<b>9</b>) positioned within the hollow channel (<b>6</b>) though a coupler. In this embodiment, a coupler may secure the needle (<b>5</b>) and thread (<b>9</b>), and preferably the unbarbed proximal end of the thread (<b>9</b>) within the internal compartment of the cap (<b>2</b>). The coupler may be disengaged to allow the independent withdrawal of the needle (<b>5</b>) while maintaining its coupling to the thread (<b>9</b>). The coupler may further be engaged to independently allow removal of the secured thread (<b>9</b>). In this embodiment, the coupler of the invention may be selected from the group consisting of a quick coupler, a twist coupler, a snap coupler, a spring-loaded coupler, a compression coupler, or a combination of the same.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The invention may include methods of mending an article of fabric (<b>14</b>) using the fabric repair device (<b>1</b>) as described herein. As generally shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b>A-C</figref>, a user may insert a thread (<b>9</b>) having a plurality of barbs into the hollow channel (<b>6</b>) of a needle (<b>5</b>) or alternatively a flexible tube (<b>13</b>), while a portion of the proximal end of the thread (<b>15</b>) may extend beyond the proximal end of the needle (<b>8</b><i>a</i>). The needle (<b>5</b>) may be secured to a cap (<b>2</b>) by inserting it into an aperture (<b>4</b>) or by another coupler mechanism such that the extended proximal end of the thread (<b>15</b>) is secured within the internal compartment (<b>3</b>) of the cap (<b>2</b>) as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The needle (<b>5</b>) may be used to penetrate, preferably in a circular sewing motion, an article of fabric (<b>14</b>) such that the needle (<b>5</b>) is interwoven along the length of the portion of fabric (<b>14</b>) to be mended. While preferably grasping the cap (<b>2</b>), which may also serve as a handle to help facilitate the mending action of the needle (<b>5</b>), the user can remove the needle (<b>5</b>) by grasping the distal end (<b>8</b><i>a</i>) and decoupling it from the cap (<b>2</b>) thereby exposing the barbed thread (<b>9</b>). The barbed thread (<b>9</b>), now being positioned so as to be interwoven along the length of the portion of fabric (<b>14</b>) to be mended, may engage with the threads of the fabric (<b>14</b>) forming a secure closure.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The cap (<b>2</b>) may further be disengaged from the barbed thread (<b>9</b>) leaving the proximal and distal ends of the thread (<b>15</b>, <b>16</b>) extending beyond the area to be mended on the article of fabric (<b>14</b>). The sewing action of the needle (<b>5</b>) may cause the fabric of the area to be mended to be constructed. In this embodiment, a user may pull the ends of the fabric (<b>14</b>) of the area to be mended along the length of the positioned thread (<b>9</b>) causing the barbs (<b>11</b>) to engage with the fabric (<b>14</b>) of the area to be mended forming a secure mended closure. Finally, the proximal and distal ends (<b>15</b>,<b>16</b>) of the barbed thread (<b>9</b>) may be removed, such as by clipping with scissors or other similar implement, leaving the thread (<b>9</b>) in place with the barbs (<b>11</b>) engaged with the fabric (<b>14</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Naturally, all embodiments discussed herein are merely illustrative and should not be construed to limit the scope of the inventive technology consistent with the broader inventive principles disclosed. As may be easily understood from the foregoing, the basic concepts of the present inventive technology may be embodied in a variety of ways. It generally involves systems, methods, techniques as well as devices to accomplish a fabric mending device and the like. In this application, the methods and apparatus for the aforementioned systems are disclosed as part of the results shown to be achieved by the various devices described and as steps which are inherent to utilization. They are simply the natural results of utilizing the devices as intended and described. In addition, while some devices are disclosed, it should be understood that these not only accomplish certain methods but also can be varied in a number of ways. Importantly, as to all of the foregoing, all of these facets should be understood to be encompassed by this disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">While the invention has been described in connection with a preferred embodiment, it is not intended to limit the scope of the invention to the particular form set forth, but on the contrary, it is intended to cover such alternatives, modifications, and equivalents as may be included within the spirit and scope of the invention as defined by the statements of invention. As can be easily understood from the foregoing, the basic concepts of the present invention may be embodied in a variety of ways. It involves both techniques as well as devices to accomplish the appropriate system. In this application, the techniques are disclosed as part of the results shown to be achieved by the various devices described and as steps which are inherent to utilization. They are simply the natural results of utilizing the devices as intended and described. In addition, while some devices are disclosed, it should be understood that these not only accomplish certain methods but also can be varied in a number of ways. Importantly, as to all of the foregoing, all of these facets should be understood to be encompassed by this disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The discussion included in this application is intended to serve as a basic description. The reader should be aware that the specific discussion may not explicitly describe all embodiments possible; many alternatives are implicit. It also may not fully explain the generic nature of the invention and may not explicitly show how each feature or element can actually be representative of a broader function or of a great variety of alternative or equivalent elements. Again, these are implicitly included in this disclosure. Where the invention may be described in some instances in method-oriented terminology, each element of the claims corresponds to a device and vice versa. Apparatus claims may not only be included for the device described, but also method or process claims may be included to address the functions the invention and each element performs. Neither the description nor the terminology is intended to limit the scope of the claims that will be included in any subsequent patent application.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">It should also be understood that a variety of changes may be made without departing from the essence of the invention. Such changes are also implicitly included in the description. They still fall within the scope of this invention. A broad disclosure encompassing the explicit embodiment(s) shown, the great variety of implicit alternative embodiments, and the broad methods or processes and the like are encompassed by this disclosure and may be relied upon when drafting any claims. It should be understood that such language changes and broader or more detailed claiming may be accomplished at a later date (such as by any required deadline) or in the event the applicant subsequently seeks a patent filing based on this filing. With this understanding, the reader should be aware that this disclosure is to be understood to support any subsequently filed patent application that may seek examination of as broad a base of claims as deemed within the applicant&#x2019;s right and may be designed to yield a patent covering numerous aspects of the invention both independently and as an overall system.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Further, each of the various elements of the invention and claims may also be achieved in a variety of manners. Additionally, when used or implied, an element is to be understood as encompassing individual as well as plural structures that may or may not be physically connected. This disclosure should be understood to encompass each such variation, be it a variation of an embodiment of any apparatus embodiment, a method or process embodiment, or even merely a variation of any element of these. Particularly, it should be understood that as the disclosure relates to elements of the invention, the words for each element may be expressed by equivalent apparatus terms or method terms &#x2013; even if only the function or result is the same. Such equivalent, broader, or even more generic terms should be considered to be encompassed in the description of each element or action. Such terms can be substituted where desired to make explicit the implicitly broad coverage to which this invention is entitled. As but one example, it should be understood that all actions may be expressed as a means for taking that action or as an element which causes that action. Similarly, each physical element disclosed should be understood to encompass a disclosure of the action which that physical element facilitates. Regarding this last aspect, as but one example, the disclosure of a &#x201c;cap&#x201d; should be understood to encompass disclosure of the act of &#x201c;capping&#x201d; &#x2013; whether explicitly discussed or not &#x2013; and, conversely, were there effectively disclosure of the act of &#x201c;capping&#x201d;, such a disclosure should be understood to encompass disclosure of a &#x201c;capping method and/or technique, and/or device.&#x201d; Such changes and alternative terms are to be understood to be explicitly included in the description.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Thus, the applicant(s) should be understood to have support to claim and make a statement of invention to at least: i) each of the methods and/or apparatus for providing a fabric mending device as herein disclosed and described, ii) the related methods disclosed and described, iii) similar, equivalent, and even implicit variations of each of these devices and methods, iv) those alternative designs which accomplish each of the functions shown as are disclosed and described, v) those alternative designs and methods which accomplish each of the functions shown as are implicit to accomplish that which is disclosed and described, vi) each feature, component, and step shown as separate and independent inventions, vii) the applications enhanced by the various systems or components disclosed, viii) the resulting products produced by such systems or components, ix) each system, method, and element shown or described as now applied to any specific field or devices mentioned, x) methods and apparatuses substantially as described hereinbefore and with reference to any of the accompanying examples, xi) the various combinations and permutations of each of the elements disclosed, xii) each potentially dependent claim or concept as a dependency on each and every one of the independent claims or concepts presented, and xiii) all inventions described herein.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">With regard to claims whether now or later presented for examination, it should be understood that for practical reasons and so as to avoid great expansion of the examination burden, the applicant may at any time present only initial claims or perhaps only initial claims with only initial dependencies. The office and any third person interested in potential scope of this or subsequent applications should understand that broader claims may be presented at a later date in this case, in a case claiming the benefit of this case, or in any continuation in spite of any preliminary amendments, other amendments, claim language, or arguments presented, thus throughout the pendency of any case there is no intention to disclaim or surrender any potential subject matter. It should be understood that if or when broader claims are presented, such may require that any relevant prior art that may have been considered at any prior time may need to be re-visited since it is possible that to the extent any amendments, claim language, or arguments presented in this or any subsequent application are considered as made to avoid such prior art, such reasons may be eliminated by later presented claims or the like. Both the examiner and any person otherwise interested in existing or later potential coverage or considering if there has at any time been any possibility of an indication of disclaimer or surrender of potential coverage, should be aware that no such surrender or disclaimer is ever intended or ever exists in this or any subsequent applications. Limitations such as arose in <i>Hakim v. Cannon Avent Group, PLC</i>, 479 F.3d 1313 (Fed. Cir 2007), or the like are expressly not intended in this or any subsequent related matter. In addition, support should be understood to exist to the degree required under new matter laws &#x2013;including but not limited to European Patent Convention Article 123(2) and United States Patent Law 35 USC 132 or other such laws&#x2013; to permit the addition of any of the various dependencies or other elements presented under one independent claim or concept as dependencies or elements under any other independent claim or concept. In drafting any claims at any time whether in this application or in any subsequent applications, it should also be understood that the applicant has intended to capture as full and broad a scope of coverage as legally available. To the extent that insubstantial substitutes are made, to the extent that the applicant did not in fact draft any claim so as to literally encompass any particular embodiment, and to the extent otherwise applicable, the applicant should not be understood to have in any way intended to or actually relinquished such coverage as the applicant simply may not have been able to anticipate all eventualities; one skilled in the art, should not be reasonably expected to have drafted a claim that would have literally encompassed such alternative embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">Further, if or when used, the use of the transitional phrase &#x201c;comprising&#x201d; is used to maintain the &#x201c;open-end&#x201d; claims herein, according to traditional claim interpretation. Thus, unless the context requires otherwise, it should be understood that the term &#x201c;comprise&#x201d; or variations such as &#x201c;comprises&#x201d; or &#x201c;comprising&#x201d;, are intended to imply the inclusion of a stated element or step or group of elements or steps but not the exclusion of any other element or step or group of elements or steps. Such terms should be interpreted in their most expansive form so as to afford the applicant the broadest coverage legally permissible. It should be understood that this application also provides support for any combination of elements in the claims and even incorporates any desired proper antecedent basis for certain claim combinations such as with combinations of method, apparatus, process, and the like claims.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Any claims set forth at any time are hereby incorporated by reference as part of this description of the invention, and the applicant expressly reserves the right to use all of or a portion of such incorporated content of such claims as additional description to support any of or all of the claims or any element or component thereof, and the applicant further expressly reserves the right to move any portion of or all of the incorporated content of such claims or any element or component thereof from the description into the claims or vice-versa as necessary to define the matter for which protection is sought by this application or by any subsequent continuation, division, or continuation-in-part application thereof, or to obtain any benefit of, reduction in fees pursuant to, or to comply with the patent laws, rules, or regulations of any country or treaty, and such content incorporated by reference shall survive during the entire pendency of this application including any subsequent continuation, division, or continuation-in-part application thereof or any reissue or extension thereon. The inventive subject matter is to include, but certainly not be limited as, a system substantially as herein described with reference to any one or more of the Figures and Description (including the following: for example, the process according to any claims and further comprising any of the steps as shown in any Figures, separately, in any combination or permutation).</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A fabric mending device comprising:
<claim-text>&#x2013; a needle having a hollow channel;</claim-text>
<claim-text>&#x2013; a cap having an aperture to receive the proximal end of said needle; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>&#x2013; a length of thread having a plurality of barbs positioned with said hollow channel, and wherein the terminal end of said thread is secured within the internal compartment of said cap such that said needle is separable from said cap and said thread.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the distal end of said needle comprises a tapered end.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said thread comprises a thread having a plurality of barbs.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said barbs comprises a plurality of barbs positioned around the circumference of said thread.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said thread includes a midline.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein said midline separates a proximal barbed section and a distal barbed section.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein said the barbs of said proximal barbed section and a distal barbed section are oriented in an opposing configuration.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said proximal end of said thread is unbarbed, and/or said distal end of said thread is unbarbed.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. (canceled)</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said needle is secured in said cap by a coupler.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said needle comprises a flexible needle having a hollow channel.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. (canceled)</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. A fabric mending device comprising:
<claim-text>&#x2013; a flexible tube having a hollow channel;</claim-text>
<claim-text>&#x2013; a cap having an aperture to receive the proximal end of said flexible tube; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>&#x2013; a length of thread having a plurality of barbs positioned with said hollow channel, and wherein the terminal end of said thread is secured within the internal compartment of said cap such that said flexible tube is separable from said cap and said thread.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the distal end of said flexible tube comprises a tapered end.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein said thread comprises a thread having a plurality of barbs.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein said barbs comprises a plurality of barbs positioned around the circumference of said thread.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein said thread includes a midline.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein said midline separates a proximal barbed section and a distal barbed section.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein said the barbs of said proximal barbed section and a distal barbed section are oriented in an opposing configuration.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein said proximal end of said thread is unbarbed, and/or said distal end of said thread is unbarbed.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text><b>21</b>. (canceled)</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text><b>22</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein said flexible tube is secured in said cap by a coupler.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text><b>23</b>. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein said cap comprises a cap selected from the group consisting of: a plastic cap, a rubber cap, a foam cap, or a combination of the same.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-24-49" num="24-49">
<claim-text><b>24</b>-<b>49</b>. (canceled)</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
