<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225255A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230705" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225255</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18189440</doc-number>
<date>20230324</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>037</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>26</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>15</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>037</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>B</section>
<class>26</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>15</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="najxmjbjydyll">Cutting Device</invention-title>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17075124</doc-number>
<date>20201020</date>
</document-id>
<parent-status>PENDING</parent-status>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18189440</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation>
<continuation>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>16195191</doc-number>
<date>20181119</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>10912259</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17075124</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation>
<division>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>15295201</doc-number>
<date>20161017</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>10172292</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>16195191</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</division>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Robert Bosch GmbH</orgname>
<address>
<city>Stuttgart</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>DE</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Zador</last-name>
<first-name>Endre</first-name>
<address>
<city>Ipswich</city>
<country>GB</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="01" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Nagy</last-name>
<first-name>Janos</first-name>
<address>
<city>Mezonagymihaly</city>
<country>HU</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="02" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Sepsi</last-name>
<first-name>Krisztian</first-name>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="03" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Glanville</last-name>
<first-name>Mark</first-name>
<address>
<city>Ipswich</city>
<country>GB</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="04" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Soltesz</last-name>
<first-name>Robert</first-name>
<address>
<city>Miskolc</city>
<country>HU</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="05" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Zsoldos</last-name>
<first-name>Zoltan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kispiac</city>
<country>HU</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A cutting device includes a first cutting element, a second cutting element, a first gripping element, a second gripping element, at least one driving element, a sensor, and a control unit. The cutting elements are configured to move relative to each other. The gripping elements are configured to move relative to each other. The at least one driving element is configured to move the first cutting element relative to the second cutting element when the at least one driving element is activated. The sensor is mounted on the first gripping element or the second gripping element and is configured to detect an object located between the first gripping element and the second gripping element. The control unit is operably connected to the at least one driving element and the sensor. The control unit is configured to deactivate the at least one driving element when the sensor detects the object.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="156.38mm" wi="236.22mm" file="US20230225255A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="227.84mm" wi="125.31mm" file="US20230225255A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="231.65mm" wi="152.15mm" file="US20230225255A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="229.79mm" wi="149.78mm" file="US20230225255A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="217.59mm" wi="126.58mm" file="US20230225255A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="192.96mm" wi="129.88mm" file="US20230225255A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="139.78mm" wi="133.52mm" file="US20230225255A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="139.78mm" wi="133.52mm" file="US20230225255A1-20230720-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="137.41mm" wi="129.37mm" file="US20230225255A1-20230720-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="131.15mm" wi="127.34mm" file="US20230225255A1-20230720-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="220.39mm" wi="102.28mm" file="US20230225255A1-20230720-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="204.22mm" wi="135.55mm" file="US20230225255A1-20230720-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00012" num="00012">
<img id="EMI-D00012" he="209.30mm" wi="135.72mm" file="US20230225255A1-20230720-D00012.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00013" num="00013">
<img id="EMI-D00013" he="189.48mm" wi="141.22mm" file="US20230225255A1-20230720-D00013.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00014" num="00014">
<img id="EMI-D00014" he="210.90mm" wi="134.79mm" file="US20230225255A1-20230720-D00014.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00015" num="00015">
<img id="EMI-D00015" he="201.59mm" wi="93.81mm" file="US20230225255A1-20230720-D00015.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" orientation="landscape"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a continuation of U.S. Application Serial No. 17/075,124 filed on Oct. 20, 2020, which claims the benefit of priority of U.S. Application Serial No. 16/195,191, filed on Nov. 19, 2018 (now U.S. Pat. no. 10,912,259, issued Feb. 9, 2021) and U.S. Application Serial No. 15/295,201, filed on Oct. 17, 2016 (now U.S. Pat. no. 10,172,292, issued Jan. 8, 2019), the disclosures of the above-identified patent application and patents are hereby totally incorporated by reference in their entirety.</p>
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="tail"?>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading level="1" id="h-0001">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">A cutting device, such as a garden cutting device, has already been proposed.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">From DE 10 2010 016 296 B4 there is already known a cutting device with two blades able to move relative to each other, with two gripping elements able to move relative to each other and with a driving element, which in one operating state is provided to assist a movement of the second blade relative to the first blade.</p>
<heading level="1" id="h-0002">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">A cutting device, such as a garden cutting device, is disclosed, with a first and a second cutting element able to move relative to each other, with a first and a second gripping element able to move relative to each other, and with at least one driving element, which in at least one operating state is provided to at least assist a movement of the second cutting element relative to the first cutting element. The cutting device comprises a spring element. The spring element can be designed as a brake element, as an opening spring, as a force sensor element, as a restoring element, as a compression or tension spring, as a spiral spring, as a tensioning spring, as a biasing spring or the like. It is proposed that the cutting device comprises at least one self-switching coupling unit, which is provided for a decoupling of the driving element in at least one operating state in which the driving element is deactivated.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Alternatively, another manual machine tool is also disclosed, with a first and a second working element able to move relative to each other, such as a gripping or pliers element, with a first and a second gripping element able to move relative to each other, and with at least one driving element, which in at least one operating state is provided to at least assist a movement of the second working element relative to the first working element, wherein the manual machine tool comprises at least one self-switching coupling unit, which is provided for a decoupling of the driving element in at least one operating state in which the driving element is deactivated.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Moreover, it is proposed that the at least one self-switching coupling unit is provided, in at least one operating state, for a decoupling of the driving element to realize of a full manual operation.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Moreover, it is proposed that the at least one self-switching coupling unit is designed as a freewheel clutch.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Moreover, it is proposed that the at least one self-switching coupling unit comprises at least one clamping body.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Moreover, it is proposed that the at least one self-switching coupling unit comprises at least one cage accommodating the clamping body, and one brake element, which is provided for a braking of the cage in at least one operating state.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Moreover, a cable winch which can be driven by the driving element and at least one cable which is and/or can be wound at least partly on the cable winch is proposed, which is tensioned at least partly between the gripping elements.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Moreover, it is proposed that the at least one self-switching coupling unit is integrated at least partly in the at least one cable winch.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Moreover, a spring element connected to the cable winch is proposed, which is configured for example as a spiral spring and which is provided to tension the cable in at least one operating state.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Moreover, at least one gear unit is proposed, which is arranged in a first gripping element of the gripping elements.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Moreover, it is proposed that the driving element and the gear unit are spatially arranged between the cutting elements and the at least one self-switching coupling unit.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Moreover, it is proposed that the at least one gear unit comprises at least two gear stages, between which the at least one self-switching coupling unit is arranged.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Moreover, at least one force sensor is proposed, which is integrated in a second gripping element of the gripping elements.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Furthermore, a method is proposed for an operation of the cutting device, wherein the driving element is switched to a closing mechanism of the cutting device when a defined user force is surpassed.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Furthermore, a method step is proposed in which the driving element is automatically halted upon reaching an end position of the cutting device and is briefly driven to open the coupling unit opposite a driving direction.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Furthermore, it is proposed that the cutting device is designed to recognize an object between the gripping elements, in order to switch off the assistance mode.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Moreover, it is proposed that a sensor is arranged for the recognition of the object at the first or second gripping element, such as on the grip inside of the first or second gripping element that is opposite the other respective gripping element.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Moreover, it is proposed that a sensor, such as a force sensor and/or displacement sensor, is arranged on the first or second gripping element to detect the need for motion assistance so that the cutting device switches off the assistance mode at least when an object is arranged between the gripping elements.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Moreover, it is proposed that a force transmission element, for example connected firm against rotation to the second cutting element, is arranged between the second cutting element and the second gripping element, which stands in operative connection with the driving element and which is arranged for determining the movement assistance, for example, for determining a switching of the motion assistance on and off, being movable relative to the second gripping element.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Moreover, it is proposed that the relative movement is a swivel movement of the force transmission element relative to the second gripping element.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Moreover, it is proposed that the second gripping element comprises at least one relative movement limiting element.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Moreover, it is proposed that a sensor, such as a force sensor and/or displacement sensor, detects the relative movement.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Moreover, it is proposed that the sensor comprises a spring and a switch as well as an assistance mode adjustment element, which is arranged for example on a grip inside of the first or second gripping element.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Moreover, it is proposed that at least one of the gripping elements is configured at least on the grip insides to avoid pinching, for example, at least partly elastic, rounded, and/or beveled.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Furthermore, it is proposed that between a pivot connecting the gripping elements and an opening spring arranged between the gripping elements there is arranged a protection device between the gripping elements.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Moreover, it is proposed that the protection device receives a cable of the cutting device, for example a power supply cable or sensor cable and/or forms a locking device for locking an intermediate space which is bounded by the gripping elements, the pivot and the opening spring, for example in order to avoid at least an accidental catching of part of a user&#x2019;s body in the intermediate space.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Furthermore, a cutting device, such as a garden cutting device, with a first and a second cutting element able to move relative to each other, with a first and a second gripping element able to move relative to each other, with an opening spring arranged between the gripping elements, with at least one driving element, which in at least one operating state is provided to at least assist a movement of the second cutting element relative to the first cutting element and with at least one driving force transmission element, which stands in operative connection with the driving element at least in the one operating state.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">It is proposed that the driving force transmission element is arranged inside the opening spring.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Moreover, it is proposed that the driving force transmission element is a cable.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Moreover, it is proposed that the cable is made of polyethylene, such as polyethylene with ultrahigh molar mass.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Moreover, it is proposed that there is arranged a guide element, such as a guide sleeve, at least on one of the gripping elements, in order to guide the driving force transmission element with low friction and/or low wear.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Moreover, it is proposed that the opening spring comprises at least one guide element, in order to guide the driving force transmission element with low friction.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Moreover, it is proposed that the driving force transmission element is arranged without contact inside the opening spring.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Moreover, it is proposed that the opening spring is an evolute spring, such as a double evolute spring.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Moreover, it is proposed that the opening spring is configured such that it seals off the cavity formed by it, for example against dust and/or moisture.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Moreover, it is proposed that the ends of the opening spring are arranged in recesses of the gripping elements.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Moreover, it is proposed that the cutting device enables a manual as well as a manual-machine assisted operation.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Furthermore, it is proposed that the cutting device on or in the first gripping element the driving element, the gear unit, the coupling unit, the restoring unit and the driving element of the driving force transmission element are arranged in this sequence, with no further gearing located between the coupling unit and the driving element.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Moreover, it is proposed that the driving element connects, firm against rotation, at least one rotating component of the coupling unit and/or restoring unit, for example connects an inner rotary element of the coupling unit and a rotary body of the restoring unit firm against rotation.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Moreover, it is proposed that an inner rotary element of the coupling unit and a rotary body of the restoring unit are joined together at least frictionally or by form fitting, firm against rotation.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">Moreover, it is proposed that an inner rotary element of the coupling unit is made of metal and a rotary body of the restoring unit is made of plastic.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Moreover, it is proposed that the driving element is connected by form fit via a polygonal profile to the coupling unit and/or the restoring unit.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Moreover, it is proposed that the restoring unit and the coupling unit are at least partly accommodated in a common housing.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Moreover, it is proposed that a securing element through a cage to accommodate clamping bodies of the coupling unit secures the coupling unit and the restoring unit on the housing.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">Moreover, it is proposed that a planet carrier of the gear unit is part of the coupling unit, for example, an outer rotary element of the coupling unit.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Moreover, an assembly method is proposed at least for the assembly of a pretensioned restoring unit for the cutting device, 
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
<li id="ul0001-0001" num="0050">wherein the restoring unit comprises a spring element connected firmly to a housing and a rotary body, and at least one part of a self-switching coupling unit, such as at least one inner rotary element, a cage for accommodation of clamping bodies, and a brake element, with at least the following steps of the method:</li>
<li id="ul0001-0002" num="0051">fixation of the restoring unit via a securing element on the housing of the coupling unit,</li>
<li id="ul0001-0003" num="0052">pretensioning of the spring element by turning of the rotary body,</li>
<li id="ul0001-0004" num="0053">temporary arrangement of an assembly jig fixing the housing with the rotary body firmly against rotation, for example, between the housing and the inner rotary element.</li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0054">Moreover, an assembly method is proposed, with at least the following additional steps of the method: 
<ul id="ul0002" list-style="none">
<li id="ul0002-0001" num="0055">connecting of the pretensioned restoring unit to a driving force transmission element of the cutting device,</li>
<li id="ul0002-0002" num="0056">removal of the assembly jig to transmit the pretensioning force of the pretensioned restoring unit to the driving force transmission element, for example, for the pretensioning of the driving force transmission element with a restoring force.</li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0057">Moreover, an assembly method is proposed, with at least the first of the following additional steps of the method: 
<ul id="ul0003" list-style="none">
<li id="ul0003-0001" num="0058">rotary connecting and axial securing of an outer rotary element of the coupling unit via a connection element to an inner rotary element of the coupling unit,</li>
<li id="ul0003-0002" num="0059">connecting of the outer rotary element, designed as a planet carrier, to a gear unit.</li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0060">Furthermore, a blocking device is proposed for a battery-operated manual machine tool, for example, for a battery-operated cutting device, such as a pair of garden shears, with a first and a second cutting element able to move relatively to each other, wherein the blocking device in a first position, in which the blocking device blocks an activation and/or tool movement of the manual machine tool, releases a charging interface and in a second position, in which the blocking device releases an activation and/or tool movement of the manual machine tool, it blocks and/or covers the charging interface.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0061">Moreover, it is proposed that the blocking device is designed as a mechanical blocking device.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0062">Moreover, it is proposed that the blocking device has a sliding switch, which either releases, or blocks and/or covers the charging interface.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0063">Moreover, it is proposed that the blocking device comprises a detent element, which is designed to mechanically block or release a tool movement, such as a tool movement in the form of a relative movement of a first and a second cutting element of the manual machine tool relative to each other.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0064">Moreover, it is proposed that the charging interface is designed at least as a USB charging interface.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0065">Moreover, it is proposed that the blocking device in the second position is designed to keep away contaminants from the charging interface.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0066">Proposed that the blocking device in the second position is designed to seal off the charging interface, for example, water and/or dust-tight.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0067">Furthermore, a cutting device is proposed, such as a garden cutting device, comprising at least a first and a second cutting element able to swivel relative to each other about an axis of rotation, wherein the cutting elements are joined together by at least one connection element arranged along the axis of rotation. It is proposed that a control device is provided, which produces a defined pressing force F<sub>an</sub> of the cutting elements relative to each other in the direction of the axis of rotation, independently of the connection element, for example, independently of a clamping force of the connection element.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0068">Moreover, it is proposed that the control device comprises a spacing element, which advantageously surrounds the connection element, for example in the form of a sleeve.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0069">Moreover, it is proposed that a lengthwise dimension 1 of the spacing element in the direction of the axis of rotation corresponds at least to a sum of the width dimensions b, b of the two cutting elements along the axis of rotation.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0070">Moreover, it is proposed that the control device comprises an elastic element, such as a spring element, preferably a corrugated spring, which applies a defined axial force F<sub>ax</sub> to the cutting elements relative to each other along the axis of rotation.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0071">Moreover, it is proposed that the elastic element is arranged such that it is braced along the axis of rotation at least indirectly by the housing of the cutting device, such as by the grip housing of the gripping element, and/or at least indirectly by the spacing element.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0072">Moreover, it is proposed that the elastic element is provided as a friction adjustment element for adjusting a frictional force between the cutting elements.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0073">Moreover, it is proposed that the elastic element is designed as an overload protection element of the cutting device, in order to prevent, at least in regions, a plastic deformation of the cutting elements during operation of the cutting device or to enable at least in regions a gaping of the cutting elements during operation of the cutting device.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0074">Moreover, it is proposed that the control device rotationally decouples at least the connection element relative to the cutting elements, for example, rotationally decouples it in twist-proof manner.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0075">Moreover, it is proposed that the connection element can be screwed into an abutment of twist-proof design and/or is designed as a single piece with at least the spacing element.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0076">Furthermore, a cutting element for a pair of garden shears is proposed, comprising a cutting blade with a mount for connection to a cutting element mount of the pair of garden shears, wherein the cutting element has an insert guide for inserting the cutting element into the cutting element mount of the pair of garden shears.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0077">Moreover, it is proposed that the insert guide is fashioned as a slanting surface and/or a round surface, for example a slanting surface and/or a round surface which is designed to be not the same as a cleanly deburred edge.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0078">Moreover, it is proposed that the slanting surface has an angle &#x3b1; of less than &#xb0;, for example less than &#xb0;, especially preferably of &#xb0;, relative to a cutting surface of the cutting element.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0079">Moreover, it is proposed that the insert guide extends at least substantially between one end of the cutting element facing away from a tip of the cutting element and a recess for the fixation of the cutting element at the cutting element mount.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0080">Moreover, it is proposed that the insert guide is designed for at least indirect spreading of an elastic element arranged at the cutting element mount.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0081">Moreover, it is proposed that the cutting element is an interchangeable cutting element for the pair of garden shears.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0082">Moreover, it is proposed that the cutting element comprises at least one form-fitting element for connection, firm against rotation, to a lever of the pair of garden shears, which can be connected to a gripping element of the pair of garden shears</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0083">Moreover, a cutting device is proposed, especially preferably a battery-operated pair of garden shears, with a first cutting element of this kind and a second cutting element of this kind.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0084">This cutting device can comprise a control device, which produces a defined pressing force F<sub>an</sub> of the first cutting element and the second cutting element relative to each other, wherein the insert guide is provided at least for the spreading of the control device during a replacement of the cutting element.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0085">Moreover, the cutting device can enable a manual as well as a manual-machine assisted operation.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0086">Preferably, the cutting device is designed as a pair of shears, especially preferably as a pair of garden shears. Preferably, the two blades which can move relative to each other are mounted so as to be able to swivel relative to each other. By a &#x201c;garden cutting device&#x201d; is meant in this context, for example, a cutting device intended for use on plants. Preferably, it means for example a cutting device which is provided for a trimming of plants, hedges, shrubs, branches, and/or other objects appearing sensible to a skilled person. By a &#x201c;cutting element&#x201d; is meant in this context, for example, an element of the cutting device which is provided for a direct contacting with an object to be cut. Preferably, it means an element which is provided for a direct dividing of an object to be cut. Basically, it is conceivable that at least one of the cutting elements is of passive design, such as an anvil and/or a passive cutting edge. Preferably, however, at least one cutting element has an active cutting edge, such as a blade, which is provided for an active cutting. Moreover, in this context, by a &#x201c;gripping element&#x201d; is meant, for example, an element which forms at least part of a handle.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0087">Preferably, it means an element which is grasped at least partly by a user during operation. Preferably, both gripping elements are grasped by a user during operation, for example, with the same hand. By &#x201c;a movement of the second cutting element relative to the first cutting element is assisted&#x201d; is meant in this context, for example, that the driving element generates a force which acts at least partly in a direction which is the same as that of the user&#x2019;s force. Preferably, it means that a manual force, which produces for example a closing movement of the cutting elements relative to each other, is assisted in at least one operating state by a force additionally generated by the driving element.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0088">By a &#x201c;self-switching coupling unit&#x201d; is meant in this context for example a coupling unit which is activated free of external, for example electrical, switching signals, such as those of a control unit. Preferably, it means a coupling unit which is activated free of explicit switching signals, such as those for a switching between coupling states. Preferably, it means for example a coupling unit which is activated on the basis of mechanical factors of influence. Especially preferably it means for example a coupling unit which is activated in dependence on at least one parameter of a drive and/or power takeoff side. The coupling unit can therefore be designed, for example, to be speed-activated, torque-activated, direction-activated and/or force-flow activated. Moreover, in this context by a &#x201c;decoupling of the driving element&#x201d; is meant, for example, a decoupling of the driving element from a closing mechanism of the cutting device.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0089">Thanks to the design of the cutting device according to the disclosure, an advantageous decoupling of the driving element can be accomplished. In this way, for example, an advantageously easy manual operation of the cutting device is made possible. Moreover, a coupling unit can advantageously be provided which is activated advantageously free of electrical switching signals. In this way, for example, there is no need for a control unit for an actuating of the coupling unit. Preferably, in this way an especially reliable coupling unit can be provided. For example, a coupling unit can be provided which is designed to be activatable independently of a power supply.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0090">By a &#x201c;full manual operation&#x201d; is meant in this context for example an operating state in which the cutting device is operated free of an assistance by the driving element. Preferably, it means an operating state in which the cutting device is operated exclusively through the active force of a user. Especially preferably it means an operating state in which the driving element is decoupled and therefore cannot be used for an assistance of the movement of the second cutting element relative to the first cutting element. To become. In this way, for example, an advantageously smooth manual operation of the cutting device is made possible. For example, in this way one can use the cutting device advantageously even without the driving element, such as when there is no power supply, and/or for easy cutting work.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0091">By a &#x201c;freewheel clutch&#x201d; is meant in this context for example a self-switching coupling which is designed to be direction-activated and/or force-flow activated. Preferably, the freewheel clutch is at least direction-activated. Preferably, the freewheel clutch is designed to open and/or close depending on a direction of rotation, for example of a driving side and/or power takeoff side of the coupling unit, and/or depending on a direction of force acting on the freewheel clutch. In the case of a direction of acting force, for example, one can distinguish whether the force is acting from the driving side or from the power takeoff side on the freewheel clutch. Preferably, the freewheel clutch is designed to open or close the driving element in at least one operating state depending on a direction of rotation, for example of a driving and/or power takeoff side, and/or depending on a direction of force acting on the freewheel clutch. In this way, for example, an especially advantageous self-switching coupling unit can be provided. For example, in this way an advantageously smooth manual operation of the cutting device can be made possible. Preferably, in this way an especially reliable coupling unit can be provided.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0092">By a &#x201c;clamping body&#x201d; is meant in this context for example an element of the coupling unit which in at least one operating state, for example in a closed state of the coupling unit, is designed to clamp between two rotary elements of the coupling unit which are mounted rotatably relative to each other. Preferably, the clamping body is connected in a clamped state to one rotary element by form fitting in one direction of rotation, and to the other rotary element by force fitting in the direction of rotation, such as by friction. Preferably, it means for example an element which is designed to couple together, firm against rotation, the rotary elements of the coupling unit depending on an operating state of the coupling unit or decouple the rotary elements of the coupling unit from each other in regard to a movement in the circumferential direction. Preferably, the clamping bodies are clamped in a closed state of the coupling unit between the rotary elements. Preferably, at least one of the rotary elements of the coupling unit comprises ramps, by which a radial spacing between the rotary elements is changed. If the clamping bodies are moved into a region with a slight radial spacing, the rampless rotary element is rotated along by means of friction. If the clamping bodies are moved into a region with a large radial spacing, no rotary entrainment of the rampless rotary element occurs, since the friction is not sufficient. Various clamping bodies which appear expedient to a skilled person are conceivable, but preferably the clamping bodies are at least partially cylindrical or at least partially spherical in shape. In this way, for example, an especially advantageous self-switching coupling unit can be provided.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0093">For example, in this way an advantageous, for example a simple-design freewheel clutch can be provided. Preferably, in this way an especially reliable self-switching coupling unit can be provided.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0094">Preferably, the coupling unit comprises several clamping bodies, which are received in the same cage. Preferably, the cage receives the clamping bodies in receiving areas separate from each other. Preferably, the brake element is provided in at least one operating state to increase the inertia of the cage. Preferably, the brake element is designed to hinder an unwanted turning of the cage. Especially preferably, the brake element is designed to prevent a rotation of the cage until a definite force is acting. Preferably, the brake element is spring loaded. For example, the brake element is pressed with a defined force against the cage. By &#x201c;cage&#x201d; is meant in this context for example an element of the coupling unit which is provided for a positioning and/or guidance of the at least one clamping body, for example, in the circumferential direction. Preferably, the cage is designed to space apart several clamping bodies in the circumferential direction and distribute them, for example uniformly about a periphery. Especially preferably, the cage is designed to guide several clamping bodies in the circumferential direction relative to each other. In this way, for example, an advantageously defined movement of the clamping bodies can be achieved. For example, with several clamping bodies it can be accomplished that the clamping bodies execute the same movement in the circumferential direction. Preferably a controlled clamping of the clamping bodies can be made possible.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0095">Moreover, the brake element can prevent an unwanted movement of the at least one clamping body. For example, an unwanted clamping can be prevented in this way. Furthermore, one can in this way make sure that the clamping bodies are only turned upon action of a force of a form-fitting rotary element of the coupling unit. For example, the brake element can reliably achieve an opening of the coupling unit. Preferably, with the brake element one can make sure that the clamping bodies stand still during an opening movement of the coupling unit and thus allow an opening of the coupling unit.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0096">Preferably the cable is firmly fixed to one gripping element and secured to the other gripping element via the cable winch. For example, a free length of the cable can be changed via the cable winch. Preferably the cable winch can be driven via the coupling unit by the driving element. Preferably the cable winch in at least one operating state can be separated via the coupling unit from the driving element. Especially preferably, the cable winch forms a power takeoff side of the coupling unit. By a &#x201c;cable winch&#x201d; is meant in this context for example a cable drum, such as a cylindrical cable drum, which in at least one operating state can be driven by a driving element. In this way, an advantageous action of the force of the driving element can be achieved. For example, in this way a simple design is made possible for assisting the motion of the second cutting element relative to the first cutting element. A user can thus be advantageously assisted by the driving element during a closing movement. Moreover, thanks to the action of the force of the driving element on the gripping elements an advantageously high torque can be provided. This, in turn, can keep the power of a driving element low.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0097">Furthermore, it is proposed that the at least one cable is stretched between the gripping elements in a region between a grip region of the gripping elements and a pivot by which the gripping elements can swivel relative to each other. Preferably, the cable is stretched between the gripping elements near the pivot, for example closer than 10 cm, preferably closer than 8 cm to the pivot. By a &#x201c;grip region&#x201d; in this context is meant for example a region of the gripping elements in which the gripping elements are regularly grasped by a user. In this way, it can be advantageously prevented that a user will be disturbed by the cable. Furthermore, the cable can advantageously be embodied to be short. In this way, for example, a cable winch can advantageously be small in design. Moreover, a fast closing of the cutting device can be made possible with a low speed of the cable winch.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0098">It is further proposed that the cutting device comprises at least one spring element connected to the cable winch, which is designed for example as a spiral spring and which is provided for a tensioning of the cable in at least one operating state. Preferably the spring element is intended to ensure a tensioning of the cable. Preferably the spring element is designed to apply a force to the cable winch, such as a force in the circumferential direction. Especially preferably, the spring element is designed to produce a tensile force on the cable via the cable winch. For example, the cable should be kept taut via the spring element. Preferably the spring element has a spring force which is less than the spring force of an opening spring. Thanks to the spring element, for example, even in a full manual operation a tensioning of the cable can be assured. Thus, advantageously, an unwanted knotting of the cable can be prevented. Furthermore, a winding of the cable without drive power can be assured.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0099">By a &#x201c;gear unit&#x201d; is meant in this context for example a step-up gear unit with a transmission ratio larger than 2, preferably larger than 10 and especially preferably larger than 50. In this way, an advantageously compact design can be achieved. Moreover, in this way an especially advantageous weight distribution can be achieved. For example, a weight of the gear unit can be arranged directly in a region of one hand of a user. This, in turn, can achieve a good operating comfort. Moreover, in this way for example the look of traditional manual pair of garden shears can be at least resembled.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0100">Preferably the force sensor is coupled to a grip region of the second gripping element. Especially preferably, the grip region is mounted movably to a base body of the second gripping element. Preferably the force sensor is designed to sense a force acting on the second gripping element, for example relative to the first gripping element. Preferably the force sensor can be adapted to detect both a precise force and only an exceeding of a limit force.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0101">Moreover, a method is proposed for the operation of a cutting device. It is proposed that, upon exceeding a defined user force, the driving element is switched on for a closing mechanism of the cutting device. In this way, an advantageously comfortable cutting device can be provided. Moreover, for example, one can ensure that the driving element is switched on only for heavy cutting work. In this way, the energy consumption can be kept low.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0102">By a &#x201c;driving direction&#x201d; is meant for example a direction of rotation of the driving element in which the driving element turns during a regular operation, for example, for an assisting of a cutting movement. In this way, a fast opening of the cutting device can advantageously be made possible. For example, an advantageously intuitive operation can be accomplished in this way. An opening of the coupling unit can reliably be made possible.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0103">Alternatively it is proposed that, upon reaching an end position of the cutting device, the driving element is automatically deactivated and the coupling unit is spontaneously decoupled upon absence of a rotary movement of the driving element. In this way, a rapid opening of the cutting device can advantageously be made possible. For example, an advantageously intuitive operation can be accomplished in this way.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0104">A blocking device for a battery-operated manual machine tool is disclosed, especially for a battery-operated cutting device. It is proposed that the blocking device in a first position, in which the blocking device blocks an activation and/or tool movement of the manual machine tool, releases a charging interface and in a second position, in which the blocking device releases an activation and/or tool movement of the manual machine tool, it blocks and/or covers the charging interface. Advantageously, in this way an activation of the manual machine tool in the charging state can be prevented. The potential for injury is minimized. The manual machine tool is more safe. An inadvertent separation of the charging cable is prevented. The danger of electric shock to a user of the manual machine tool upon accidental severing of the charging cable is minimized. The electronics and control system of the manual machine tool are protected, since a simultaneous operation and charging of the manual machine tool is prevented. Thus, the often miniaturized electronics cannot become overheated. Damage to the manual machine tool is avoided. The charging interface is protected against mechanical influences or effects, especially damage, during operation of the manual machine tool. Fouling and corrosion at and in the charging interface is prevented. The lifetime of the charging interface is increased.</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0105">Moreover it is proposed that the blocking device is designed as a mechanical blocking device. Advantageously, the blocking device can have a robust design in this way. The elements of the blocking device can be manufactured easily and cheaply. It is able to safely withstand operating forces and transport stress without becoming damaged.</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0106">Furthermore, it is proposed that the blocking device has a sliding switch, which either releases, or blocks and/or covers the charging interface. Advantageously, a sliding switch is easy to activate. It can be easily guided in the housing of the manual machine tool. It can be easily installed when the manual machine tool has a two-shell design. It allows a good grip and ergonomic use.</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0107">Furthermore, it is proposed that the blocking device comprises a detent element, which is designed to mechanically block or release a tool movement, in particular a tool movement in the form of a relative movement of two cutting blades of the manual machine tool relative to each other. A detent element advantageously affords a detachable form-fitting connection. It can be manufactured cheaply. It is sturdy.</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0108">Furthermore, it is proposed that the charging interface is designed at least as a USB charging interface. Advantageously, the manual machine tool can therefore be charged with any charging device, for example, that for mobile radio devices. The charging interface is compact and dependable and is widely used as the standard in the IT industry. It is also possible to charge with no problems through a USB charging interface in a vehicle or at least its cigarette lighter, making possible a mobile charging. Moreover, device data can be read out via the USB interface, especially during a charging process, a software update can be loaded, or a fault diagnostics can be performed for the manual machine tool.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0109">Moreover it is proposed that the blocking device in the second position is provided to keep contaminants away from the charging interface. Furthermore, it is proposed that the blocking device seals off the charging interface in the second position, in particular in watertight manner. Advantageously, in this way the charging interface is protected against a penetration of dirt or moisture during operation of the manual machine tool. Thus, the penetration of dirt or moisture especially into the electronic components of the manual machine tool is prevented in this way. An error-free operation or constant functionality of the manual machine tool is assured.</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0110">Furthermore, it is proposed that the battery-operated manual machine tool is a pair of garden shears, preferably a pair of garden shears which enables a pure manual as well as a manual-machine assisted operation. The cutting elements of the pair of garden shears in the unblocked state present a risk of injury to the user. This is heightened on account of the electromechanically activatable assistance. Furthermore, a battery-operated pair of garden shears, especially a pair of garden shears which is adapted for single-hand operation, should be as compact as possible. Thanks to the blocking device according to the disclosure, the charging interface can be compact and resistant to dirt and moisture. Thanks to the combination of the charging interface cover and the blocking of the activation and/or tool movement, the number of components can be kept small. A compact and weight-saving design of the manual machine tool is realized.</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0111">Moreover, it is disclosed that the cutting elements comprise through-boreholes in the direction of the axis of rotation, through which the connection element protrudes. The radial surfaces of the through-boreholes of the cutting elements form bearing surfaces, which are rotatably mounted in particular on a corresponding bearing surface of the control device, especially a sleeve radially enclosing the connection element, especially as a sliding bearing. By a &#x201c;clamping force&#x201d; is meant in particular an axial force generated by the connection element or a pretensioning force of the connection element. The connection element is in particular at least one screw and one screw nut. By the &#x201c;pressing force&#x201d; is meant in particular a force by which the axial sliding surfaces of the cutting elements are pressed against each other at least in the region of the connection element. In dependence on the pressing force of the cutting elements, an activating force for the turning or swiveling of the cutting elements that is applied to the gripping elements must be greater or smaller.</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0112">Advantageously, thanks to the control device the problems with cutting devices of the prior art are solved. The pressing force or the pretensioning force can be preadjusted. Independently of the force applied by a user and/or the tightening torque of the connection element, the pressing force of the cutting elements is at least practically constant. The cutting result is improved. A gaping, especially a plastic deformation of the cutting elements, is prevented, and the durability of the cutting device is improved.</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0113">Furthermore, it is proposed that the control device comprises a spacing element, which advantageously surrounds the connection element, especially in the form of a sleeve. The spacing element can be designed as a single piece with the connection element. The spacing element can also form the connection element. The spacing element establishes the spacing, especially a minimum spacing, of two clamping force transmission elements of the connection element in the direction of the axis of rotation. The clamping force transmission elements are in particular the screw head and the screw nut of the screw which transmit a pretensioning force at least partly to the spacing element and/or at least indirectly to the axial surfaces of the cutting elements. This serves to accomplish a minimum spacing of the two cutting elements in the direction of the axis of rotation at least in the region of the connection element, advantageously in the connection or sliding region of the cutting blades. The spacing element can also space apart the cutting elements in the radial direction of the connection element. In this way, the connection cross section of the cutting elements and the connection element or the control device is increased. This, in turn, enables a greater toughness of the cutting device. A suitability of the pair of garden shears for transmitting larger forces especially during a force assistance mode can be realized.</p>
<p id="p-0107" num="0114">Moreover, it is proposed that a lengthwise dimension of the spacing element in the direction of the axis of rotation corresponds to at least a sum of the widths of the two cutting elements along the axis of rotation, especially to at least a sum of the widths of the two cutting elements in the region of the recess of the cutting elements. In this way, independently of the clamping force of the connection element and/or the tightening torque of a connection screw, an at least minimum play can be guaranteed between the cutting elements, so that it is assured that the cutting device can be activated.</p>
<p id="p-0108" num="0115">Furthermore, it is proposed that the control device comprises an elastic element, especially a spring element, which applies a defined axial force or clamping force along the axis of rotation to the cutting elements relative to each other. The elastic element is advantageously disposed at least so that it braces at least indirectly one of the cutting elements axially in regard to the spacing element. The elastic element can be designed as a friction adjustment element for adjusting a friction force between the cutting elements. Advantageously, in this way, a constant basic activating force can be established for the closing of the cutting device. Independently of a manufacturing width of the cutting blade within a tolerance band, the pressing force of the cutting elements relative to one another is always approximately constant. In this way, a replacement of the cutting element is possible without further adjusting of the clamping force of the screw. In the case of cutting elements of different size, different elastic elements with different spring stiffness can be used, depending on the cutting blade used, without having to change the connection element.</p>
<p id="p-0109" num="0116">It is proposed that the elastic element is disposed such that it is braced along the axis of rotation at least indirectly by the housing of the cutting device, especially the grip housing and/or at least indirectly by the spacing element. Thanks to the bracing on the housing, the connection element and especially the connection and spacing elements can be removed, for example to replace a cutting element, while the elastic element continues to be securely accommodated in the cutting device. Furthermore, the cutting element to be removed or which is replaceable is also secured at least against falling out from the cutting device even without the connection element installed. Thus, in this way, the operating comfort of the cutting device can be further simplified, especially when replacing a cutting element. The abutment, especially the screw nut of the connection element, is preferably likewise received firm against twisting in the housing of the cutting device, especially the grip housing, in particular, by a hexagonal form-fitting element. In this way, the operating comfort can be further enhanced when removing the connection element, for example, to replace the cutting element.</p>
<p id="p-0110" num="0117">Furthermore, it is proposed that the elastic element is provided as a friction adjustment element for adjusting a friction force between the cutting elements. Thus, for example, a gaping dimension can be made adjustable, for example in order to handle different materials to be cut, different cutting elements and/or different cutting purposes in simple manner with a single cutting device.</p>
<p id="p-0111" num="0118">Furthermore, it is proposed that the elastic element is designed as an overload protection element of the cutting device, so as to prevent at least in regions a plastic deformation of the cutting elements during operation of the cutting device, or to make possible at least in regions a gaping of the cutting elements during the operation of the cutting device. Thanks to the elastic element, a threshold value is adjusted, as it were, after which the cutting element can elastically gape open. Thus, even when the cutting device is overloaded, for example by an attempt to cut a branch which is too thick or material which is too strong, no damage to the cutting device results. The elastic behavior and the desirable gaping when a certain criterion is surpassed thus protects the cutting device and likewise increases its service life.</p>
<p id="p-0112" num="0119">Furthermore, it is proposed that the control device rotationally decouples the connection element from the cutting elements, in particular in a twist-proof manner. Thus, the operationally-required rotation or swiveling of the cutting elements advantageously does not cause any loosening or twisting of the connection element. For this, the control device and/or the connection element can provide at least one detent element for the rotational fixation of the control device and/or the connection element about the axis of rotation. For example, a detent element arranged on a washer serves as a twist-preventing element, interacting with a detent recess in the grip housing or a built-on part. Moreover, the connection element and/or the spacing element or a ring especially securing the elastic element can be mounted twist-proof in the grip housing.</p>
<p id="p-0113" num="0120">Moreover it is proposed that the connection element can be screwed into the stationary cutting element and/or is fashioned in particular as a single piece with at least the spacing element.</p>
<p id="p-0114" num="0121">Furthermore, it is proposed that the cutting device is in particular a pair of garden shears, especially preferably a battery-operated pair of garden shears which enables a manual as well as a manual-machine assisted operation.</p>
<p id="p-0115" num="0122">It is proposed that the cutting element comprises an insert guide for introducing the cutting element into the cutting element mount of the pair of garden shears. The mount for connection to a cutting element mount of the pair of garden shears is advantageously designed as a borehole or recess. Through the recess, a connection element especially in the form of a screw and/or sleeve can be inserted for the fixation to the cutting element mount of the pair of garden shears. The connection element serves as a rotary bearing for the cutting element and forms with it a pivot. Advantageously, a changing of the cutting element can be simplified by the insert guide.</p>
<p id="p-0116" num="0123">Moreover, it is proposed that the insert guide be fashioned as a slanting surface and/or a round surface, not like a pure deburred edge and/or round surface. By a pure deburred edge is meant, for example, a broken edge, especially an edge broken at an angle of 45&#xb0;, in order to prevent injury when grabbing or grasping the cutting element. A pure deburred edge can also be a rounded edge. The sector lengths of the broken edge are substantially the same. On the contrary, the slanting surface according to the disclosure has a distinct difference regarding the length of the sectors of the beveled edges, especially in a ratio of at least 1:3. Thanks to the slanting surface, the cutting element is wedge-shaped in the region of the insert guide. The slanting surface serves advantageously for the spreading of the cutting element mount, especially the spring-loaded cutting element mount, when inserting or changing the cutting element.</p>
<p id="p-0117" num="0124">Furthermore, it is proposed that the slanting surface has an angle of less than 30&#xb0;, especially less than 15&#xb0;, especially preferably 5&#xb0; relative to a cutting surface of the cutting element. Advantageously, in this way a large spring force of the cutting element mount of the pair of garden shears can be overcome when introducing the cutting element. A thickness of the cutting element decreases between the mount and the end of the cutting element, especially from 3.5 mm also 2.7 mm.</p>
<p id="p-0118" num="0125">Furthermore, it is proposed that the insert guide extends at least substantially between an end of the cutting element facing away from a tip of the cutting element and a recess for fixation of the cutting element on the cutting element mount. By &#x201c;substantially&#x201d; is meant in this context a region of more than 50%, especially more than 75%, especially preferably 85%. Advantageously, in this way one can achieve, on the one hand, an easy spreading of the cutting element mount of the pair of garden shears. Moreover, the region around the recess is not weakened. Furthermore, a sufficient bearing surface is preserved parallel to the cutting plane, which is braced at least axially along an axis of rotation against the other cutting element of the pair of garden shears, especially in addition against a lever of the cutting device.</p>
<p id="p-0119" num="0126">Furthermore, it is proposed that the insert guide is designed for the at least indirect spreading of an elastic element arranged on the pair of garden shears. Advantageously, the elastic element can be spread by the insert guide with no further aids, merely with the manual force of a user when inserting the cutting element into the pair of garden shears. Thanks to the elastic element, in turn, further benefits can be achieved, such as an overload protection of the pair of garden shears, a securing of the cutting element against unintentional dropping of the cutting element out from the pair of garden shears during a replacement of the cutting element, or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0120" num="0127">Furthermore, it is proposed that the cutting element is an interchangeable cutting element for the pair of garden shears. Advantageously, the cutting element can be replaced when the blade is worn, or different cutting blades can be used for example for the cutting of different materials and changed in easy manner.</p>
<p id="p-0121" num="0128">Moreover, it is proposed that the cutting element comprises at least a form-fitting element for connection, firm against rotation, to a lever of the pair of garden shears, which can be connected to a gripping element of the pair of garden shears, the lever and the cutting element having a coaxial recess transverse to the cutting surface of the cutting element by which they can be located on a pivot of the pair of garden shears and are able to swivel. Advantageously, an operation of the pair of garden shears assisted by a driving force can be realized in this way. Moreover, the disposition of the lever can protect the fingers from being pinched. A good force transmission and a good interchangeability of the cutting element are improved in this way.</p>
<p id="p-0122" num="0129">Furthermore, a cutting device is proposed, especially preferably a battery-operated pair of garden shears having a cutting element according to the disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0123" num="0130">Moreover, a cutting device is proposed which comprises a control device, producing a defined pressing force of the cutting element and an additional cutting element against each other, wherein the insert guide is provided for the spreading of the control device when replacing the cutting element. The control device preferably comprises the elastic element. In this way, an overload protection, a defined gaping, a simplified cutting element replacement or the like can be advantageously achieved.</p>
<p id="p-0124" num="0131">Furthermore, a cutting device is proposed which enables a manual as well as a manual-machine assisted operation.</p>
<p id="p-0125" num="0132">Cutting device, such as a garden cutting device, with a first and a second cutting element able to move relative to each other, with a first and a second gripping element able to move relative to each other, and with at least one driving element, which in at least one operating state is provided to at least assist a movement of the second cutting element relative to the first cutting element, and a spring element, characterized in that the spring element is designed as a tensioning element for the tensioning of a driving force transmission element driven by the driving element, such as one in the form of a cable, such as a cable which can be at least partly wound onto a cable winch.</p>
<p id="p-0126" num="0133">Cutting device characterized in that the spring element is designed as a spiral spring, for example a spiral spring connected to a cable winch and/or accommodated in the cable winch.</p>
<p id="p-0127" num="0134">Cutting device characterized by at least one gear unit, for example a multistage gear unit, such as one in the form of a multistage planet gear unit, wherein the gear unit is disposed in the first gripping element, for example between the driving element and the self-switching coupling unit.</p>
<p id="p-0128" num="0135">Cutting device, such as a pair of garden shears or battery-operated pair of garden shears, characterized in that the cutting device enables a manual as well as a manual-machine assisted operation.</p>
<p id="p-0129" num="0136">Cutting device, characterized in that the spring element is designed as an elastic element for generating a defined pressing force of the two cutting elements against each other in the direction of an axis of rotation of the cutting elements and independently of a clamping force (F<sub>klemm</sub>) of a connection element of the two cutting elements.</p>
<p id="p-0130" num="0137">Cutting device, characterized in that the cutting device comprises a blocking device, which in a first position, in which the blocking device blocks an activation and/or tool movement of the manual machine tool, releases a charging interface and in a second position in which the blocking device releases an activation and/or tool movement of the manual machine tool it blocks and/or covers the charging interface.</p>
<p id="p-0131" num="0138">Cutting device, characterized in that the cutting device comprises a cutting element, having a cutting blade with a mount for connection to a cutting element mount of the cutting device, wherein the cutting element comprises an insert guide for introducing the cutting element into the cutting element mount of the pair of garden shears.</p>
<p id="p-0132" num="0139">Furthermore, a cutting device includes a first gripping element, a first cutting element extending from the first gripping element, a second gripping element operably connected to the first gripping element at a pivot and configured to move relative to the first gripping element about the pivot, and a second cutting element extending from the second gripping element and configured for movement relative to the first cutting element about the pivot. The cutting device further includes an opening spring extending from the first gripping element and the second gripping element, and a protection device located (i) between the first gripping element and the second gripping element, and (ii) between the pivot and the opening spring. An intermediate space is defined between the pivot and the opening spring. The protection device at least partially fills the intermediate space, such that objects are prevented from being inserted into the intermediate space.</p>
<p id="p-0133" num="0140">Moreover, a cutting device includes a first gripping element defining a grip housing space, a first cutting element extending from the first gripping element, a second gripping element operably connected to the first gripping element at a pivot and configured to move relative to the first gripping element about the pivot, and a second cutting element extending from the second gripping element and configured for movement relative to the first cutting element about the pivot. The cutting device further includes a driving element located in the grip housing space, a gear unit operably located in the grip housing space and operably connected to the driving element, and a driving force transmission element partially located in the grip housing space and operably connected to the gear unit and the second gripping element to transfer a force from the driving element to the second gripping element for closing the first cutting element and the second cutting element about the pivot.</p>
<p id="p-0134" num="0141">Furthermore, a cutting device includes a first gripping element, a first cutting element non-movably extending from the first gripping element, a second gripping element operably connected to the first gripping element at a first pivot and configured to move relative to the first gripping element about the first pivot, and a second cutting element operably connected to the second gripping element at a second pivot and configured for movement (i) relative to the first cutting element about the first pivot, and (ii) relative to the second gripping element about the second pivot.</p>
<p id="p-0135" num="0142">Furthermore, a cutting device includes a first cutting element, a second cutting element, a first gripping element, a second gripping element, at least one driving element, a sensor, and a control unit. The first cutting element and the second cutting element are configured to move relative to each other. The first gripping element and the second gripping element are configured to move relative to each other. The first gripping element extends from the first cutting element, and the second gripping element extends from the second cutting element. The at least one driving element is configured to move the first cutting element relative to the second cutting element when the at least one driving element is activated. The sensor is mounted on or in the first gripping element or the second gripping element and is configured to detect an object located between the first gripping element and the second gripping element. The control unit is operably connected to the at least one driving element and the sensor. The control unit is configured to deactivate the at least one driving element when the sensor detects the object.</p>
<p id="p-0136" num="0143">Moreover, a method for operating a cutting device includes activating at least one driving element for moving (i) a first cutting element and a first gripping element relative to (ii) a second cutting element and a second gripping element. The first griping element extends from the first cutting element and the second gripping element extends from the second cutting element. The method further includes sensing an object located between the first gripping element and the second gripping element with a sensor during the activation of the at least one driving element. The sensor is mounted on or in the first gripping element or the second gripping element. The method also includes switching off the at least one driving element, using a control unit, by deactivating the at least one driving element when the sensor detects the object. The control unit is operably connected to the at least one driving element and the sensor.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading level="1" id="h-0003">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0137" num="0144">Further benefits will emerge from the following drawing description. The drawings show a sample embodiment of the disclosure. The drawing, the description, and the claims contain numerous features in combination. The skilled person will also expediently consider the features individually and assemble them into further meaningful combinations.</p>
<p id="p-0138" num="0145">There are shown:</p>
<p id="p-0139" num="0146"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> shows a cutting device according to the disclosure with two cutting elements and two gripping elements in a closed state,</p>
<p id="p-0140" num="0147"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> shows the cutting device in an opened state, wherein a force assistance mode is deactivated, as well as an enlarged representation of a force sensor of the cutting device,</p>
<p id="p-0141" num="0148"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> shows the cutting device of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, but wherein a force assistance mode is activated,</p>
<p id="p-0142" num="0149"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> shows the gear unit, the coupling unit, the restoring unit and the cable winch of the cutting device in a schematic sectional representation of Detail I,</p>
<p id="p-0143" num="0150"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> shows the coupling unit and the restoring unit of the cutting device in a schematic sectional representation of Detail II,</p>
<p id="p-0144" num="0151"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> shows the coupling unit of the cutting device in a coupled state, or in the assistance mode, in a schematic sectional representation in cross section IV-IV,</p>
<p id="p-0145" num="0152"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> shows the coupling unit of the cutting device in a decoupled state in a schematic sectional representation in cross section IV-IV,</p>
<p id="p-0146" num="0153"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> shows the coupling unit of the cutting device in a schematic sectional representation in cross section V-V,</p>
<p id="p-0147" num="0154"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref> shows the restoring unit of the cutting device in a schematic sectional representation in cross section VI-VI,</p>
<p id="p-0148" num="0155"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref> shows a flow chart of a method for an operation of the cutting device,</p>
<p id="p-0149" num="0156"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b></figref> shows a blocking device in a sectional representation of Detail III as well as a partial cutout view of the blocking device, in a first state,</p>
<p id="p-0150" num="0157"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>12</b></figref> shows a blocking device in a sectional representation of Detail III&#x2032; as well as a partial cutout view of the blocking device, in a second state,</p>
<p id="p-0151" num="0158"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>13</b></figref> shows a cutting element mount of the cutting device in a sectional representation in cross section III&#x2032;-III&#x2032;,</p>
<p id="p-0152" num="0159"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>14</b></figref> shows a cutting element for the cutting device in a top view and a side view, and</p>
<p id="p-0153" num="0160"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>15</b></figref> shows a representation of the cutting element connected to a force transmission element.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading level="1" id="h-0004">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0154" num="0161"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> shows a cutting device <b>10</b> according to the disclosure. The cutting device <b>10</b> is designed as a garden cutting device. The cutting device <b>10</b> is designed as a pair of garden shears. The cutting device is designed as a battery-operated cutting device <b>10</b>. Basically, however, another design of the cutting device <b>10</b> would also be conceivable, such as a pair of carpet or sheet metal shears or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0155" num="0162">The cutting device <b>10</b> has two cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> able to move relative to each other (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>, <b>3</b></figref>). The cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> can swivel relative to each other. A first cutting element <b>12</b> is in this case designed as a passive blade with a cutting edge. The second cutting element <b>14</b> is designed as an active blade with a blade. Moreover, the cutting device <b>10</b> comprises two gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> able to move relative to each other. The gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> can swivel or rotate relative to each other. The gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> are able to swivel relative to each other by at least one pivot <b>42</b>. The cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> are likewise able to swivel relative to each other by the pivot <b>42</b>. The pivot <b>42</b> is disposed between the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> and the cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b>. The first gripping element <b>16</b> and the first cutting element <b>12</b> are joined together and arranged on different sides of the pivot <b>42</b>. Moreover, the second gripping element <b>18</b> and the second cutting element <b>14</b> are at least indirectly joined together and arranged on different sides of the pivot <b>42</b>. A force transmission element <b>800</b>, here in the form of a lever <b>80</b>, connects the second cutting element <b>14</b> to the second gripping element <b>18</b>. The gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> are designed to be grasped by a user. The gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> are designed to be grasped by a user with the same hand. Basically, however, it would also be conceivable for the cutting device <b>10</b> to be designed for a two-handed operation. For example, additional lever and or transmission elements could be provided in order to alter a cutting force F<sub>cut</sub> at least partly relative to the force applied to the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>, especially an operating force F<sub>user</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0156" num="0163">Furthermore, between the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> is arranged an opening spring <b>50</b>. The opening spring <b>50</b> is arranged in regard to a lengthwise dimension of the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> closer to the pivot <b>42</b> than to a free end of the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>. The opening spring <b>50</b> is designed as a compression spring. The ends of the opening spring <b>50</b> are braced against the first and second gripping element <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>. The opening spring <b>50</b> is designed to force apart the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> and thereby open the cutting device <b>10</b>. The opening spring <b>50</b> is moreover designed to receive and/or guide, in a cavity formed by the latter, a driving force transmission element <b>340</b>, here in the form of a cable <b>34</b>, standing in operative connection with a driving element <b>20</b>, as further explained below.</p>
<p id="p-0157" num="0164">Moreover, between the opening spring <b>50</b> and the pivot <b>42</b> is arranged a protection device <b>300</b>. The protection device <b>300</b> extends between the two gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>. The protection device <b>300</b> is advantageously connected firmly to the second gripping element <b>18</b>. The protection device <b>300</b> moreover is movably mounted in the first gripping element <b>16</b>. The protection device can be designed, for example, as a telescopic device or as a rigid device. The protection device <b>300</b> is provided to protect at least one cable (not shown) of the cutting device <b>10</b>, which is led for example from the first into the second gripping element <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>, against external influences and/or to mount it securely between the first and second gripping element <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>. The cable for example is a cable for the electrical connection of an energy storage unit <b>54</b> and a control unit <b>52</b> and/or a driving element <b>20</b> or a sensor cable, which is led from a <b>401</b> to the control unit <b>52</b>. The protection device <b>300</b>, however, also narrows an otherwise free intermediate space <b>301</b> between the pivot <b>42</b> and the opening spring <b>50</b> or fills it up at least partly, so that the user for example can only with difficulty stick his finger inadvertently into this intermediate space or a material being cut such as a twig or a branch can only with difficulty get caught in this intermediate space. Accordingly, the protection device <b>300</b> is also a locking device for the intermediate space <b>301</b>. In the intermediate space <b>301</b> between the pivot <b>42</b> and the opening spring <b>50</b> is especially a danger of pinching of an object <b>17</b>, especially the fingers or skin of a user, since the forces operating in this a are high on account of the leverage or lever length of the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> around the pivot <b>42</b>. Thus, thanks to the protection device <b>300</b> a protected and secure leading of electronic region parts between the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> is assured. Furthermore, the protection device <b>300</b> serves to prevent injury.</p>
<p id="p-0158" num="0165">Moreover, the cutting device <b>10</b> comprises a driving element <b>20</b>. The driving element <b>20</b> is designed as an electric motor. The electric motor is designed to be powered with a voltage less than 110 V, especially with a voltage of 1 V to 36 V, preferably 3.6 V. The driving element <b>20</b> is arranged in the first gripping element <b>16</b>. The driving element <b>20</b> is arranged in a grip housing <b>44</b> of the gripping element <b>16</b>. The driving element <b>20</b> is arranged at an end of the first gripping element <b>16</b> facing away from the cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b>. The grip housing <b>44</b> comprises two housing shells, in which the driving element <b>20</b> is firmly mounted. The driving element <b>20</b> is adapted in at least one operating state to assist a movement of the second cutting element <b>14</b> relative to the first cutting element <b>12</b>. The driving element <b>20</b> is designed to assist a closing movement of the cutting device <b>10</b> executed by the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> in the event of heavy cutting work. In this way, a force required of a user F<sub>user</sub> to activate the cutting device <b>10</b> can be reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0159" num="0166">Furthermore, the cutting device <b>10</b> comprises a gear unit <b>38</b>. The gear unit <b>38</b> is arranged in the first gripping element <b>16</b>. The gear unit <b>38</b> is arranged in the grip housing <b>44</b> of the gripping element <b>16</b>. The gear unit <b>38</b> is arranged on a side of the driving element <b>20</b> facing the cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b>. The gear unit <b>38</b> in the present case is driven directly by the driving element <b>20</b>. A force transmission from the driving element <b>20</b> to the gear unit <b>38</b> occurs via a power takeoff shaft <b>21</b> of the driving element <b>20</b> to a pinion <b>82</b> of the gear unit <b>38</b>. The gear unit <b>38</b> is designed as a gear transmission unit. The gear unit <b>38</b> comprises at least one gear stage. The gear unit <b>38</b> advantageously comprises several gear stages. The gear unit <b>38</b> comprises in particular one to six gear stages, advantageously four gear stages. The at least one gear stage is designed as a planetary gear stage <b>381</b>, <b>382</b>, <b>383</b>, <b>384</b>. The gear unit <b>38</b> is designed as a planetary gear transmission unit (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>). The transmission ratio of the gear unit <b>38</b> is advantageously from <b>30</b>:1 to <b>300</b>:1, especially from <b>100</b>:1 to <b>150</b>:1, especially <b>130</b>:1. Basically, however, another transmission ratio would also be conceivable. The gear unit <b>38</b> is mounted via a housing <b>74</b> of the gear unit <b>38</b> in the gripping element <b>16</b>. The housing <b>74</b> of the gear unit <b>38</b> is formed by at least one ring gear <b>385</b> of the at least one planetary gear stage <b>381</b>, <b>382</b>, <b>383</b>, <b>384</b>. The housing <b>74</b> of the gear unit <b>38</b> can also be formed by individual serially arranged ring gears of the planetary gear stages <b>381</b>, <b>382</b>, <b>383</b>, <b>384</b>. The force transmission within the at least one planetary gear stage <b>381</b>, <b>382</b>, <b>383</b>, <b>384</b> occurs each time from a driven sun wheel <b>386</b> via planets <b>387</b> of the respective planetary gear stage, which are braced against a stationary ring gear <b>381</b>, to a planet carrier <b>388</b> revolving with the planets <b>387</b>. The planet carrier <b>388</b> in turn drives a sun wheel of the next gear stage <b>382</b>, <b>383</b>, <b>384</b>. The planet carrier <b>389</b> of the last gear stage <b>384</b> forms the power takeoff of the gear unit <b>38</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0160" num="0167">The cutting device <b>10</b> moreover comprises a coupling unit <b>22</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b> and <b>5</b></figref>). The coupling unit <b>22</b> is designed as a self-switching coupling unit <b>22</b>. By a &#x201c;self-switching coupling unit&#x201d; is meant in this context in particular a coupling unit <b>22</b> which is activated free of external, for example electrical, switching signals, especially those of a control unit <b>52</b>. Preferably, it means a coupling unit <b>22</b> which is activated free of explicit switching signals, for a switching between coupling states. Preferably, it means a coupling unit <b>22</b> which is activated on the basis of mechanical factors of influence. Preferably it means a coupling unit <b>22</b> which is activated in dependence on at least one parameter of a driving and/or power takeoff side. The coupling unit <b>22</b> can therefore be designed, in particular, to be speed-activated, torque-activated, direction-activated and/or force-flow activated. The self-switching coupling unit <b>22</b> is designed as a freewheel clutch. By a &#x201c;freewheel clutch&#x201d; is meant in this context especially a self-switching coupling which is designed to be direction-activated and/or force-flow activated. Preferably, the freewheel clutch is at least direction-activated. Preferably, the freewheel clutch is designed to open and/or close depending on a direction of rotation, especially of a drive and/or power takeoff side of the coupling unit <b>22</b>, and/or depending on a direction of force acting on the freewheel clutch. In the case of the direction of acting force, for example, one can distinguish whether the force is acting from the driving side or from the power takeoff side on the freewheel clutch. Preferably, the freewheel clutch is designed to open or close the driving element <b>20</b> in at least one operating state depending on a direction of rotation, especially of a driving and/or power takeoff side, and/or depending on a direction of force acting on the freewheel clutch. The coupling unit <b>22</b> is arranged in the first gripping element <b>16</b>. The coupling unit <b>22</b> is arranged in the grip housing <b>44</b> of the first gripping element <b>16</b>. The coupling unit <b>22</b> is designed to decouple the driving element <b>20</b> in at least one operating state in which the driving element <b>20</b> is deactivated. In particular, upon reaching an end position of the cutting device <b>10</b> and/or upon relaxing an operating force F<sub>user</sub> exerted on the gripping element <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>, the driving element <b>20</b> is automatically deactivated and the coupling unit <b>22</b> with no further rotary movement of the driving element <b>20</b> is automatically decoupled. By a &#x201c;decoupling of the driving element&#x201d; is meant in particular a decoupling of the driving element <b>20</b> from a closing mechanism of the cutting device <b>10</b>. The coupling unit <b>22</b> is also designed to decouple the gear unit <b>38</b> in at least one operating state in which the driving element <b>20</b> is deactivated. The coupling unit <b>22</b> is designed to decouple the driving element <b>20</b> and/or the gear unit <b>38</b> at least to realize a full manual operation. By a &#x201c;full manual operation&#x201d; is meant in this context in particular an operating state in which the cutting device <b>10</b> is operated free of an assistance by the driving element <b>20</b>. Preferably, it means an operating state in which the cutting device <b>10</b> is operated exclusively through the active force F<sub>user</sub> of a user. Especially preferably it means an operating state in which the driving element <b>20</b> is decoupled and therefore cannot be used for an assistance of a movement of the second cutting element <b>14</b> relative to the first cutting element <b>12</b>. In this way, in particular, an advantageously smooth manual operation of the cutting device can be made possible. In particular, in this way one can use the cutting device <b>10</b> advantageously even without the driving element <b>20</b>, such as when there is no power supply, and/or for easy cutting work. The coupling unit <b>22</b> is advantageously designed to accelerate the opening or spreading movement of the two cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> or the two gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>. The coupling unit <b>22</b> enables an accelerated winding and/or unwinding of a driving force transmission element <b>340</b>, here in the form of a cable <b>34</b>, from a cable winch <b>32</b> or cable drum <b>320</b> of a cable winch <b>32</b>, during an opening or spreading of the cutting device <b>10</b>, as described further below. In this way, the speed of operation of the cutting device or the processing speed can be boosted and the operating comfort increased. The number of possible cuts per unit of time can be increased. After a previous closing process of the cutting device <b>10</b>, during which at least the driving element <b>20</b> assists a movement of the second cutting element <b>14</b> relative to the first cutting element <b>12</b>, the coupling unit <b>22</b> is designed to decouple the driving element <b>20</b> and again couple it with motorized force assistance during another closing movement.</p>
<p id="p-0161" num="0168">The coupling unit <b>22</b> comprises an inner rotary element <b>46</b> and an outer rotary element <b>48</b>. The inner rotary element <b>46</b> can turn in at least one state relative to the outer rotary element <b>48</b>. The outer rotary element <b>48</b> is advantageously connected to the power takeoff of the gear unit <b>38</b>. A portion of the coupling unit <b>22</b> advantageously forms a portion, especially of the last gear stage <b>384</b> of the gear unit <b>38</b>. The outer rotary element <b>48</b> is advantageously formed as a single piece with the one portion of the gear unit <b>38</b>, especially the planet carrier <b>389</b> of the last gear stage <b>384</b> and/or the power takeoff of the gear unit <b>38</b>. The inner rotary element <b>46</b> and the outer rotary element <b>48</b> are secured against each other by means of a connection element <b>47</b>, especially a coaxial one. The connection element <b>47</b> is designed as a connecting pin. The connection element <b>47</b> secures the inner and outer rotary element <b>46</b>, <b>48</b> at least axially and/or radially to each other. The connection shaft <b>47</b> is preferably firmly, especially frictionally joined to the outer rotary element <b>48</b> and at least with rotary play to the inner rotary element <b>46</b>. The connection shaft <b>47</b> is received in a slide-bearing manner on the inner rotary element <b>46</b>. The connection shaft <b>47</b> moreover has a shoulder <b>471</b> for the axial securing of the inner rotary element <b>46</b> against the outer rotary element <b>48</b>. The shoulder <b>471</b> is braced against a surface of the inner rotary element <b>46</b>, especially a rim-like surface.</p>
<p id="p-0162" num="0169">Moreover, the coupling unit <b>22</b> has several clamping bodies <b>24</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b> and <b>7</b></figref>). By a &#x201c;clamping body&#x201d; is meant in this context in particular an element of the coupling unit <b>22</b> which in at least one operating state, especially in a closed state of the coupling unit <b>22</b>, is designed to jam between two rotary elements of the coupling unit <b>22</b> which are mounted to rotate relative to each other. The clamping bodies <b>24</b> are arranged between the inner rotary element <b>46</b> and the outer rotary element <b>48</b>. The clamping bodies <b>24</b> are arranged in the circumferential direction one behind the other around the inner rotary element <b>46</b>. The clamping bodies <b>24</b> are designed as cylinders and/or a roller, especially as a cylindrical roller. Basically, however, some other configuration of the clamping bodies <b>24</b> would also be conceivable, such as a sphere or barrel or the like. The outer rotary element <b>48</b> comprises, on its inner side, several consecutive ramps <b>49</b> in the circumferential direction. A number of ramps <b>49</b> corresponds here to a number of clamping bodies <b>24</b>. The clamping bodies <b>24</b> are arranged movable between the ramps <b>49</b>, and when the outer rotary element <b>48</b> is rotated the clamping bodies <b>24</b> are driven along with it. If the outer rotary element <b>48</b> is driven in the circumferential direction against a ramp slope, the clamping bodies <b>24</b> roll in a narrowly tapering region between the outer rotary element <b>48</b> and the inner rotary element <b>46</b> and are pressed against the inner rotary element <b>46</b>. This occurs when the outer rotary element <b>48</b> is driven in the driving direction <b>41</b>. By a &#x201c;driving direction&#x201d; is meant in particular a direction of rotation of the driving element <b>20</b> in which the driving element <b>20</b> rotates in regular operation, in particular to assist a cutting movement. The inner rotary element <b>46</b> is driven along with it. The coupling unit <b>22</b> is closed in this state, as represented in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref>. On the other hand, if the inner rotary element <b>46</b> is driven, regardless of a direction of rotation, the clamping bodies <b>24</b> remain in a valley of the ramps <b>49</b> or roll back into this and are spaced apart from the outer rotary element <b>48</b>. The clamping bodies <b>24</b> are arranged free between the rotary elements <b>46</b>, <b>48</b>. There is no entrained rotation. The coupling unit <b>22</b> is opened in this state, as represented in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref>. The outer rotary element <b>46</b> is driven via the gear unit <b>38</b> by the driving element <b>20</b>. The gear unit <b>38</b> and the driving element <b>20</b> form a driving side of the coupling unit <b>22</b>. If the inner rotary element <b>46</b> is driven against a driving direction <b>41</b>, the clamping bodies <b>24</b> are moved into the valley of the ramps <b>49</b> and are likewise arranged free between the rotary elements <b>46</b>, <b>48</b>. The self-switching coupling unit <b>22</b> is arranged spatially between the cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> and the driving element <b>20</b>. The self-switching coupling unit <b>22</b> is arranged spatially between a cable winch <b>32</b> and the gear unit <b>38</b>. At least the cable winch <b>32</b> or a power takeoff element of the cable winch <b>32</b> forms a power takeoff of the coupling unit <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0163" num="0170">The self-switching coupling unit <b>22</b> has a cage <b>26</b> accommodating the clamping bodies <b>24</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b>, <b>7</b></figref>). The cage <b>26</b> accommodates the clamping bodies <b>24</b> in receiving areas which are separate from each other. The cage <b>26</b> serves for a positioning and guiding of the clamping bodies <b>24</b> in the circumferential direction. The cage <b>26</b> is designed to space the clamping bodies <b>24</b> apart and distribute them evenly in the circumferential direction. In particular, when there are several clamping bodies <b>24</b>, it is possible for the clamping bodies <b>24</b> to perform the same movement in the circumferential direction. Preferably, a controlled clamping of the clamping bodies <b>24</b> can be made possible. The cage <b>26</b> is partly in the shape of a ring. The cage <b>26</b> is partly in the shape of a cylinder. On a cylindrical base body of the cage <b>26</b>, several axially projecting webs in the shape of a circle segment are mounted, extending in the circumferential direction between the clamping bodies <b>24</b>. The cage <b>26</b> is supported on the inner rotary element <b>46</b> of the coupling unit <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0164" num="0171">Moreover, the coupling unit <b>22</b> comprises a brake element <b>28</b>, which is designed for a braking of the cage <b>26</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref>). The brake element <b>28</b> is designed as a spring element. The brake element <b>28</b> is designed as a kind of spiral spring. The brake element <b>28</b> is designed as a wrap spring. The brake element <b>28</b> is arranged by one end firmly in a recess <b>29</b> of the cage <b>26</b>. The brake element <b>28</b> extends at least partly in the circumferential direction in a spiral around the cage <b>26</b>. The brake element <b>28</b> is wrapped around the cage <b>26</b>. An outer surface of the brake element <b>28</b> is at least partly braced against a securing element <b>27</b> radially surrounding the brake element <b>28</b> or the cage <b>26</b>. The securing element <b>27</b> is designed as a securing ring or fixation ring. The securing element <b>27</b> is arranged stationary on the coupling unit <b>22</b>. The securing element <b>27</b> is connected firmly, especially at least firm against rotation, preferably frictionally, to the housing <b>23</b> of the coupling unit <b>22</b>. For better force transmission, the inner surface of the housing <b>23</b> is structured, in particular ribbed, in the region of the region where the securing element <b>27</b> is disposed. The brake element <b>28</b> enables a rotation of the cage <b>26</b> relative to the stationary grip housing <b>44</b> in one direction of rotation, especially in a driving direction of rotation, and blocks a rotation of the cage <b>26</b> in the opposite direction of rotation. The brake element <b>28</b> enables a rotation of the cage <b>26</b> relative to the housing <b>23</b> of the coupling unit <b>22</b> or to the securing element <b>27</b> in one direction and blocks a rotation of the cage <b>26</b> in the opposite direction of rotation. At least one portion, especially the greater portion of the outer surface of the brake element <b>28</b> presses by means of a spring force against the securing element <b>27</b> in the radially outward direction. The brake element <b>28</b> is designed to enable a freewheeling of the cage <b>26</b>. The brake element <b>28</b> is designed to brake the cage <b>26</b> or curb a rotation in the counter-driving direction <b>410</b> or fix the cage in the counter-driving direction <b>410</b> and to enable a rotation or the cage <b>26</b> relative to the outer supporting surface or the securing element <b>27</b> in the driving direction <b>41</b>, especially to enable this with low friction. This kind of wrap-around clutch drags its free end along during a rotation of the cage <b>26</b> in the driving direction <b>41</b> and thereby slides on the inner surface of the securing element <b>27</b>. Upon turning in the contrary driving direction <b>410</b>, on the other hand, this kind of wrap-around clutch spreads out and at least brakes or blocks the cage <b>26</b> relative to the securing element <b>27</b>. The brake element <b>28</b> is designed to prevent an unwanted rotation of the cage <b>26</b>. The brake element <b>28</b> is designed to prevent a rotating of the cage <b>26</b> until a force is applied, especially a force is applied by the driving element <b>20</b>. The brake element <b>28</b> can also be designed as a locking pawl element, another element creating a freewheeling, or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0165" num="0172">Moreover, the inner rotary element <b>46</b> comprises at least one, especially two form-fitting elements <b>460</b>, 460&#x2032;. The form-fitting element is designed as a flange, but it can also have a different form. The cage <b>26</b> likewise comprises a form-fitting element <b>260</b>. The rotary body <b>370</b> comprises a form-fitting element <b>370</b>. The securing element <b>27</b> comprises at least one form-fitting element <b>270</b>. At least through the form-fitting elements <b>260</b>, <b>270</b>, <b>370</b>, <b>460</b>, 460&#x2032; and also any frictional connections between rotary body <b>37</b> and inner rotary element <b>46</b>, elements of the coupling unit <b>22</b> and the restoring unit <b>31</b> are securely connected to each other. Thus, an axial securing of these elements against each other is ensured. But the axial securing can also occur in a different manner. An additional bearing, for example by plain or roller bearing, is also advantageously unnecessary. Furthermore, thanks to the connection element <b>47</b> the outer rotary element <b>48</b> is also axially secured against the inner rotary element <b>46</b> and thus positioned by the securing element <b>27</b> axially to the coupling unit <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0166" num="0173">Furthermore, the cutting device <b>10</b> comprises a restoring unit <b>31</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref>). The restoring unit <b>31</b> is arranged in the first gripping element <b>16</b>. The restoring unit <b>31</b> is advantageously arranged in the grip housing <b>44</b> of the gripping element <b>16</b>. The restoring unit <b>31</b> is arranged in the coupling unit <b>22</b>. Preferably, the restoring unit <b>31</b> is designed to ensure a tensioning of the cable. Preferably, the restoring unit <b>31</b> is designed to apply a force to the cable winch <b>32</b>, especially a force in the circumferential direction. Especially preferably, the restoring unit <b>31</b> is designed to produce a tensile force through the cable winch <b>32</b> on the cable <b>34</b>. In particular, the cable <b>34</b> should be held in permanent tension thanks to the restoring unit <b>31</b>. Preferably, the restoring unit <b>31</b> produces a restoring force F<sub>vs</sub>, which is less than an opening force F<sub>os</sub> of the opening spring <b>50</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>). Thanks to the restoring unit <b>31</b>, in particular, a tensioning of the cable <b>34</b> can be assured even during a full manual operation. Thus, advantageously, an unwanted knotting of the cable <b>34</b> can be prevented. Furthermore, a winding up of the cable <b>34</b> without drive power can be assured. The restoring unit <b>31</b> comprises a spring element <b>36</b> and a rotary body <b>37</b>. One end of the spring element <b>36</b> is firmly connected to the housing <b>23</b> of the coupling unit <b>22</b>. The other end of the spring element <b>36</b> is firmly connected to the rotary body <b>37</b>. The spring element <b>36</b> is disposed radially between the housing <b>23</b> of the coupling unit <b>22</b> and the rotary body <b>37</b>. The spring element <b>36</b> surrounds the rotary body <b>37</b>  radially. The spring element <b>36</b> is wrapped several times around the rotary body <b>37</b>. The restoring unit <b>31</b> is connected in particular via the rotary body <b>37</b> at least indirectly to the cable winch <b>32</b>. The rotary body <b>37</b> is fixed by the spring element <b>36</b> with limited rotation ability relative to the grip housing <b>44</b> or the housing <b>23</b> of the coupling unit <b>22</b>. The rotary body <b>37</b> is connected by a shaft <b>35</b> to the cable winch <b>32</b>. The rotary body <b>37</b> is moreover advantageously connected by the shaft <b>35</b>, firm against rotation, to the inner rotary element <b>46</b> of the coupling unit <b>22</b>. The rotary body <b>37</b> can be connected at least via a radial and/or axial form-fitting element to the inner rotary element <b>46</b>. The rotary body <b>37</b> has a coaxial recess. The recess is polygonal in configuration. The inner contour of the recess is formed corresponding to the outer contour of the shaft <b>35</b>. The spring element <b>36</b> is designed to apply a force to the shaft <b>35</b> in the driving direction <b>41</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0167" num="0174">The spring element <b>36</b> is designed to apply a force to the inner rotary element <b>46</b> in the driving direction <b>41</b>. The spring element <b>36</b> is designed to transmit via the cable winch <b>32</b> a tensile force to the cable <b>34</b>. By the spring element <b>36</b>, the cable <b>34</b> should be held permanently at tension, especially a tensile stress. To simplify the assembly of the cutting device <b>10</b>, or at least that of the coupling and restoring unit <b>22</b>, <b>31</b>, the spring element <b>36</b> can be pretensioned and fixed by an assembly jig <b>360</b> relative to the housing <b>23</b> of the coupling unit <b>23</b>. In this way, at least the restoring unit <b>31</b> can be installed with pretension, especially in connection with the coupling unit <b>22</b> as an assembly. Moreover, alternatively, the spring element <b>36</b> can be used to open the coupling unit <b>22</b> once the drive motor is deactivated. Thus, the inner rotary element <b>46</b> can be turned in the driving direction <b>41</b> via the spring element <b>36</b>, so that in turn the cage <b>26</b> is braked via the brake element <b>28</b> once the drive motor <b>20</b> is deactivated. Thus, advantageously, an alternative reversal of the direction of rotation of the drive motor <b>20</b> for the opening of the coupling unit <b>22</b> can be avoided.</p>
<p id="p-0168" num="0175">Moreover, the cutting device <b>10</b> comprises a cable winch <b>32</b> which can be driven by the driving element <b>20</b>. The cable winch <b>32</b> is disposed in the first gripping element <b>16</b>. Preferably, the cable winch <b>32</b> is designed to be drivable via the coupling unit <b>22</b> by the driving element <b>20</b>. Preferably, the cable winch <b>32</b> can be decoupled in at least one operating state from the driving element <b>20</b> via the coupling unit <b>22</b>. Thanks to the cable winch <b>32</b>, an advantageous application of force of the driving element <b>20</b> can be achieved. In particular, a simple design for assisting a movement of the second cutting element <b>14</b> relative to the first cutting element <b>12</b> can be made possible in this way. Thus, a user can be advantageously assisted by the driving element <b>20</b> during a closing movement. Moreover, thanks to the application of force of the driving element to the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>, an advantageously large torque can be provided. This, in turn, can keep low a power of the driving element <b>20</b>. The cable winch <b>32</b> is disposed in the grip housing <b>44</b> of the first gripping element <b>16</b>. The cable winch <b>32</b> is arranged on a side of the coupling unit <b>22</b> facing the cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b>. The cable winch <b>32</b> is connected to the shaft <b>35</b>. The shaft <b>35</b> is advantageously formed as a single piece with the cable winch <b>32</b>. The shaft <b>35</b> is mounted by a bearing, especially by plain bearings <b>77</b>, 77&#x2032;. The bearing <b>77</b> facing the cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> is braced in the grip housing <b>44</b> of the gripping element <b>16</b>. The bearing 77&#x2032; facing away from the cutting element <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> is braced in the housing <b>23</b> of the coupling unit <b>22</b>. The shaft <b>35</b> is connected to the coupling unit <b>22</b>. The shaft <b>35</b> is connected, firm against rotation, to the inner rotary element <b>46</b>. Moreover, the shaft <b>35</b> is connected, firm against rotation, to the rotary body <b>37</b>. The shaft <b>35</b> has a polygonal profile. It can also have a different profile for the connection to the coupling unit <b>22</b>, such as a square, a tongue and groove, or another shaft and hub connection profile. Due to the fact that the cable winch <b>32</b> is connected directly to the inner rotary element <b>46</b> of the coupling unit <b>22</b> and the rotary body <b>37</b> of the restoring unit and furthermore these two elements are joined together, the device has a very compact construction. The self-switching coupling unit <b>22</b> can also be partly integrated in the cable winch <b>32</b>. The coupling unit <b>22</b> can be partly enclosed by the cable winch <b>32</b>. Moreover, the cable winch <b>32</b> forms a power takeoff side of the coupling unit <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0169" num="0176">The cable winch <b>32</b> comprises a cable drum <b>320</b>. The cable drum <b>320</b> is substantially cylindrical in shape. An axial extension of the cable drum <b>320</b> is advantageously provided in order to wind up the cable <b>34</b> in only a single layer. The axial extension of the cable drum <b>320</b> is advantageously 5-15 mm, especially 6 mm. For the positioning of the cable <b>34</b> on the cable drum <b>320</b>, this forms a shoulder at least on the side facing the pivot <b>42</b>. The diameter of the cable drum <b>320</b> is advantageously less than 10 mm, especially 7 mm. The cable winch <b>32</b> has a mount <b>33</b> for the fixation of the cable <b>34</b>. The mount <b>33</b> is fashioned as an opening or a through-hole in the transverse axial direction of the cable winch <b>32</b> or shaft <b>35</b>. The mount <b>33</b> has an at least substantially rectangular cross section. The mount <b>33</b> can also be oval, round, polygonal or the like. The mount <b>33</b> can have a clamping seat for the advantageously secure and compact mounting of a cable end of the cable <b>34</b>. In the region of the mount <b>33</b>, the shaft <b>35</b> advantageously has a larger diameter than in the region of the cable drum <b>320</b>. This is advantageously 8 mm.</p>
<p id="p-0170" num="0177">The cutting device <b>10</b> furthermore comprises the cable <b>34</b>. Preferably, the cable <b>34</b> is firmly fixed to the second gripping element <b>18</b> and secured to the first gripping element <b>18</b> so that it can be wound up via the cable winch <b>32</b>. Preferably, the cable <b>34</b> is situated closer to the pivot <b>42</b>, in regard to the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>, than to the ends of the gripping elements  <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> spaced away from the pivot <b>42</b>, especially closer than 10 cm, preferably between 6 and 8 cm from the pivot <b>42</b>. It is taut between the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>. The cable <b>34</b> can be mounted in the first gripping element <b>16</b> and/or second gripping element <b>18</b> via a guide element <b>780</b>, especially a guide sleeve <b>78</b>. The guide sleeve <b>78</b> is preferably a hollow cylinder and has a flange <b>783</b> at one end. The flange <b>783</b> can advantageously serve for the fixation on the first or second gripping element <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>. Moreover, the guide element <b>780</b> can position and/or fix the opening spring <b>50</b> on the first and/or second gripping element <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>. The cylinder of the guide sleeve <b>78</b> is oriented in particular transversely to the lengthwise dimension of the gripping element <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>, in the direction of the opposite gripping element <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>. An outer surface <b>784</b> of the cylinder supports the inside or inner surface of the opening spring <b>50</b>. At least at one opening, especially at both openings of the guide sleeve <b>78</b>, a fillet <b>782</b> is respectively provided. A radius of the fillet <b>782</b> is advantageously 0.6 mm. This contributes to a low-friction mounting of the cable <b>34</b>. Moreover, the inner diameter of the cylinder widens conically in the direction of the flange <b>783</b>. In this way, the cable <b>34</b> advantageously touches the guide element <b>780</b> only at the opening of the guide element <b>780</b> facing the other respective gripping element <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>, which likewise serves for a low-friction mounting of the cable <b>34</b> on the guide element <b>780</b> and a no-contact mounting of the cable <b>34</b> inside the opening spring <b>50</b> and/or enables a winding up of the cable <b>34</b> in nearly guided manner across the entire width of the drum. The cable <b>34</b> is taut between the two gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>. The ends of the opening spring <b>50</b> are mounted on the guide sleeves <b>78</b> in the first and second gripping element <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>. The guide sleeves <b>78</b> are made of stronger material than the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>. The cable <b>34</b> is led inside the opening spring <b>50</b>. The opening spring <b>50</b> is designed as an evolute spring, especially a double evolute spring. Preferably, the opening spring <b>50</b> in the relaxed state has a length of less than 100 mm, especially 70 mm. In the compressed state, the opening spring <b>50</b> has a length of less than 25 mm, especially 17 mm. The opening spring <b>50</b> in the compressed state has for example an opening force of less than 100 N, especially 32 N. A diameter of the spring is, for example at the ends, 4 to 8 mm, especially 6.6 mm, and in the middle of the opening spring <b>50</b> around 10 to 15 mm, especially 11 mm. The opening spring <b>50</b> is advantageously designed to make possible an opening angle &#x3c3; of the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> around the pivot <b>42</b> of up to 70&#xb0;, especially of up to 50&#xb0; and especially preferably of up to 35&#xb0;.</p>
<p id="p-0171" num="0178">The cable <b>34</b> can be mounted inside the opening spring <b>50</b> with low friction. The cable <b>34</b> can be mounted inside the opening spring <b>50</b> free of damage, so that a damaging of the cable by sharp edges of the opening spring <b>50</b>, for example, is prevented. The opening spring <b>50</b> can have additional guide elements <b>781</b>, which lead the cable <b>34</b> in protective and low-friction manner inside the opening spring <b>50</b>. The cable <b>34</b> is advantageously made of polyethylene, especially polyethylene with ultrahigh molar mass (UHMW-PE). It is a Dyneema&#xae; cable <b>34</b>. Advantageously, it has a diameter of 2 mm and withstands for example a repeated tensile force of 1000 N and a winding up on the cable drum <b>320</b>. Such a cable <b>34</b> is especially resistant to abrasion. It can be arranged directly in the opening spring <b>50</b> or led through the opening spring <b>50</b> with no further friction- or damage-reducing elements. It has good winding properties, high strength, and good aging resistance and toughness. However, the cable <b>34</b> can also be made of polyacrylics, Kevlar, wire or the like. The cable <b>34</b> is connected in a region between the pivot 42b and an end of the second gripping element <b>18</b> facing away from the cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> at least indirectly to the second gripping element <b>18</b>. It can exert on this an assisting force via the driving force transmission element <b>340</b> for the closing of the cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b>. The cable <b>34</b> is connected via the force transmission element in the form of the lever <b>80</b> to the second gripping element <b>18</b>. At the first gripping element <b>16</b>, the cable <b>34</b> can be wound up in variable manner on the cable winch <b>32</b>. Due to the fact that the cable <b>34</b> is led in the opening spring <b>50</b>, it can be advantageously prevented that a user will be disturbed by the cable <b>34</b> when using the cutting device <b>10</b>. Furthermore, a damaging, a soiling, an exposure to the weather elements, damage to the cable <b>50</b> and/or the like can be prevented in particular by the use of the evolute spring. Thanks to a driving of the cable winch <b>32</b>, a free length of the cable <b>34</b> can be varied, or a spacing or opening angle &#x3c3; of the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> and/or an opening angle of the cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> can be varied (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>, <b>3</b></figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0172" num="0179">A drive train for the force-assisting operation of the manual machine tool is advantageously formed by the following elements: drive motor <b>20</b>, gear unit <b>38</b>, coupling unit <b>22</b>, restoring unit <b>31</b> and cable winch <b>32</b>. These elements are arranged serially, especially in the aforementioned order. They are preferably arranged in the first gripping element <b>16</b>. When required, the drive motor <b>20</b> drives the gear unit <b>38</b>, which drives the cable winch <b>32</b> via the coupling unit <b>22</b>. The restoring unit <b>31</b> holds the cable <b>34</b> permanently under tension and can be designed, in concert with the elements of the coupling unit <b>22</b>, to decouple the coupling unit <b>22</b> during a switch from the force-assisted to the non-force-assisted operation. The drive train is advantageously mounted or fixed in the grip housing <b>44</b> solely via the housing of the motor unit <b>20</b>, the housing <b>74</b> of the gear unit <b>38</b>, the housing <b>23</b> of the coupling unit <b>22</b>, as well as the rotary bearing <b>77</b> of the cable winch <b>32</b> facing the cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b>. The coupling unit <b>22</b> and the restoring unit <b>31</b> are very compact in design and enable an easy assembly. The first gripping element <b>16</b> can at least be made compact or short as a result. An extension of the first or second gripping element <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> between an end of the first or second gripping element <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> facing away from the pivot <b>42</b> and the opening spring <b>50</b> is less than 150 mm, especially 120 to 130 mm. An extension of the first or second gripping element <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> from the end facing away from the pivot <b>42</b> up to the pivot <b>42</b> is advantageously less than 200 mm, especially 170 to 190 mm. The overall extension of the cutting device <b>10</b> is advantageously less than 300 mm, especially 200 to 300 mm, preferably 250 to 260 mm. An envelope circle diameter around the first gripping element <b>16</b> in the grip region <b>62</b> is advantageously less than 40 mm, especially 30 to 35 mm. An envelope circle diameter around the second gripping element <b>18</b> in the grip region is advantageously less than 30 mm, especially around 25 mm. Advantageously, the cutting device <b>10</b> achieves similar feel and/or ergonomics to a nonmotorized, purely manual cutting device. Furthermore, it is possible to arrange the drive train and to arrange the energy storage unit <b>54</b> at least in one of the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0173" num="0180">Furthermore, at least one of the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> has an at least partly elastic and/or beveled and/or rounded region <b>620</b> at least at the transitions of the grip inside <b>600</b> to the side surfaces <b>610</b> of the at least one gripping element <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>). The region can be set back relative to the side surface <b>610</b> in the direction of a parting plane of the housing shells of the at least one gripping element <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>. By the grip insides <b>600</b> is meant in particular the facing inner surfaces of the grip. An opening angle &#x3b2; of the beveled regions <b>620</b> of both gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> relative to each other is advantageously between 30&#xb0; and 150&#xb0;, or the angle between an imaginary parting plane between the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> and a beveled region <b>620</b> of the first or second gripping element <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> is half of that. In particular, the opening angle &#x3b2; between the pivot <b>42</b> and the ends of the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> facing away from the pivot <b>42</b> varies at least between 60&#xb0; and 120&#xb0;. A sector length s of the beveled surface is advantageously 5 to 10 mm and can likewise vary in its length. In the region of the ends of the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> facing away from the pivot <b>42</b> there is provided a spacing element <b>630</b>  at the inner surfaces of the grip, especially a soft stopping element. The outside <b>64</b> of the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> is advantageously likewise rounded, especially rounded according to the aforementioned envelope circle diameter of the respective gripping element <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>. The outside <b>64</b> has advantageously a soft grip surface in order to heighten user comfort and/or a structuring to prevent slippage during use. The gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> are designed to at least almost touch. Advantageously, an unwanted pinching, especially a pinching of the skin on a user&#x2019;s hand, can be avoided thanks to the elastic or rounded configuration of the grip insides. This enhances the safety of use of the cutting device <b>10</b>. An envelope circle diameter around the closed cutting device <b>10</b> is advantageously less than 100 mm, in particular an envelope circle diameter around the grip region <b>62</b> of the closed gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> is less than 70 mm, preferably 50 to 60 mm.</p>
<p id="p-0174" num="0181">Moreover, the cutting device <b>10</b> comprises a control unit <b>52</b>. The control unit <b>52</b> is disposed in the first gripping element <b>16</b>. The control unit <b>52</b> is disposed in the grip housing <b>44</b> of the gripping element <b>16</b>. The control unit <b>52</b> is designed to actuate the driving element <b>20</b>. Basically, there can be both a pure controlling of the driving element <b>20</b> and a regulating of the driving element <b>20</b>. For this, the control unit <b>52</b> supplies energy to the driving element <b>20</b>. But in theory, the driving element <b>20</b> can also be connected directly via the switch <b>72</b> to the energy storage unit <b>54</b>. The control unit <b>52</b> is arranged between the driving element <b>20</b> and the pivot <b>42</b>. The control unit <b>52</b> is arranged between the cable winch <b>32</b> and the pivot <b>42</b>. The control unit <b>52</b> is advantageously connected to an indicator element <b>200</b>. The indicator element <b>200</b> displays an activation or an operation of the driving element <b>20</b>, but can also enable some other form of indication of states. The indicator element <b>200</b> is a light. The light is a LED. The indicator element <b>200</b> can display to a user, for example through the color of the light, information about the charge status of an energy storage unit <b>54</b>, the assistance force during an assistance mode, or the like, and/or indicate whether an assistance mode is active or not. The control unit <b>52</b> is connected to the energy storage unit <b>54</b>. Via the energy storage unit <b>54</b>, the driving element <b>20</b> can be supplied with energy by the control unit <b>52</b>. The energy storage unit <b>54</b> comprises at least one storage battery. The storage battery <b>58</b> is formed from lithium ion cells. Basically, however, some other design of the at least one storage battery <b>58</b> would also be possible. The storage battery <b>58</b> is arranged in the second gripping element <b>18</b>. The storage battery <b>58</b> is arranged in a grip housing <b>60</b> of the second gripping element <b>18</b>. The storage battery <b>58</b> is connected to the control unit <b>52</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>, <b>3</b></figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0175" num="0182">Moreover, the battery-operated manual machine tool or cutting device <b>10</b> comprises a blocking device <b>202</b>. The blocking device <b>202</b> is arranged on the first gripping element <b>16</b>. The blocking device <b>202</b> is arranged in the grip housing <b>44</b> of the gripping element <b>16</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>11</b></figref> shows a cutout view of the cutting device <b>10</b> and the blocking device <b>202</b> in a first state. The cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> of the cutting device <b>10</b> are in a closed state. The blocking device <b>202</b> is in a first position. The blocking device <b>202</b> blocks an activation and/or tool movement of the cutting device <b>10</b> to each other, especially that of the cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> or gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>. The blocking device <b>202</b> is designed as a mechanical blocking device <b>202</b>. The blocking device <b>202</b> comprises a sliding switch <b>204</b>. The sliding switch <b>204</b> is designed to block and/or close a charging interface <b>211</b>, or to release it. The sliding switch <b>204</b> is intended to be moved by a user, especially using one finger of a user. The blocking device <b>202</b> comprises a detent element <b>206</b>. The detent element <b>206</b> is designed to mechanically block or release a relative movement of the two cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> to one another. The sliding switch <b>204</b> is mechanically connected to the detent element <b>206</b>. The sliding switch <b>204</b> is connected via a pivot <b>208</b> to the detent element <b>206</b>. The blocking device <b>202</b> is arranged in the region of the control unit <b>52</b>. The blocking device <b>202</b> is arranged in the region of a thickening of the gripping element <b>16</b>. The blocking device <b>202</b> or the sliding switch <b>204</b> of the blocking device can be activated advantageously at least by one thumb of the user in a single-handed operation of the cutting device <b>10</b>. The sliding switch <b>204</b> is guided or mounted in lengthwise movable manner through grooves <b>207</b> in the gripping element <b>16</b>. The sliding switch <b>204</b> can be moved relative to the gripping element <b>16</b>. The sliding switch <b>204</b> is designed to close or at least partly release an opening <b>209</b> of the grip housing <b>44</b>. The sliding switch <b>204</b> is designed to cover or close the charging interface <b>211</b>, or to release it. The sliding switch <b>204</b> is designed to release the charging interface <b>211</b> in the first position and to close the charging interface <b>211</b> in a second position.</p>
<p id="p-0176" num="0183">The detent element <b>206</b> is connected at one free end to the pivot <b>208</b>. The detent element <b>206</b> has a locking element <b>210</b> at the other free end. The detent element <b>206</b> is designed to engage, by means of the locking element <b>210</b>, in a first and a second recess <b>212</b>, <b>214</b> of the first and second cutting element <b>12</b>, <b>14</b>, as long as the cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> are in a closed state. In the closed state, the first and second recess <b>212</b>, <b>214</b> of the cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> are aligned in the direction of the axis of rotation <b>149</b> of the pivot <b>42</b>. The detent element <b>206</b> or locking element <b>210</b> in this position is designed to engage in the aligned recess <b>212</b>, <b>214</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0177" num="0184"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>12</b></figref> shows the blocking device <b>202</b> in a second state. The blocking device <b>202</b> is in the second position. The cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> of the cutting device <b>10</b> are in an opened position. In the second state, the cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> can move relative to each other. The cutting device <b>10</b> is in a state at least intended for manual operation. In the second position of the blocking device <b>202</b>, the blocking device <b>202</b> releases an activation and/or tool movement of the cutting device <b>10</b>, especially of the cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> or gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>, relative to each other. The charging interface <b>211</b> is blocked or closed by the sliding switch <b>204</b> of the blocking device <b>202</b>. The detent element <b>206</b> does not protrude into the recesses <b>212</b>, <b>214</b> of the cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b>. At least one of the recesses <b>212</b>, <b>214</b> can also be arranged in at least one structure connected firm against rotation to one of the cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b>. For example, the recess <b>214</b> can also be arranged in the lever <b>80</b>. On both the sliding switch <b>204</b> and the gripping element <b>18</b> there can be arranged a seal element (not shown), which enables a sealing of the charging interface <b>211</b>. The seal element is arranged in particular between the gripping element <b>18</b> and the sliding switch <b>204</b>. The at least one seal element advantageously provides for a sealing of the charging interface <b>211</b> in the second position of the blocking device. Thus, advantageously, the control unit <b>52</b> or other electronic components of the cutting device <b>10</b> which are at least in electronic contact with the charging interface <b>211</b> can also be protected against dust and moisture, especially during operation of the cutting device.</p>
<p id="p-0178" num="0185">The cutting device <b>10</b> moreover comprises the force transmission element in the form of the lever <b>80</b>. The lever <b>80</b> connects the second cutting element <b>14</b> to the second gripping element <b>18</b>. The lever <b>80</b> comprises at least one form-fitting element for the connection to the cutting element <b>14</b>. The second gripping element <b>18</b> is connected by at least one further pivot <b>65</b> to the lever <b>80</b>. The gripping element <b>18</b> and the lever <b>80</b> are able to swivel relative to each other at least to a limited degree. The gripping element <b>18</b> and the lever <b>80</b> swivel about the further pivot <b>65</b>. The gripping element <b>18</b> and the lever <b>80</b> are able to swivel relative to each other about the swivel axis <b>66</b>. The swivel movement is limited at least by the inner contour of the hollow gripping element <b>18</b>. Moreover, the swivel movement can be limited by a form fitting-element configured in the gripping element <b>18</b>. The gripping element <b>18</b> is moreover braced against the lever <b>80</b> by means of a spring <b>68</b>. The gripping element <b>18</b> is braced at one free end of the lever <b>80</b> against the lever <b>80</b> by means of the spring <b>68</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0179" num="0186">The cutting device <b>10</b> moreover comprises a sensor <b>401</b>. The sensor <b>401</b> is designed to sense an operating state in which a force assistance mode is required. Advantageously, the sensor <b>401</b> or other sensors (not shown here) can sense an operating state in which an assistance mode needs to be discontinued or switched off for purposes of operating safety of the cutting device, especially when an object <b>17</b> is arranged between the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>. Preferably, the sensor <b>401</b> is a force sensor <b>40</b> which is designed to sense a force acting on the second gripping element <b>18</b>, especially relative to the first gripping element <b>16</b> and/or relative to the lever <b>80</b>. Preferably the force sensor <b>40</b> can be designed both to detect a precise force and merely a transgressing of a limit force. The force sensor <b>40</b> is arranged on the second gripping element <b>18</b> and/or on the force transmission element, designed as a lever <b>80</b>. The force sensor <b>40</b> is advantageously integrated in the second gripping element <b>18</b>. The force sensor <b>40</b> is arranged between the lever <b>80</b> and the gripping element <b>18</b>. The force sensor <b>40</b> comprises at least one spring <b>68</b> and a switch <b>72</b>, especially a microswitch. The spring <b>68</b> braces the lever <b>80</b> advantageously against an outer side <b>64</b> of the second gripping element <b>18</b>. As long as a cutting force F<sub>cut</sub> is acting on the cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b>, during a closing of the cutting device <b>10</b>, for example in order to cut a material <b>11</b> being cut, the second gripping element <b>18</b> can be moved, in particular swiveled, relative to the force transmission element or the lever <b>80</b>, against the spring force F<sub>gs</sub> of the spring <b>68</b>. For this, the lever <b>80</b> and the gripping element <b>18</b> are arranged able to swivel about the common further pivot <b>65</b>. The spring <b>68</b>, as it were, couples the gripping element <b>18</b> to the lever <b>80</b> in at least one operating state. The lever <b>80</b> has a recess and the gripping element <b>18</b> a projection, which forms an axis of rotation <b>66</b>, especially when the two grip shells of the second gripping element <b>18</b> are joined, about which the lever <b>80</b> can turn or swivel in at least a limited degree. The gripping element <b>18</b> is advantageously able to swivel in limited degree relative to the lever <b>80</b> about the axis of rotation <b>66</b>. The swivel limitation is provided by at least corresponding form-fitting elements at the second gripping element <b>18</b> and the lever <b>80</b>. Moreover, the spring <b>68</b> can also constitute a swivel limitation, especially the compressed spring <b>68</b>. The second gripping element <b>18</b> is advantageously braced against the lever <b>80</b> by means of the spring <b>68</b> at one free end of the lever <b>80</b>. Advantageously, a mounting element <b>69</b> is shoved onto the lever <b>80</b>. The mounting element <b>69</b> advantageously serves as a mount, especially a guide mount, for the spring <b>68</b> and advantageously as a mount for the switch <b>72</b>, especially as a plug mount. So long as the operating force F<sub>user</sub> exerted on the gripping element <b>18</b> for the activation of the cutting element <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> is greater than a spring force F<sub>gs</sub>, the gripping element <b>18</b> swivels relative to the lever <b>80</b>. In the present case, the outer side <b>64</b> of the gripping element <b>18</b> comes closer to the lever <b>80</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0180" num="0187">In order to detect this swivel movement or swiveling force or to detect at least a crossing of a threshold value, a movement of the spring <b>68</b> and/or the like, the force sensor <b>40</b> has a switch <b>72</b>. The switch <b>72</b> is designed as a microswitch, especially as an opener or changer. The switch <b>72</b> has a trigger element, designed as a pressure element. The pressure element is designed as a swivel element <b>71</b>, especially a swiveling lever. It is provided for an activation of the switch <b>72</b>. The switch <b>72</b> advantageously senses a swiveling away or a distancing of the switch <b>72</b> from the inside <b>63</b> of the second gripping element <b>18</b>. Thus, the switch <b>72</b> is activated upon swiveling out of the swivel element <b>71</b>. Or in other words the switch <b>72</b> is deactivated in a state in which the swivel element <b>71</b> bears against the switch <b>72</b>, and deactivated in a state in which the swivel element <b>71</b> is swiveled out relative to the switch <b>72</b>. Thus, the switch <b>72</b> closes upon a defined swiveling out of the swivel element <b>71</b>. The swivel element <b>71</b> can be braced directly against the housing of the gripping element <b>18</b> or against an additional pressure element <b>81</b> or the like. Moreover, the pressure element <b>81</b> can be designed such that it is provided for the selection of a sensitivity of the force sensor <b>40</b>. The pressure element <b>81</b> is advantageously part of the force sensor <b>40</b>, which is advantageously disposed at a further switch <b>73</b>. The further switch serves as an assistance mode adjustment element. The further switch <b>73</b> is advantageously able to move transversely to the swivel element <b>71</b>. The further switch <b>73</b> can move in the direction of the pivot <b>42</b>. The further switch <b>73</b> is arranged on the side of the second gripping element <b>18</b> facing the first gripping element <b>16</b>. Thus, the further switch <b>73</b> is arranged on the inside <b>63</b> of the second gripping element <b>18</b>. An unintentional activation of the further switch <b>73</b>, especially during a cutting process, can be prevented in this way. The further switch <b>73</b> is designed as a sliding switch. The further switch <b>73</b> has a pressure element <b>81</b> which is wedge shaped. The pressure element <b>81</b> is designed to make contact with the swivel element <b>71</b> in all operating states. By a displacement of the further switch <b>73</b> relative to the switch <b>72</b> or the swivel element <b>81</b>, the sensitivity of the force sensor <b>40</b> or a threshold value for the triggering of the switch <b>72</b> can be varied. Thanks to the trigonometric distance relationship of the pressure element <b>81</b> to the swivel element <b>71</b>, especially the lever length of the lever <b>80</b> within the second gripping element <b>18</b>, the sensitivity of the force sensor <b>40</b> can be altered upon displacement of the further switch <b>73</b>. When the further switch <b>73</b> is displaced in the direction of the first or second cutting element <b>12</b>, <b>14</b>, the switch <b>72</b> is activated only at a larger operating force F<sub>user</sub>. When the further switch <b>73</b> is displaced in the opposite direction, on the other hand, the switch <b>72</b> is activated at a lower operating force F<sub>user</sub>. Thus, in an economical manner with mechanical means, the sensitivity of the force sensor <b>40</b> can be adjusted. Different activation levels or threshold values can be adjusted for the assistance mode of the cutting device <b>10</b>, for example in dependence on a varying hand force of a user. The further switch <b>73</b> advantageously has three detent positions in connection with the switch mount, especially the gripping element <b>18</b>. In this way, three assistance mode levels can be defined advantageously. Thanks to the design, an additional on/off switch for the activation of an alternative, purely electronic force or displacement sensor is unnecessary, which would need a permanent electrification in order to sense a defined crossing of a threshold value. Advantageously, therefore, the switch <b>72</b> and thus the assistance drive is only activated when a mechanical force of the spring <b>68</b> in the form of a threshold value is crossed. Or in other words, a threshold value depending on the spring-loaded swivel movement of the lever <b>80</b> within the gripping element <b>18</b> about the pivot <b>67</b> is crossed, so that the switch <b>72</b> is triggered. In this way, an especially economical and simple-design force sensor <b>40</b> can be provided.</p>
<p id="p-0181" num="0188">Moreover, the driving force transmission element <b>340</b> in the form of the cable <b>34</b> being in operative connection with the driving element <b>20</b> engages with the lever <b>80</b>. Upon activation of the driving element <b>20</b>, the lever is thus subjected to the driving force F<sub>an</sub> and assists the closing movement of the cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b>. Thus, the lever <b>80</b> decouples the driving force F<sub>an</sub> from a direct force application to the gripping element <b>18</b>. For example, if during a force assistance mode of the cutting device <b>10</b> an object <b>17</b> is found between the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>, the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> can no longer move toward each other. The driving force F<sub>an</sub> moves the lever <b>80</b> within the gripping element <b>18</b> in the direction of its starting position, the switch <b>72</b> is opened, and the force assistance mode is ended. Thus, the force sensor <b>40</b> or the lever <b>80</b>, the spring <b>68</b> and the switch <b>72</b> decouples a force assistance mode for the pressing together of the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>. Thus, so long as an object <b>17</b> is found between the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>, the switch <b>72</b> will necessarily be opened and the driving element <b>20</b> deactivated, so that there can be no undesirable pinching of, for example a part of the body or skin of the user, or a damaging of the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>, for example if a branch is found between them. In such instances, only the operating force F<sub>user</sub> will be instrumental in a squeezing of the object <b>17</b>. Thanks to the arrangement of the lever <b>80</b> in the gripping element <b>18</b>, in particular, a presence of an object <b>17</b> in the entire region between the further pivot <b>65</b> of the lever and the ends of the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> facing away from the pivot <b>42</b> can be recognized and the assistance mode switched off. No additional sensor (not shown here) is needed for recognizing an object <b>17</b> between the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>. Thus, advantageously, only the force sensor <b>40</b> is needed, which is triggered by a crossing of a threshold value, in order to activate the assistance mode, and at the moment when an object <b>17</b> is present between the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> it necessarily switches off the assistance mode. In this way, the fault vulnerability and risk of injury, as well as the control engineering expense in order to possibly several alternative sensors for recognition of the different operating instances&#x2013; -force assistance mode necessary, object <b>17</b> present between the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> &#x2013; is far less.</p>
<p id="p-0182" num="0189">Basically, however, an alternative configuration of the force sensor <b>40</b> would be conceivable. For example, by a force sensor on the grip surface of the first or second gripping element <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> or a displacement sensor for recognition of the relative movement between the second gripping element <b>18</b> and the lever <b>80</b> or other kinds of sensors for recognition of an operating force F<sub>user</sub> acting on the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> and/or for recognition of a reactive force caused by the object <b>17</b> between the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> and opposing the closing movement of the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>. Alternative arrangements of the spring <b>68</b>, the switch  <b>72</b> or the further switch <b>73</b> to realize the same functionality are also conceivable. In this way, one could likewise detect the forces currently present on the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>, especially the need for the force assistance mode and the special instance of an object <b>17</b> between the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> and discontinuance of the force assistance mode. Moreover, a triggering force of the force sensor or sensors <b>40</b> could be defined freely by software. Basically, furthermore, it would be conceivable for the force sensor <b>40</b> to distinguish among different degrees of depressing of the switch <b>72</b> or swiveling of the swivel element <b>71</b> in order to infer a precise operating force F<sub>user</sub> that is present.</p>
<p id="p-0183" num="0190">Moreover, the force sensor <b>40</b> is connected to the control unit <b>52</b>. The control unit <b>52</b> is designed to control the driving element <b>20</b> in dependence on a signal of the force sensor <b>40</b>. The control unit <b>52</b> is designed to activate the driving element <b>20</b> when a defined measurement value of the force sensor <b>40</b> is crossed. The control unit <b>52</b> is designed to activate the driving element <b>20</b> upon a closing of the switch <b>72</b> of the force sensor <b>40</b>. Moreover, the control unit <b>52</b> is designed to halt the driving element <b>20</b> upon opening of the switch <b>72</b> of the force sensor <b>40</b>. A direct connection of the driving element <b>20</b> to the energy storage unit <b>54</b> via the switch <b>72</b> and without the control system <b>52</b> is also conceivable.</p>
<p id="p-0184" num="0191">For an operation of the cutting device <b>10</b>, one can distinguish between a manual mode of the cutting device <b>10</b>, in which a complete cutting force F<sub>cut</sub> is applied by a user, and an assisted mode in which a portion of the cutting force F<sub>cut</sub> is furthermore applied by the driving element <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0185" num="0192">The second cutting element <b>14</b> is designed as an active cutting element <b>14</b> with cutting edge. It is designed as an interchangeable cutting element <b>14</b>. The second cutting element <b>14</b> is connected by at least one form-fitting element <b>216</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>11</b>, <b>12</b></figref>) to the lever <b>80</b> of the cutting device <b>10</b>, which in turn is connected to the second gripping element <b>18</b>. The form-fitting elements <b>216</b> are designed at least to transmit forces in the radial direction about the axis of rotation <b>420</b>, but can also be designed to transmit axial forces F<sub>ax</sub> in the direction of the axis of rotation <b>420</b>, to the lever <b>80</b> or the cutting element <b>14</b>. On the lever <b>80</b> is formed a locking lug <b>220</b>, which engages with the form-fitting element <b>216</b> of the cutting element <b>14</b> in the connected state. Moreover, at least one axial guide surface <b>332</b> is provided for inserting the cutting element <b>14</b> into the cutting element mount <b>400</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0186" num="0193"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>13</b></figref> shows a cross section III-III&#x2032; through the cutting device <b>10</b> and the cutting element mount <b>400</b>. The first and the second cutting element <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> are connected indirectly by a shaft arranged along the axis of rotation <b>420</b>. The shaft forms a pivot <b>42</b> for the cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b>. The shaft is at least formed by a connection element <b>421</b>. On the connection element <b>421</b>, moreover, there is arranged a spacing element <b>423</b>. The spacing element <b>423</b> serves at least for the axial, and in the present instance also the radial spacing of the connection element <b>421</b> from the cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b>. The spacing element <b>423</b> can be fixed by a securing element <b>430</b> to the connection element <b>421</b>. The connection element <b>421</b> can also be designed as a single piece with the spacing element <b>423</b>. The connection element <b>421</b> is designed as a screw. The screw can be loosened and advantageously removed along with the spacing element <b>423</b> from the cutting device <b>10</b> or the grip housing <b>44</b>. The spacing element <b>423</b> is part of a control device <b>422</b>, which independently of a clamping force F<sub>klemm</sub> of the connection element <b>421</b> applies a defined pressing force F<sub>anpr</sub> of the cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> against each other in the direction of the axis of rotation <b>420</b>. The cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> have through-boreholes <b>120</b>, <b>140</b> in the direction of the axis of rotation <b>420</b>, through which the connection element <b>421</b> protrudes. The radial surfaces of the through-boreholes <b>120</b>, <b>140</b> form bearing surfaces, which are arranged on a corresponding bearing surface of the spacing element <b>423</b> or a sleeve radially encircling the connection element <b>421</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0187" num="0194">The spacing element <b>423</b> at least indirectly establishes a minimum spacing of two clamping force transmission elements in the direction of the axis of rotation <b>420</b>, here in the form of the screw head <b>443</b> of the screw and in the form of an abutment <b>425</b>, wherein the abutment is designed as a screw nut, especially a screw nut mounted firm against rotation, to which the screw is connected. These clamping force transmission elements transmit a pretensioning force F<sub>klemm</sub> of the connection element <b>421</b> at least indirectly to the spacing element <b>423</b>. The spacing element <b>423</b> transmits only a definable portion of the clamping force F<sub>klemm</sub> to the axial surfaces <b>121</b>, <b>141</b> of the cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b>. Thus, at least an axial position of the two cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> along the axis of rotation or a friction force between the cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b>, which occurs when these swivel relative to each other, can be established independently of a tightening torque of the connection element <b>423</b> or independently of another factor of influence.</p>
<p id="p-0188" num="0195"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>. A lengthwise dimension 1 of the spacing element <b>423</b> in the direction of the axis of rotation <b>420</b> enables a relative movement of the cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b>, especially a swivel movement of the cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> to each other. This corresponds advantageously at least to the sum of the widths b<sub>1</sub>, b<sub>2</sub> of the two cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> along the axis of rotation <b>420</b>. In this way, independently of the clamping force F<sub>klemm</sub> of the connection element <b>421</b> or the tightening torque of the screw, a distance or a maximum pressing force F<sub>an</sub> can be established between the cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b>, at least in the non-activated state of the cutting device <b>10</b>, so that an activating ability of the cutting device <b>10</b> is guaranteed.</p>
<p id="p-0189" num="0196">Moreover, the control device can comprise an elastic element <b>424</b>, which applies a defined axial force or clamping force F<sub>klemm</sub> to the cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> against each other along the axis of rotation <b>420</b>. The elastic element <b>424</b> is designed as a spring, especially a compression spring, especially preferably a corrugated spring. The elastic element <b>424</b> is arranged indirectly between an axial surface <b>122</b> of the first cutting element <b>12</b> and a radial shoulder <b>426</b> of the spacing element <b>423</b>. The elastic element is arranged between the axial surface <b>122</b> of the first cutting element <b>12</b> and a securing ring <b>427</b>. The securing ring <b>427</b> is braced against the shoulder <b>426</b> of the spacing element <b>423</b>. Moreover, the securing ring <b>427</b> is also braced against the grip housing <b>44</b>. The force with which the elastic element <b>424</b> is compressed corresponds to the axial force F<sub>ax</sub> and acts as a pressing force F<sub>an</sub> or as a pressing force or normal force between the two cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b>. Thus, the elastic element <b>424</b> adjusts a friction force between the cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b>. In this way, a basic activating force for the closing of the cutting device <b>10</b> can be at least partly established. In this way, a basic distance between the cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> can be adjusted. Regardless of the manufacturing width &#x2013; within a tolerance band &#x2013; of the cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b>, the pressing force F<sub>an</sub> of the cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> against each other remains approximately constant, due to the spring constant of the elastic element <b>424</b>. Further tolerances of the cutting element mount <b>400</b> can also be equalized. Advantageously, a sheet of paper as well as a tree branch can thus be cut by the cutting device <b>10</b>, since the cutting gap can be adapted to the requirement dictated by the material <b>11</b> being cut. A replacement of the second cutting element <b>14</b> is possible without fine tuning the clamping force or a tightening torque of the screw or a changing of intermediate elements. Regardless of the clamping force or the tightening torque of the connection element <b>423</b> or the screw, the pressing force F<sub>an</sub> between the cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> remains almost constant. The corrugated spring advantageously has an outer diameter in the range of 20 mm and an inner diameter in the range of 15 mm. A free axial length of the corrugated spring is advantageously less than 5 mm, especially 3.25 mm. The clamping force of the corrugated spring is advantageously <b>15</b> to 25 N, for a compressed length of 1.1 to 1.5 mm.</p>
<p id="p-0190" num="0197">Moreover, when the connection element <b>423</b> is loosened and especially when the connection and spacing element <b>421</b>, <b>423</b> is entirely removed, the securing ring <b>427</b> is axially braced against the grip housing <b>44</b>. Thus, at least a reduced axial force F<sub>ax</sub> of the spring or a pressing force F<sub>an</sub> at least against the first cutting element <b>12</b> is preserved. In this way, the second cutting element <b>14</b> being replaced can be at least positioned, even without connection element <b>421</b>, and/or is secured against unintentional dropping out from the cutting device <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0191" num="0198">For at least the transmission of the axial force F<sub>ax</sub> of the elastic element <b>424</b>, the first in particular stationary cutting element <b>12</b> is also designed to be transversely movable, i.e., movable in the direction of the axis of rotation <b>420</b>. It is secured in the direction of rotation about the axis of rotation by form-fitting elements. These are braced against corresponding form-fitting elements in the first gripping element <b>16</b>. In particular, the corresponding form-fitting elements are connection elements for the connecting of the grip shells of the first gripping element <b>16</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0192" num="0199">The elastic element <b>424</b> also serves as an overload protection element of the cutting device <b>10</b>. It prevents a plastic deformation of the cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> in operation of the cutting device <b>10</b>. Thanks to the elastic element <b>424</b> a threshold value F<sub>ax</sub> is adjusted, after which the cutting element <b>10</b> can gape open. Upon exceeding the spring force F<sub>ax</sub> the elastic element yields, at least as far as the axial stop of the second cutting element <b>14</b> against an end stop element <b>442</b> and thus enables at least a slight axial displacement and/or a tilting within the first gripping element <b>16</b> or along the axis of rotation <b>420</b>. The elastic behavior and the desired gaping upon crossing a defined threshold value can be adjusted through the spring force of the elastic element <b>424</b> and the arrangement of the control device <b>422</b>. In the present instance, the control device <b>422</b> comprises at least the connection element <b>421</b>, the spacing element <b>423</b>, the securing ring <b>427</b> and the elastic element <b>424</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0193" num="0200">The abutment <b>425</b> of the connection element <b>421</b> in the form of the screw nut is firmly mounted in the grip housing <b>44</b> of the cutting device <b>10</b>. Thanks to a hexagonal form-fitting element <b>428</b>, it is mounted firm against twisting. A cover <b>429</b>, which is connected to the grip housing <b>44</b>, secures the screw nut axially, so that it is positioned on the cutting device <b>10</b> even when the connection element <b>421</b> is removed. Moreover, between grip housing <b>44</b> and lever <b>80</b> there is arranged a sliding element <b>440</b> in the form of a sliding ring or a sliding disk. The sliding disk is at least a fixation element <b>441</b> joined firm against rotation to the grip housing <b>44</b>. Moreover, the sliding element <b>440</b> is also arranged between spacing element <b>423</b> and the abutment <b>425</b> configured as the screw nut. Thus, the abutment is axially secured between sliding element <b>440</b> and the cover <b>429</b> especially when the connection element <b>421</b> is removed. Moreover, the sliding element <b>440</b> decouples a potential rotary movement of the spacing element <b>423</b> from the abutment <b>425</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0194" num="0201"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>. The control device <b>422</b> can be secured, firm against twisting, at least indirectly at one or more places to the grip housing <b>44</b> and/or the stationary first cutting element <b>12</b>, so that the relative movement of the lever <b>80</b> or the first cutting element <b>12</b> does not result in an unwanted loosening of the connection element <b>421</b>. For this, for example, the sliding element, the abutment <b>425</b> and/or the spacing element <b>423</b> are mounted, firm against twisting, on the grip housing <b>44</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0195" num="0202">A thickness of the first cutting element <b>12</b> is advantageously 4 mm. A thickness of the second cutting element <b>14</b> at its thickest point is advantageously 3.5 mm. A thickness of the lever <b>80</b> is advantageously 3.5 mm.</p>
<p id="p-0196" num="0203"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>14</b></figref> shows a cutting element, fashioned as the second cutting element <b>14</b>, in a top view, as well as a side view. The second cutting element <b>14</b> has a blade <b>143</b>. The second cutting element <b>14</b> is an interchangeable cutting element for the cutting device <b>10</b>. The second cutting element <b>14</b> has a tip <b>146</b> and an end <b>148</b> opposite the tip <b>146</b>. In the region of the end <b>148</b>, the second cutting element <b>14</b> has a recess <b>214</b>. The recess <b>214</b> serves as a mount for a locking element <b>210</b> of the blocking device <b>202</b> of the cutting device <b>10</b> for blocking a movement of the cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> toward each other. Moreover, the second cutting element <b>14</b> comprises the form-fitting element <b>216</b>, which is designed as a counter locking recess for the locking lug <b>220</b> of the lever <b>80</b> of the cutting device <b>10</b>. The form-fitting element <b>216</b> serves to transmit radial forces of the gripping element <b>18</b>, especially via the lever <b>80</b>, about the pivot <b>42</b> of the cutting device <b>10</b>. The end <b>148</b> of the second cutting element <b>14</b> is moreover at least partly rounded. Between the end <b>148</b> of the second cutting element <b>14</b> and a mount <b>142</b>, designed as a recess <b>140</b>, which is designed for the rotary mounting of the second cutting element <b>14</b> in the cutting device <b>10</b>, the second cutting element <b>14</b> has an insert guide <b>144</b> in the form of a slanting surface. The insert guide <b>144</b> is beveled with respect to a cutting plane of the second cutting element <b>14</b>, formed by the cutting surface <b>145</b>, but it can also be round, in particular convex. The insert guide <b>144</b> runs substantially from the center of the mount <b>142</b> in the radial direction as far as the end <b>148</b> of the second cutting element <b>14</b>. A thickness of the second cutting element <b>14</b> decreases in the region of the insert guide <b>144</b> in the direction of the end <b>148</b>. The thickness decreases from around 3.5 mm to 2.7 mm. A sector length of the slanting surface is advantageously 9 mm. The angle &#x3b1; of the slanting surface is advantageously less than 30&#xb0;, especially less than 15&#xb0; and most especially preferably around 5&#xb0;. Between the insert guide <b>144</b> and the blade <b>143</b> extends a bearing surface <b>149</b>. The bearing surface <b>149</b> is designed for the form-fitting connection to the lever <b>80</b>. It is flat in configuration and oriented normal to the direction of the recess <b>142</b> or normal to the direction of an axis of rotation <b>420</b> of the pair of garden shears <b>10</b>. The opposite cutting surface <b>145</b> is designed to slide along the first cutting element <b>12</b>. It swivels, sliding along the first cutting element <b>12</b>, about the axis of rotation <b>420</b> or the pivot <b>42</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0197" num="0204">A method for operating the cutting device <b>10</b> will be described below (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>10</b></figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0198" num="0205">Preferably an activation of the cutting device is only possible when the blocking device is in the second position. Preferably no charging process of the cutting device is provided in this second position. The cutting device <b>10</b> is constantly in an operating mode. As soon as the switch <b>72</b> is closed, the control unit <b>52</b> activates the drive motor <b>20</b>. Basically, however, it would also be conceivable for the cutting device <b>10</b> to have in particular in addition an operating switch, by means of which the cutting device <b>10</b> can be activated and deactivated. Alternatively, it would also be conceivable for the cutting device <b>10</b> to activate itself, for example by a defined closing and/or opening sequence of the cutting device <b>10</b>. A deactivation would be conceivable in dependence on the time, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0199" num="0206">If a user would like to perform a cutting process during operation, such as cutting through a branch, he must position the material <b>11</b> to be cut between the cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> of the cutting device <b>10</b>. Next, the cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> can be closed by pressing together the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> relative to each other, especially as with a traditional pair of garden shears. The gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> in a step <b>1180</b> are manually pressed together by a user. As long as the spring force of the force sensor <b>40</b> is not exceeded, the switch <b>72</b> does not put out any signal. In step <b>1200</b>, the control unit <b>52</b> monitors a signal of the force sensor <b>40</b> or switch <b>72</b>. The control unit <b>52</b> thus monitors a force required for a cutting process. The control unit <b>52</b> checks whether the switch <b>72</b> of the force sensor <b>40</b> is open or closed.</p>
<p id="p-0200" num="0207">If the force of a user F<sub>user</sub> which is required for the cutting process is less than a force as defined by the force sensor <b>40</b>, which is needed for a closing of the switch <b>72</b>, the cutting device <b>10</b> is used in a manual mode. If the switch <b>72</b> is opened, step <b>1200</b> is repeated in the following decision loop <b>1220</b>. In manual mode, the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> are manually swiveled toward each other by a user. In manual mode, the cable <b>34</b> is wound up on the cable winch <b>32</b> by means of the restoring unit <b>31</b> or the spring element <b>36</b>. Since in this case a force from a power takeoff side is acting on the coupling unit <b>22</b>, the coupling unit <b>22</b> is in an opened state. The cable winch <b>32</b> can therefore be turned without any resistance of the gear unit <b>38</b> and the driving element <b>20</b>. The cable <b>34</b> in this state is held taut by the spring element <b>36</b>. If a user reduces a force on the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>, for example because a cutting process is ended, the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> are moved apart by means of the opening spring <b>50</b> and the cutting device <b>10</b> is opened. The cable <b>34</b> is unwound against the spring force of the spring element <b>36</b> from the cable winch <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0201" num="0208">If an energy storage unit <b>54</b> of the cutting device <b>10</b> is empty, the cutting device <b>10</b> can be used in a manual mode, in which case the driving element <b>20</b> remains deactivated even upon exceeding a force as defined by the force sensor <b>40</b>. There is no activation of the driving element <b>20</b>, so that the coupling unit <b>22</b> also remains opened.</p>
<p id="p-0202" num="0209">If a force of a user F<sub>user</sub> required for the cutting process is greater than a force defined by the force sensor <b>40</b> which is needed for a closing of the switch <b>72</b>, the cutting device <b>10</b> is used in an assisted mode. A switching from a manual mode to an assisted mode is done basically during a cutting process. In the manual mode, the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> are swiveled manually against each other by a user. If a hard material <b>11</b> is being cut, the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> must be pressed together by a user with large force. If a force applied is so large that the switch <b>72</b> is closed upon overcoming a spring force F<sub>gs</sub>, this will be sensed by the control unit <b>52</b>. The control unit <b>52</b> thereupon activates the driving element <b>20</b>. If it is determined in the decision loop <b>1220</b> that the switch <b>72</b> has been closed, the driving element <b>20</b> is activated via the control unit <b>52</b> in a step <b>1240</b>. The driving element <b>20</b> accordingly is switched on for a closing mechanism of the cutting device <b>10</b> upon exceeding a defined user force. The driving element <b>20</b> thereupon drives the inner rotary element <b>46</b> of the coupling unit <b>22</b> via the gear unit <b>38</b>. The driving element <b>20</b> is driven in the driving direction <b>41</b>. The coupling unit <b>22</b> is closed and drives the cable winch <b>32</b>. The cable <b>34</b> is wound up on the cable winch <b>32</b>. The gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> are now pushed or drawn together by a driving force F<sub>as</sub> in addition to a user force F<sub>user</sub>. The driving element <b>20</b> in this operating state applies an additional force to the cutting elements <b>12</b>, <b>14</b>, during a partly manual movement. The driving force F<sub>as</sub> in this case acts on the cable <b>34</b> via the cable winch <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0203" num="0210">The driving force F<sub>as</sub> in this case acts via the cable <b>34</b> on the lever <b>80</b>. As long as the operating force F<sub>user</sub> continues to be greater than a force as defined by the force sensor <b>40</b>, which is required for a closing of the switch <b>72</b>, the manual movement continues to be assisted by the driving force F<sub>an</sub>. On the other hand, if the operating force F<sub>user</sub> is relaxed such that the switch <b>72</b> opens, the driving element <b>20</b> halts in a step <b>1260</b>. A halting of the driving element <b>20</b> in step <b>1260</b> can also be achieved if the two gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> are closed or touch via the spacing element <b>630</b> or an object <b>17</b> is present between the gripping elements <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>, so that likewise a force as defined by the force sensor <b>40</b> and needed for a closing of the switch <b>72</b> is undershot. The operating force F<sub>user</sub> in this state can no longer act on the force sensor <b>40</b>, since the driving force F<sub>as</sub> acts on the lever <b>80</b> via the cable <b>34</b> and moves it to its starting position in which the switch <b>72</b> is opened. The driving element <b>20</b> is then driven in a step <b>1280</b> briefly in the counter-driving direction <b>410</b> in order to open the coupling unit <b>22</b>. The brake element <b>28</b> brakes the cage <b>26</b>, the clamping bodies <b>24</b> no longer clamp the outer against the inner rotary element <b>46</b>, <b>48</b>. This reversal of direction of the driving element <b>20</b> or the drive of the driving element <b>20</b> in the counter-driving direction <b>410</b> can be brief, for example less than 100 milliseconds, especially 40 milliseconds. Then the driving element <b>20</b> is deactivated in a step <b>1300</b>. After a deactivation of the driving element <b>20</b>, the process can begin from the start.</p>
<p id="p-0204" num="0211">Basically the coupling unit <b>22</b> can also automatically decouple the driving element <b>20</b> in absence of a rotary movement. The cutting device <b>10</b>, when a rotary movement of the driving element <b>20</b> is halted, can also in theory be at least partly opened by the opening spring <b>50</b> and the cable winch <b>32</b> turned via the cable <b>34</b> partly against a driving direction <b>41</b> of the driving element <b>20</b>. Likewise, a rotation of the inner rotary element <b>46</b> toward the outer rotary element <b>48</b> of the coupling unit <b>22</b> can also take place, and the coupling unit <b>22</b> opened in this way. Basically, however, some other method of opening the coupling unit <b>22</b> would also be conceivable.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A cutting device comprising:
<claim-text>a first cutting element and a second cutting element configured to move relative to each other;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first gripping element and a second gripping element configured to move relative to each other, the first gripping element extending from the first cutting element, and the second gripping element extending from the second cutting element;</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one driving element configured to move the first cutting element relative to the second cutting element when the at least one driving element is activated;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a sensor mounted on or in the first gripping element or the second gripping element and configured to detect an object located between the first gripping element and the second gripping element; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a control unit operably connected to the at least one driving element and the sensor, the control unit configured to deactivate the at least one driving element when the sensor detects the object.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The cutting device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the first gripping element defines a first grip inside surface facing the second gripping element,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second gripping element defines a second grip inside surface facing the first gripping element, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the sensor is located on either the first grip inside surface or the second grip inside surface.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The cutting device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the sensor is a force sensor configured to detect a force acting on the second gripping element relative to the first gripping element for detecting the object.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The cutting device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the force sensor includes a spring and a switch located inside of the first gripping element or the second gripping element,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the switch is configurable in a first state and a second state, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the sensor detects the object when movement of the second gripping element relative to the second cutting element causes the switch to change from the first state to the second state.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The cutting device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a further switch operably connected to the switch and configured for displacement relative to the switch,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a threshold value for triggering the switch to change from the first state to the second state is based on the displacement of the further switch.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The cutting device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the second gripping element is operably connected to the second cutting element by a force transmission element,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second cutting element is connected firm against rotation to the force transmission element,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second gripping element is pivotably connected to the force transmission element at a pivot axis, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the sensor is configured to detect pivoting of the second gripping element about the pivot axis to detect the object.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The cutting device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the at least one driving element is activated in an assistance mode of the cutting device,</claim-text>
<claim-text>in the assistance mode a user&#x2019;s force produces a closing movement of the first cutting element relative to the second cutting element, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>in the assistance mode the at least one driving element generates a force which acts at least partly in a direction which is the same as that of the user&#x2019;s force.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The cutting device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a force transmission element arranged between the second cutting element and the second gripping element, and connected firm against rotation to the second cutting element, the force transmission element standing in operative connection with the at least one driving element in the assistance mode,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the force transmission element is movable relative to the second gripping element, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the sensor detects the object based on the movement of force transmission element relative to the second gripping element.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The cutting device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the movement of the force transmission element is a swivel movement of the force transmission element relative to the second gripping element.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The cutting device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the second gripping element comprises at least one relative movement limiting element.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The cutting device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a displacement sensor configured to detect the movement of the force transmission element relative to the second gripping element.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The cutting device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein at least one of the first gripping element and the second gripping element defines a rounded configuration to avoid pinching a part of a user&#x2019;s body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. The cutting device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a protection device located between the first gripping element and the second gripping element;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an opening spring extending from the first gripping element and the second gripping element; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a cable extending between the first gripping element and the second gripping element,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second gripping element is operably connected to the first gripping element at a pivot,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the protection device is located between the pivot and the opening spring,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein an intermediate space is defined between the pivot and the opening spring,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the protection device at least partially fills the intermediate space, such that further objects are prevented from being inserted into the intermediate space, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the protection device receives the cable.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The cutting device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one driving element allows (i) manual operation for cutting with the first and the second cutting elements in which the at least one driving element is deactivated, and (ii) machine-assisted manual operation for cutting with the first and the second cutting elements in which the at least one driving element is activated in the assistance mode.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. A method for operating a cutting device comprising:
<claim-text>activating at least one driving element for moving (i) a first cutting element and a first gripping element relative to (ii) a second cutting element and a second gripping element, the first griping element extending from the first cutting element and the second gripping element extending from the second cutting element;</claim-text>
<claim-text>sensing an object located between the first gripping element and the second gripping element with a sensor during the activation of the at least one driving element, the sensor mounted on or in the first gripping element or the second gripping element; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>switching off the at least one driving element, using a control unit, by deactivating the at least one driving element when the sensor detects the object, the control unit operably connected to the at least one driving element and the sensor.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. The method for operating a cutting device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein sensing the object comprises:
<claim-text>sensing pivoting of the second gripping element relative to the second cutting element.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. The method for operating a cutting device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the sensor is a force sensor configured to detect a force acting on the second gripping element relative to the first gripping element for detecting the object,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the force sensor includes a spring and a switch located inside of the first gripping element or the second gripping element,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the switch is configurable in a first state and a second state, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the sensor detects the object when movement of the second gripping element relative to the second cutting element causes the switch to change from the first state to the second state.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. The method for operating a cutting device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>selecting a threshold value for trigging the switch to change from the first state to the second state based on a displacement of a further switch,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the further switch is operably connected to the switch and is configured for displacement relative to the switch.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. The method for operating a cutting device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein at least one of the first gripping element and the second gripping element defines a rounded configuration to avoid pinching a part of a user&#x2019;s body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. The method for operating a cutting device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>activating the at least one driving element in an assistance mode of the cutting device,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein in the assistance mode a user&#x2019;s force produces a closing movement of the first cutting element relative to the second cutting element, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein in the assistance mode the at least one driving element generates a force which acts at least partly in a direction which is the same as that of the user&#x2019;s force.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
