<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225554A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230710" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225554</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18097853</doc-number>
<date>20230117</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>202220146551.9</doc-number>
<date>20220120</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>37</main-group>
<subgroup>06</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>36</main-group>
<subgroup>32</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>37</main-group>
<subgroup>0641</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>36</main-group>
<subgroup>32</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="frddzcqy9oqsn">LIFTING MULTIFUNCTIONAL AIR FRYER</invention-title>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>NINGBO CARELINE ELECTRIC APPLIANCE CO., LTD.</orgname>
<address>
<city>Ningbo</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>ZHANG</last-name>
<first-name>Yichi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Ningbo</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="01" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>PAN</last-name>
<first-name>Huayuan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Ningbo</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="02" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>BAI</last-name>
<first-name>Rongjie</first-name>
<address>
<city>Ningbo</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="03" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>LIANG</last-name>
<first-name>Jiahe</first-name>
<address>
<city>Ningbo</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Provided is lifting multifunctional air fryer, including machine body, cookware and lifting drive component, wherein the cookware includes at least frying basket and frying pan, and the machine body includes machine head, base, and side plate arranged between the machine head and the base, to define first cooking chamber for accommodating the frying basket and second cooking chamber for accommodating the frying pan. Air frying module is arranged above the first cooking chamber, and the air frying module communicates the inner chamber of frying basket; first heating element is arranged above the second cooking chamber, and second heating element is arranged below, both of them are connected to the frying pan; the first heating element is driven by the lifting drive component to lift, so that the height between the first heating element and the second heating element is adapted to that of ingredients on the frying pan.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="106.00mm" wi="122.77mm" file="US20230225554A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="198.04mm" wi="143.93mm" file="US20230225554A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="214.55mm" wi="146.56mm" file="US20230225554A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="92.63mm" wi="111.84mm" file="US20230225554A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading level="1" id="h-0001">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present disclosure claims the priority to the Chinese patent application filed with the Chinese Patent Office on Jan. 20, 2022 with the filing No. CN 2022201465519, and entitled &#x201c;Lifting Multifunctional Air Fryer&#x201d;, the contents of which are incorporated herein by reference in entirety.</p>
<heading level="1" id="h-0002">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates to the technical field of kitchen appliances, in particular to a lifting multifunctional air fryer.</p>
<heading level="1" id="h-0003">BACKGROUND ART</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The air fryer guides the hot air to flow quickly over the surface of the food, so as to form a crispy surface of the food, thereby achieving a cooking taste similar to deep fried food. At present, the existing air fryers have a single function, and can only fry ingredients by air, such as fried chicken and fries, which are unable to cook ingredients with multiple tastes.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In order to meet a variety of use requirements, some multifunctional air fryers have also appeared. For example, the patent application with the filing number CN202022544512.8 discloses a multifunctional air fryer, which comprises: a lower body, which is equipped with a lower thermal-radiation heating component inside; an upper body, which is equipped with a hot air convection component inside, wherein the upper body can be fitted with or separated from the lower body, when the upper body and the lower body are matched with each other, an air frying chamber can be formed, and the lower thermal-radiation heating component cooperates with the hot air convection component to perform air frying to the ingredients in the air frying chamber; and when the upper body is separated from the lower body, the upper body can keep away from the top of the lower body, so that the lower body provides a cooking chamber with an opening facing upward; and a cooking utensil, which can be arranged in the air frying chamber or the cooking chamber, and is used for accommodating ingredients to be cooked. Although the air fryer can realize the function of frying and grilling, it can only grill one side of the ingredients and can only cook the ingredients in one way, rather than air frying one while grilling another one, thereby lowering the cooking efficiency.</p>
<heading level="1" id="h-0004">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The present disclosure provides a lifting multifunctional air fryer to solve the problem that the existing multifunctional air fryer can only grill one side of the ingredients and cannot cooking different ingredients at the same time.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In order to solve the above-mentioned technical problems, the present disclosure provides a lifting multifunctional air fryer, the air fryer comprises:
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
<li id="ul0001-0001" num="0007">a cookware, including at least one frying basket and at least one frying pan;</li>
<li id="ul0001-0002" num="0008">a machine body, including a machine head, a base, and a side plate, wherein the side plate is arranged between the machine head and the base, and defines a first cooking chamber for accommodating the frying basket and a second cooking chamber for accommodating the frying pan, an air frying module is provided above the first cooking chamber, the air frying module communicates with the inner chamber of the frying basket, a first heating element is provided above the second cooking chamber, a second heating element is provided below the second cooking chamber, and the first heating element and the second heating element are both connected to the frying pan; and</li>
<li id="ul0001-0003" num="0009">a lifting drive component, configured to actuate the first heating element to carry out lifting movement, so as to enable the height between the first heating element and the second heating element to match the height of the ingredient on the frying pan.</li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0010">In an optional embodiment, the first heating element is a heating plate, and the heating plate includes a plate body and electrical heated tubes set in the plate body. In this embodiment, a heating plate is used as the first heating element, which has a simple structure and is easy to assemble and clean.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0011">In an optional embodiment, the lifting drive component includes a drive motor, a gear sleeved on the output shaft of the drive motor, and a rack meshed with the gear, the rack is vertically arranged and connected to the first heating element. In this embodiment, the gear-rack transmission mechanism is used to convert the high-speed rotation of the drive motor into the low-speed linear movement of the rack. In this way, the lifting drive component can smoothly drive the first heating element to carry out the lifting movement, which can prevent the first heating element from being unstable during the lifting process due to the excessively fast speed.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0012">In an optional embodiment, the air fryer also includes:
<ul id="ul0002" list-style="none">
<li id="ul0002-0001" num="0013">a safety switch, which is arranged in the machine head, including an ascending switch and a descending switch;</li>
<li id="ul0002-0002" num="0014">a rotary handle, which is rotatably connected to the machine head, the inner end of the rotary handle is provided with a trigger part, and the trigger part is in linkage with the safety switch; and</li>
<li id="ul0002-0003" num="0015">a controller, which is arranged in the machine head and electrically connected with the safety switch and the drive motor, wherein</li>
<li id="ul0002-0004" num="0016">the rotary handle is rotated with at least a first position and a second position, when the rotary handle is rotated to the first position, the trigger part triggers the ascending switch to control the first heating element to rise; and when the rotary handle is rotated to the second position, the trigger part triggers the descending switch to control the first heating element to go down. In the present disclosure, the rotary handle is used to control the lifting of the first heating element, so as to simplify the operation, avoid maloperation and improve user experience.</li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0017">In an optional embodiment, a limiting part is provided on the rack. In this embodiment, the setting of the limiting part makes the movement of the rack within a controllable range, and prevents the rack from being disengaged with the gear while moving up and down.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0018">In an optional embodiment, a third heating element is provided in the base, and the third heating element is located below the first cooking chamber and is arranged correspondingly to the bottom of the frying basket. The setting of the third heating element in this embodiment, on the one hand, can improve the hot air circulation in the frying basket to increase the heating efficiency, and allow the food to be heated more evenly; on the other hand, it can expand the working mode of the air fryer.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0019">In an optional embodiment, the frying basket includes a bottom plate and a vertical plate arranged around the bottom plate, the bottom plate and the vertical plate are integrally formed to form a receiving chamber with an open top, when the frying basket is placed in the first cooking chamber, part region of the vertical plate is surrounded by side plates, and the remaining region is directly exposed to the external environment. In this embodiment, the air fryer is in an open structure, the frying basket is directly communicated to the external environment, and the side wall of the frying basket has no cold air circulation structure such as lower core, shell, etc. On the one hand, the material cost and the assembly cost of the frying basket are saved, thereby reducing the production cost of the air fryer; on the other hand, it is convenient to clean the machine head and frying basket.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0020">In an optional embodiment, the projected length of the side plate on the base is not greater than half of the perimeter of the base. In the present disclosure, the cookware can be put inside and outside the first cooking chamber and the second cooking chamber from various angles on the side surfaces of the air fryer while in the prior art the cookware can only be put in from the front, which improves the user experience and aesthetic of the air fryer. At the same time, since most part of the vertical plate is exposed, the heat dissipation effect of the frying basket is improved.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0021">In an optional embodiment, when the frying basket is placed in the first cooking chamber, there are steam outlets between the vertical plate and the machine head. In this embodiment, there is no need to provide steam outlet on the side surface of the machine head, which simplifies the structure of the air fryer and improves the aesthetics of the air fryer.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0022">In an optional embodiment, the frying basket further includes a pot lid that is covered on the vertical plate, and the inner wall of the vertical plate is provided with a step surface, and the step surface is selectively equipped with a steaming plate or a frying pan. In this embodiment, the frying basket can not only fry food, but also can steam food, which can be used for multiple purposes, and has very good practicability.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0023">Compared with prior art, the beneficial effect of the present disclosure is as follows.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0024">The present disclosure designs the structure of the air fryer. By configuring the first cooking chamber, the second cooking chamber, the air frying module, the second heating element, the frying basket and the frying pan, the air fryer can fry and deeply fry the food at the same time, so as to meet the users&#x2019; different cooking needs. By configuring the first heating element and the lifting drive component, the lifting drive component actuate the first heating element to move up and down, so that the air fryer can fry food with different thicknesses on both sides, achieving a more efficient and delicious frying effect.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading level="1" id="h-0005">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0019" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a schematic structural view of a lifting multifunctional air fryer according to an example of the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a sectional view of the lifting multifunctional air fryer when the first heating element of the example of the present disclosure is raised to the highest point;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a sectional view of the lifting multifunctional air fryer when the first heating element of the example of the present disclosure is lowered to the lowest point;</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is a partially exploded view drawing of the lifting multifunctional air fryer according to the example of the present disclosure; and</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is a schematic structural view of the frying basket of the embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading level="1" id="h-0006">EXPLANATION OF REFERENCE SIGNS</heading>
<p id="p-0024" num="0030"><b>1</b>, machine head; <b>2</b>, air frying module; <b>201</b>, rotating motor; <b>202</b>, cooling fan; <b>203</b>, air duct plate; <b>204</b>, thermal circulation fan; <b>205</b>, heating tube; <b>3</b>, first heating element; <b>4</b>, partition plate; <b>5</b>, base; <b>6</b>, second heating element; <b>7</b>, side plate; <b>8</b>, first cooking chamber; <b>9</b>, second cooking chamber; <b>10</b>, frying basket; <b>101</b>, bottom plate; <b>102</b>, vertical plate; <b>103</b>, pot lid; <b>104</b>, step surface; <b>11</b>, frying pan; <b>12</b>, drive motor; <b>13</b>, gear; <b>14</b>, rack; <b>15</b>, safety switch; <b>151</b>, ascending switch; <b>152</b>, descending switch; <b>16</b>, rotary handle; <b>17</b>, trigger part; <b>18</b>, third heating element; <b>19</b>, steam outlet.</p>
<heading level="1" id="h-0007">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0025" num="0031">In order to exhibit the above-mentioned objects, features and advantages of the present disclosure more obvious and understandable, the present disclosure will be further described in detail below with reference to the accompanying drawings and specific embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0032">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>, the present disclosure shows a lifting multifunctional air fryer, which comprises a machine body, a cookware and a lifting drive component, wherein the cookware at least includes a frying basket <b>10</b> and a frying pan <b>11</b>. The machine body includes a machine head <b>1</b>, a base <b>5</b>, and a side plate <b>7</b>. The side plate <b>7</b> is arranged between the machine head <b>1</b> and the base <b>5</b>, and defines a first cooking chamber <b>8</b> for accommodating a frying basket <b>10</b> and a second cooking chamber <b>9</b> for accommodating a frying pan <b>11</b>. Herein, an air frying module <b>2</b> is arranged above the first cooking chamber <b>8</b>, and the air frying module <b>2</b> is communicated with the inner chamber of the frying basket <b>10</b>; and the first heating element <b>3</b> is arranged above the second cooking chamber <b>9</b> and the second heating element <b>6</b> is arranged below the second cooking chamber <b>9</b>, and both the first heating element <b>3</b> and the second heating element <b>6</b> are connected to the frying pan <b>11</b>. The first heating element <b>3</b> is driven by the lifting drive component to move up and down, so that the height between the first heating element <b>3</b> and the second heating element <b>6</b> matches the height of the ingredients on the frying pan <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0033">Specifically, a partition plate <b>4</b> is provided inside the machine head <b>1</b> to divide the machine head <b>1</b> into a first installation chamber and a second installation chamber, and the air frying module <b>2</b> is located in the first installation chamber and above the first cooking chamber <b>8</b>; the first heating element <b>3</b> and the lifting drive component are located in the second installation chamber and above the second cooking chamber <b>9</b>; and the second heating element <b>6</b> is located in the base <b>5</b> and is arranged oppositely to the first heating element <b>3</b>. The air frying module <b>2</b>, the first heating element <b>3</b>, the second heating element <b>6</b> and the lifting drive component are respectively electrically connected to the controller. Specifically, from top to bottom, the air frying module <b>2</b> includes a rotating motor <b>201</b>, a cooling fan <b>202</b>, an air duct plate <b>203</b>, a thermal circulation fan <b>204</b>, and a heating tube <b>205</b> in sequence, and the cooling fan <b>202</b> and the thermal circulation fan <b>204</b> are both sleeved on the output shaft of rotating motor <b>201</b>; and the air duct plate <b>203</b> divides the first installation chamber into a heat dissipation chamber and a heating chamber, and the heating chamber communicates with the first cooking chamber <b>8</b>. The first heating element <b>3</b> and the second heating element <b>6</b> are selected from any one of heating plate, heating tube, coil disk, and heating film.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0034">When cooking, the frying basket <b>10</b> can be placed in the first cooking chamber <b>8</b>, and the frying pan <b>11</b> can be placed in the second cooking chamber <b>9</b>, such that the food can be deeply fried and fried at the same time. When frying food, the height of the first heating element <b>3</b> can be adjusted through the lifting drive component to adapt to food with different heights and realize double-sided frying. The air frying module <b>2</b>, the first heating element <b>3</b> and the second heating element <b>6</b> can work simultaneously or independently. The present disclosure designs the structure of the air fryer. By configuring the first cooking chamber <b>8</b>, the second cooking chamber <b>9</b>, the air frying module <b>2</b>, the second heating element <b>6</b>, the frying basket <b>10</b> and the frying pan <b>11</b>, the air fryer can simultaneously deeply fry and fry the food to meet users&#x2019; different cooking needs. By configuring the first heating element <b>3</b> and the lifting drive component, the lifting drive component actuates the first heating element <b>3</b> to move up and down, so that the air fryer can fry food with different thicknesses on both sides, achieving a more efficient and delicious frying effect.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0035">In an optional embodiment, referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, the lifting drive component includes a drive motor <b>12</b>, a gear <b>13</b> sleeved on the output shaft of the drive motor <b>12</b> and a rack <b>14</b> meshed with the gear <b>13</b>. The rack <b>14</b> is arranged vertically and connected with the first heating element <b>3</b>. In this embodiment, the drive motor <b>12</b>, the gear <b>13</b> and the rack <b>14</b> are all mounted on a bracket, the bracket is provided with a guide rail groove, and the rack <b>14</b> moves up and down in the guide rail groove. The first heating element <b>3</b> is fixedly connected to the lower end of rack <b>14</b>. When working, the drive motor <b>12</b> rotates to actuate the gear <b>13</b> to rotate, and the rotation of gear <b>13</b> drives the rack <b>14</b> to move linearly, and further drives the first heating element <b>3</b> to move up and down. By controlling the rotation direction of the drive motor <b>12</b>, the first heating element <b>3</b> is switched between ascending and descending, and the height of the first heating element <b>3</b> from the second heating element <b>6</b> is controlled by the rotation time of the motor. For example, if the height of the first heating element <b>3</b> needs to be lowered so that it contacts the surface of the food, the drive motor <b>12</b> is controlled to rotate forward; and when the height of the first heating element <b>3</b> needs to be raised, the drive motor <b>12</b> is controlled to rotate in reverse. In this embodiment, the transmission mechanism with gear <b>13</b> and the rack <b>14</b> is used to convert the circular motion of the drive motor <b>12</b> into linear motion, which has a simple structure and strong practicability. It should be noted that, for this embodiment, the lifting drive component for driving the first heating element <b>3</b> to lift is not limited to the scheme of this embodiment, and the lifting structure formed by the cooperation of the gear <b>13</b> and the rack <b>14</b> can be replaced by a cooperating structure of nut and screw.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0036">In an optional embodiment, the first heating element <b>3</b> is a heating plate, and the heating plate includes a plate body and an electrical heated tube arranged in the plate body. The electrical heated tube is spirally wound in the plate body and the heat generated by the electrical heated tube is transferred to the food through the plate body to heat the food. Certainly, the second heating element <b>6</b> can also be composed of a heating tube and a frying plate arranged under the heating tube. In this embodiment, when the food is fried by the heating plate, the heating plate can transfer heat to the ingredients evenly, making the food more delicious. The heating plate is used as the second heating element <b>6</b>, which has a simple structure, and is easy to assemble and clean.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0037">In an optional embodiment, referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>, the air fryer further comprises a safety switch <b>15</b> and a controller disposed in the machine body, and a rotary handle <b>16</b> rotatably connected to the machine body, wherein the safety switch <b>15</b> includes an ascending switch <b>151</b> and a descending switch <b>152</b>. The inner end of the rotary handle <b>16</b> is provided with a trigger part <b>17</b>. The trigger part <b>17</b> is linked with the safety switch <b>15</b>. The safety switch <b>15</b> is electrically connected with the controller and the drive motor <b>12</b>. The rotary handle <b>16</b> is rotated with at least a first position and a second position. When the rotary handle <b>16</b> is rotated to the first position, the trigger part <b>17</b> triggers the ascending switch <b>151</b> to control the first heating element <b>3</b> to rise; and when the rotary handle <b>16</b> is rotated to the second position, the trigger part <b>17</b> triggers the descending switch <b>152</b> to control the first heating element <b>3</b> to go down. Specifically, both the ascending switch <b>151</b> and the descending switch <b>152</b> are micro switches, and the trigger part <b>17</b> is a contact block arranged at the inner end of the rotary handle <b>16</b>. When external force is applied to the rotary handle <b>16</b> to make it rotate, the contact block triggers the safety switch <b>15</b>, and the rotating direction of the rotary handle <b>16</b> toward the ascending switch <b>151</b> is opposite to that of the rotary handle <b>16</b> toward the descending switch <b>152</b>. When the rotary handle <b>16</b> rotates forward to the first position, the contact block triggers the descending switch <b>152</b>, and the controller controls the drive motor <b>12</b> to rotate forward, so as to lower the first heating element <b>3</b>; after the external force is removed, the motor stops acting, and the first heating element <b>3</b> stays on the surface of food. When the rotary handle <b>16</b> is reversely rotated to the second position, the contact block triggers the ascending switch <b>151</b>, and the controller controls the motor to rotate reversely, so that the first heating element <b>3</b> rises, the first heating element <b>3</b> moves away from the food surface, and the food can be taken out. In the present disclosure, using the rotating handle <b>16</b> to control the lifting of the first heating element <b>3</b> makes the operation simple and convenient. It can be operated by the elderly and children, and still assure high safety, which achieves good user experience.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0038">In an optional embodiment, the rack <b>14</b> is provided with a limiting part. For example, a stopper can be provided at the top of the rack <b>14</b> to restrain the movement of the rack <b>14</b> within a controllable range, and prevent the rack <b>14</b> from being disengaged with the gear <b>13</b> when moving up and down.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0039">In an optional embodiment, referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, the base <b>5</b> is provided therein with a third heating element <b>18</b>, and the third heating element <b>18</b> is located below the first cooking chamber <b>8</b> and is arranged correspondingly to the bottom of the frying basket <b>10</b>. In this embodiment, the third heating element <b>18</b> is selected from any one of heating plate, heating tube, coil disk, and heating film. The third heating element <b>18</b> is set correspondingly to the air frying module <b>2</b>. On the one hand, it can improve the hot air circulation in the frying basket <b>10</b> and increase the heating efficiency, thereby allowing the food to be heated more evenly; on the other hand, it can extend the working mode of the air fryer, such as frying and steaming different ingredients at the same time.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0040">In an optional embodiment, referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, the frying basket <b>10</b> includes a bottom plate <b>101</b> and a vertical plate <b>102</b> arranged around the bottom plate <b>101</b>, wherein the bottom plate <b>101</b> and the vertical plate <b>102</b> are integrally formed to form a receiving chamber with an open top. When the frying basket <b>10</b> is placed inside the first cooking chamber <b>8</b>, part region of the vertical plate <b>102</b> is surrounded by the side plate <b>7</b>, and the remaining region is directly exposed to the external environment. In this embodiment, the frying basket <b>10</b> is directly communicated to the external environment, and the side wall of the frying basket <b>10</b> has no cold air circulation structure such as a lower core and a shell. On the one hand, the material cost and the assembly cost of the frying basket <b>10</b> are saved, reducing the production cost of the air fryer; on the other hand, it is convenient to clean the machine head <b>1</b> and the frying basket <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0041">In an optional embodiment, referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, the projected length of the side plate <b>7</b> on the base <b>5</b> is not greater than half of the perimeter of the base <b>5</b>. When the frying basket <b>10</b> is placed below the air frying module <b>2</b>, a small part of region of the frying basket <b>10</b> is located in an enclosing region formed by the machine head <b>1</b>, the base <b>5</b> and the side plate <b>7</b>, and most of the region is located outside the enclosing region, that is, most part of the region of the vertical plate <b>102</b> is exposed outside, only a small part is surrounded by the side plate <b>7</b>. In the present disclosure, the cookware can enter and exit the first cooking chamber and the second cooking chamber at various angles from the side surfaces of the air fryer, and is not limited to the prior art that it can only be put in from the front, which improves the user experience and aesthetics of the air fryer. At the same time, since most part of the vertical plate <b>102</b> is exposed outside, the heat dissipating effect of the frying basket <b>10</b> is improved.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0042">In an optional embodiment, referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, when the frying basket <b>10</b> is placed in the first cooking chamber <b>8</b>, there are steam outlets <b>19</b> between the vertical plate <b>102</b> and the machine head <b>1</b>. In this embodiment, there is a gap between the top of the vertical plate <b>102</b> and the air frying module <b>2</b>, forming steam outlets <b>19</b>, through which excess heat in the receiving chamber is discharged. Since there are steam outlets <b>19</b> set and is no need to form holes on the side wall of the air fryer, the structure of the air fryer is simplified and the aesthetics of the air fryer is improved.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0043">In an optional embodiment, referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, the frying basket further includes a pot lid <b>103</b> covering the top of the vertical plate <b>102</b>, the inner wall of the vertical plate <b>101</b> is provided with a step surface <b>104</b>, and the step surface <b>104</b> is selectively equipped with a steaming plate or a frying plate. In this embodiment, the frying basket <b>10</b> can not only fry food, but also can steam food, which can be used for multiple purposes, and has very good practicability.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0044">It should be noted that the terminology herein is only used for the purpose of describing specific embodiments, but not to limit the exemplary embodiments according to the present disclosure. As used herein, unless it is clearly dictated in the context, the singular is intended to include the plural, and it should also be understood that when the terms &#x201c;contain&#x201d; and/or &#x201c;include&#x201d; are used in this specification, they indicate that the features, steps, operations, means, components and/or combinations thereof exist.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0045">The relative arrangements of components and steps, numerical expressions and numerical values set forth in these embodiments do not limit the scope of the present disclosure unless specifically stated otherwise. At the same time, it should be understood that, for the convenience of description, the sizes of the various parts shown in the drawings are not drawn according to the actual proportional relationship. Techniques, methods and devices known to those of ordinary skill in the relevant art may be discussed not in detail, but in appropriate cases, such techniques, methods and devices should be considered part of the patent grant. In all examples shown and discussed herein, any specific values should be construed as exemplary only, but not as limitations. Therefore, other examples of the exemplary embodiment may have different values. It should be noted that similar numerals and letters refer to similar items in the following figures, therefore, once a certain item is defined in one figure, it does not require further discussion in subsequent figures.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0046">In the description of the present disclosure, it should be understood that orientation words such as &#x201c;front, back, up, down, left, right&#x201d;, &#x201c;transverse, upright, vertical, horizontal&#x201d; and &#x201c;top, bottom&#x201d; and so on indicate the orientation or positional relationship generally based on the orientation or positional relationship shown in the drawings, and is only for the convenience of describing the present disclosure and simplifying the description. In the absence of a contrary statement, these orientation words do not indicate or imply the referred device or elements must be in a specific orientation or be constructed and operated in a specific orientation, so they cannot be construed as limiting the protection scope of the present disclosure; and the orientation words &#x201c;inside, outside&#x201d; refer to the inside and outside relative to the outline of each component itself.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0047">To allow for description, terms relating to space may be used here, such as &#x201c;on ...&#x201d;, &#x201c;over ...&#x201d;, &#x201c;on the upper surface of ...&#x201d;, &#x201c;above&#x201d;, etc., to describe the spatial location relationship between one device or feature and other devices or features as shown in the drawings. It should be understood that the spatially relative terms are intended to encompass different orientations when using or operating the device besides the orientation depicted in the figures. For example, if the device in the figures is turned over, the device described as &#x201c;above other devices or configurations&#x201d; or &#x201c;over other devices or configurations&#x201d; would then be oriented as &#x201c;under other devices or configurations&#x201d; or &#x201c;below other devices or configurations&#x201d;. Thus, the exemplary term &#x201c;above ...&#x201d; can encompass both orientations of &#x201c;above ...&#x201d; and &#x201c;below ...&#x201d;. The device may be otherwise oriented (rotated by 90 degrees or at other orientations) and the spatially relative descriptions used herein may be interpreted accordingly.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0048">In addition, it should be noted that the use of words such as &#x201c;first&#x201d; and &#x201c;second&#x201d; to define components is only for the convenience of distinguishing corresponding components. If there is no other statement, the above words have no special meaning, and therefore cannot be interpreted as limiting the protection scope of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0049">The lifting multifunctional air fryer provided by the present disclosure has been introduced in detail above. In the present disclosure, specific examples are used to illustrate the principle and embodiment of the present disclosure. The description of the above embodiments only helps understanding the method and its core idea of the present disclosure. At the same time, for those of ordinary skill in the art, based on the idea of the present disclosure, there will be changes in the specific embodiment and scope of application. In summary, the content of this specification should not be understood as limitation of the present disclosure.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A lifting multifunctional air fryer, wherein the air fryer comprises:
<claim-text>a cookware, comprising at least one frying basket and at least one frying pan;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a machine body, comprising a machine head, a base and a side plate, wherein the side plate is arranged between the machine head and the base, and defines a first cooking chamber for accommodating the frying basket and a second cooking chamber for accommodating the frying pan, above the first cooking chamber is provided with an air frying module, the air frying module communicates with an inner chamber of the frying basket, a first heating element is arranged above the second cooking chamber, and a second heating element is arranged below the second cooking chamber, and both the first heating element and the second heating element are connected to the frying pan; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a lifting drive component, configured to actuate the first heating element to carry out lifting movement, so that a height between the first heating element and the second heating element matches a height of an ingredient on the frying pan.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The lifting multifunctional air fryer according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first heating element is a heating plate, and the heating plate comprises a plate body and electrical heated tubes arranged in the plate body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The lifting multifunctional air fryer according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the lifting drive component comprises a drive motor, a gear sleeved on an output shaft of the drive motor and a rack meshing with the gear, wherein the rack is arranged vertically and connected with the first heating element.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The lifting multifunctional air fryer according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the air fryer further comprises:
<claim-text>a safety switch, arranged in the machine head, and comprising an ascending switch and a descending switch;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a rotary handle, which is rotatably connected to the machine head, wherein an inner end of the rotary handle is provided with a trigger part, and the trigger part is in linkage with the safety switch; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a controller, arranged in the machine head, and electrically connected with the safety switch and the drive motor, wherein</claim-text>
<claim-text>the rotary handle is rotated with at least a first position and a second position, and when the rotary handle is rotated to the first position, the trigger part triggers the ascending switch to control the first heating element to rise, and when the rotary handle is rotated to the second position, the trigger part triggers the descending switch to control the first heating element to descend.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The lifting multifunctional air fryer according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the rack is provided with a limiting part.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The lifting multifunctional air fryer according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein a third heating element is arranged in the base, and the third heating element is located below the first cooking chamber and is arranged correspondingly to a bottom of the frying basket.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The lifting multifunctional air fryer according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the frying basket comprises a bottom plate and a vertical plate arranged around the bottom plate, wherein the bottom plate and the vertical plate are integrally formed to form a receiving chamber with an open top, when the frying basket is placed in the first cooking chamber, part region of the vertical plate is surrounded by the side plate, and a remaining region is directly exposed to an external environment.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The lifting multifunctional air fryer according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein a projected length of the side plate on the base is not greater than half of a perimeter of the base.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The lifting multifunctional air fryer according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein when the frying basket is placed in the first cooking chamber, steam outlets are provided between the vertical plate and the machine head.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The lifting multifunctional air fryer according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the frying basket further comprises a pot lid covering a top of the vertical plate, and an inner wall of the vertical plate is provided with a step surface, and the step surface is optionally equipped with a steaming plate or a frying plate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The lifting multifunctional air fryer according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the frying basket comprises a bottom plate and a vertical plate arranged around the bottom plate, wherein the bottom plate and the vertical plate are integrally formed to form a receiving chamber with an open top, when the frying basket is placed in the first cooking chamber, part region of the vertical plate is surrounded by the side plate, and a remaining region is directly exposed to an external environment.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The lifting multifunctional air fryer according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the frying basket comprises a bottom plate and a vertical plate arranged around the bottom plate, wherein the bottom plate and the vertical plate are integrally formed to form a receiving chamber with an open top, when the frying basket is placed in the first cooking chamber, part region of the vertical plate is surrounded by the side plate, and a remaining region is directly exposed to an external environment.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. The lifting multifunctional air fryer according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the frying basket comprises a bottom plate and a vertical plate arranged around the bottom plate, wherein the bottom plate and the vertical plate are integrally formed to form a receiving chamber with an open top, when the frying basket is placed in the first cooking chamber, part region of the vertical plate is surrounded by the side plate, and a remaining region is directly exposed to an external environment.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The lifting multifunctional air fryer according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the frying basket comprises a bottom plate and a vertical plate arranged around the bottom plate, wherein the bottom plate and the vertical plate are integrally formed to form a receiving chamber with an open top, when the frying basket is placed in the first cooking chamber, part region of the vertical plate is surrounded by the side plate, and a remaining region is directly exposed to an external environment.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. The lifting multifunctional air fryer according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the frying basket comprises a bottom plate and a vertical plate arranged around the bottom plate, wherein the bottom plate and the vertical plate are integrally formed to form a receiving chamber with an open top, when the frying basket is placed in the first cooking chamber, part region of the vertical plate is surrounded by the side plate, and a remaining region is directly exposed to an external environment.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
