<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225473A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225473</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>17576194</doc-number>
<date>20220114</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>17</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>45</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>11</main-group>
<subgroup>18</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>45</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>13</main-group>
<subgroup>10</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>45</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>11</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>N</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>45</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>11</main-group>
<subgroup>182</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>45</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>13</main-group>
<subgroup>1069</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>45</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>2011</main-group>
<subgroup>002</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Mobile Device Case</invention-title>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lietzke</last-name>
<first-name>Jeffrey</first-name>
<address>
<city>Strongsville</city>
<state>OH</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lietzke</last-name>
<first-name>Jeffrey</first-name>
<address>
<city>Strongsville</city>
<state>OH</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A foldable wallet-style mobile phone case is disclosed. The case includes a first flap and a second flap separated from the first flap by a central portion. The central portion allows the first flap to be folded onto the second flap along a fold axis. The first flap includes at least one card slot therein, and a retainer having a first end coupled to the first flap and a second end that is free. The second end of the retainer includes a securing structure that is able to be coupled to a mating securing structure on the second flap. At least a portion of the retainer is located in a blocking arrangement over top the at least one card slot.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="186.18mm" wi="158.75mm" file="US20230225473A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="225.30mm" wi="155.62mm" file="US20230225473A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="220.39mm" wi="174.75mm" file="US20230225473A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="235.46mm" wi="144.53mm" file="US20230225473A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="235.63mm" wi="151.21mm" file="US20230225473A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="237.49mm" wi="172.38mm" file="US20230225473A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="220.56mm" wi="170.52mm" file="US20230225473A1-20230720-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="238.84mm" wi="152.99mm" file="US20230225473A1-20230720-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">None</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Mobile phones have continued to see dramatic increase in usage since their introduction, never more rapid than in recent years. Indeed, according to some sources, including the online research of Statista, as of December 2021 there were over 6 billion smartphone users in the world. This means that over 80% of the world's population owns a smart phone. In the United States, according to the Pew Research Center, over 97% of Americans now own a cellular phone of some kind. The relative percentage of those cellular phones classified as smart phones has risen from 35% in 2011 to over 85% in 2021.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Accompanying such dramatic increase in popularity of cell phones has also been the desire, indeed the need, to carry the cell phone with the owner during the large majority of a person's day. In fact, most cell phone owners keep their cell phones with them nearly at all times during the day. Moreover, as cell phones have become more sophisticated, they have become capable of doing things that were not possible even just a short time in the past. Nowadays, a smart phone can not only communicate via text message and voice call, but can also send and receive electronic mail, make video calls, take photos and videos of extremely high quality, translate speech in real time, interface with any web site available, and conduct personal and business transactions online, including acting as a payment source. As a result, users tend to always carry their phones with them. As a further result, users sometimes desire to only carry their phones with them, to the exclusion of their wallets, but still desire to carry with them other items, such as their driver's license, credit cards, identification cards, secure-access cards, insurance cards, and the like (all of these types of items, and all similar items commonly carried in wallets and mobile device cases, are hereinafter referred to simply as &#x201c;cards&#x201d;). Users tend to prefer that such cards be placed inside a card-holding device to protect the cards, and to prevent losing the cards. Obviously, wallets have been used for such purposes for decades, if not hundreds of years. However, as stated above, a growing trend is that people tend to only want to carry with them one item, and that item tends to be the smart phone.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">As such, some smart phone products have been developed to house these cards. These products tend to fall into two categories. A first category is a wallet or portfolio-style (that is, a &#x201c;folding&#x201d; case) cell phone holder that houses a cell phone on one side and credit cards on the opposite side. An example of this prior art device is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>. A second category is a pouch style attachment for the back side of a cell phone. The pouch is attached to the back of a cell phone case (typically with adhesive), and the pouch includes one or more slots for cards. Some pouches themselves have an internal sliding mechanism with a pull tab attached thereto. When the user needs to retrieve a card, the user pulls the pull tab to slide out the card holders. Once the user is finished, the card can be returned to the card holder, and the card holder is slid back into the pouch, with the pull tab remaining accessible to pull the card holder again when needed.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">One of the many problems with products of the first category is that cards tend to fall out of the card slots. This is especially problematic where the card slots are open in a direction that is not blocked by some physical structure. And, because many of the wallet-style cell phone holders are made of leather, the tendency of cards to fall out of the holder increases over time and with use, as the slots for the cards get broken in, worn, and tend to expand. Further, many cards are of different sizes and thicknesses, and thicker cards tend to stretch the slots and enclosures more so than thinner cards. Then, when a thinner card is placed in a slot that has previously housed a thicker card, the thinner card tends to escape more easily. Although wallet-style phone holders have many benefits, including the general ability to provide more space for cards, cash, and the like, many users have lamented the loss of cards that have slipped out of their slots. Similar problems exist for the pouch category as well, especially if the slots wear or break-in over time and therefore become loose. And, pouches that are adhered to the back side of a phone provide no protection or cover for the phone itself.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Accordingly, a need exists in the art to provide a phone case, and in particular, a wallet-style phone case, that also carries multiple card-like items, yet prevents the cards from falling out.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The herein-described embodiments address these and other problems associated with the art by providing a phone case with a locking feature to prevent credit cards from falling out.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">A mobile device case embodiment is disclosed comprising a first flap having at least one card slot therein, wherein the at least one card slot is configured to receive at least one card insertable into the at least one card slot in an insertion direction; a second flap configured to receive a mobile device; a central portion connecting the first flap to the second flap in a foldable arrangement in which the first flap can be folded about a fold axis and can be moveable through a range of positions from at least a first, unfolded position to at least a second, folded position; and a retainer configured to be coupled to each of the first flap and the second flap, wherein when the retainer is coupled to both the first flap and the second flap, at least a portion of the retainer is in blocking alignment over the at least one card slot in the insertion direction, wherein the insertion direction is parallel to said fold axis.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">A mobile device case embodiment is disclosed comprising: a first flap; a second flap; a central portion foldably connecting the first flap to the second flap along a fold axis; and a retainer having a first end fixedly coupled to the first flap and a second end removably coupled to the second flap; wherein the first flap includes at least one card slot oriented in a direction that is not parallel to the fold axis and is configured to receive a card; and wherein the second end of the retainer further comprises a first securement structure that is engageable to a second securement structure that is coupled to the second flap; and wherein at least a portion of the retainer is physically situated over at least a portion of the at least one card slot.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">A method of preventing a credit card from escaping a mobile device case is disclosed, the method comprising: providing a foldable wallet-style mobile device case, wherein the case includes a first flap and a second flap separated from the first flap by a central portion along a fold axis, and wherein the first flap includes at least one card slot oriented in a direction that is not parallel to the fold axis, and wherein the first flap includes a retainer having a first end coupled to the first flap and a second end not coupled to the first flap, and wherein the retainer is situated on the first flap above the at least one card slot in a direction parallel to the fold axis; coupling a mobile device to the second flap; inserting a card into the at least one card slot; closing the case by folding the first flap onto the mobile device; and securing the second end of the retainer to the second flap.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">A mobile device case is disclosed comprising: a first flap having a first edge, a second edge, and a third edge; a second flap having a first edge, an second edge, and a third edge; a central portion foldably connecting the first flap to the second flap along a fold axis, the fold axis being between the third edge of the first flap and the third edge of the second flap; wherein the first flap includes at least one card slot oriented in a direction that is not parallel to the fold axis and is configured to receive a card; and wherein a card is inserted into the card slot from a first position closer to the central portion to a second position closer to the third edge of the first flap.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">These and other advantages and features, which characterize the invention, are set forth in the claims annexed hereto. For a better understanding of the invention, and of the advantages and objectives attained through its use, reference should be made to the Drawings, and to the accompanying descriptive matter, in which there is described example embodiments of the invention. This summary is merely provided to introduce a selection of concepts that are further described below in the detailed description, and is not intended to identify key or essential features of the claimed subject matter, nor is it intended to be used as an aid in limiting the scope of the claimed subject matter.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In the drawings, like reference characters generally refer to the same parts throughout the different views. The drawings are not necessarily to scale, emphasis instead generally being placed upon illustrating the principles of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref> shows a prior art wallet-style cell phone holder.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>B</figref> shows a prior art pouch style cell phone holder.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref> shows a second prior art pouch style cell phone holder.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a front view of a mobile device case according to an embodiment of the present invention, showing the case in an open configuration, and with the phone having been removed for better viewing.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a front view of the mobile device case of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, showing the case in a closed configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is a perspective view of the mobile device case of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, with the phone having been removed for clarity, showing a card being prevented from exiting the case by the retainer.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b>A</figref> is a perspective view of the mobile device according to a second embodiment, showing the card slots arranged in a first configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b>B</figref> is a perspective view of the mobile device according to a second embodiment, showing the card slots arranged in a second configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref> is a perspective view of the mobile device according to a third embodiment, showing the card slots arranged in a first configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>B</figref> is a perspective view of the mobile device according to a third embodiment, showing the card slots arranged in a second configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>A</figref> is a perspective view of the mobile device according to a fifth embodiment, showing the card slots arranged in a first configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>B</figref> is a perspective view of the mobile device according to a fifth embodiment, showing the card slots arranged in a second configuration.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The invention is not limited to the embodiments shown and described herein. Rather, the invention should limited only by the claims appended hereto. However, various embodiments have been selected to be discussed herein to illustrate exemplary, non-limiting implementations of the inventive concepts. The embodiments discussed hereinafter are directed in part to a case for a mobile device having a retainer to prevent loss of cards therefrom.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A-<b>1</b>C</figref> illustrate representative prior art mobile device cases or holders. With regard to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref>, the case is a typical wallet-style case, and includes a plurality of card slots on the left side of the case to house credit cards, etc., and a phone holding section on the right side of the case. The card slots are oriented in a horizontal direction when a user is holding the case, such that the cards are inserted into the slots vertically. The cards, which are typically longer than they are tall (that is, they are in a &#x201c;landscape&#x201d; orientation when viewing the face of the card), are inserted into the slots in a downward vertical direction. The card slots are open at the top, which allows top access to the cards. A separate long slot, or pouch, is also present, and has its opening along a side, not the top. Such long slot is commonly used for things like cash, as well as additional cards, etc. As can be seen, the opening to this area, being on the side, is such that when the phone case is closed, the opening is blocked by the material in the fold of the case itself.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>B</figref> shows a common phone case that has one or more slots on a back side of the phone case itself. Because of the size of most common mobile devices, the slots typically hold cards in portrait orientation, with openings at the top.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref> shows a different pouch style card holder. This holder is not a mobile device case at all, and is instead a separate item that attaches itself to the back of a phone or a phone case. This holder includes a sliding &#x201c;tray&#x201d; of card slots that, again, typically hold cards in a portrait orientation. These slots are hidden, however, and are contained on a sliding card tray. The entire card tray is moveable from a first position (in which the cards are contained fully within the pouch, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref>) to a second position (in which the cards are accessible and able to be removed from their slots). The device that allows a user to move the card tray from the first position to the second position is a tab or flap.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Turning now to the embodiments disclosed and claimed herein, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> depicts a mobile device case <b>10</b> according to one embodiment of the present invention. The case <b>10</b> shown in this embodiment is a folding wallet or portfolio-style case. The case <b>10</b> includes a first flap <b>20</b>, a second flap <b>40</b>, and a central portion <b>50</b> connecting the first flap <b>20</b> to the second flap <b>40</b>. The first flap <b>20</b> includes an outer flap surface <b>21</b> and an inner flap surface <b>22</b>. The second flap <b>40</b> also includes an outer flap surface <b>41</b> and an inner flap surface <b>42</b>. In the embodiment shown, the first flap <b>20</b> is located on the left and is the portion of the case <b>10</b> that receives one or more cards or cash, and the second flap <b>40</b> is located on the right and is the portion of the case <b>10</b> that receives the mobile device (not shown). Obviously, these could be reversed, with the second flap <b>40</b> on the left side and the first flap <b>20</b> with card slots <b>26</b> on the right side.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The inner flap surface <b>22</b> of the first flap <b>20</b> includes a pouch surface <b>23</b>. Pouch surface <b>23</b> is mated to the inner flap surface <b>22</b> about three sides: along a top <b>22</b><i>a</i>, an outer edge <b>22</b><i>b</i>, and a bottom <b>22</b><i>c</i>. In this manner, a pouch opening <b>24</b> exists, creating an interior space <b>25</b> between the inner flap surface <b>22</b> and the pouch surface <b>23</b>, bounded by the top <b>22</b><i>a</i>, outer edge <b>22</b><i>b</i>, and bottom <b>22</b><i>c</i>, but open at the pouch opening <b>24</b>. This interior space <b>25</b> is preferably larger than the interior spaces for the various cards (described below). Items such as cash, receipts, other paper items, or even other or additional cards, for example, can be placed within the interior space <b>25</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Additionally, the pouch surface <b>23</b> (or, if no pouch exists, then alternatively the inner flap surface <b>22</b>) further includes one or more card slots <b>26</b> therein. Each card slot <b>26</b> is an opening into a card interior space <b>27</b>. The card slot <b>26</b> shown in this embodiment is sized to accept standard forms of cards, but could be altered in dimension for custom or different items, if desired.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The second flap <b>40</b> includes a top edge <b>40</b><i>a</i>, an outer edge <b>40</b><i>b</i>, and a bottom edge <b>40</b><i>c</i>. These first, second, and third edges are shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>-<b>4</b></figref> in a portrait orientation, as one example. The fourth edge of the embodiment is coupled to the central portion <b>50</b>. As stated above, the second flap <b>40</b> in this embodiment receives and retains the mobile device. Various methods of retaining the mobile device on, to, or in the inner flap surface <b>42</b> of the second flap <b>40</b> are known. Such methods include, but are not limited to, magnetic connections, adhesives, hook and loop material, retaining clips, retaining ledges, friction fit, geometric retention mechanisms, slidable or movable arms that can movably overlie the mobile device, and so forth. The second flap <b>40</b> preferably (but this is not required) additionally includes one or more cutouts <b>43</b> in its perimeter. The cutout <b>43</b> provides an opening or free space to line up with various portions of the mobile device. As an example, the cutout <b>43</b> can be sized and located to align with the camera that is part of the mobile device in order to allow the camera to be used while the mobile device is retained by the second flap <b>40</b>. The location, size, shape, and number of cutouts <b>43</b> is variable, depending on user preference, brand, and style of mobile device. As stated above, the cutout <b>43</b> may indeed be absent from the second flap <b>40</b> altogether.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The central portion <b>50</b> in the embodiment shown is generally of a relatively flexible material to allow the first flap <b>20</b> to fold over top the second flap <b>40</b>. The central portion <b>50</b> can be (but need not be) of the same material as the first flap <b>20</b> and second flap <b>40</b>, and can be continuous (that is, the same material can comprise the first flap <b>20</b>, central portion <b>50</b>, and second flap <b>40</b>, all in one piece), or it can be separately joined to the first flap <b>20</b> and second flap <b>40</b> (such as, for example, at seams). The central portion <b>50</b> also can be of a different material than that of the first flap <b>20</b> or second flap <b>40</b>. This might be the case, as one example, where the first flap <b>20</b> and/or second flap <b>40</b> is made from a rigid or semi-rigid material. In such case, a flexible material will comprise the central portion <b>50</b>, and the central portion <b>50</b> will be joined to the first flap <b>20</b> at a first seam <b>51</b>, and will be joined to the second flap <b>40</b> at a second seam <b>52</b>. As stated above, the case <b>10</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>-<b>4</b></figref> is a folding case, and the folding occurs via the central portion <b>50</b>. The flexible central portion <b>50</b> allows the first flap <b>20</b> to fold about an imaginary fold axis <b>53</b>. This foldability enables the case <b>10</b> to occupy a range of positions, from open to closed. Additional embodiments described below locate the central portion <b>50</b> (and therefore the fold axis <b>53</b>) in different locations and orientations.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">In the open position as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the first flap <b>20</b> is located on the left side of the second flap, where the mobile device would be retained. In this open position, it can be seen that the one or more card slots <b>26</b> are oriented substantially perpendicular to the fold axis <b>53</b>. Also, the pouch opening <b>24</b> is oriented substantially parallel to the fold axis <b>53</b>. In this open position, one or more cards can be place into the card interior spaces <b>27</b> by inserting the card vertically downwardly from the top and in a direction parallel to the fold axis through the card slot <b>26</b>. It can be seen that, to remove a card, a user pulls the desired card vertically upwardly until such card leaves the card interior space <b>27</b> by exiting the card slot <b>26</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Also in the open position of this embodiment, items can be placed inside the interior space <b>25</b> of the pouch between the inner flap surface <b>22</b> and the pouch surface <b>23</b>. Placing items therein is accomplished by inserting them horizontally from the right to the left (as viewed in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>-<b>4</b></figref>), in a direction perpendicular to the fold axis <b>53</b>, through the pouch opening <b>24</b>. Once inside interior space <b>25</b>, the cards are secured because the material of the central portion <b>50</b> occludes pouch opening <b>24</b>, therefore preventing the cards from exiting. Removing items is accomplished by purposefully pulling them horizontally from the left to the right in a direction perpendicular to the fold axis <b>53</b> through the pouch opening <b>24</b> (as viewed in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>-<b>4</b></figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> shows the case of the embodiment in a closed position. In this position, the material that makes up the central portion <b>50</b> provides a physical barrier to the removal of items within the interior space <b>25</b>. That is, any card or paper currency residing in the interior space <b>25</b> is not able to fall out of the interior space <b>25</b>, due to the presence of the material that makes up the central portion <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">With reference again to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the structure that prevents loss of cards from the card interior space <b>27</b> will now be described. The first flap <b>20</b> additionally includes a retainer <b>30</b>. The retainer <b>30</b> of the embodiment shown includes a strap portion <b>31</b> having a first end <b>32</b> and a second end <b>33</b>. The first end <b>32</b> is coupled to the first flap <b>20</b>. The method of coupling includes all known methods, and, for example, could involve stitches, welding, rivets, magnets, and the like, and could even be simply an extension of the outer flap surface <b>21</b> or the inner flap surface <b>22</b>. The second end <b>33</b> includes a securement portion <b>34</b>, to which a first securement structure <b>35</b> is coupled. The first securement structure <b>35</b> is designed to be coupled to a complementary second securement structure <b>44</b> of the second flap <b>40</b>. Various structures for the first securement structure <b>35</b> and second securement structure <b>44</b> are possible, with the idea being that they work together to retain the first flap <b>20</b> in a closed relationship with the second flap <b>40</b> when activated. Non-limiting examples of the removably securable structures of the first securement structure <b>35</b> and the second securement structure <b>44</b> include: a magnet and a metallic surface; hook and loop fasteners; male and female portions of snaps; button and button hole; post and hole; strap and post; geometric closures; and the like. The preferred form, as shown in the figures, involves a magnet <b>36</b> attached to or within the securement portion <b>34</b> of the strap portion <b>31</b>, and a magnetic metal located on or in the second flap <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The strap portion <b>31</b> has a length that is dimensioned so as to adequately span the necessary thickness of the case <b>10</b> during use, accounting for the thicknesses of the material of the first flap <b>20</b> and second flap <b>40</b>, the mobile device, the cards, and anything else desired to be housed in the card interior space <b>27</b> and the interior space <b>25</b>. In the embodiment shown, the strap portion <b>31</b> has a length of approximately 1.25 to 1.5 inches. Obviously, the strap portion <b>31</b> could be any length between approximately one half inch to approximately 9 inches, but preferably would be between approximately 1 inch to approximately 6 inches, and more preferably would be between approximately 1 inch to approximately 2 inches. Similarly, the strap portion <b>31</b> theoretically could be larger than 9 inches, for example if the retainer <b>30</b> were desired to not just lap over the top portion of the case <b>10</b> (as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>-<b>4</b></figref>), but were desired to wrap completely around the case <b>10</b> (analogous, e.g., to the wrap-around leather tie of an old-style journal). However, such an arrangement would not be preferred, and indeed would defeat the spirit of the ease with which the retainer <b>30</b> of the present embodiment is used.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">With additional reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>, in order to prevent losing the cards from the case <b>10</b> when the case <b>10</b> is in a closed position, the location of the retainer <b>30</b> is important. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> shows the case <b>10</b> in a closed position, with the retainer <b>30</b> having its first securement structure <b>35</b> engaged with the second securement structure <b>44</b> of the second flap <b>40</b>. In this embodiment, the second securement structure <b>44</b> is a magnetic metal thin plate embedded within the second flap <b>40</b>. As shown in the figures, and especially in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>, all or at least a portion of the retainer <b>30</b> is situated vertically above at least a portion of the card slot <b>26</b>. In this manner, the vertical travel of a card upwardly and out of the card slot <b>26</b> is impeded by all or a portion of the strap portion <b>31</b> of the retainer <b>30</b>. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>, a credit card is shown having moved vertically within the card interior space <b>27</b> in an exiting direction that is upwards in the figure, parallel to the fold axis <b>53</b>. As the vertical distance between the top-most card slot <b>26</b> and the strap portion <b>31</b> is less than the size of a standard card, the card cannot escape the card slot <b>26</b>, and thus is prevented from exiting the case <b>10</b> and being lost.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">To use the case <b>10</b> of the embodiment shown, the retainer <b>30</b> is disengaged, if previously engaged, from the second flap <b>40</b>, and the case <b>10</b> is folded to an open position. As described above, the method of disengagement depends on the type of securement structures <b>35</b>, <b>44</b> employed for the case <b>10</b>. A mobile device is secured to the second flap <b>40</b> in a manner that is common in the industry for wallet-style mobile device cases, as described above. Preferably, the case <b>10</b> includes one or more cutouts <b>43</b> that correspond with the camera that is part of the mobile device. One or more cards is inserted into the card slots <b>26</b> by engaging an edge of the card into the card slot <b>26</b> and then moving the card in a direction parallel to the fold axis <b>53</b> until the card is fully seated within the card interior space <b>27</b>. If desired, one or more cards, or cash, is inserted into pouch opening <b>24</b> by moving the card or cash in a direction perpendicular to the fold axis <b>53</b> until the card or cash is adequately contained within the interior space <b>25</b>. Then, once the desired cards and other items have been inserted into the respective locations of the first flap <b>20</b>, the case <b>10</b> is folded to a closed position. In this position, the cards within the card slots <b>26</b> make surface contact with the face of the mobile device that is secured on second flap <b>40</b>. Now, the retainer <b>30</b> is engaged to the second flap <b>40</b> by bringing the second end <b>33</b> of the strap portion <b>31</b> onto the outer flap surface <b>41</b>. The securement portion <b>34</b> is then brought into proximity to the second securement structure <b>44</b> to engage or couple the first securement structure <b>35</b> to the second securement structure <b>44</b>. Once secured in this manner, the cards are prevented from inadvertently falling out of the case <b>10</b>, even when case <b>10</b> is held upside down.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">As stated above, additional embodiments of the case <b>10</b> are also contemplated. As described above with respect to the embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>-<b>4</b></figref>, the retainer <b>30</b> includes a strap portion <b>31</b> having a first securement structure <b>35</b> that, when coupled to the second securement structure <b>44</b>, occupies a position above the card slots <b>26</b> such that a portion of the strap portion <b>31</b> overlies the direction of travel of the card, thus preventing its unintended escape. Also as described with respect to the embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>-<b>4</b></figref>, the central portion <b>50</b> defines a fold axis <b>53</b>, and, because the fold axis <b>53</b> is perpendicular to the direction of travel of the cards or other items in the interior space <b>25</b> of the pouch opening <b>24</b>, the central portion <b>50</b> itself blocks unintended escape of items from the card interior space <b>27</b>. Other arrangements of the central portion <b>50</b>, fold axis <b>53</b>, and retainer <b>30</b> (in embodiments having a retainer <b>30</b>) can also be employed to perform adequate card loss prevention of the case <b>10</b>. In particular, the fold axis <b>53</b> can be located at the top (for flip up style opening), the bottom (for flip down style opening), or on the opposite side from that shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>-<b>4</b></figref>. In general, where card slots <b>26</b> are parallel to the fold axis <b>53</b>, the central portion <b>50</b> can serve as a physical barrier to card exit.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">In a second embodiment of the case <b>10</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>5</b>A and <b>5</b>B</figref>, the central portion <b>50</b> could be located at the top of the folio style case <b>10</b>, such that the first flap <b>20</b> opens in a &#x201c;flip-phone&#x201d; manner from the second flap <b>40</b>. In this embodiment, the fold axis <b>53</b> is now oriented in a horizontal direction, as opposed to the vertical direction shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>-<b>4</b></figref>. This embodiment also includes one or more card slots <b>26</b> creating card interior spaces <b>27</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b>A</figref> depicts such a case wherein the card slots <b>26</b> are disposed in a first configuration, wherein the cards can be inserted into the card slots <b>26</b> vertically from above the card slots <b>26</b> in a direction from the top <b>22</b><i>a </i>of the first flap <b>20</b> toward the central portion <b>50</b>. In this configuration, the fold axis <b>53</b> is perpendicular to the travel direction of the cards into and out of the slots <b>26</b>. When this case is opened (i.e., first flap <b>20</b> is flipped upwardly about the fold axis <b>53</b>), cards are able to be inserted into and removed from the card slots <b>26</b> from above the card slots <b>26</b>. When this case is closed, first flap <b>20</b> is placed overtop the mobile device (if present) and the second flap <b>40</b>, and the retainer <b>30</b> is wrapped around the bottom edge <b>40</b><i>c </i>of the second flap <b>20</b>. The first securement portion <b>34</b> is coupled with the second securement portion <b>44</b>. The retainer of this embodiment serves to prevent card loss because at least a portion of the strap portion <b>31</b> blocks the line of travel of a card out of a slot <b>26</b>, in a fashion that is similar to that of the first embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">A second variation of this second embodiment, shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b>B</figref>, can alternatively include card slots <b>26</b> that are oriented in the same direction as that of the first variation just described; however, the cards can be loaded from below the card slots <b>26</b> in a direction from the central portion <b>50</b> toward the top <b>22</b><i>a </i>of first flap <b>20</b>. When this case is opened (i.e., first flap <b>20</b> is flipped upwardly about the fold axis <b>53</b>), cards are able to be inserted into and removed from the card slots <b>26</b> from below the card slots <b>26</b>. When this case is closed, first flap <b>20</b> is placed overtop the mobile device (if present) and the second flap <b>40</b>, and the retainer <b>30</b> (if present) is wrapped around the bottom edge <b>40</b><i>c </i>of the second flap <b>20</b>. However, because in this second variation the cards are loaded into the card slots <b>26</b> from below the card slots <b>26</b>, the central portion <b>50</b> itself provides a physical barrier to inadvertent exit of the cards. That is, there is no need for a separate retainer <b>30</b> to prevent card loss. A retainer <b>30</b> can still be used, if desired, and would beneficially keep the case <b>10</b> in a closed manner.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b>A and <b>6</b>B</figref> show two variations of a third embodiment of the case <b>10</b>. In both variations shown, the fold axis <b>53</b> is oriented in a horizontal direction, as was the case with the second embodiment, but in these variations the fold axis is below the mobile device instead of above it. Therefore, in this third embodiment, the case <b>10</b> is a bottom-flip-style opening case. This embodiment also includes one or more card slots <b>26</b> in first flap <b>20</b> creating card interior spaces <b>27</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>A</figref> depicts such a case wherein the card slots <b>26</b> are disposed in a first configuration, wherein the cards can be inserted into the card slots <b>26</b> vertically from above the card slots <b>26</b>, in a direction from the central portion <b>50</b> toward the bottom <b>22</b><i>c </i>of the first flap <b>20</b>. In this configuration, the fold axis <b>53</b> is perpendicular to the travel direction of the cards into and out of the slots <b>26</b>. When this case is opened (i.e., first flap <b>20</b> is flipped downwardly about the fold axis <b>53</b>), cards are able to be inserted into and removed from the card slots <b>26</b> from above the card slots <b>26</b>. In this third embodiment, the central portion <b>50</b> is also located above the card slots <b>26</b>. When this case is closed, first flap <b>20</b> is placed overtop the mobile device (if present) and the second flap <b>40</b>, and the retainer <b>30</b> (if present) is wrapped around the top edge <b>40</b><i>a </i>of the second flap <b>20</b>. However, because in this variation the cards are loaded into the card slots <b>26</b> from above the card slots <b>26</b>, and because the central portion <b>50</b> is also located above the card slots, the central portion <b>50</b> itself provides a physical barrier to inadvertent exit of the cards. That is, there is no need for a separate retainer <b>30</b> to prevent card loss. A retainer <b>30</b> can still be used, if desired, and would beneficially keep the case <b>10</b> in a closed manner.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">A second variation of this second embodiment, shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b>B</figref>, can alternatively include card slots <b>26</b> that are oriented in the same direction as that of the first variation just described; however, the cards can be loaded from below the card slots <b>26</b>, in a direction from the bottom <b>22</b><i>c </i>of the first flap <b>20</b> toward the central portion <b>50</b>. When this case is closed, first flap <b>20</b> is placed overtop the mobile device (if present) and the second flap <b>40</b>, and the retainer <b>30</b> is wrapped around the top edge <b>40</b><i>a </i>of the second flap <b>20</b>. The first securement portion <b>34</b> is coupled with the second securement portion <b>44</b>. The retainer of this embodiment serves to prevent card loss because at least a portion of the strap portion <b>31</b> blocks the line of travel of a card out of a slot <b>26</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">A fourth embodiment (not shown) exists that is a mirror image of the first embodiment (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>-<b>4</b></figref>), where basically the first flap <b>20</b> and the second flap <b>30</b>, along with all the structures thereof described with respect to the first embodiment, are swapped. This places the mobile device on the left of the case <b>10</b> when the case <b>10</b> is in an open configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">A fifth embodiment is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>7</b>A and <b>7</b>B</figref>. The embodiment in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>7</b>A and <b>7</b>B</figref> arranges the card slots <b>26</b> vertically, that is, parallel to the fold axis <b>53</b>. As a result, the direction of entry into and exit from the card slots <b>26</b> is perpendicular to the fold axis <b>53</b>. And, more specifically, the cards are inserted into the slots from the central portion <b>50</b> toward the outer edge <b>22</b><i>b</i>. As a result, when the case <b>10</b> is folded closed, the central portion <b>50</b> itself poses a physical barrier to the cards escaping the card slots <b>26</b>. As with other embodiments described above, a retainer <b>30</b> could be used, but is not required in this fifth embodiment. In a variation of this fifth embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b>B</figref>, the direction of card insertion could be from the outer edge <b>22</b><i>b </i>toward the central portion <b>50</b>. In this variation, one or more retainers <b>30</b> could then be located on the outer edge <b>22</b><i>b </i>or <b>40</b><i>b</i>, depending on whether the case <b>10</b> is a left-hand open case or a right-hand open case.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">While several embodiments have been described and illustrated herein, those of ordinary skill in the art will readily envision a variety of other means and/or structures for performing the function and/or obtaining the results and/or one or more of the advantages described herein, and each of such variations and/or modifications is deemed to be within the scope of the embodiments described herein. More generally, those skilled in the art will readily appreciate that all parameters, dimensions, materials, and configurations described herein are meant to be exemplary and that the actual parameters, dimensions, materials, and/or configurations will depend upon the specific application or applications for which the teachings is/are used. Those skilled in the art will recognize, or be able to ascertain using no more than routine experimentation, many equivalents to the specific embodiments described herein. It is, therefore, to be understood that the foregoing embodiments are presented by way of example only and that, within the scope of the appended claims and equivalents thereto, embodiments may be practiced otherwise than as specifically described and claimed. Embodiments of the present disclosure are directed to each individual feature, system, article, material, and/or method described herein. In addition, any combination of two or more such features, systems, articles, materials, and/or methods, if such features, systems, articles, materials, and/or methods are not mutually inconsistent, is included within the scope of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">All definitions, as defined and used herein, should be understood to control over dictionary definitions, definitions in documents incorporated by reference, and/or ordinary meanings of the defined terms.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The indefinite articles &#x201c;a&#x201d; and &#x201c;an,&#x201d; as used herein in the specification and in the claims, unless clearly indicated to the contrary, should be understood to mean &#x201c;at least one.&#x201d;</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">The phrase &#x201c;and/or,&#x201d; as used herein in the specification and in the claims, should be understood to mean &#x201c;either or both&#x201d; of the elements so conjoined, i.e., elements that are conjunctively present in some cases and disjunctively present in other cases. Multiple elements listed with &#x201c;and/or&#x201d; should be construed in the same fashion, i.e., &#x201c;one or more&#x201d; of the elements so conjoined. Other elements may optionally be present other than the elements specifically identified by the &#x201c;and/or&#x201d; clause, whether related or unrelated to those elements specifically identified. Thus, as a non-limiting example, a reference to &#x201c;A and/or B&#x201d;, when used in conjunction with open-ended language such as &#x201c;comprising&#x201d; can refer, in one embodiment, to A only (optionally including elements other than B); in another embodiment, to B only (optionally including elements other than A); in yet another embodiment, to both A and B (optionally including other elements); etc.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">As used herein in the specification and in the claims, &#x201c;or&#x201d; should be understood to have the same meaning as &#x201c;and/or&#x201d; as defined above. For example, when separating items in a list, &#x201c;or&#x201d; or &#x201c;and/or&#x201d; shall be interpreted as being inclusive, i.e., the inclusion of at least one, but also including more than one, of a number or list of elements, and, optionally, additional unlisted items. Only terms clearly indicated to the contrary, such as &#x201c;only one of&#x201d; or &#x201c;exactly one of,&#x201d; or, when used in the claims, &#x201c;consisting of,&#x201d; will refer to the inclusion of exactly one element of a number or list of elements. In general, the term &#x201c;or&#x201d; as used herein shall only be interpreted as indicating exclusive alternatives (i.e. &#x201c;one or the other but not both&#x201d;) when preceded by terms of exclusivity, such as &#x201c;either,&#x201d; &#x201c;one of,&#x201d; &#x201c;only one of,&#x201d; or &#x201c;exactly one of.&#x201d; &#x201c;Consisting essentially of,&#x201d; when used in the claims, shall have its ordinary meaning as used in the field of patent law.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">As used herein in the specification and in the claims, the phrase &#x201c;at least one,&#x201d; in reference to a list of one or more elements, should be understood to mean at least one element selected from any one or more of the elements in the list of elements, but not necessarily including at least one of each and every element specifically listed within the list of elements and not excluding any combinations of elements in the list of elements. This definition also allows that elements may optionally be present other than the elements specifically identified within the list of elements to which the phrase &#x201c;at least one&#x201d; refers, whether related or unrelated to those elements specifically identified. Thus, as a non-limiting example, &#x201c;at least one of A and B&#x201d; (or, equivalently, &#x201c;at least one of A or B,&#x201d; or, equivalently &#x201c;at least one of A and/or B&#x201d;) can refer, in one embodiment, to at least one, optionally including more than one, A, with no B present (and optionally including elements other than B); in another embodiment, to at least one, optionally including more than one, B, with no A present (and optionally including elements other than A); in yet another embodiment, to at least one, optionally including more than one, A, and at least one, optionally including more than one, B (and optionally including other elements); etc.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">It should also be understood that, unless clearly indicated to the contrary, in any methods claimed herein that include more than one step or act, the order of the steps or acts of the method is not necessarily limited to the order in which the steps or acts of the method are recited.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">In the claims, as well as in the specification above, all transitional phrases such as &#x201c;comprising,&#x201d; &#x201c;including,&#x201d; &#x201c;carrying,&#x201d; &#x201c;having,&#x201d; &#x201c;containing,&#x201d; &#x201c;involving,&#x201d; &#x201c;holding,&#x201d; &#x201c;composed of,&#x201d; and the like are to be understood to be open-ended, i.e., to mean including but not limited to. Only the transitional phrases &#x201c;consisting of&#x201d; and &#x201c;consisting essentially of&#x201d; shall be closed or semi-closed transitional phrases, respectively, as set forth in the United States Patent Office Manual of Patent Examining Procedures, Section 2111.03.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">It is to be understood that the embodiments are not limited in its application to the details of construction and the arrangement of components set forth in the description or illustrated in the drawings. The invention is capable of other embodiments and of being practiced or of being carried out in various ways. Unless limited otherwise, the terms &#x201c;connected,&#x201d; &#x201c;coupled,&#x201d; &#x201c;in communication with,&#x201d; and &#x201c;mounted,&#x201d; and variations thereof herein are used broadly and encompass direct and indirect connections, couplings, and mountings. In addition, the terms &#x201c;connected&#x201d; and &#x201c;coupled&#x201d; and variations thereof are not restricted to physical or mechanical connections or couplings.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">The foregoing description of several embodiments of the invention has been presented for purposes of illustration. It is not intended to be exhaustive or to limit the invention to the precise steps and/or forms disclosed, and obviously many modifications and variations are possible in light of the above teaching.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A mobile device case comprising:
<claim-text>a first flap having at least one card slot therein, said at least one card slot configured to receive at least one card insertable into said at least one card slot in an insertion direction;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second flap configured to receive a mobile device;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a central portion connecting said first flap to said second flap in a foldable arrangement in which said first flap can be folded about a fold axis and can be moveable through a range of positions from at least a first, unfolded position to at least a second, folded position; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a retainer configured to be coupled to each of said first flap and said second flap, wherein when said retainer is coupled to both said first flap and said second flap, at least a portion of said retainer is in blocking alignment over said at least one card slot in said insertion direction, wherein said insertion direction is parallel to said fold axis.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The mobile device case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said in said first position a mobile device is accessible for use on said second flap.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The mobile device case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein in said second position a mobile device is not accessible for use on said second flap.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The mobile device case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein retainer further comprises a strap portion having a first end and a second end.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The mobile device case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein said first end of said strap portion is coupled to said first flap.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The mobile device case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein said second end of said strap portion is removably coupled to said second flap.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The mobile device case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein said second end of said strap portion further comprises a securement portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The mobile device case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein said securement portion further comprises a first securement structure and said second flap further comprises a second securement structure complementary to said first securement structure.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The mobile device case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein said first securement structure is selected from the group consisting of magnets, magnetic metal, hook material, loop material, snaps, buttons, posts, holes, straps, string, and rope.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The mobile device case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein said second securement structure is selected from the group consisting of magnetic metal, magnets, loop material, hook material, snaps, holes, buttons, posts, straps, string, and rope.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The mobile device case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein where said first securement structure is a magnet and said second securement structure is a magnetic metal embedded within second flap.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The mobile device case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said retainer is an extension of said first flap.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. The mobile device case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein said strap portion is coupled to said first flap in a manner selected from the group consisting of adhesives, sewing, stitching, rivets, seam welding, and geometric retainers.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The mobile device case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said second flap further comprises a cutout configured to align with a camera of a smartphone.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. The mobile device case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein movement of a card in said insertion direction begins at a position closer to said central portion and ends at a position farther from said central portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. A mobile device case comprising:
<claim-text>a first flap;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second flap;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a central portion foldably connecting said first flap to said second flap along a fold axis; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a retainer having a first end fixedly coupled to said first flap and a second end removably coupled to said second flap;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said first flap includes at least one card slot oriented in a direction that is not parallel to said fold axis and configured to receive a card;</claim-text>
<claim-text>and wherein said second end of said retainer further comprises a first securement structure that is engageable to a second securement structure that is coupled to said second flap;</claim-text>
<claim-text>and wherein at least a portion of said retainer is physically situated over at least a portion of said at least one card slot.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. The mobile device case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein insertion of a card into one of said at least one card slots begins at a position closer to said central portion and ends at a position farther from said central portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. A method of preventing a credit card from escaping a mobile device case comprising:
<claim-text>providing a foldable wallet-style mobile device case, wherein said case includes a first flap and a second flap separated from said first flap by a central portion along a fold axis, and wherein said first flap includes at least one card slot oriented in a direction that is not parallel to said fold axis, and wherein said first flap includes a retainer having a first end coupled to said first flap and a second end not coupled to said first flap, and wherein said retainer is situated on said first flap above said at least one card slot in a direction parallel to said fold axis;</claim-text>
<claim-text>coupling a mobile device to said second flap;</claim-text>
<claim-text>inserting a card into said at least one card slot;</claim-text>
<claim-text>closing said case by folding said first flap onto said mobile device; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>securing said second end of said retainer to said second flap.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. A mobile device case comprising:
<claim-text>a first flap having a first edge, a second edge, and a third edge;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second flap having a first edge, an second edge, and a third edge;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a central portion foldably connecting said first flap to said second flap along a fold axis, said fold axis being between said third edge of said first flap and said third edge of said second flap;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said first flap includes at least one card slot oriented in a direction that is not parallel to said fold axis and configured to receive a card;</claim-text>
<claim-text>and wherein a card is inserted into said card slot from a first position closer to said central portion to a second position closer to said third edge of said first flap.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. The mobile device case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, further comprising a retainer coupled to said first flap and releasably coupled to said second flap.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
