<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225515A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225515</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18187281</doc-number>
<date>20230321</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>60</class>
<subclass>Q</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>76</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>60</class>
<subclass>Q</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>50</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>60</class>
<subclass>N</subclass>
<main-group>2</main-group>
<subgroup>90</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20170201</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>B</section>
<class>60</class>
<subclass>Q</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>76</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20170201</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>B</section>
<class>60</class>
<subclass>Q</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>50</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20180201</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>B</section>
<class>60</class>
<subclass>N</subclass>
<main-group>2</main-group>
<subgroup>90</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e43">ILLUMINATED SEAT PANEL</invention-title>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>16800561</doc-number>
<date>20200225</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11607049</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18187281</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>62820999</doc-number>
<date>20190320</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Century Plastics, LLC d/b/a CIE USA</orgname>
<address>
<city>Shelby Township</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Nelson</last-name>
<first-name>Jeffery M.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Imlay City</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Century Plastics, LLC d/b/a CIE USA</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Shelby Township</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A seat panel for assembly into a rear surface of a seat assembly includes a light assembly which generates task lighting directed to a task area and of sufficient brightness to be useful in performing a task within the task area. The light assembly is selectively actuable to emit light through an aperture defined by the seat panel in a defined light pattern to illuminate a recessed space in the seat panel. The seat assembly when configured as a forward seat assembly of a vehicle provides task lighting for a passenger seated rearward of the forward seat assembly, to illuminate a task area which can include one or more of the exterior surface of the seat panel, a leg space between the forward seat assembly and the passenger's seat assembly, and/or a seat space generally including a portion of the upper leg and/or lap area of the passenger.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="126.83mm" wi="119.89mm" file="US20230225515A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="231.22mm" wi="163.75mm" file="US20230225515A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="224.54mm" wi="135.89mm" file="US20230225515A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="202.78mm" wi="136.82mm" file="US20230225515A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="217.17mm" wi="142.75mm" file="US20230225515A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="209.63mm" wi="129.46mm" file="US20230225515A1-20230720-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This Application claims the benefit of U.S. Non-Provisional application Ser. No. 16/800,561 filed Feb. 25, 2020, which claims priority to U.S. Provisional Application 62/820,999 filed Mar. 20, 2019, which are each hereby incorporated by reference in its entirety.</p>
<?cross-reference-to-related-applications description="Cross Reference To Related Applications" end="tail"?>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates to a seat panel for a seat assembly, and more particularly, to an illuminated seat panel.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Most vehicles include interior lighting for assisting a passenger in performing a task. In many cases, the lighting is positioned overhead relative to a passenger, such that a light pattern provided by the overhead lighting can extend beyond the required task area of the passenger within the vehicle, for example, into the field of vision of a driver of the vehicle. Overhead task lighting can illuminate the interior of the vehicle such that the light is perceptible by drivers of adjacent vehicles, and/or the contents of the vehicle are illuminated for viewing by others outside of the vehicle. In some cases, ambient lighting can be used to illuminate various areas of the vehicle interior, such as the instrument panel, infotainment interfaces, etc., however, this lighting may not be sufficiently bright for use as task lighting and/or may not illuminate the required task area of the vehicle passenger.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Described herein is a seat panel for assembly into a rear surface of a seat assembly, the seat panel including a light assembly configured to generate task lighting which is directed to a task area and of sufficient brightness to be useful to a passenger within the vehicle in performing a task. The seat panel defines at least one aperture and includes a light assembly which is selectively actuable to emit light through the aperture in a defined light pattern. In one example, the seat panel includes a recessed portion which can contain a pocket assembly, and the light assembly and aperture are configured such that the light emitted by the light assembly through the aperture illuminates the recessed space, including a pocket defined by the pocket assembly, for the convenience of a user looking to locate items in the pocket. In one example, the seat assembly is a forward seat assembly of a vehicle, such that the light assembly provides task lighting for a passenger seated rearward of the forward seat assembly, where the light pattern can be configured to illuminate a task area which can include one or more of the exterior surface of the seat panel, a leg space between the forward seat assembly and the passenger's seat assembly, and/or a seat space generally including a portion of the upper leg and/or lap area of the passenger, such that the illuminated seat panel is advantaged by providing task lighting to the passenger to perform tasks such as accessing the contents of the seat pocket, locating objects on the floor of the vehicle in the leg space, or performing tasks in the passenger's seat space proximate the seat panel. In one example, the light pattern emitted from the lighting assembly is configured such that the light pattern is contained between a plane extending through the aperture and substantially parallel to the vehicle floor, such that the light pattern is not perceptible by a passenger in the forward seat and/or does not substantially illuminate the area above the plane.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In one example, the seat panel includes a perimeter portion, a beveled portion, and a recessed portion which are arranged such that the beveled portion is intermediate the perimeter portion and the recessed portion, where the recessed space is defined by the recessed portion and the beveled portion. In one example, the aperture is located in the beveled portion. In one example, the aperture is located in the recessed portion.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The seat panel can include a switch in communication with the light assembly and selectively actuable to actuate the light assembly. In one example, the switch is a haptic switch which is actuable by contact with the seat panel. The light assembly includes a light source which can include at least one light emitting diode (LED). In one example, the light source includes at least one of a LED bulb, an LED array, an LED strip, and an LED tube.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In an example configuration, the seat panel, in an installed position relative to a mounting surface such as a floor, defines a plane extending through the at least one aperture, where the plane is substantially parallel to the mounting surface, and where the light pattern emitted via the aperture is contained between the plane and the mounting surface. The plane, for example, can include and/or pass through an uppermost edge of the aperture.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The seat panel can further include a control unit in communication with the light assembly, where the control unit is actuable to actuate the light assembly to emit the light pattern. In one example, the control unit is configured to receive power at a first voltage level from a power source and to output power at a second voltage level to the light assembly.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In one example, the seat panel is installed to a vehicle which includes a network in communication with a power source. In this example, the control unit is in communication with the network to receive power from the power source to actuate the light assembly. In one example, the vehicle includes a control interface located remotely from the seat panel and in communication with the control unit via the network, configured such that the control interface is actuable to actuate the light assembly.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In one example, the seat panel is installed to a rearward side of a forward seat assembly of a vehicle, where the vehicle includes a rearward seat assembly positioned rearward of the forward seat assembly to define a leg space therebetween, such that the light pattern emitted via the aperture in the seat panel illuminates the leg space. In this example, the rearward seat assembly defines a seat space and the light pattern as emitted via the aperture at least partially illuminates the seat space. The forward seat assembly can include a seat back and a seat portion, with the seat panel is installed to seat back, and can be mounted to a floor of the vehicle such that the seat back is moveable between a first incline angle and a second incline angle. In one example, with the seat back in the first incline angle the light pattern is contained between a plane and the floor of the vehicle, where the plane is substantially parallel to the floor and extends through the at least one aperture. In one example, the seat panel includes a pocket portion attached to the seat panel. where the pocket portion at least partially encloses the recessed space to define a pocket such that the light pattern at least partially illuminates the pocket.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The above features and advantages, and other features and advantages, of the present teachings are readily apparent from the following detailed description of some of the best modes and other embodiments for carrying out the present teachings, as defined in the appended claims, when taken in connection with the accompanying drawings.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a schematic side view of a forward seat assembly and a rearward seat assembly positioned in a vehicle, showing a sectional view of section <b>5</b>-<b>5</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> and including an illuminated seat panel installed to a rearward side of a seat back of the forward seat assembly;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a schematic rear view of the forward seat assembly of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, showing an example illuminated seat panel installed to the rearward side of the seat back of the forward seat assembly;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a schematic view of an exterior side of the example illuminated seat panel of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is a schematic view of the interior side of the example illuminated seat panel of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is a sectional view of section <b>5</b>-<b>5</b> of the example illuminated seat panel of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> is a sectional view of section <b>5</b>-<b>5</b> of the illuminated seat panel of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, in a first inclined position;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> is a sectional view of section <b>5</b>-<b>5</b> of the illuminated seat panel of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, in a second inclined position;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> is another example illuminated seat panel of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>; and</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref> is another example illuminated seat panel of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The elements of the disclosed embodiments, as described and illustrated herein, may be arranged and designed in a variety of different configurations. Thus, the following detailed description is not intended to limit the scope of the disclosure, as claimed, but is merely representative of possible embodiments thereof. In addition, while numerous specific details are set forth in the following description in order to provide a thorough understanding of the embodiments disclosed herein, some embodiments can be practiced without some of these details. Moreover, for the purpose of clarity, certain technical material that is understood in the related art has not been described in detail in order to avoid unnecessarily obscuring the disclosure. Furthermore, the disclosure, as illustrated and described herein, may be practiced in the absence of an element that is not specifically disclosed herein. Referring to the drawings wherein like reference numbers represent like components throughout the several figures, the elements shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>-<b>9</b></figref> are not necessarily to scale or proportion. Accordingly, the particular dimensions and applications provided in the drawings presented herein are not to be considered limiting. The following listing of elements shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>-<b>9</b></figref> is provided for reference only, and is not intended to be limiting:
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0001-0001" num="0022"><b>100</b> Vehicle</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0002" num="0023"><b>10</b> Seat assembly (forward)</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0003" num="0024"><b>12</b> Seat back</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0004" num="0025"><b>14</b> Seat portion</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0005" num="0026"><b>16</b> Mounting surface, floor</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0006" num="0027"><b>18</b> Seat assembly (rearward)</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0007" num="0028"><b>20</b> Seat panel</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0008" num="0029"><b>22</b> Recessed space</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0009" num="0030"><b>24</b> Beveled portion</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0010" num="0031"><b>26</b> Central axis of seat back</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0011" num="0032"><b>28</b> Light pattern</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0012" num="0033"><b>30</b> Lighting module</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0013" num="0034"><b>32</b> Pattern axis</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0014" num="0035"><b>34</b> Leg space, floor space</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0015" num="0036"><b>36</b> Task space, seat space</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0016" num="0037"><b>38</b> Passenger</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0017" num="0038"><b>40</b> Light assembly</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0018" num="0039"><b>42</b> Light switch</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0019" num="0040"><b>44</b> Exterior side of seat</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0020" num="0041"><b>46</b> Pocket</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0021" num="0042"><b>48</b> Pocket portion</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0022" num="0043"><b>50</b> Aperture</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0023" num="0044"><b>52</b> Diffuser lens</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0024" num="0045"><b>54</b> Bezel</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0025" num="0046"><b>56</b> Recessed portion</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0026" num="0047"><b>58</b> Perimeter portion</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0027" num="0048"><b>60</b> Light source (LED)</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0028" num="0049"><b>62</b> Forward side of seat back</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0029" num="0050"><b>64</b> Rearward side of seat back</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0030" num="0051"><b>66</b> Interior side of seat panel</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0031" num="0052"><b>68</b> Housing</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0032" num="0053"><b>70</b> Control unit</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0033" num="0054"><b>72</b> Assembly cover</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0034" num="0055"><b>74</b> Connector/wiring harness</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0035" num="0056"><b>76</b> Network/vehicle bus</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0036" num="0057"><b>78</b> Power source</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0037" num="0058"><b>80</b> Control interface</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0038" num="0059"><b>82</b> Channel</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0039" num="0060"><b>84</b> Bevel plane</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0040" num="0061"><b>86</b> Fastener</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0041" num="0062"><b>88</b> Reference plane</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0042" num="0063"><b>90</b> Uppermost edge of aperture</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0043" num="0064">A Bevel angle</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0044" num="0065">B Beam angle</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0045" num="0066">C Incline angle</li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0067">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>-<b>9</b></figref>, wherein like reference numbers represent like components throughout the several figures, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> shows, in an illustrative example, a vehicle <b>100</b> including a plurality of seat assemblies <b>10</b>, <b>18</b> positioned on a mounting surface <b>16</b> of the vehicle <b>100</b> such that the seat assembly <b>10</b> is forward of the seat assembly <b>18</b>. For illustrative purposes, the seat assembly <b>10</b> can be referred to herein as the forward seat assembly and the seat assembly <b>18</b> can be referred to herein as the rearward seat assembly. In the present example, the mounting surface <b>16</b> is a floor of the vehicle <b>100</b>, and the forward and rearward seat assemblies are connected to the floor <b>16</b> to define a leg space <b>34</b> between the forward seat assembly <b>10</b> and the seat portion <b>14</b> of the rearward seat assembly <b>18</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>. The leg space <b>34</b> can include a portion of the floor <b>16</b> disposed between the forward and rearward seat assemblies <b>10</b>, <b>18</b>, such that the leg space <b>34</b> can also be referred to herein as a floor space <b>34</b>. Each of the seat assemblies <b>10</b>, <b>18</b> include a seat back <b>12</b> and a seat portion <b>14</b> which are hingedly connected to each other such that the seat back <b>12</b> can be selectively inclined relative to the seat portion <b>14</b> and relative to the floor <b>16</b> at an incline angle C defined by a central axis <b>26</b> of the seat back <b>12</b>. In one example, the seat back <b>12</b> can be selectively inclined to a position which is between a first incline angle C<b>1</b> and a second incline angle C<b>2</b>, relative to the floor <b>16</b> and central axis <b>26</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b> and <b>7</b></figref>. Each seat back <b>12</b> includes a forward side <b>62</b> and a rearward side <b>64</b>. In the example shown, a passenger <b>38</b> is seated in the rearward seat assembly <b>18</b> such that the feet and lower portion of the passenger <b>38</b> legs extend into the leg space <b>34</b>, and such that a passenger task space <b>36</b> is defined in the area above the seat portion <b>14</b> of the rearward seat assembly <b>18</b> which includes the upper portion and lap of the seated passenger <b>38</b>. As such, the task space <b>36</b> includes the area where the passenger <b>38</b> may be performing a task such as reading, writing, eating, using a user device such as a phone, computing or gaming device, or other task where illumination is required or preferred. In one example, when the rearward seat <b>18</b> is not occupied by a passenger <b>38</b>, the task space includes the space immediately above and including the seat portion <b>14</b>, such that, as used herein, the task space <b>36</b> may also be referred to as the seat space <b>36</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0068">The seat back <b>12</b> of the forward seat assembly <b>10</b> includes a seat panel <b>20</b> affixed and/or installed to a rearward side <b>64</b> of the seat back <b>12</b>, such that an exterior side <b>44</b> of the seat panel <b>20</b> faces a forward side <b>62</b> of the rearward seat assembly <b>18</b>, and an interior side <b>66</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>) is contained within the seat back <b>12</b>. The interior side <b>66</b> can include one or more fasteners <b>86</b> for fastening the seat panel <b>20</b> to the seat back <b>12</b>. The seat panel <b>20</b> includes a lighting module generally indicated at <b>30</b>, including a light assembly <b>40</b> configured to emit a light pattern <b>28</b> through at least one aperture <b>50</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>) defined by the seat panel, where the light pattern <b>28</b> is emitted rearward and/or downward from the seat panel <b>20</b> such that, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, the light pattern <b>28</b> illuminates at least a portion of the rearward side <b>64</b> and seat panel <b>20</b> of the forward seat assembly <b>10</b>, and illuminates, as shown in the example, the leg space <b>34</b> and task space <b>36</b> located between the forward and rearward seat assemblies <b>10</b>, <b>18</b>. In a non-limiting example, the light pattern <b>28</b> emitted from the aperture <b>50</b> can be defined by a pattern axis <b>32</b> and a beam angle B where the light pattern <b>28</b> defines an illuminated space, e.g., the space illuminated by the light emitted from the aperture <b>50</b>. In one example, the light pattern <b>28</b> may be substantially conical, where, depending on the configuration of the aperture <b>50</b> and the light assembly <b>40</b>, the conical shape of the light pattern <b>28</b> can be one of a circular cone, an oblique circular cone, and an elliptical cone. The example is non-limiting, such that it would be understood that the lighting module <b>30</b> and/or apertures <b>50</b> could be configured to emit a light pattern <b>28</b> defining an illuminated space characterized by one of a conical, cuboidal, cylindrical, pyramidal, and/or prismal shape, depending on the shape of the light pattern <b>28</b> desired, and/or the configuration of one or more of the seat panel <b>20</b>, the seat assemblies <b>10</b>, <b>18</b>, and the vehicle <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0069">In a non-limiting example, the seat panel <b>20</b> includes a perimeter portion <b>58</b>, a beveled portion <b>24</b>, and a recessed portion <b>56</b>, where the beveled portion <b>24</b> is intermediate the perimeter portion <b>58</b> and the recessed portion <b>56</b>, and the recessed portion <b>56</b> is offset from the perimeter portion <b>58</b> such that the recessed portion <b>56</b> and the beveled portion <b>24</b> define a recessed space <b>22</b> in the seat panel <b>20</b>. In an installed position, e.g., with the seat panel <b>20</b> installed to the seat back <b>12</b>, a bevel plane <b>84</b> defined by the beveled portion <b>24</b> can be characterized by a bevel angle A relative to the central axis <b>26</b> of the seat back <b>12</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>, <b>6</b> and <b>7</b></figref>. The seat panel <b>20</b> can include a pocket portion <b>48</b> configured to define a pocket <b>46</b> in the recessed space <b>22</b>. In one example, the pocket portion <b>48</b> can be made of a mesh material as shown in the illustrative figures, or of another material coordinating with and/or matching other materials covering the seat assembly <b>10</b> and/or the interior of the vehicle <b>100</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>, <b>2</b>, <b>6</b> and <b>7</b></figref>, the light pattern <b>28</b> illuminates at least a portion of the rearward side <b>64</b> and seat panel <b>20</b> of the forward seat assembly <b>10</b>, such that the light pattern <b>28</b> advantageously illuminates the pocket <b>46</b> and pocket portion <b>48</b>, to assist a passenger, for example, in positioning and/or locating items within the pocket <b>46</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0070">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>-<b>5</b></figref>, the lighting module <b>30</b> includes at least one light assembly <b>40</b> and at least one light switch <b>42</b> for actuating the at least one light assembly <b>40</b> to emit light through at least one aperture <b>50</b> defined by the seat panel. Each light assembly <b>40</b> includes a housing <b>68</b>, which houses a light source <b>60</b>. The housing <b>68</b> is attachable to the seat panel <b>20</b> to position the light source <b>60</b> relative to the aperture <b>50</b> such that light emitted from the light source <b>60</b> via the aperture <b>50</b> forms the light pattern <b>28</b>. In one example, the housing <b>68</b> can further include one or more reflectors and/or optical surfaces for reflecting the light emitted from the light source <b>60</b>, to form the light pattern <b>28</b>. In one example, a lens <b>52</b> is positioned in the housing <b>68</b> and/or in the aperture <b>50</b>, through which light from the light source <b>60</b> is emitted. The lens <b>52</b> can be configured, shaped, and/or patterned as a diffuser lens to diffuse the light emitted from the light source <b>60</b> in a predetermined pattern, shape, brightness, etc., to at least partially define the light pattern <b>28</b>. In one example, the lens <b>52</b> can include one or more of a louver, insert, grid, mullion, etc., for defining the light pattern <b>28</b> and/or as decorative trim. In one example, the light assembly <b>40</b> and/or the seat panel <b>20</b> can include one or more bezels <b>54</b> for attaching the light assembly <b>40</b> to the seat panel <b>20</b> and/or to the aperture <b>50</b>, and/or as decorative trim. In one example, the bezel <b>54</b> and/or the housing <b>68</b> can be configured such that the light assembly <b>40</b> is repositionable relative to the seat panel <b>20</b>, for example, such that the light assembly <b>40</b> can be rotated or angled relative to the seat panel <b>20</b> during installation and/or in use. In one example, the housing <b>68</b> can include a heat sink to dissipate heat generated from operation of the light assembly <b>40</b> including heat generated by the light source <b>60</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, the lighting module <b>30</b> can include an assembly cover <b>72</b> configured to cover one or more of the at least one light assembly <b>40</b>, the switch <b>42</b>, and/or the control unit <b>70</b>, for example, to isolate, cushion, and/or protect these elements from loading and/or vibration transferred through the forward side <b>62</b> of the seat back <b>12</b> of the forward seat assembly <b>10</b>, and/or to provide a heat sink to dissipate heat generated by the lighting module <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0071">In a non-limiting example, the light source <b>60</b> includes at least one light emitting diode (LED). The at least one LED can be configured as a combination of one or more of an LED bulb, an LED array, an LED strip, an LED tube, an LED chip, and/or can include micro LED and/or mini LED elements or a combination of these, by way of non-limiting example. The light source <b>60</b> and/or the at least one light emitting diode can be configured to emit light in one or more colors, color temperatures, brightness, patterns, etc. In one example, the light source is configured to be dimmable and/or to emit light in a pattern which can include a combination of one or more of a static light, blinking light, flashing light, alternating patterns or colors of light, varying brightness, varying color temperature, and/or a sequenced progression of one or more of these.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0072">The light source <b>60</b> is configured to output a light pattern <b>28</b> characterized by a luminous flux (measured in lumens) which is sufficient to provide visible light in the illuminated spaces, e.g., to the pocket <b>46</b>, floor space <b>34</b>, and task space <b>36</b>, to illuminate tasks performed by the passenger <b>38</b>. The range of luminous flux required can vary depending on the configuration and position of at least one aperture <b>50</b>, the configuration and position of the at least one lighting assembly <b>40</b>, the configuration and position of the interior components of the vehicle <b>100</b> including the seat assemblies <b>10</b>, <b>18</b>, etc. In an illustrative example, the aperture(s) <b>50</b> and the lighting module <b>30</b> including the light assembly(s) <b>40</b>, the lenses <b>52</b>, etc., can be configured to provide a light pattern <b>28</b> which is characterized by a luminous flux in a range of 20 to 200 lumens. In one example, the aperture(s) <b>50</b> and lighting module <b>30</b> is configured to provide a light pattern <b>28</b> which is characterized by a luminous flux in a range of 20 to 450 lumens. In one example, the aperture(s) <b>50</b> and lighting module <b>30</b> is configured to provide a light pattern <b>28</b> which is characterized by a luminous flux in a range of 70 to 450 lumens. In one example, the aperture(s) <b>50</b> and lighting module <b>30</b> is configured to provide a light pattern <b>28</b> which is characterized by a luminous flux in a range of 70 to 800 lumens. In the examples shown, it would be understood that a particular range of luminous flux would be selected based on the intended use of the light, e.g., for illumination of the area, which may require a relatively lower range of luminous flux, or to provide task lighting, which may require a relatively higher range of luminous flux, where the range of luminous flux selected may also be affected by the configuration of the space to be illuminated, the aperture pattern and size, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0073">In a non-limiting example, the light switch <b>42</b> can be located on the seat back <b>12</b> such that the light switch <b>42</b> is conveniently accessed by a passenger <b>38</b> seated in the rearward seat <b>18</b>. For example, the light switch <b>42</b> can be located in and/or on the seat panel <b>20</b>, in and/or on the light assembly <b>40</b>, integrated into the bezel <b>54</b>, etc. In one example, the light switch <b>42</b> is configured as a haptic switch actuable by touch input from a user such as a passenger <b>38</b>. The switch <b>42</b> may be positioned on the interior side <b>66</b> of the seat panel <b>20</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>-<b>6</b></figref>, and the position of the haptic switch <b>42</b> may be indicated on the exterior side <b>44</b> of the seat panel <b>20</b> by location (for example, on beveled portion <b>24</b> between the apertures <b>50</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>), or by a symbol or marking (for example, on recessed portion <b>56</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>). The light switch <b>42</b> can be configured to actuate the lighting module <b>30</b>, for example, to light one or more of the light assemblies <b>40</b>, to actuate the at least one light assembly to emit the light pattern <b>28</b>, and/or to actuate the at least one light assembly <b>40</b> to emit a variation of the light pattern <b>28</b>, including, for example, changing the brightness of the light pattern <b>28</b>, dimming the light pattern <b>28</b>, changing the color, lighting sequence (static, blinking, flashing), etc., of the light pattern <b>28</b>, according to the user's preferences.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0074">As shown on <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>4</b> and <b>5</b></figref>, the lighting module <b>30</b> can be connected to a power source <b>78</b> for powering the at least one light assembly <b>40</b> via a connector <b>74</b>. The lighting module <b>30</b> can include a control unit <b>70</b> in communication with and connected to the at least one light assembly <b>40</b> and the light switch <b>42</b>. The control unit <b>70</b> can be connected to the power source <b>78</b> such that the control unit <b>70</b> receives power from the power source <b>78</b> and outputs power to the at least one light assembly <b>40</b> and to the light switch <b>42</b>. In one example, the control unit <b>70</b> is configured to regulate the power supply received from the power source <b>78</b> prior to outputting power to the at least one light assembly <b>40</b> and to the switch <b>42</b>. In one example, the control unit <b>70</b> includes circuitry to regulate, e.g., step down incoming power in the range of 12 volts (V) to an outgoing power level in the range of 6 volts or less. In one example, the control unit <b>70</b> is configured to regulate incoming power such that the power outgoing from the control unit <b>70</b> to the light assembly <b>40</b> is in the range of 1 to 4 volts. In one example, the connector <b>74</b> is connected to a network <b>76</b> of a vehicle <b>100</b>, where the network <b>76</b> is configured, for example, as a CAN bus connected to a power source <b>78</b> of the vehicle <b>100</b>, which can be, for example, a battery of the vehicle <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0075">The control unit <b>70</b> can include one or more algorithms for processing input signals received from the light switch <b>42</b> and outputting control signals to the at least one light assembly <b>40</b>, where the control signals are defined by the input signals received from the light switch <b>42</b> and include signals, for example, to actuate the at least one light assembly <b>40</b>, to deactuate the at least one light assembly <b>40</b>, and/or to control and/or modify the pattern, color, brightness, etc. of the light emitted from the at least one light assembly <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0076">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, in one example, the lighting module <b>30</b> is controllable via a control interface <b>80</b> which is located remotely from the seat panel <b>20</b>. In one example, the control interface <b>80</b> is located in the vehicle <b>100</b> such that the control interface <b>80</b> is accessible by a passenger located in the forward seat <b>10</b>, which may be the driver of the vehicle <b>100</b>. For example, the control interface <b>80</b> can be located in one of the instrument panel, steering wheel, door switch cluster, or other location in vehicle <b>100</b> accessible by a forward seat passenger, such that the lighting module <b>30</b> can be controlled via from the forward seat <b>10</b> of the vehicle <b>100</b>. This can be advantageous, for example, when the rearward seat assembly <b>18</b> is occupied by a passenger <b>38</b> who is not able to operate the light switch <b>42</b>, for example, a younger child constrained by a seat belt or child seat, or when the rearward seat assembly <b>18</b> is unoccupied and task lighting is required, for example, to illuminate the floor space <b>34</b> and/or the seat space <b>36</b> of the vehicle <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0077">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>-<b>5</b></figref> and further referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b> and <b>7</b></figref>, in an illustrative example, the seat panel <b>20</b> defines at least one aperture <b>50</b> which is contained within the recessed space <b>22</b>, and within the beveled portion <b>24</b>, such that the light emitted through the at least one aperture <b>50</b> forms a light pattern <b>28</b> which is directed downward and rearward from the beveled portion <b>24</b>. The light pattern <b>28</b>, in the present example, is characterized by a pattern axis <b>32</b> which is substantially perpendicular to a bevel plane <b>84</b> defined by the beveled portion <b>24</b>, where, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>, <b>6</b> and <b>7</b></figref>, the bevel plane <b>84</b> is inclined to the central axis <b>26</b> of the seat back <b>12</b> at a bevel angle A. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>, <b>6</b> and <b>7</b></figref>, the light pattern <b>28</b> is emitted from the apertures <b>50</b> located in the beveled portion <b>24</b> such that the seat pocket <b>46</b>, the leg space <b>34</b> and the task space <b>36</b> are fully illuminated by the light assemblies <b>40</b>, however, the light pattern <b>28</b> is contained between the floor <b>16</b> and a reference plane <b>88</b> which extends through the apertures <b>50</b> and is substantially parallel to the floor <b>16</b>. In one example, the reference plane <b>88</b> extends through an uppermost edge <b>90</b> of the at least one aperture <b>50</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>6</b> and <b>7</b></figref>, the light pattern <b>28</b> is contained between the reference plane <b>88</b> and the floor <b>16</b> through the range of inclination of the seat back <b>12</b> from a first incline angle C<b>1</b> to a second incline angle C<b>2</b>. As such, in the present example, the light pattern <b>28</b> does not extend beyond the floor and task areas <b>34</b>, <b>36</b> of the passenger <b>38</b> within the vehicle, that is, the light pattern <b>28</b> is controlled such that it does not extend into the field of vision of a driver of the vehicle <b>100</b>, another passenger of the vehicle <b>100</b>, or outward from the vehicle <b>100</b>, and so that the light pattern <b>28</b> is not perceptible by drivers of adjacent vehicles, and/or the contents, including the passengers, of the vehicle <b>100</b> are not illuminated for viewing by others outside of the vehicle.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0078">The example configuration shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>-<b>7</b></figref> is not intended to be limiting and it would be understood that the lighting module <b>30</b> can be configured with various combinations of apertures <b>50</b>, light assemblies <b>40</b>, light sources <b>60</b>, lenses <b>52</b>, switches <b>42</b>, and control algorithms, which can be incorporated into the seat panel <b>20</b> to provide various light patterns <b>28</b> to illuminate one or more of the pocket <b>46</b>, the floor area <b>34</b> and the task are <b>36</b> of the vehicle <b>100</b>. The example of a pocket <b>46</b> provided in the recessed space <b>22</b> is not intended to be limiting and it would be understood that other configurations of the pocket <b>46</b> or a storage space can be provided, or other features, such as a folding, extendable, and/or retractable tray or table can be included in the recessed space <b>22</b> for use by a passenger <b>38</b> in performing a task.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0079">For example, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>8</b></figref> illustrates an example configuration of a seat panel <b>20</b> including one or more apertures <b>50</b> formed in the recessed portion <b>56</b> to define a decorative shape, which in the present example is configured as a &#x201c;Logo&#x201d;, which in the example of a vehicle <b>100</b>, may be the logo of the vehicle brand, make, model, etc., or may be another decorative shape. The aperture <b>50</b> and/or the light assembly <b>40</b> can be configured such that the light pattern <b>28</b> emitted from the lighting module <b>30</b> illuminates the pocket <b>46</b>, the floor area <b>34</b> and the task are <b>36</b> of the vehicle <b>100</b>, however does not extend above a reference plane <b>88</b> which extends through an uppermost edge <b>90</b> of the &#x201c;Logo&#x201d; aperture <b>50</b>. In the example shown, the light switch <b>42</b> can be configured as a button or toggle switch which in the present example is located in the recessed portion <b>56</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0080"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref> illustrates another example including a light assembly <b>40</b> including a housing <b>68</b> which includes a channel <b>82</b> formed at the junction of the recessed portion <b>56</b> and the beveled portion <b>24</b>, where the light source <b>60</b>, in the present example, can be configured as an LED tube or LED strip extending the length of the channel <b>82</b>. The channel <b>82</b>, housing <b>68</b>, the light source <b>60</b>, and/or the light assembly <b>40</b> can be configured, in the present example, such that the light pattern <b>28</b> emitted from the lighting module <b>30</b> illuminates the pocket <b>46</b>, the floor area <b>34</b> and the task are <b>36</b> of the vehicle <b>100</b>, however does not extend above a reference plane <b>88</b> which extends through an uppermost edge <b>90</b> of the aperture <b>50</b> and/or the light channel <b>82</b>. In the example shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>9</b></figref>, the light switch <b>42</b> is a haptic switch integrated into the beveled portion <b>24</b> of the seat panel <b>20</b>, where the location of the switch <b>42</b>, in the present example, is indicated by a &#x201c;Logo&#x201d; or other decorative feature formed into and/or applied to exterior side <b>44</b> of the seat panel <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0081">The term vehicle <b>100</b>, as used herein, is not limited to an example such as an automobile having forward and rearward seat assemblies <b>10</b>, <b>18</b>. Rather, a vehicle, as that term is used herein, can be configured as any one of an automobile, a truck, a bus, a train, an airplane, a helicopter, a boat, a ship, etc. having a plurality of seat assemblies wherein each seat assembly which is forward of another seat assembly can contain an illuminated seat panel as described herein, for the convenience and use of a passenger positioned in the rearward seat assembly, and/or for lighting of the floor and/or seat areas between the seats of the vehicle.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0082">The term &#x201c;comprising&#x201d; and variations thereof as used herein is used synonymously with the term &#x201c;including&#x201d; and variations thereof and are open, non-limiting terms. Although the terms &#x201c;comprising&#x201d; and &#x201c;including&#x201d; have been used herein to describe various embodiments, the terms &#x201c;consisting essentially of&#x201d; and &#x201c;consisting of&#x201d; can be used in place of &#x2018;comprising&#x2019; and &#x201c;including&#x201d; to provide more specific embodiments and are also disclosed. As used in this disclosure and in the appended claims, the singular forms &#x201c;a&#x201d;, &#x201c;an&#x201d;, &#x201c;the&#x201d;, include plural referents unless the context clearly dictates otherwise.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0083">The detailed description and the drawings or figures are supportive and descriptive of the disclosure, but the scope of the disclosure is defined solely by the claims. While some of the best modes and other embodiments for carrying out the claimed disclosure have been described in detail, various alternative designs and embodiments exist for practicing the disclosure defined in the appended claims. Furthermore, the embodiments shown in the drawings or the characteristics of various embodiments mentioned in the present description are not necessarily to be understood as embodiments independent of each other. Rather, it is possible that each of the characteristics described in one of the examples can be combined with one or a plurality of other desired characteristics from other examples, resulting in other embodiments not described in words or by reference to the drawings. Accordingly, such other embodiments fall within the framework of the scope of the appended claims.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A seat panel assembly for insertion into a vehicle seat, the seat panel assembly comprising:
<claim-text>a seat panel including a recessed portion defining a recessed space;</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one aperture defined by the recessed portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a light assembly operatively connected to the seat panel and selectively actuable to emit light through the at least one aperture;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the at least one aperture defines a light pattern of the light emitted by the light assembly; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the light pattern at least partially illuminates the recessed space.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The seat panel assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a switch in communication with the light assembly;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the switch is selectively actuable to actuate the light assembly.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The seat panel assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the switch is a haptic switch; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the switch is actuable by contact with the seat panel.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The seat panel assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the light assembly includes a light source; and
<claim-text>wherein the light source includes at least one light emitting diode (LED).</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The seat panel of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the light source includes at least one of a LED bulb, an LED array, an LED strip, or an LED tube.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The seat panel assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein with the seat panel assembly inserted into a mounting surface of a vehicle sear, the seat panel defines a plane extending through the at least one aperture;
<claim-text>wherein the plane is substantially parallel to the mounting surface; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the light pattern is contained between the plane and the mounting surface.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. The seat panel assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a control unit actuable to actuate the light assembly to emit the light pattern;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the control unit is configured to:
<claim-text>receive power at a first voltage level from a power source; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>output power at a second voltage level to the light assembly.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The seat panel assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a pocket portion at least partially enclosing the recessed space to define a pocket;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the light pattern at least partially illuminates the pocket.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. A seat panel assembly configured for insertion into a vehicle seat including a rearward side having an opening for receiving the seat panel assembly; the seat panel assembly comprising:
<claim-text>a seat panel including:
<claim-text>an exterior side;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an interior side;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a perimeter portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a recessed portion defining a recessed space relative to the perimeter portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one aperture defined by the recessed portion;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>the at least one aperture configured such that a light projected from the interior side to the exterior side of the seat panel illuminates the recessed space.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The seat panel assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a light assembly operatively connected to the interior side of the seat panel and selectively actuable to emit the light through the at least one aperture.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. A seat panel assembly configured for insertion into a rearward side of a forward seat assembly of a vehicle including a rearward seat assembly positioned rearward of the forward seat assembly to define a leg space therebetween, the seat panel assembly comprising:
<claim-text>a seat panel defining at least one aperture;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a light assembly selectively actuable to emit light through the at least one aperture;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the at least one aperture defines a light pattern of the light emitted by the light assembly; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein with the seat panel inserted into the forward seat assembly the light pattern is configured to illuminate the leg space.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The seat panel assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the rearward seat assembly defines a seat space; and
<claim-text>wherein the light pattern at least partially illuminates the seat space.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. The seat panel of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the forward seat assembly is attachable to a floor of the vehicle and includes a seat back defining an incline angle relative to the floor;
<claim-text>wherein with the seat panel inserted into the rearward side of the forward seat assembly the light pattern is contained between a plane and the floor of the vehicle;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the plane extends through the at least one aperture and is substantially parallel to the floor.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The seat panel of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the incline angle is a first incline angle;
<claim-text>wherein the seat back is movable between the first incline angle and a second incline angle which is different from the first incline angle; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein with the seat back at the second incline angle the light pattern is contained between the plane and the floor of the vehicle.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
