<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-application SYSTEM "us-patent-application-v46-2022-02-17.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-application lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230225432A1-20230720.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20230704" date-publ="20230720">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230225432</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20230720</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18246954</doc-number>
<date>20210920</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>SE</country>
<doc-number>2051136-6</doc-number>
<date>20200930</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>13</main-group>
<subgroup>11</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>13</main-group>
<subgroup>1176</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>2300</main-group>
<subgroup>328</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>A</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>2500</main-group>
<subgroup>52</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>A</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20230720</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e61">FACE MASK</invention-title>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Soliver AB</orgname>
<address>
<city>Helsingborg</city>
<country>SE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>SE</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>KNUTSSON</last-name>
<first-name>Per</first-name>
<address>
<city>Helsingborg</city>
<country>SE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Soliver AB</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Helsingborg</city>
<country>SE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/SE2021/050900</doc-number>
<date>20210920</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c12-date><date>20230328</date></us-371c12-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">This invention relates to a face mask (<b>100, 200, 300</b>) comprising a central area (<b>40</b>), comprising a fabric material (<b>45</b>), an elastic area (<b>20</b>), extending laterally at least partially from the central area (<b>40</b>) and comprising an elastic material (<b>15</b>), and being connected to the central area (<b>40</b>) at an interface section (<b>30</b>). Further, the elastic area (<b>20</b>) comprises an adhesive (<b>11</b>) provided on a bottom surface (<b>12</b>) of the elastic material (<b>15</b>) along at least a portion of a periphery of the face mask (<b>100, 200, 300</b>), forming an adhesive sealing profile (<b>10</b>). A space between the intersection section (<b>30</b>) and the sealing profile (<b>10</b>) comprising the elastic material (<b>15</b>) is an intermediate elastic area (<b>25</b>).</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="234.95mm" wi="107.02mm" file="US20230225432A1-20230720-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="183.90mm" wi="152.48mm" file="US20230225432A1-20230720-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="238.25mm" wi="168.32mm" file="US20230225432A1-20230720-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="220.13mm" wi="141.73mm" file="US20230225432A1-20230720-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="184.91mm" wi="139.87mm" file="US20230225432A1-20230720-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention relates to an elastic face mask.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Face masks are used to protect the user from the environment, and face masks are commonly used for example by health care staff, in chemical and/or mining industries or is used to protect the user from air pollution and exhaust fumes.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The design of the face mask is adapted depending on what they aim to protect the user from. Face masks having variable complexity and degree of protection are available on the market. For instance, some face masks are strapless and may be attached directly onto the face of the user, while other comprise a valve for improved breathing ability.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Climate change caused by dangerously high emissions of fumes cause chronical lung diseases among the population in several countries globally, and the use of face masks in everyday life is common in many countries. Further, in health care, face masks are often required to prevent staff from being exposed to pathogens and to avoid the spread of body fluids from the mouth and nose of staff to patients.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In order for face masks to achieve and maintain proper function, the seal between the periphery of the mask and the face of the user is of importance. Leakage in the seal causes air containing pollutions, pathogens or other hazardous compositions to penetrates the barrier otherwise formed by the face mask, and its effect is diminished. Ruptures in the face mask seals are usually a result of movements in the face, e.g. caused when the user is talking.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">WO2004/080219 discloses a face mask comprising a sealed face mask including a periphery with a seal surrounding the nostrils and the mouth, and which sticks to the skin. The adhesive of the seal may be a skin friendly adhesive or a skin unfriendly adhesive, and the seal includes a strip that may be elastomeric. With the skin unfriendly adhesive, the adhesive includes a strength sufficient to remove a first layer of skin from the face when the seal is pulled from the face. However, such removal is painful and harmful for the skin of the user and a skin friendly adhesive may result in a leakage caused by movements in the face.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">EP1214896 relates to a face mask to control and improve the quality of inhaled air. The respiratory face mask comprises a flange and a filter layer, and the face masks are strapless and rely on a hydrogel adhesive for attachment and sealing or the face mask to the user. The adhesive may have elastic properties. However, none of the prior art documents present a well thought construction, which in turn has caused the face masks to lack a functionality which is industrially applicable and usable, and at the same time being cost effective.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Hence, there is a need for an improved elastic face mask solving the issue of seal leakages and mitigating the above mentioned problems within the art.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Accordingly, the present invention preferably seeks to mitigate, alleviate or eliminate one or more of the above-identified deficiencies in the art and disadvantages singly or in any combination and solves at least the above mentioned problems by proposing a solution according to the appended independent claims. Advantageous embodiments are defined in the appended dependent claims.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In a first aspect, there is provided a face mask comprising a central area, comprising a fabric material, an elastic area, which extends laterally at least partially from the central area and comprises an elastic material and is connected to the central area at an interface section. The elastic area comprises an adhesive provided on a bottom surface of the elastic material along at least a portion of a periphery of the face mask, forming an adhesive sealing profile. A space between the intersection section and the sealing profile comprising the elastic material is an intermediate elastic area.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In one embodiment, the intermediate elastic area has an elasticity greater than that of the central area. Further, the intermediate elastic area may have an elasticity greater than that of the adhesive sealing profile.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Further advantages will be apparent from the detailed description as well as the appended dependent claims.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">These and other aspects, features and advantages of which the invention is capable, will be apparent and elucidated from the following description of embodiments of the present invention, reference being made to the accompanying drawings, in which</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref> shows a user wearing a face mask according to the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>B</figref> shows a longitudinal cross-section of the face mask worn by the user in</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref> shows a cross-section of an elastic material comprised in the face mask according to the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>A</figref> shows a second face mask according to the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>B</figref> shows a user wearing the face mask shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>A</figref>; and</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> shows yet another alternative example of a face mask according to the present disclosure.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Embodiments of the present invention will be described in more detail below with reference to the accompanying drawings in order for those skilled in the art to be able to carry out the invention. The invention may, however, be embodied in many different forms and should not be construed as limited to the embodiments set forth herein. Rather, these embodiments are provided so that this disclosure will be thorough and complete, and will fully convey the scope of the invention to those skilled in the art. The embodiments do not limit the invention, but the invention is only limited by the appended patent claims. Furthermore, the terminology used in the detailed description of the particular embodiments illustrated in the accompanying drawings is not intended to be limiting of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">With reference to the <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A-<b>3</b></figref>, three embodiments of face masks <b>100</b>, <b>200</b>, <b>300</b> are shown. The three face masks <b>100</b>, <b>200</b>, <b>300</b> all comprise four main areas <b>10</b>, <b>20</b>, <b>30</b>, <b>40</b>, arranged as follows:
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0001-0001" num="0000">
    <ul id="ul0002" list-style="none">
        <li id="ul0002-0001" num="0023">a central area <b>40</b>, comprising a fabric material <b>45</b>;</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0002" num="0024">an elastic area <b>20</b>, arranged and extending laterally from the central area <b>40</b> and formed from an elastic material <b>15</b>. The elastic material <b>15</b> is connected to the central area <b>40</b> at an interface section <b>30</b>; and</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0003" num="0025">the elastic area <b>20</b> comprises an adhesive matrix <b>11</b> (also referred to as an adhesive <b>11</b>) provided on a bottom surface <b>12</b> of the elastic material <b>15</b> along at least a portion of a periphery <b>110</b>, <b>210</b>, <b>310</b> of the face mask <b>100</b>, <b>200</b>, <b>300</b> thus forming an elastic adhesive sealing profile <b>10</b> and an intermediate area <b>25</b> located between said sealing profile <b>10</b> and the interface.</li>
    </ul>
    </li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0026">Hence, an elastic intermediate area <b>25</b> is formed between the interface section <b>30</b> and the elastic adhesive sealing profile <b>10</b>, which is also referred to as the sealing profile <b>10</b> herein.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A and <b>1</b>B</figref> show a user U wearing the face mask <b>100</b>, covering the mouth M (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>B</figref>) and nose area of the user U. The face mask <b>100</b> is a strapless face mask <b>100</b>, which is attached directly onto the skin of the user U by means of the adhesive matrix <b>11</b> of the elastic material <b>15</b> in the sealing profile <b>10</b>. In the face mask <b>100</b>, the elastic material <b>15</b> and the sealing profile <b>10</b> extend around the periphery <b>110</b> of the face mask <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0028">The mouth M and a portion of the nose, up to a certain height of the nasal bone NB, represent a critical area which is of importance to cover by a face mask <b>100</b>. To cover the mouth M and nose prevents pollutions in the air from the environment, such as pathogens or dust, to be inhaled by the user U, and prevents body fluids to spread from the user U to the surroundings. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A and <b>1</b>B</figref>, the face mask <b>100</b> covers such critical area with sufficient margin.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0029">The face mask <b>100</b> comprises the four main areas <b>10</b>, <b>20</b>, <b>30</b>, <b>40</b> and a breathing valve <b>50</b>. The elastic area <b>20</b> comprises the elastic material <b>15</b>, which is divided into the elastic intermediate area <b>25</b> and the sealing profile <b>10</b>. The outer periphery <b>110</b> of the elastic material <b>15</b> (and the face mask <b>100</b>) comprises the elastic sealing profile <b>10</b>, in which the elastic material <b>15</b> is provided with the adhesive matrix <b>11</b> (also referred to herein as an adhesive <b>11</b>) on the bottom surface <b>12</b> thereof. The adhesive <b>11</b> attaches to the skin of the user U such that the face mask <b>100</b> does not need any fastening straps.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0030">Centrally disposed, next to the elastic sealing profile <b>10</b>, the face mask <b>10</b> comprises the intermediate area <b>25</b> formed from the same elastic material <b>15</b> as used for the sealing profile <b>10</b>. However, the elastic material <b>15</b> of the intermediate area <b>25</b> is not provided with an adhesive on its bottom surface facing the user U. Hence, the dashed area of the sealing profile <b>10</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref> indicates the area of the elastic material <b>15</b> which is provided with the adhesive matrix <b>11</b> on the bottom surface <b>12</b> thereof (as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref>). As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>B</figref>, the intermediate elastic area <b>25</b> is separated from and not in contact with the face of the user U. Hence, there is a free passage between the face of the user U and the intermediate elastic area <b>25</b> due to the spacing distance there between.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref> shows a cross-section of mainly the elastic area <b>20</b> comprising the elastic material <b>15</b> forming the intermediate area <b>25</b> and the sealing profile <b>10</b>. An artificial boundary between the sealing profile <b>10</b> and the intermediate area <b>25</b> is indicated by the dashed vertical line in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref>, the elastic adhesive sealing profile <b>10</b> comprises the adhesive <b>11</b> on the bottom surface <b>12</b>. The boundary between the elastic area <b>20</b> and the interface section <b>30</b> is also indicated by a dashed line in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref>. The elastic material <b>15</b> is arranged on top of the fabric material <b>45</b> in the interface section <b>30</b>. Further, a portion of the central area <b>40</b> comprising the fabric material <b>45</b> is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref>. The boundary between the interface section <b>30</b> and the central area <b>40</b> is also indicated by a dashed line. Observe that <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref> is not in scale.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0032">The adhesive matrix <b>11</b> adheres to the skin of the user U such that the face mask <b>100</b> does not require any attachment straps and also helps forming barrier between the face mask <b>100</b> and the user's skin.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0033">Optionally, a second elastic material may be used to form the intermediate area <b>25</b>. Such material should exhibit similar elastic properties, preferably having equally elastic properties, to that of the elastic material <b>15</b> used to form the sealing profile <b>10</b>. In the case of the use of a second elastic material, the sealing profile <b>10</b> and the intermediate area <b>25</b> should be bonded in a way such that no rigid or stiff interface is formed. Such interface would decrease the possibility if the sealing profile <b>10</b> to compensate for facial movements. Experiments have shown that stiff joints between the sealing profile <b>10</b> and the intermediate area <b>25</b> formed from two different elastic materials results in leakage in the critical area of the nasal region. The interaction between the sealing profile <b>10</b> and the intermediate area <b>25</b> will be explained more in the following.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0034">Further with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A and <b>1</b>B</figref>, the intermediate area <b>25</b> (and thus the elastic material <b>15</b>) is joined with the central area <b>40</b> in the interface area <b>30</b>, either by sewing, by an adhesive (e.g. a glue), by a combination of sewing and an adhesive, or any other suitable attachment technique known in the art. Preferably, the intermediate area <b>25</b> is attached to the central area <b>40</b> by sewing, as indicated by the dotted lines in the interface area <b>30</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A</figref>. The interface area <b>30</b> is also referred to as the interface section <b>30</b> herein.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0035">In the interface section <b>30</b>, the elastic material <b>15</b> forming the intermediate area <b>25</b> overlap with the fabric material <b>45</b> constituting the central area <b>40</b>. The fabric material <b>45</b> is preferably a fibre cloth <b>45</b> (such as ventilated cotton cloth), which exhibits little or no elasticity. Since the fibre cloth <b>45</b> has little or no elasticity, the interface area <b>30</b> also exhibits little or no elasticity.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0036">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>A and <b>1</b>B</figref>, the face mask <b>100</b> is provided with the valve <b>50</b> arranged in the central area <b>40</b> in the fibre cloth <b>45</b>. The valve <b>50</b> may be a plastic filter valve which is fitted in the face mask <b>100</b> using a snip-fit mechanism, which requires a relatively non-elastomeric material to ensure a secure attachment. If the central material <b>40</b> is made of e.g. the elastic material <b>15</b>, the elastic material <b>15</b> will stretch during an attempt to fasten the valve <b>50</b>. However, the central area <b>40</b> made of a fibre cloth <b>45</b> is less elastic and enables a secure and durable attachment of the valve <b>50</b> therein, and which can withstand the force of attaching a valve <b>50</b> with a snap-fit mechanism. If the central area <b>40</b> was made of a material with elastic properties, the valve <b>50</b> may come off when the material is compressed in the direction of the thickness of the material <b>45</b> and it is difficult to ensure a secure attachment.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>B</figref> shows a longitudinal cross-section of the face mask <b>100</b> attached to the user U. The bottom surface <b>12</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref>) of the sealing profile <b>10</b> is provided with an adhesive <b>11</b> forming a tight seal between the face mask <b>100</b> and the face of the user U, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>B</figref> showing the attachment of the face mask <b>100</b> to the user's nasal bone NM and chin C.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0038">The intermediate area <b>25</b> adjacent to the sealing profile <b>10</b> is arranged centrally of the periphery <b>110</b> and is connected to the central area <b>40</b> in the interface section <b>30</b>. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>B</figref>, the fabric material <b>45</b> is disposed closer to the face of the user U than the elastic material <b>15</b> in the interface section <b>30</b>. However, the central area <b>40</b> and the intermediate area <b>25</b> may be arranged oppositely, the elastic material <b>15</b> being arranged closer to the user's face. The valve <b>50</b> is connected to the fabric material <b>45</b> of the central area <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>A</figref> shows a rectangular shaped face mask <b>200</b> comprising the same four regions as the face mask <b>100</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A and <b>1</b>B</figref>, namely the elastic area <b>20</b> comprising the sealing profile <b>10</b> and the intermediate area <b>25</b>, the interface section <b>30</b> and the central area <b>40</b>. The sealing profile <b>10</b> and the intermediate area <b>25</b> are formed from the elastic material <b>15</b> and the elastic area <b>20</b> exhibits the same cross-section as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref> (i.e. the sealing profile <b>10</b> is provided with an adhesive matrix <b>11</b> on the bottom surface <b>12</b> facing the user U when attached to the face, while the intermediate area <b>25</b> does not comprise such adhesive <b>11</b>). The elastic material <b>15</b> of the intermediate area <b>25</b> is stitched to the central area <b>40</b> in the interface section <b>30</b>, as indicated by the dashes in the interface area <b>30</b>. The central area <b>40</b> is formed from a fabric material <b>45</b>, which has been folded into a plurality of creases, as shown by the vertical lines in the central area <b>40</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>2</b>A and <b>2</b>B</figref>. Preferably, in this embodiment the fabric material <b>45</b> is a cotton material.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0040">The rectangular shape of the face mask <b>200</b> facilitates the production and is cheap to produce. Also in the face mask <b>200</b>, a thickness of the elastic material <b>15</b> is in the range of 0.1 to 1.5 mm, preferably between 0.1 and 0.4 mm. A thinner elastic material <b>15</b> also decreases manufacturing costs. Even though the design of the face mask <b>200</b> is simple and easy to manufacture, the sealing profile <b>10</b> and the intermediate area <b>25</b> comprising the same elastic material <b>15</b> result in a tight seal also in the rectangular design shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>A</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0041">Further, two stretch areas <b>22</b> and <b>24</b> in the intermediate area <b>25</b> are shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>A</figref>. The lines in the stretch areas <b>22</b>, <b>24</b> indicate a non-linear stretching of the elastic material <b>15</b>. Closer to the interface section <b>30</b>, the elastic material <b>30</b> is less stretched than adjacent to the sealing profile <b>10</b>, since the interface area <b>30</b> is stiff, while the sealing profile <b>10</b> is elastic. The degree of stretching of the elastic material <b>15</b> is indicated by the lines in the stretch areas <b>22</b>, longer lines indicating more stretching.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0042">An exemplary total width of the elastic material <b>15</b> in the face mask <b>200</b> is 25 mm (along all four sides). In such case, the elastic material <b>15</b> is disposed as 10 mm as the sealing profile <b>10</b>, 10 mm as the intermediate area <b>25</b> and 5 mm in the interface section <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0043">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b>B</figref>, the face mask <b>200</b> is worn by the user U.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0044"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> discloses a face mask <b>300</b> according to another embodiment disclosed herein, in which the sealing profile <b>10</b> is arranged partially along the circumference of the face mask <b>300</b>. The sealing profile <b>10</b> extends along an outer edge of the face mask <b>300</b> in the critical nasal bone area NB, which usually is the most complicated area in the face of a user U (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b>A, <b>1</b>B and <b>2</b>B</figref>) to achieve a tight seal.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0045">The sealing profile <b>10</b> comprises an elastic material <b>15</b> and an adhesive matrix <b>11</b> arranged on a bottom surface <b>12</b> of the profile <b>10</b>, as shown with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>C</figref>. The elastic material <b>15</b> extends from the sealing profile <b>10</b> to form an intermediate area <b>25</b>, which do not comprise the adhesive <b>11</b>. A central area <b>40</b> comprises a fabric material <b>45</b>, preferably a fibre cloth <b>45</b> and a valve <b>50</b>. The fibre cloth <b>45</b> is connected to the elastic material <b>15</b> of the intermediate area <b>25</b> in an interface section <b>30</b>. Further, the face mask <b>300</b> comprises adjustable straps <b>60</b>, which helps to hold the face mask <b>300</b> in place during use.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0046">Other face masks in the art provides solutions where a nasal clip is arranged in an attempt to achieve a seal between face mask and face of the user. However, such attempt is non-reliable and does not provide a tight seal, and is further easily affected negatively due to nasal movements.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0047">During use, the outer peripheral sealing profile <b>10</b> is in direct contact with the face of the user U through the adhesive <b>11</b>. Hence, all facial movements caused by the user U place high demands on the sealing profile <b>10</b> to prevent leakage. Face masks known in the art struggle to keep the barrier between face mask and skin intact.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0048">However, the face mask <b>100</b> of the present disclosure include the intermediate area <b>25</b> formed from the elastic material <b>15</b>. Since the material <b>15</b> of intermediate area <b>25</b> will stretch upon stress and strain, an effect of the use of the elastic material <b>15</b> for the intermediate area <b>25</b> is that the adhesive <b>11</b> of the sealing profile <b>10</b> will not detach from the skin of the user U even upon vigorous facial movements. In addition, since the adhesive <b>11</b> in the sealing profile <b>10</b> in combination with the elastic material <b>15</b> in the intermediate elastic area <b>25</b> is equally effective over the entire facial contour, hot air is prevented from passing between the nose and the face mask <b>100</b>, <b>200</b>, <b>300</b>, which in turn may cause condensation on glasses or protective glasses used by the user U. This issue is a major disadvantage with face masks known in the art, which fail to prevent the formation of such condensation, due to non tight seals between the nose and the face of the user. This will be explained more in the following.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0049">Since the fibre cloth <b>45</b> forming the central area <b>40</b> has limited stretchability or is non-stretchable, the elastic material <b>15</b> has decreased elasticity in the interface section <b>30</b> where it is overlapping with the central area material <b>45</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>B</figref>). However, the intermediate area <b>25</b> between the interface section <b>30</b> and the sealing profile <b>10</b> is stretchable, which facilitates the sealing profile <b>10</b> to exhibit its full elastic behaviour without the risk of detaching from the face of the user U. Since the sealing profile <b>10</b> and the intermediate area <b>25</b> are formed from the same material <b>15</b>, there is no stiff interface between them. Therefore, the intermediate area <b>25</b> will compensate for facial movements and thereby decrease the transfer of drag and tensions to the sealing profile <b>10</b>. This means that even in the case of substantial facial movements, such as jaw movements, will not cause the adhesive matrix <b>11</b> on the bottom surface <b>12</b> of the elastic sealing profile <b>10</b> to come off the user's face. Hence, a tight barrier can be maintained and the risk of leakage of ambient air into the face mask <b>100</b> is decreased.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0050">Width of the sealing profile <b>10</b> and the intermediate area <b>25</b> is also important for the interaction there between. Another effect of using the elastic material <b>15</b> also in the intermediate area <b>25</b> is that a smaller contact area between the skin of the user U and the sealing profile <b>10</b> is required to maintain a fluid tight seal there between. To allow an optimised elasticity interaction, the width of the sealing profile <b>10</b> and the intermediate area <b>25</b> is each preferably <b>2</b> to 25 mm. More preferably, the intermediate area <b>25</b> has at least the same width as the sealing profile <b>10</b>. This width range allows for enough wiggle room such that the sealing profile <b>10</b> is not pulled to such extent that it detaches from the face of the user U upon facial movements. Experiments performed on hydrocolloid adhesive dressings have shown this to be true. In addition, the adhesiveness of the adhesive <b>11</b> can be decreased, and still maintain the sealed barrier.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0051">Preferably, a width of the interface section <b>30</b> is 25-35% of a width of the intermediate area <b>25</b>. Hence, 65-75% of the width of the elastic material <b>15</b> in the intermediate area <b>25</b> will be able to provide elastic movements.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0052">If the sealing profile <b>10</b> were to be attached directly to a less elastic or non-elastic area, such as the central area <b>40</b>, and the intermediate area <b>25</b> was excluded, facial movements would cause the stiffer material <b>45</b> to pull the sealing profile <b>10</b>. Hence, tensions in the sealing profile <b>10</b> would result in a leakage between the sealing profile <b>10</b> and the user's face.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0053">Instead, in the face mask <b>100</b>, the intermediate area <b>25</b> provides even more elasticity than the sealing profile <b>10</b> even when formed from the same elastic material <b>15</b>, since the intermediate area <b>25</b> is not provided with an adhesive <b>11</b> and since there is a clearance <b>120</b> between the face of the user U and the second elastic material <b>25</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b>B</figref>). Thus, the elastic material <b>15</b> in the intermediate area <b>25</b> will relieve the sealing profile <b>10</b> from tensions, drag and movements in the face mask <b>100</b>. The clearance <b>120</b> is of particular importance during a substantial opening of the mouth M.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0054">In face masks comprising a sealing profile with an adhesive attaching said mask to the skin of the user, there is an interaction between the adhesiveness of the adhesive matrix and the experienced feeling upon removal of the face mask. Higher adhesiveness results in higher pain upon removal. The width of the sealing profile also affects the level of experienced pain during detachment. Hence, the face mask <b>100</b> disclosed herein is designed such that the user U does not experience such pain. By extending the elastic material <b>15</b> beyond the sealing profile <b>10</b> to form the intermediate area <b>25</b>, the adhesive matrix <b>11</b> can have an adhesiveness sufficiently high to adhere to the skin of the user U, but sufficiently low to avoid painful removal of the face mask <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0055">The sealing profile <b>10</b> and the intermediate area <b>25</b> preferably have a thickness in the range of 0.1-1.5 mm, more preferably between 0.1-0.4 mm. The adhesiveness of the sealing profile <b>10</b> and the interface region <b>30</b> allows for a thin thickness of the elastic material <b>15</b>, improving the elastic characteristics, while simultaneously using the more course central area <b>40</b> to bear the valve <b>50</b> without any issues. The thickness of the elastic material <b>15</b> also affects its elasticity. A thinner elastic material <b>15</b> is more formable with respect to irregularities of the facial contour and during movements, since it is more stretchable. A thickness of the sealing profile <b>10</b> is preferably in the range of 0.1-1.5 mm, more preferred within 0.1-0.4 mm. Further, a thin thickness is advantageous in that it provides for a cost effective production.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0056">In hospital environments, specifically in for instance intensive care units, the user U will wear the face mask <b>100</b> during long periods at the time. The face mask <b>100</b> must therefore provide a sustainable barrier to the ambient air and surroundings to prevent leakage between the face mask <b>100</b> and the user's skin.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0057">Preferably, the elastic material <b>15</b> is an elastomer which may be stretched to at least its double length, and then return to its resting state without suffering from stress relaxation. Hence, the elastic material <b>15</b> is formable. The elastic material <b>15</b> may be a thermoplastic elastomer (such as a thermoplastic olefin (TPO) based material, a polyurethane (TPU) based material or a hydrogel), a synthetic rubber sheet, or a silicone sheet. Preferably, the elastomer is a biodegradable elastomer. Preferably, the elastic material <b>15</b> and the adhesive <b>11</b> used on the bottom surface <b>12</b> thereof are medical grade materials. This reduces the risk of side effects for the user U, such as rashes, wounds or skin irritation.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0058">The elastic material <b>15</b> and the adhesive matrix <b>11</b> on the bottom surface <b>12</b> thereof may also provide an anti-septic barrier. In such case, an anti-septic is added to the adhesive matrix <b>11</b> to prevent pathogens from penetrating the barrier formed between the user U and the attached face mask <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0059">Further, the invention has mainly been described with reference to a few embodiments. However, as is readily understood by a person skilled in the art, other embodiments than the ones disclosed above are equally possible within the scope of the invention, as defined by the appended claims.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0060">In the claims, the term &#x201c;comprises/comprising&#x201d; does not exclude the presence of other elements or steps. Furthermore, although individually listed, a plurality of means, elements or method steps may be implemented by e.g. a single unit or processor. Additionally, although individual features may be included in different claims, these may possibly advantageously be combined, and the inclusion in different claims does not imply that a combination of features is not feasible and/or advantageous. In addition, singular references do not exclude a plurality. The terms &#x201c;a&#x201d;, &#x201c;an&#x201d;, &#x201c;first&#x201d;, &#x201c;second&#x201d; etc do not preclude a plurality. Reference signs in the claims are provided merely as a clarifying example and shall not be construed as limiting the scope of the claims in any way.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-01-17" num="01-17">
<claim-text><b>1</b>.-<b>17</b>. (canceled)</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. A face mask comprising:
<claim-text>a central area including a fabric material;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an elastic area extending laterally at least partially from the central area, the elastic area including an elastic material connected to the central area at an interface section; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the elastic area includes an adhesive provided on a bottom surface of the elastic material along at least a portion of a periphery of the face mask to form an adhesive sealing profile; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a space between the interface section and the adhesive sealing profile including the elastic material is an intermediate elastic area.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. The face mask according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein the intermediate elastic area has an elasticity greater than that of the central area.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. The face mask according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein the intermediate elastic area has an elasticity greater than that of the adhesive sealing profile.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text><b>21</b>. The face mask according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein the elastic material is selected from the group consisting of a thermoplastic elastomer, a hydrocolloid, and a medical grade synthetic rubber sheet or silicone sheet.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text><b>22</b>. The face mask according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein the adhesive is made of a hydrogel, or a plaster adhesive matrix.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text><b>23</b>. The face mask according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein the elastic material is stretchable to a length being at least twice its extension in its resting state in all three dimensions, and return to its resting state upon relaxation.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024" num="00024">
<claim-text><b>24</b>. The face mask according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein a width of the elastic area is in a range of 10 to 50 mm.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025" num="00025">
<claim-text><b>25</b>. The face mask according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein a width of the adhesive sealing profile is in a range of 2 to 25 mm.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026" num="00026">
<claim-text><b>26</b>. The face mask according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein a width of the intermediate elastic area is in a range of 2 to 25 mm.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027" num="00027">
<claim-text><b>27</b>. The face mask according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein a width of the interface section is 25-35% of a width of the intermediate elastic area.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028" num="00028">
<claim-text><b>28</b>. The face mask according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein a thickness of the elastic material is in a range of 0.1 to 1.5 mm.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029" num="00029">
<claim-text><b>29</b>. The face mask according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein the elastic area extends around the entire central area of the face mask.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030" num="00030">
<claim-text><b>30</b>. The face mask according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00029">claim 29</claim-ref>, wherein the adhesive provided on the bottom surface of the elastic material extends around the periphery of the face mask, such that the adhesive sealing profile circumvents the face mask.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031" num="00031">
<claim-text><b>31</b>. The face mask according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, further comprising a valve arranged in the central area.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032" num="00032">
<claim-text><b>32</b>. The face mask according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00031">claim 31</claim-ref>, wherein the valve is attached to the central area by a snap-fit mechanism.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033" num="00033">
<claim-text><b>33</b>. The face mask according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein the adhesive and/or the elastic material further comprises an anti-septic agent.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034" num="00034">
<claim-text><b>34</b>. The face mask according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein the elastic material is connected to the fabric material of the central area in the interface section by sewing, through an adhesive, or a combination thereof.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035" num="00035">
<claim-text><b>35</b>. The face mask according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein the intermediate elastic area is separated from and not in contact with the face of a user.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application>
